but that composed the car and they have very very little things
there is also the label f four that we
we did in collaboration with bryan russell offices in somewhere here
here our goal was to create annotation tool
that will live online this was also inspired by the CMU game ESP game developed
by this one and the idea was that you put this on the way people
will go there and take more objects and this can grow beyond what a single
up to do
so these are some examples this is a snapshot of the tool online
and you can go to the web page and an image will appear and people
can label objects so here some of the
later this only going here has annotated
the boundary of this object and then a pop-up window will appear i will ask
you what is the name of the subject so here they will say this oppose
and we have collected all the data we have about half a million
annotated objects now
so there is a lot of data when we start in is one of our
concerns was what's going to be the quality that you can get when you ask
people to label images online because you know you don't really give much instructions even
if you put instructions the were page people and they don't really read them anyway
at the beginning we have instructions here and then remove them until people which is
the same some mother
but despite that there is a very good labeling so here are some examples of
the best label that we got so here you can see these three here somebody
has label all the branches here everything all the details or this just here all
the different towers have label even or the police among the oldest is done by
hand stimulated to some people have
the time in the hands
here from the silhouettes here you can tell the gender
just based on the silhouettes of oscilloscope have very very good quality and of course
this is not always the case sometimes we get something in the
and sometimes people get really creative and you have things the these
which is correlated with the image content but not what we want
or things like this
so these two different labelings somebody labelled the book and then somebody else can here
just kill them
and and then denoted at some point we also decided to
allow people to upload images and when you that you open a new kind of
you can imagine but will get uploaded and immediately of course
the point that i loved it
and and body parts that were never meant to be labeled with labels
and the funny thing is that so when i saw that there are hundreds of
images like that i removed them immediately and they were all labeled consistently
and of course only a few weeks later i got an email from a mysterious
alien all my images have disappeared have been here a while so i can really
show you the images but they consider the labels
come to the next scale
so now we move to the millions of images
so now the fence of the powers of six or seven
and here things is really good starting
to get out of hand there are so many images is really hard to know
what they are so now things is really difficult to do by yourself so you
decide to create that few million images just as you cannot do it immediately so
you have to think of other ways of doing it
and there are a number of air force not about trying to get some of
them i already explained them so one is the ESP game at at CMU in
which what they do is they had this game the players will play on the
an image as a result of playing the game images get label so that's one
way of getting a the labels that is the label and for the we are
trying to get there and there are some of the process will be a lot
of skill that's it that's all the time to get very large databases
so there are different strategies
one thing you can get people to play games on the web or you can
do is higher amongst graduate students closed them on roman said to them good appears
the the label million images and that's basically what is being on going on here
so when that said we created is the eighty million images dataset
inc which what we did was we took wordnet which is this electronic dictionary developed
by princeton and we took seventy five thousand words that correspond to a known as
the announcer things that could correlate with this well
this concepts and then we took a bunch of all line search engines
so this was done with focus and he will talk a little bit more about
that than its
so we took seven online image search engines and we starting with all these different
so the seventy five thousand words with that over one g and we don't know
the all the images on google this is that
after you know a lot of time when you don't know images we collected eighty
million images were collected more but many of them were duplicates one journal the journal
of them you joined up with eighty million images and there is a website that
you can navigate and it gives you like an index to all these images
another project also related to this is the imagenet done by fyfe and collaborators in
which they basically do the same thing that they were not to download images correspond
to all these different words but now they choose humans in order to clean up
the labels so they will all the search engines have lot of noise when you
do this one is you don't get what you are asking for dinner and you
get a lot of noise on them and the goal then is to have human
annotators to clean up the labels
so for that they use mechanical turk
mechanical turk is very interesting
application developed by and on
and probably some of you know but for those of you that don't know what
amazon is an online site an application that allows you to interact with walkers so
people that have articles small tasks that can be posted on the web can advertise
their the tasks here
and there are hundreds of thousands of workers that this is this page continuously and
they will look at what are the best available there for a very small amount
of money they will perform the task so
here is an example of putin label me a mechanical turk
and so
just mechanical for computer vision was made most popular by sonication and foresight in
and they show that you can actually get a lot of work done for labeling
images using mechanical turk so this is an example of justin
label me on mechanical turk
and the way that they will look is that this a header that this typical
of song and then here there will be the task w fine
like in this case place labels many of its kind in this image
and the the image appears and is just basically like the label means interface just
click around an object and you countries the polygon and then it will actually the
name and that's what the work has to do
one of them with the task you click submit and you get your money
and really they don't get a lot of money
generally that's going to be paid one cent
and you can wonder what people can do for one cent well it's amazing what
they can once and so here is the schools so the question here is please
label one object in this image taken label anything
but no this guy when labelled the vote
everything all the different peoples of the about once and he could have labelled the
four clicks and you will have got his one set
you know this guy really doesn't have an eye for business
and this is the only one here is another one
one object all these details one cent
of course when we started with say OK maybe this is we are asking only
for one hundred what we ask for the label as much as you want and
what they will do
well they
still don't they will label like about three four different habitats
and despite the just the all opinion once and so i have push it and
is that
if you think about the, I don't know, amount of mass that its that is in the tail
it's so it's so large and the variance here is so large that pretty much everything fails, so what happens with power-laws, right, power-laws are distributions that have infinite expectation, so depending on the slope a power-law distribution can have infinite expectation and infi infini infinite variance
or just infinite variance and so on, so basically
from from how to say it, if you look at the moments depending on the on the slope, all the moments from, I don't know, third, fourth, fifth, doesn't matter on will be infinite, so this is why power-laws are
hard distributions to deal with
and I I think recently that were some papers on statistical tests for power-laws, but what usually people just like to do, they plot this on log log scales
and they are sort of happy with it and that's not good
or we are not too happy about this or I don't know, how to say, but still
evidence that your your distribution has a heavy tail, which would mean that the amount of mass in the tail is
is polinomial and not and doesn't decay exponentially, this can easily be seen or distinguished from the exponential distribution when plotted on log log scales
okay and I can point you to the reference, if you'd like for for these things okay
here I just want to show what is the difference between
poisson and scale-free network or a network that has a a
power-law degree distribution so, right, this would be a erdos-renyi random graph
so the graph that would be created by the process
I introduced earlier, right, and this is how the degree distribution would look like
so this is the graph
on the same number vertices and everything that has a power-law degree distribution and you can immediately see the difference, right, so here pretty mu every node has about the same degree, right, there is there is a the the distribution of the degree has a mode, here we have these hubs, right this would be the node with the highest degree, then there are a lot of nodes that have just the degree of one
right so this is
and what turns out is that real graphs are more like this and they're not like that
another thing with graphs that you can observe is you can ask, how
resilient are they to attacks, right, how how many nodes do I need to remove from the graph, so that the graph falls apart, so the question we are asking is, how does the connectivity of the network change as vertices or edges get removes removed and in the most basic question we can ask two things, we can ask what will happen if the vertices are removed uniformly at random
and what if you just sort them by the degree and start degree removing high degree vertices first
and why is this important, it's important, for example for studies of how epidemics happen in the network and how many people do we need to imunize, so so to sort of disconnect the network that the virus couldn't spread all across it
and here I'm just showing what happens if we remove the node, right, so by removing these two node our network gets disconnected
and what turns out is that real networks are highly robust to node removal
to explain this two graphs, so here we have the graph of the internet
and here we have the average path length and this is the fraction of the nodes we removed
the random node removal is the bottom line, so basically it says that average path length doesn't really change, even if we remove half of the nodes or eighty percent of the nodes, the average path length remains the same, while if we go and remove high degree nodes right if remove the hubs
then we need to remove very small fraction of them and the network falls apart all the all the mean path length increases a lot, okay, and this is intuitively this makes sense
if if our graph is like this, we just remove this guy and we disconnect many many nodes, right, and in a case like that nothing really matters
and here I ha I show
the random graph, the one that I had it on the left, so this is again the random node removal and this is high degree node removal, right, and you can see that the the the
average path length increases much slowly
okay, so what this means is that real graphs are very resilient to random node removal, but if you would go and, I don't know, knock off
top ten
computers on the internet, the internet would fall apart and we see this every day pretty much
the other thing that is also
in the structure of the networks it's called community structure, right, most in the social networks we have this notion of communities that more that similar people are more densily grouped together than they are grouped across commmunities and
he he here would be an example of a friendship network in in some school, right, and here you can see sort of these communities that are more denisily link linked inside that than they are link linked across and there are very different algoritms, how to how to find communities or clusters in the network and you can do spectral clustering, there are methods by newman and et al, but
I I don't want to go into that
there are what you can also do is you can study the spectral properties of the graph adjacent symetrics and here I don't, all I want to say is if if you plot
so yesterday we talked about basic definitions of convex sets and functions and some
we reviewed some applications so in the first lecture today we'll discuss interior
methods that are implemented in many of the general-purpose solvers for convex optimization so these solvers
usually use a conic optimization format that I've explained first and then we'll discuss two methods two
types of interior point methods for convex optimization in this conic format the first one's the
first methods are primal barrier methods and the second one are primal dual methods that are
also more symmetric so what's a conic optimization problem so it's a problem with
conic inequalities and what that means is the following suppose K is a convex cone
and I define an inequality X greater or equal to Y with respect to the cone K
and I use this notation just to mean that X minus Y is in a cone
so I use this inequality sign with the subscript K to denote an inequality with
respect to that convex cone K  so if K is a non-negative orthant then this simply
means that X is greater or equal to Y component-wise right so X
minus Y is in the non-negative otrhant means X greater or equal to Y component-wise
so it's an extension of component-wise vector inequality to other types of  vector
inequalities and I also use this X strictly greater than Y if X minus Y is
in the interior of K so here K can be any convex cone there are
some  conditions you have to impose to actually you know in order to
make sure that these inequalities can be used for example you want the cone to be
pointed and a pointed cone means that if a vector X is in the cone minus
X is in a cone then X is zero so a non-pointed cone would be a line
a straight line through the origin for example is a non-pointed cone so obviously that's something
you would like to have as a condition K if you want to use these
inequality signs otherwise you could have a non zero X that's non-negative and non-positive right you want
nonempty interior in a cone in order to be able to use the strict inequalities and
you want it to be closed for example so these are some technical conditions you impose
on the cones and a convex cone that satisfies them is called the proper cone
and then we use this inequality sign so yesterday we used this type of inequality
for matrices so X greater or equal to zero with this inequality sign
meant X is positive semidefinite here we use it for a general conic inequality we
add the subscript K in the inequality if we mean a particular cone K and we omit
the subscript if it's just a general generic convex cone right so that's definition of a
conic inequality and then a conic linear programming problem is simply defined like this it's defined like
in a standard linear programming problem in inequality form you minimize a linear objective you have
linear inequality constraints but instead of componentwise inequalities we replace this with inequalities respect to
a convex cone right so the special case if K is a non-negative orthant
is a standard PL but we'll look at several interesting nonpolyhedral convex cones
you can use instead so everything else is linear the objective is linear the inequalities are
linear so all the non-linearity  is hidden in the cone really the fact that you
use a nonpolyhedral  cone makes this a general a nonlinear convex problem so it's  widely
used as a standard form in the recent literature on convex optimization for
a mass was
to give you some rough ideas of
what periods will be
substitutes for l one meter
are you take four g nine point eight that this character
you multiply by two pi
and what you find is
that's the period is about two seconds
the pendulum one meter long
as a period of about two seconds
so to go from here to here is about one second
if i make it four times shorter
l four times shorter describe for is two
then the period
the period is changing four times shorter period must be two times short
make roughly twenty five centimetres
i'm not trying to be very qualitative here not whole period must be about one
six roughly one sec
so you see
that the period is extremely sensitive
two the length of the
i now want to
compare with you the results that we have
for spring
with the results that we have
the pendulum to give you
some further insight
we have the string
and we have the pendulum
and i'm only going to look at the period
here is two pi
divided by the square root
m over k
and here is two pi
times square root of l
over g
if i look here
there's a amassing here
independent of the mass
why is the same as in here
that is very easy to see
if i take a spring
and i extend the spring over a certain distance
then there is a certain force
but i feel
that force is independent of the mass of the output at the end of this
the spring doesn't know what the masses you're going to put on all it knows
is i'm too long and i want to go back to a click away
that forces the fixed force if i double the mass
that fixed force will give on double the mass half the acceleration if acceleration goes
down the period of oscillation goes up is very clear
so you can immediately see
that was just plain
the vast must enter into the period
now go to the pendulum
if i double the mass of my bob at the end of the pendulum
the vertical component of the tension will also double
that means this
restoring force which is proportional was attention goes also double
so now the restoring force doubles
and the math doubles acceleration remains the same the period remains the same
so you can simply argue
there should be no mass you know isn't
about this case
if k is high
the spring is stiff if
what does it mean stiff spring it means that if i give it a small
extension that the spring force is which
you have the spring force
acceleration on a given mass will be high
if i have high acceleration the period will be short
and that's exactly what you see
if k is high
the period will be short
imagine that you have a pendulum in outer space there is no gravity nothing
the pendulum will not swing
the period of the pendulum will be infinitely long
going to the shuttle
with the proceeds gravity in their frame of reference
received their wages remember their perceive gravity is zero
you take pendulum in the shuttle you put at this angle you let it go
it will stay there forever and ever and ever the period is infinitely long
but take a spring in the short
and that the spring oscillate and it does
so you can actually measure the mass of an object
using this brain on the shuttle that oscillate if you know the spring constant and
that's the way it's actually done
yes indeed
that these
on the right-hand side
you plug in the current value
you can't guess he said OK can guess and on the left hand side
part the new value
and you stop when the value function stop changing more than a certain amount
so on
and you can sort of arbitrary value function this works
so this is the planning version of policy evaluation when you know the model if
no the model again planning was not going to do exactly the same thing except
for the state action value equations
this is q value iteration same stopping criteria
OK i'm going to be very fast the value function of important things and
the crucial
property that makes all of RL value function based RL work is this notion of
contraction which is that when you do iteration
you might start off with the same as in two-dimensional value function space on national
state space the origin that access is true it is
is that so that's the labelled the stars the true value
the optimal value function you start with an arbitrary guess my point one
and basically at every iteration the maximum the box normal
shrinks by multiplicative factor gamma
so the
maximum error cross any state from state the unknown true value function shrinks by multiplicative
factor gamma this is the underlying principle lorp
the planning out central to the reinforcement learning algorithms that the TV and q learning
out and everyone
at least heard of problem
that was planning
learning is set to a situation where you don't have a real system you don't
have a model
so you don't have a model but you can play in the real system
and so you can generate experience you can be in some status of zero subscripts
and time we take an action you get towards next state action toward these experience
like this
and his pictorial representation you in some state choice of action to take one action
which could lead to a choice of the a distribution on next states you sample
one next state choice of action gives particular trajectory like this is what life looks
like we
taking actions we getting this process
so on
the two classes methods indirect matters indirect methods what is the indirect method most obvious
thing you can imagine we take experience to estimate the model
here is the simplest
nonparametric form of a model estimation just to the empirical estimates of the probability of
seeing state j one x nine state a take current model
find the politics often with respect to it and that's the estimate of the on
policy scholar seventy good policy
it's long get enough data model to converge and the are supposed converge
of course you can use parametric models and much much more things that is this
is the flavor of in direct indirect direct chris watkins developed this q learning which
is exactly the same
recursive form that you've seen before except of course you can't take expectations so you
just take the
the part that i to point part that the square brackets without front is the
sample of the recursive formula the recursion iteration you would do
so the actual what you get a discount best value of the actual state again
because you get a noisy estimate you don't
move fully to the new estimate you mix it with your list
that's collected
in and
basically it's a noisy a noisy contraction
stochastic approximation theory works and that's the result that q learning convert property one
so much more
so so far i tell you what an MDP definition is what the planning and
learning algorithms are
four for policy evaluation optimal control
i was the first to learning i thought i'd say this because chris is here
the first provably convergent adaptive control system and then made a huge
huge social logical and practical impact in in reinforcement learning
this sometimes works stochastic sometimes work something does
OK so why aren't we done
well part of it is have until you sold exploration exploitation problem and that is
how do we actually the q learning to learn the value function then tell you
how to behave
now you you've got the optimal q value function then you are ahead but you
don't know how do you how do we hear why learning OK well one answers
epsilon really just
some small property explore
now exploit and you can provide conditions under which is
and we have the other really interesting class of ideas which i'll just say one
sentence but there are tons of papers that soldier field here
it's called the idea of optimism under uncertainty
this beautiful work has been done
in the exploration exploitation problem with the following idea
whenever you uncertain about something
about transition probability somewhere
four songs or you value functions
more optimism then maybe towards
c pretend things you don't know
that the things you know
and that leads but of course if you keep doing that then you forever
explore and that's not good so that the amount of optimism has to go down
over time
so shrinking optimism under uncertainty shrinking in time optimism under uncertainty is a class of
ideas starting from
exploration bonus work the today and the the first sort of the really
i did this right and then a whole bunch of algorithms that have been are
being produced even today
exploits idea optimism optimism under uncertainty and it gets really nice strong results
polynomial time results
for optimism under uncertainty so if you if you if you find this topic interesting
to lots of things to read about
and finally i'm just again only one sentence there's bayesian class of methods where
you're doing
planning if you like
in the state of knowledge rather than physical state
and if you plan state of knowledge you can make you can optimally solve the
exploration exploitation problem i would say much more about that so that's
that's so that solutions to exploration exploitation
so now again what what's already done we can we do can we solve the
problem of building a second live in the real world
it really is stochastic
of course not because all the things that only about more or less fall for
but that of course is not practical so how do we deal with
scaling and again this is the last bit of on the table and then one
of the more interesting parts are very quickly that you've never or not been exposed
to enforce community maybe forty percent if you didn't raise your hand something like that
i give you a quick tour
of these ideas
so the function approximation ideas the most obvious ones instead of storing things in the
lookup table distorting the function approximation can favor function approximator
backprop electrical basis functions c-max nearest neighbour decision trees whatever
just replace
indexing things into a table with a parametric or whatever the parametric form is linear
and very partial linear but then the only idea of course
so there are other extensions of gas in processes
there are
the couple i can talk about
in this slide are two
and then
o i
i could say a couple words about there's a process mixtures people are interested
this is a fruitful area i mean there are lots of things you can do
if you if you wanted to nonparametric bayesian things you're forced into coming up with
new ideas because
you know you never satisfied with how flexible your car model is
cholera snow's and i were not very satisfied with gas processes
a few years ago
just the ordinary gasoline prices because
it is difficult to specify really flexible covariance functions so
you want you might have data where the function has varying spatial frequency like here
it's more weakly here unless we hear you might have varying signal amplitude here it's
more it's less you have varying noise level
like more noise here last night here and this sort of stationary covariance functions don't
handle that very well
another problem with gas processes is the prediction in training requires
finding an inverse of this covariance matrix which to be exact is order and q
of the we can try to approximate it so
both of these things can be fixed to some extent
applying is sort of divide and conquer strategy
so what we're going to do
divide of the input space into different regions and have different gases processes for these
different parts of the input space
this is an idea very similar to an old idea called mixture of experts
except we're not going to divide it up reorient to these regions really let the
learning algorithm to find the reason regions on its own
and the other thing we wanted to do is we don't want to restrict
priority how many regions there were we don't want to say find me five regions
it turns out using some tricks
from the sun to talk about
for a couple minutes in the second half
we can actually remove that restriction we can just say
there are countably infinite number of regions
you don't have to have a finite number of regions
but don't worry about that sort of
the trick which makes it even more nonparametric
and the basic idea is that you can have different covariance functions in different parts
of the space
and once you do that you can handle all of these kinds of things
another property of this is that by dividing up the space you're also dividing the
the dataset into the datapoints belonging to one gaussianprocess versus another casting process was another
casting process so instead of doing one big order and q
matrix inversion you can split up the order and q to be into smaller
matrix inverses for each
o thing so
for any particular partitioning of the data
this divide and conquer policy
is faster but you have to do inference over all possible
it is also
my model
multimodality in this space there are some reasons why this prior functions is not so
nice because
you have to put in sufficient to the function
in this region has to match with the function in this region you can spin
it to make some positive by saying you've multimodality or you can make it sound
negative by saying you have a weird function that can jump from this is that
part of this part
i don't know depends on your application whether that's a good thing
the last sort of thing the last kind of snapshot i want to give is
that you can do that you can learn the kernel parameters using
a combination of e and this EP algorithm
which i know could tell you about how these you're interested in
and this is the nice property that that you get policies have is that you
can learn the kernel from data
and the way you do that is just you think
we tried to get process latent variable models you think of the
function values is being hidden and then you have an algorithm if you're familiar with
that and when you want to infer the latent function values in your e step
you do some sort of inference like this EP
which are not going to talk about now this work is really
much inspired by work by over winter healthsouth income here seeger
so some of these guys are here in the room
let me conclude about casting processes
their general framework for nonparametric function approximation
and they can be extended in several ways
an old one is classification
there are other ones like one regression ordinal regression in mixture of casting process experts
it is straightforward to infer the kernel from data using bayesian methods and CMC in
the past so MEP algorithm
i have about
zero minutes maybe
i sort of predicted this
that's why this
how think
i think this is just passes
let me just take
you know
half of my remaining time
and just tell you
a couple words about a different thing that's nonparametric and bayesian OK to say don't
think it's all only gas processes
don't look at any equations
OK that'll make it faster
everybody probably knows what gas the mixture model is
now usually in a gas mixture model you have to decide on some finite number
of components k and you find the maximum likelihood settings of these parameters using the
EM algorithm
a dirichlet process mixture
or in particular dirichlet process mixture of gaussians
is a beautiful trick for
so rather than having a finite number of components you can have countably infinite number
so that sort of in doing elimination in the usual forward way i get to
i'm going put glasses on so that i can
capture this fantastic problem right
so this is
in the forward direction all indicate those by plus
the standard eliminating forward now i don't know if you ever gave any thought to
the possibility of doing the elimination
starting at the bottom row and working upward
the viewer was no reason we couldn't do that
in that order from one to n isn't
the only possibility
what what what will happen if i do elimination upwards
and we just pretend have matrix here
what do i do then
i've taken multiple of that row
subtract from the row above
to produce zero there
then i got something new than that from the robot
now what kind of factors one of my one of my guess my original he
was tried diagonal
i'm coming from
upward direction
and one of my reaching
reaching in l
so the region you are reaching l
the factorizations
in the opposite direction would be a u
finds the
times and
and i just have to give those
those that l is different from the other l
and that's like the reverse
the reverse LDU OK
and that's the
so that's coming up now here's the fantastic four no
we're interested in
are inverse
the inverse
the entries on the diagonal of the inverse
that's what all this stuff is going to be about
OK and here's the formula for
that it's
the plus it's the diagonal entry of the plus
and the diagonal entries of d minus
minus the diagonal entry of t
well i call that night
and the need for
and but i don't call
only answers that i've seen to this question which i don't have with i don't
know the answers with
i don't call them
and i feel that if i really
if i were kalman
i could
i'd say oh yeah that's that
that's the formula
and of course i guess i believe that if this
four is true which i think it is
that would
generalized to blocks
let me take one released like
special case of this formula
suppose let's look at what common is most important looking at the let the n
k equal and
that n by n block of
the last
so what's the
what do i get when k is an
when i went there so the point is this is true for all the middle
between one and
but i we conceive quickly why it's true it and similarly quickly why it's true
so i'm just hoping you might
like realizes like press
all right let me take a to be and
what is the
what is the minus and and
it's the diagonal entry c
end we know there was any time admissible mess things up we do that this
is rho n
what i'm saying is that that is the same as that
i matrix t
with and and guy in the corner
and when i do elimination of words still there never
never got to call the alterations
happened upwards
if if k is an
and this is just saying that members the and an entry three
it's the same as
the end entry
of the
and that's all i want to say is that special case is clear
that is if i'm looking at k ghulam and that's the same as that
it's just the regular
last inverse
and that's what calman has to be computed
his colonies
in this
in this part before it does any smoothing he's going for the and and the
most recent one
and that's this is the quantity we want and it's the block here so
cameron has to do elimination
on this
on this matrix
so that's a comment whether with the question of repeatedly
and the notes
i guess you and i should feel that if we don't find the answer because
a lot of other people didn't find but then
it would be nice to do it in nice to do an interesting way
all the possibility that out of
out of our own
work on something
it's of interest outside too
well one of my going to do with common
when i write down some of those formulas so we got five things then the
new you
there is more damping here damping force here let's see can really talk that way
since the units of different but does this number is bigger than that 1
it seems clear at any rate OK now what's the characteristic equation look now watch
please do what I do or even by I found in the past even by
the middle of the terms but there are still students who feel that they must
substitute y equals e to the RT and go through that whole little derivation defined
and you don't do that it's a waste of time I did it that you
might not ever have to do it again OK
immediately right down the characteristic equation that's not very or squared plus 4 more or
less 3 equals 0
and you can write down its roots immediately splendid but let's not assume that level
of competence or so it's ah + 3 times or plus 1
equals 0
OK factor all of this being 18
0 3 alot of the times the routes will be integers when they're not God
forbid you use the quadratic formula OK but here the rotor integers is after all
in the 1st example so the solution the general solution is y equals c one
e to the negative notice the root is minus 3 and minus 1 minus 3
T plus the 2
In e to the negative
now suppose you its initial value problem so I gave you initial conditions both the
initial conditions where that's why 0 or 1
so at the start of the mass masses been moved over to the position 1
here will we expected them to
start doing that but this is fairly heavily damped this is heavily damped I'm going
to assume that the mass starts at rest so as in the standard the spring
is the standard masses over here but there is no motion at time 0 this
way or that way in other words I'm not pushing it on just releasing it
and letting it do its thing after that OK so why prime of zero all
assume is 0
so it starts at rest but in the extended position
1 unit to the right in front of the equilibrium position
now all you have to do is
use these 2 conditions notice I have 2 conditions because there are 2 constants I
have to find the value of
alright so
let substituted
quality we're going to have to calculate the derivatives so when we do that right
away so this is minus 3 C 1 you minus 3 T
of minus C 2 the to the negative
and now by substituting at 0 0
when t equals 0
for get will 1st equation the left says the y of 0 should be 1
and the right says this is the 1 that's 1 so it's c 1 +
C 2 as the result of substituting t equals 0
all about substituting which I substitute in the 2nd equation well why prime 0 0
0 0 so the 2nd equation when I put into equals 0 let's solid is
0 according to that initial value and the right side is negative 3 C 1
make minus
you see would you end up with therefore force a pair of simultaneous linear equations
and this is why you learn to study linear search pairs of simultaneous linear equations
in high school
these are among the most important
solving problems of this type are among the most important applications that kind of algebra
and this kind of algebra
right what's the answer finally well if I add the 2 of them I get
minus 2 C 1
equals 1 so
C 1 is equal to
minus 1 half
and 1 is minus higher than C 2 is minus 3 C 1 so it
it's C 2 is 3 halves
the final question is what is that look like as a solution while in general
these combinations of 2 exponentials on very easy to plot by yourself 0 that's 1
of the reasons you are being given this little visual which plots them for you
all you have to do is as you'll see set the damping constant set the
constants set the initial conditions if by magic the curve appears on the screen and
if you change the either the either the constants the curve will change nicely right
along with it
so solution is
the solution is
y equals minus one half
and if you make each guest kind of independently you know if you're ninety percent
accurate each step of the way are basically guaranteed to be run by the time
you done so
one of the park's real accomplishments was finding way too
pac only get together and avoid resolving it until you have more information in the
pipeline that took a very long time to actually work not just through the sort
of shallow levels of syntax but all the way through the semantic processing pipeline that
was really big accomplishment another big accomplishment was only done kind of in the last
seven years which was integrated statistics into the whole system
before that there there was no knowledge to prefer one partial interpretation of the others
and then there was the amount of work done integrating the school methods with the
with the sort of the pure linguistic methods
so that's one set of things the other set was really around more slots
OK that the computing resources didn't just didn't exist so
when when powerset came start working with park
they were very excited because they had this sort of seven hundred sentences that they
OK and those things could take a long time and now
it's not
i really do before
so i like to say that computing resources five years ago
if you're thinking about passing the whole web and went past the hole and yet
we're starting with millions of documents getting our algorithms down there and then scaling but
five years from now five five years ago no amount of computing the whole planet
could do this
and five years from now
it's going to look relatively cheap
and you know right now is interesting time where things are converging so
i guess that this shore short answer is that the technology actually kind of got
to a point where the team themselves like can be commercially viable which was not
the case for thirty years the available to community resources like wordnet available to web
scale data as you could use statistics on it and large amount of computing resources
have all kind of converge to make these things possible to extend we're doing now
that were not possible earlier
and i think the question was other advantages to asking structured queries as opposed to
natural language queries
so yes if you could just let people access structured queries they it of course
it's actually
much better from a systems perspective because it doesn't have to risk getting wrong interpretation
of the user's query
so we actually have a system
maybe i'll even show it here
OK so
here's a much deeper system that we have for development which generates the query execution
like that
and then goes down and takes the graphical structures and ultimately has scoring and everything
like that and that when we play with this
we were able to do a really great things by working correctly and that kind
of query language and so so yes you could do really great things the challenge
there is will users actually will consumers actually do it
that that's your question but certainly can do really great things by doing structured queries
the system
so let's see the first question was about
and do we have statistics on how well our system performs
and various other task so
the basic answer is yes
we do internally we measure
accuracy at the semantic role level
accuracy of sort of named entity extraction recognition
so any step of the pipeline we to measure accuracy and then the at the
higher level we measure overall search relevance so
given the query
take all the results to come back and we have human you know people
actually going to evaluate the result quality
so we can compute metrics compare ourselves to other kinds of search techniques and so
on that the overall system level
there are interesting things which is which are that the improvement in a given component
may or may not actually making improvement at the overall level of perceived relevance by
users and other than that i mean there's some components and these things work in
progress i don't have specific things about the exact specific accuracy
the second question is about our business model
however small is really two two parts one is direct-to-consumer so
like other search engines have a search engine users can come
and use and make money of advertising so
users can you know users can use that advertisers can say the kind of users
they like to reach basically connect then were also interested in licensing our technology to
other people who are who have large set content to make their own search better
or to the large search engines to help them you know make some of the
queries better touch language
as you saw this these kinds of examples
you know
with with power mouse
being able to go on group of these kinds of entities well then you can
go and say OK well we already if we know the dinosaurs that analysis sources
of dinosaur we know what our sources have
and we know that you know what think will probably dinosaurs have and what properties
in reptiles have then you can really make some very interesting much cleaner ontologies can
be used by other systems really we haven't done working that yet we're excited to
and certainly will be interested to collaborate with people and we will be planning to
put out an API so that people can go and take these things and no
doubt about the raw data and going going user more
OK so the question is with respect your interaction freebase
how exactly a little bit more detail about how that works because clearly freemasons has
its own terminology
and then there's wordnet and how those things actually go together work and then how
that applies to sort out and more different things
so i think the first thing is that as we all know these kind of
problems are hard
and so
you know i don't i don't know the powerset has better answers on that and
then a lot of people here in and in the community in fact we look
to this work to help make these kind of ontology mapping integration better one specific
interesting challenges out freebase
some pretty cool things it's going on outside vision as well
quick outline here we don't have time to time to go through a sort of machine learning refresher crash course
just kind of
sort of refresher if you take machine learning class but it's been a while or
you have taken machine learning class maybe been through like intro
ai something
sort of the sense for how machine learning is done how it works
and then we're going to go through sort of natural extension of that
to supervised deep learning
and sort of
give you
so tools for actually training deep neural network so the basic algorithms used there
and then also
tell you a bit about what the application specific things we want to use for computer vision or
if you want to use neural networks for vision problems
turns out you need some extra ingredients to with those are
also a bit about debugging
i'm just a couple slides on that
and then i'll go back to what maybe story more familiar to some of you who've been
watching deep learning for a while
which is about unsupervised deep learning
involves using unsupervised algorithms where we don't have label data
for trying to train deep networks
and then at the very end we have some references resources are for you guys to pick
on the web
including link to tutorial that you can do online later
in supervised learning
sort of a common mode that we want to operate an
we're we're going to be given a whole bunch of training examples
and our training examples all have label associated with them
that usually given to us by human some kind of system with a lot of knowledge it
basically we have a whole bunch of pairs
so the first element of this pair is vector x
and this is essentially our input data it's the thing that we're given
and then we have some output y which is the vac variable that we want to predict
and why could be a vector could be a whole bunch of continuous quantities are might
be discrete
so for example
or in the case we've been talking about someone as an image and i would like to
is cat
we could represent cat as a vector of
pixel intensities
and then we're going to
pass through some function i'm just going to call f of x here
and they were asked to predict the discrete
binary label either zero if it's not a cat
or one if it is cat
and the question for machine learning
for supervised learning algorithm is
to try to find some f of x so that it correctly predicts the label y
on all of our training examples of whatever i put x sin correctly says as cat
or not cat for all the examples are as many examples as possible
in the training set that we've been given
and hopefully if all goes well
this learned predictor is going to work on some test data so if i give you an
image you've never seen before
you actually get the correct prediction out of it
so one review very simple binary classification algorithm so
if you want to actually solve this problem
one thing that you could try doing
is to start from a function has this form so
it's f acts and then this will semi-colon here just means that
the variables to the right are sort of parameters but you can just think of x and theta here has been
to inputs to f
and f of x is going to have this definition words one over one plus acts of minus
the inner product or dot product of of data indexed
so this linear function here
is really to i'm
going to try to give positive values
to things that are cats and is going to try to give negative values to things not cats and
this nonlinear function that sort of wrapped around it which i'm label sigma everywhere
is a sigmoid function you can just think of it as a squashing function which is going to take this
otherwise linear value and scrunched down so it fits
into the range between zero and one
and the reason we want to do that and so that we can interpret the output
of this function f acts as a probability
so our goal is to try to train
this f of x function
to tell us the probability that same picture in this image represented by acts
is actually kept
so we want to be large
when y is equal to one meaning it's cat and we want to be small y equals zero
meaning it's not cat
and to do that not going to go through exactly where this function comes from
but this is an objective function that we want to minimize
so basically
what we want to do here
is this cost function or loss function as a function of theta
tells us how well our function f fits our training data so i'm going to do
a sum over all the examples
and whatever the label is one
i want to basically make
this value here large
which is actually the probability why is one
and whatever labels says that zero i want to make this probability very small
so if we find
that the data that minimizes this that's also going to be the one
that makes good predictions on our training set
so how we actually tunes data to minimize this thing
one algorithm that we can actually used to do this and fact there are lots of algorithms we could choose
but almost all share the same basic approach
which is that we need to compute the gradient
of this loss function
and this is something you can do by hand for logistic regression if you just go
pull your calculus book compute a bunch of derivatives
then you find that the gradient looks like this
you can pass this to some off the-shelf optimizer if you want
or you can just implement your own gradient descent algorithm where we do is we pick
some initial guess for data that could just be random values
and then we're going to do is every time
we want to make up date we compute this gradient
and then we make a small change to data points in the negative direction so remember that the gradient
is pointing in the uphill direction so if i change data in the opposite direction go down el
so this is a very simple optimization algorithm
i'm going to return to this with ways to make a much better
when we talk about
deep learning
and finally i'm sort of
technical difference and when we actually implement this is what we have a lot of data
we don't sum over the whole dataset we just take a few examples maybe one example one hundred examples
and compute the gradient from those
before we make an update
that way we can make lots of updates very quickly and hopefully make more progress
so it turns out this is pretty nice
function that i showed you that we want to minimize is convex
so that very simple optimizer i showed you was always going to take you to some nice minimum one you set
step size properly
and this works for simple problems so if i give you these digits zeros and ones
and to give you the labels that tells you whether there's zero or one it turns out
this this classifier work great
but the reason that works
is because there's some pixels in these things turn out to be very highly informative
so for example the pixel in the center
usually tell whether it's zero or one
because the zeros in the whole
and one it's it's turned on
so it turns out that linear function works pretty well
but if i give you something more complex
that you know to our eyes these very simple
this algorithm will fail completely
so for example if i ask you or is this a coffee mug
or you have
very little hope you can take my word for because this is a problem that i've
played with for quite it for quite a while
to related problem
if you want to compute
i can functions of integral operators there again
computing eigen vectors you can do it you can solve differential equations in integral form
so if you have a good integration method you can compute the standing waves
alpha particle in a box around the optimal
and you can you know
lasers and all these quantum things
they can also study the physical properties of objects statistical properties
materials and so on
and basically think that last but there is
it's all about monte carlo in this setting is all about counting lot very quickly
here's an example of how you can use the full simulation this comes from a
graph paper of the journey and foresight
if i can get this to right
the got that have
sorry about the formatting of difficulty with this
just by
this is a monte carlo simulation of dice
you know like the casino
and yes some people really love things that they did is to try to make
things that are realistic look realistic
that looks like three or by computer program
but at the same time you have full control the thing
so in particular if your servant
the one goes to one of the two will go to it two
the three will go to three
and so on
so it's like if you designing computer games you want to create realistic settings
and you want to at the same time have control of these
you know some people in the graphics literature have been doing this
there's quite a few more examples
just showing one
we're going to be more interested with using monte carlo to the machine learning is
this machine learning summer school
and so the idea is you know we were trying to come up with
some sort of model
of the world
i'm using attacked to describe the world of forces
and we would like to do something is good this so
let me give you now for another cookie
you go is another
there's a bunch of things here
and i have highlighted three of the two class
i one to here
another one here
and this is the third to
so for of cooking
OK to asked this question
you think side
the arguments less
that's a good question
will come back to that
can someone tell me let's indexed this will be rolled the columns of this is
two one
three one to three two
in one
o point out where there's true for
three four
this guy
how many people agree that this is the two four
i mean it people think it's not too far
OK so whoever that cannot get the cooking
OK another one
i would say many people agree
the great
how about
let me make one might and i
this guy how many people think that i think this goes through
if people think it
this is how much freight company
two thing is that you have
what about the two forward like a baby to for growing and
OK so that the
but it was later quite a few people chose not to vote
i have no clue what to do about it
all i know is i can take a bunch of tricks symbols i can tell
you what are two first
and very quickly in
there is
you actually made a pretty strong opinions of what to was
and what was not
and sometimes
and also was subjective system
didn't take on the same features
this kind of very fast learning very kind of strike action is
what we would like to build a given day to be able to do this
and actions
what justin bangles them the induction leads
we very quickly learn
what something is
so using bayes rule so the idea is want to learn this given the data
we want to learn this hypothesis and bayes rule provides us with the mechanism for
that as long as we have a prior model of the hypothesis and we have
the data and this is the sort of simulation ideas for my class
the sheep
you know a child might have a distribution indicating
you know according to the height of this
how likely something is to be a shape
and so there's a few goats there because god kind of
cookies have arrived
others can i mean the
the guides were asking the question then let's look
all come into play
by the time
OK it'll come to me but said
I'm going to leave this example
to finish OK and the beauty of the of the sliding boards
I can make it go away and cannot
let me let me not doing yeah let me
take a 2nd example
me take a 2nd example where the matrix is singular
so rank 1
OK so let me take as an example to
where are my matrix a is going to be a rectangular again
let me make that may just make it for 3
OK that's a rank one matrix
so that the null space
and only a one-dimensional
rose space and column space so actually that that might buy picture it becomes easy
for this matrix
because what's my columns of my rose space for this 1 so this is 2
by 2
so my my pictures of both two-dimensional my
my rose space is all multiples of that vector for 3
so that all the row space is just a line right
that's the row space and the null space of course is the perpendicular so the
row space
for this matrix is multiple
but of course
for 3
a typical wrong OK with the column space
the columns are all multiples of 4 3 6 1 2
the column space then goes in and like this direction
so the column space
when I look at those columns the columns space only dimensional to the rank is
1 its multiples of
all of for 8 OK
and what's the null space of A transpose
the perpendicular
there's so this was the null space
of 8 and this is the null space of A transpose OK
what I want to say here is that the
that choosing these orthogonal basis
for the row space and the columns space is like no problems
that there only one dimensional
so what should be the
they should be
V 1 but yet the ones that have the wines is supposed to be a
unit vector there's only 1
the wondered choose here only 1 dimension in the row space I just wanna make
it a unit vectors so the 1 will be
be this vector but made into a unit vector so
4 . 8 . 6
453 350
and what will be you want you want will be the unit vector there so
I wanna turn for 8 or 1 true into a unit vectors so you want
will be
the it's 1 2 minutes what multiple of 1 to do I want that has
length square root of 5 so I have to divide by square root of
let me complete the singular value decomposition for this made
so this matrix
4 3 8 6
so I know what you want here's the here's a
and I wanna get you the basis and
column space
and it has to start with the
1 over the square root of 5 2 over square of
then I 1
the signal
what expecting our 1st signal
where is what this is only about is only a rank one matrix where only
expecting a signal 1
which I have to find
0 0 OK so what signal was
if we should see that should be
where where did the signals coming from
they came from a transpose
so I can do that little calculation over here A transpose is
for 3 4 3 8 6
times 4 3 8 6
this had better this is a rank one matrix this is gonna be the whole
thing will have rank 1 that 16 and 64 is 80
12 and 48 is 16
12 and 14 years 60 and 9 36 and 45 OK it's a rank rank-one
Of course
every row is a multiple of 4 3
and what's the eigen the eigen values of the matrix
so this is like the calculated like practising now what are the eigenvalues of this
rank one matrix
well tell me when eigen value since the rank is only once
1 eigen value is going to be
and then you know that the other eigen value is going to be
so that's sigma squared right in a transpose so this will be the square root
of a twenty
and then finally
the UV transpose
the movies will be
there is the 1
and wanted the to
wants me to
what's how do I make this into it
orthonormal basis
well the 2 is
all in the null space direction it's it's perpendicular that's 0 . 6 and minus
so those are the visa go going here
. 6
and . 6 minus point
and I guess a better finishes here so this guy
all I want is to complete the orthonormal basis be coming from their it'll be
2 over square root of 5 and a minus 1 over square of I could
have taken to take square 5 out of that
matrix to make it look better
so 1 over square root of 5
at times 1 2
minus 1
well we're going to get
when we do
show that these are equivalent i'm just
hands of approach because of the air and it's quite long enough have time
you think
to one of these proofs
converting something like this
and then
that i is where you take
they have offices in here and it
to them
you do to the later
it's something it implied by all the hypothesis sorry
to do that sort
here it is stated that are in the input semicolons between the position of the
i was thinking of the mission to
i just wrote a paper on this
but i was converting
two sequent calculus but to a hilbert style so
that's the difference
now the disjunction rules as usual a little bit fiddly
production ones aren't
this is straightforward the disjunction
elimination rule
a little bit for
i mean that
exactly the destruction you think about it
in those terms
the disjunction introduction rules
the fitch style system
now mission rules a little bit different
and every very very interesting i had interesting to us writing notes for this particular
really interesting consequence that
i had no idea
the great both
four five times actually
four times
the two anonymous course and that's a in in logic
the notice this this particular feature that and what was interesting is a male two
and you never noticed the there's something very very
right then it's informative here
you need some make
what this tells us that if we had the structure why would replace
and then that
and we
the structure would be in in
place today
and it entails
and x
turnstiles entails a or b
we could replace
they are the with access to get c
this is sort transitivity
four transitivity
it tells us
if we can get this from
a or b and we could get a
from x we could use x instead
and now this one is very different about this rule and all the rest
navigation and this is the rules get complicated and we're they get where they get
we just don't have that much time and what i don't want to
OK good morning over the weekend your assigned
material from chapter one of the test and they don't really with three
famous beginnings of pieces of classical music somebody tell me at the outset what were
those three famous pieces
and lady down here
OK beethoven's fifth symphony what was the second one
piano concerto number one of tchaikovsky and the third one
this piece by ricard straus with this funny sounding german name will just call it
our approach this profits are interested in those with three pieces and the issues there
had to do with musical genre that we're going to talk a little bit more
about it a moment and the instruments
the instruments and you went ahead and work with listening exercises nine to eleven to
engage the musical instruments a bit in those particular exercises and we have performers here
today there are going to as you can see a demonstrate some of these instruments
instruments for us
let's make one point very clear at the outset
often times i get student papers refer to beethoven's fifth song or tchaikovsky's
first piano song
now that's that's not good at all
i these songs
what you have to have to make something is all
you get have ten
so we don't have in eighty percent of classical music we don't have the right
we don't have attacked well yes with opera of course but the other eighty percent
is purely instrumental music it works its magic again through purely instrumental so we can't
really call those songs and this puzzle me one day i was sitting there and
i two and i wanted to buy an interior movement of the modes are serenade
so i was all set to purchase this said by
so far
that told me into that's where this terminology comes into play because an item is
we buy song it could be purely instrumental but it's called by us all
but we don't want to use that sort of parlance we want to be more
and more sophisticated than that if you will and use other terms so we'll talk
generally about beethoven's compositions beethoven's piece or beethoven's work or his master worker schedule for
our fancy you want to get where we could also go on and be a
little little more precise and say it belongs to a particular genre we could use
the name of the genre now be talking a lot about usual in this course
genre is simply a fancy word for type or kind so what genre of peace
is this by told well it's symphony
symphonies have four movements have four movements what some movement
well a movement is simply an independent piece
it works often times the multiple movements in a symphony or concerto works with other
movements they are independent yet they are complementary
think of for example a sculpture garden you might have four independent sculptures in there
but they relate one to another they make some sort of special sense one to
another so symphonies have these four movements and they usually operate in the following way
of fast opening movement a slower more lyrical second movement then a third movement that
derive from the dance and then a fourth movement for movement that sort of again
uptempo fast emphatic conclusion
let's see how these play out let's see how things play out by means of
a quick review of beethoven's fifth symphony so we're going to do here and it
is going to go from the beginning of the track for the first movement of
the second movement and so on and was just start let's just by way of
of refreshing your memory the beginning of beethoven's fifth symphony
although there and we said last time it operates
in that fashion and that beginning gives us a good opportunity to make a distinction
between two types of melody between this idea of a motive
and a theme both are sort of subsets of melody if you if you will
as i say in the textbook there is the beginning of the beethoven fifth something
like a musical punch in the nose right about it and grabbing here he interface
whatever music it's not very long idea how many nodes in this opening gambit here
four but short rods OK so that's a classic example of a motive motor just
a little cell and you're out of which the composer will build other musical material
my name is alexander the roads
from united technologies research centre this is the story real
using different data mining techniques for
anomaly detection
and this is a joint work with people from university of minnesota where i was
there earlier
the start how many of you
working in the field of an infection
right now
a few people by some other interested to
get involved in this area because of its
one of the input field so this would be like
outline of the story of the first to give some brief introduction
they cover different aspects of anomaly detection in different applications we will present some taxonomy
anomaly detection techniques can be
classified and present some of these techniques
and finally present some case study
i made some changes from the
slides that you can probably
on your proceedings
so you can
download the new version of light my website
you can copy from here
not many changes but still some time to do some new slides which don't have
so you can just send me email and
you know i also need the link and the presentation
it's easier for you
OK so so much continue
OK so
as you know real doing work in data mining and we thank thee
drowning the data but at the same time we started for the knowledge this is
the famous actors from eight to whole field of data mining begins
and whoever in spite of this large amounts of data in particular is this is
still quite rare
and this is this is me here we have a dramatic influence
and often in a negative sense
what actually anomalies
if you have any
so what is actually
better in a way that does not belong to like regular behaviour does not
belong to expected behavior
from the data
and on this also referred to as
outliers some people called it the particularities some people call it surprises
and so and so on
in instances where anomaly detection can be useful cyber intrusions
for example when you try to catch
the senior computer network of computer credit card fraud detection than out of
millions of credit card transactions people do all over the world
some people still continues in fraudulent
also different forcing mechanical systems for example if you collect the data
when you're playing on your car and you also have to figure out
there sort of false can be coming or if you want to take that unfolds
in advance before they happen
so all of this application basically
anomaly detection can be important
as i said
these are real world anomalies
and i mentioned the credit card fraud detection and cyber intrusions
so this is a simple example what normally can be
so far
so let's assume that we have these
this big
groups of data
and one into the correspond to normal here
coins that did not conform to this number here
simplicity or one or two may be typical of of anomalies
also the small groups of data that are far from anything else may also be
considered as anomalies this is really after application sometimes
this may correspond to be here or sometimes this may correspond to
to some group for example if you're dealing with the network intrusion detection
in the network intrusion detection there are computer text called denial-of-service attacks
analysis of service attacks there is no single natural connection involved in that attack there
is usually hundreds of that you can actually be involved in that tag but
and they look quite a normal and then you want to make the difference between
them you want to see coming that regressions appear in the last few
a few seconds coming from specific source that's probably the best way to that this
kind of text so basically to construct additional features
to make this data points most of us would be form the clusters which is
far from anything else so it's not necessarily the anomalies only the single instances
so the dimension that people from different communities call the problem of anomaly detection
with different names some of them are using the rare class mining summarises in china
people use novelty detection exception mining noise removal and recently there is a book by
nasim talib the black swan
it's basically a very interesting book and his explaining why there is a huge impact
on this highly improbable events like the nine eleven
or predicting the stock market which may cause these days and so on
so what are the key challenges when you're doing anomaly detection
so first the big challenge is to define our representative the normal
region usually
it's hard to get
clear understanding what is normal especially when
you don't have the label so there's another challenge the labelled data for training is
not usually available for example in many real life applications have any labels you don't
know what is normally knows what is normally if you're lucky you may know what
is normal sometimes you know
several types of faults that may
help you in your analysis
also the boundary between normal and
outlying or anomalous behavior is not clear sometimes you have to figure it out and
also the
exact notion of an outlier is
a different for different application for example
if you have the same kind of data set
OK we have more people
if you go the same
data sets that correspond to for example network intrusion detection log correspond to fault diagnostics
if the tax system
in the data set one
from one application may be perfect behaviour while normally in another data set may correspond
of probability theory
what i want to know now is what is now my belief about
given that i have observed one
head OK
bayes rule tells me that what i have to do is i have to multiply
my prior probabilities pi times the likelihood
OK and the likelihood is simple i i have it here is justified so basically
i have multiplied by by the beta distribution with whichever parameters i had earlier OK
now if i do that
actually things come out extremely simple
the posterior
is also beta distribution
and that's a very cool thing is very convenient thing
and technically what this means is that
the beta distribution is the conjugate prior to the to the bernoulli distribution
so you say that if you have the likelihood function
and if you pick a prior that when you multiply the posterior comes out in
the same
distribution family as a as a prior when you called conjugate
now i have my personal strong opinion about conjugate priors like to share with you
conjugate priors are
essentially motivated by
convenience most of the time
i'm perfectly fine with them
they're not limiting
but if
if you force yourself to choose a conjugate prior
just because you are lazy
and if you want to get nice distributions that are in the same family as
the prior and you don't want to get
things that are analytically intractable right because sometimes the problem is you can't even compute
the normalizing constant you multiply an arbitrary likelihood by an arbitrary prior and you need
to you know that to get the posterior need to compute the normalisation constant
well tough luck sometimes you can write
i just want to raise a word of caution here
which is
the most important thing is that you're certain
that the fact that the prior you've specified is not very limiting or is not
biasing the whole thing dramatically OK
so if
if conjugacy means that you're going to betray
your prior in a certain sense
then you should just not
so now we can turn on the record again so this was offline
OK so i have a bit
have observed ahead and now it all makes sense right we had said that i
find it unlike like pseudocount in way right there in the way i expressed my
prior as in sort of using pseudo counts so now the number of pseudo counts
increase the final phase is the one that takes care of the heads or make
sense right so how does it look like in pictures
it looks like this i had these two possible priors earlier OK beta one one
beta three three and now observed overserved ahead a single head so how is the
posterior going look like well both posteriors sort of gore little bit to the right
OK so they both think that by now is is closer to one than it
was before but they do it slightly differently
and if you want what we can do this afternoon we can we can just
work out those equations and you see that there there fairly simple if you're interested
now again if we
if you
you know if is about was talking about customers and consultants and stuff like that
so if you have a customer client comes and says and you giving this right
is going to look at you and say you know what the hell i mean
give me a number give me something i can understand them you figure the distribution
so we said earlier that one thing we could do
is we could output
the average OK for example so we can give the
we could give the average pi
overall posterior
now in general
if we are going to make predictions we have a probabilistic model and we have
done bayesian inference with it
we're going to do is the following and i'll show you some
some figures made nervous about the time said OK
if i have a posterior things neural networks again right now and given a new
input and i have to make a prediction
and all i have is a posterior distribution over words i don't have the value
well it's easy what i would do conceptually is that we take samples from
my posterior of the weights
evaluate my neural net there that input producer prediction repeat repeat repeat an average all
that OK
and this is just a clumsy way of saying that i just integrate out OK
performed into one of my neural net over the distribution of the posterior distribution
on the weights
how does that work in this case
well in this case now my customer wants to know you what the probability that
the coin is going to be heads that's what i want to don't give me
distribution or anything like that
they can say OK fair enough enough
for a fixed by
if i didn't have a prior on it right then this trivially would be but
i mean this equation here is simply but what's the probability of of heads given
by his by but now
we've we've changed the way we do things we're not doing maximum likelihood anymore so
now we actually have a distribution over part
OK we had prior distribution and now we've given ourselves the posterior distribution
what this integral does
abstract than that
they can just be sending a message to another the computer
so the machine with this need to send the messages the actuator and then the
action is actually the message is also can be something that abstract is that
at the top
the perceptron observations received by stencils
so if it was
a robot of some kind
probably expect to be
some to computer some sort of the camera
which the robot is using to perceive the world could be sound or some other
or it could just be receiving
characters from keyboard
so i can be quite abstract two quite concrete like a camera
so what we concerned about today is just going to
this way
so what we consider that today is what's in a question mark
we have these environments we have this
task we want the idea is to undertake
we know what it's got it's got a consensus about actuators
what sort of software
and where do we need to put in that box there
in order
for it to
intelligently in some sense
OK so he's just a bit more terminology
so per percept
is something that the agent receives from time to time from
the environment
percept sequence is the complete history of the percepts
that the oceans receded since it started being deployed
and typically
in fact in the most general case
the problem is this
given the percept sequence
what should be the right action to perform
in order to achieve some goal in order to maximize forms
mathematically that's the problem we have to somehow solve
so this energy function
abstract the agents
o is represented by agent function
the agent function takes as input a percept sequence
some of the stuff
that outputs in action
the ground like again
so the problem i i
the problem of intelligence agents
is the problem of designing the eigenfunctions
plus the other problems and some related to the
so in practice
and i functions implemented by some programs
and not just one thing that typically
when the there should be sort of slightly different the agent programs
he takes the last person is important
that some stuff and then
produces an action
the previous percepts being received
man may not be stored
and in the most general case
the agent
program can keep the entire percept history
the new two and
which action to perform
or maybe something different that come to light
the action programme in each state the
it's a percept
that's some reasoning
finds in action
guess randomly began
rest the distinguish
hardware from software
so the architecture they called the actual machinery
the agent made it might just be
a laptop or maybe some fancy robot
of running around my someone like that
OK many questions that i have been
after discussing
so it is a very simple example to get the ideas across perhaps is too
simple but anyway
i hope
so we very simple
agent it's vacuum cleaner can be in two different rooms
i and b understood
so the percepts
come in the form of appear
consisting of the remnants in
and whether in this study on
this is this a year
and the actions are either to move left and right
to sack the
or the not
so this is an incredibly
simple environment and the nation but because start somewhere
so the percept sequence
a sequence of pairs
for the role
so this is just the
percepts when there's anyone
subsequent and there's only one person in it
and that's too and then goes on down the page to infinitely long
lavatory law
so there's a percept sequence and i suppose that these are the actions of the
agent will apply
particular cases
and you can see the agent programs
is very very simple idea
just the one
and the bottom there
so what it does is
it simply takes the last person
it looks to see
the first component
so the second component
it's clean or dirty
in this study that sex
otherwise it's claim
and looks to see whether it's location i in which case it goes to location
expecting that the standard location they always get the other way
OK so now
very simple percepts
very simple actions that can be applied
very simple programs it's decides given percept
the percept sequence which action to apply
rational agent
in some sense does the right thing the question is
what should the writing d
so in order to find that you have to have some kind of performance measure
and the usual thing is that
the agent designer
imposes a performance measure on the edge
by some method or another
so the idea that is the agent got some purpose in mind
it's got operating miles whatever else
so be given some performance measure
and the idea is that then the agent tries to achieve performance measure
given the performance measure can be
quite tricky thing
but in some cases incredibly difficult
one possible thing is to
essentially trying tell us what to do
under different circumstances
so you're trying to learn how to behave
generally speaking it's
more convenient
to give the idea to give the agent the idea of how good stages
have some measure how good state is
that the agent trying to get to good states
some say that
so this behavior is determined by this design
to get a good state rather than
telling it
which state to get to
so there's a mathematical way of doing that
which is
concept called utility which has been heavily studied and i and
especially in economics before that
parts of engineering
of these structures  that are correct that's that are important at small Z so the measurements
are cleaner of systematic effects due to nonlinearities at large Z  however you don't
expect dark energy to be important at large Z people say that but I don't
know what I expect from dark energy so baryon acoustic oscillations are an
emerging technique to give us information about dark energy another technique is measuring galax is
galaxy cluster surveys which measure a cluster mass a redshift and the spatial pro
clustering properties of clusters this is sensitive to dark energy in many ways the volume
redshift relation the angular diameter distance relation the growth rate of structure and the amplitude
of clustering however there are problems with this technique the cluster selection must be well understood
how do you tell whether there's a  calus a  cluster what proxy do do you use
for the mass of the cluster when you see the cluster it doesn't tell you
what the mass is  and presumably you're going to need photozes for this technique
also finally there's the emerging technique of weak lensing so here is our observer again
they all look like this looking at an object that undergoes gravitational lensing or a  deflection
of light by some mass and  the angular scale of the deflection is related
to the mass of the lens the impact parameter and various geometric distances the distance
between the lense and the source and the distance between the observer and the source dark
energy affects the growth rate of the mass so dark energy enters here and dark
energy affects all the distance factors because it affects how the universe expands so weak
lensing gives us information about dark energy now weak lensing is about the opposite of
supernovae for supernovae every single supernovae was useful for weak lensing the signal from any
single galaxy is too small to be useful but luckily there are a lot of
galaxies in the universe so with  weak lensing you're sort of adding up the
contribution from millions of galaxies to get a good signal there are systematic errors in weak
lensing one systematic error is the point spread function of the image caused by
the atmosphere and the telescope so if you have a point-like source of course
the image because it's travelling through the atmosphere atmospheres are not convenient to astronomers and
the telescope is not perfect as some blurringins of the image caused by the atmosphere and
the telescope and there will also be errors in the photometric redshift there is an
argument or a discussion under way about whether it's best to do this from space
or the ground of course if you go to space there's no atmosphere to blur the images
in space you can go to the near infrared which gives us better information
for photozes  however on the ground  you can have a bigger telescope and ground
is less expensive the thing to remember in comparing ground projects to space projects is
that money weighs less in space the landscape today in dark en in weak lensing
there are projects going on today that look at hundreds of square degrees in deep multicolored data
the multicolor is important for the photometric redshifts there are also projects that look at thousands
of square degrees more shallow in twocolor data in two thousand and ten the dark energy survey will be
the next step in this direction that will look at thousands of square degrees
in deep multicolor data and the for the ground  the next step in this that
will be two thousand fourteen two thousand fifteen two thousand thirteen is the LSST the large synoptic survey telescope which will
look at the full hemisphere very deep in six colors so we modeled one
of the questions that we were asked is are these projects worth it how well will
you do in being able to limit the properties of dark energy so we decided
to parameterize a dark energy equ equation  of state as simply as possible
by two parameters again we wanna  measure the function W of A or W of Z
but we never measure functions we only measure parameterizations of functions so we pick
a very simple parameterization and then we imagine as a standard eight-dimensional cosmological model
that includes the dark energy parameters W zero  the value today and W A
which characterizes the change in the dark energy parameter omega dark energy omega matter omega baryon
H nod the amplitude of fluctuations and the spectral index of the fluctuations so
this again you assume a cosmological model and you can predict how well some future
experiment will be  now we decided that it's not very useful to get precision measurements of
omega dark energy the theory is off by a hundred and twenty orders of magnitude so asking
observers to work very hard to get another significant figure on the result doesn't seem
to be a good thing to do so the thing that we decided on
is sixty four times more likely than hot to cold and back to her
because these are better by a factor of eight to one so that way overrides
one is from decision we still think it might be called right the probability that
this is you know we're still getting we're still getting something on the paths that
go through called say here
just a lot less than we would have died in a one i screamed like
this which is surrounded by cold it's were pretty sure called
let's do some experiments because that's why it's fun to do this stuff respiratory
what would happen now if
what would happen now if we we can this whether inertia
actually that's just totally take this whether inertia away
OK so hot there is
on cold days are equally likely to follow each other
OK what does this look like now
looks like the data
so in fact
what this is saying this is seven days
seven to one probability
the three ice-cream date will be hard to exactly this seven to one ratio here
there's no information
at all from the surrounding days
because the day before the day after had nothing to do with the weather on
this day so this looks exactly like the picture that just squish down into the
well one seven two one seven range instead of the one to three range
it's exactly tracking the so this is like this is
kind of what you'd expect what would happen if we went to nt inertia
so we decided the weather kind of with saws isn't earth venus rich earth after
the catastrophe
after a cold day
it's likely to be a hot day
and after a hard day it's likely to be a cold day a
OK now what we have
now this is trying very hard to whipsaw
so here actually this is rather interesting we have three one ice cream days in
a row things the middle one probably not just trying really hard to alternate
so going
i mean this is sort of the mirror image of what we had before and
eleven were preferred ha ha that was sixty four times more likely here and saying
it prefers cold hot cold that sixty four times more likely than cold cold cold
and when i sprinted
so it's trying alternate over here didn't quite manage to alternate
because you know there's sort of this phase reversal
where it could manage to stitch the left half together with the right half by
alternating it was able to alternate much more happily and explained that he will still
kind of explaining the that over here
five and over here similarly if it took to heart disease and rho
but it's trying real hard to alternate just as
back in the original set up
it was trying real hard
something like this to keep the same weather
here is keeping the same whether even though there's is
three hours per day
in the middle of the heart spell it just keeps in the middle of the
cold spell decides to keep it cold
so let's try another experiment
maybe all
well it's too quickly
so what happens if
what happens if we
change this column here
so that these are
let's try this
OK what's going on here
so now i've said that both cold days and hot days are likely to be
followed by heart disease
so one thing that certainly happen is that they become more likely
both how does this relate to this picture after
basically no inertia again
again these values here
correspond exactly to
one two and three
because again we get no evidence from the surrounding whether
maybe a little counterintuitive but think about from here
the probability of a hot day to day doesn't doesn't depend on what the weather
was the previous day
so we get no inertia effect
or so
we have that's just undo this here OK
so we have this reconstruction this looks pretty nice right
but there is something fundamentally funny about
what's funny about it is we claimed here
that cold day is about twenty percent of the time i two ice-creams and hot
days similarly
now let's look at the at the days here that i predicted to be called
yes it's true that about twenty percent of the time i made into ice ice-creams
but if we look at the days that i predicted to be that we predicted
to be high
about forty percent of the time i'm meeting two ice-creams this numbers
basically and consistent with the data
it should be point four according to our reconstruction
so all assumptions seem to be undermining themselves when we use
these assumptions which i just pulled out my error right to to estimate this graph
the graph on the data the graph then gives us some conclusions which are inconsistent
with my original assumption
so what we really like is for them to be consistent
so what do you think we could do
maybe we should just these assumptions
in fact one reasonable way to adjust the assumptions is to take the probabilities that
we estimated here
and put them back into the table
it's also to do that in a minute but first i want to show you
the results
so as we scroll right on the spreadsheet i've got another graph
where i've updated the probabilities based on what we saw in the previous graph on
the previous graph forty two percent of the two ice cream days
of the highlights from today's given high
we're two ice days and still about twenty percent of the coldest winters were two
ice cream days
so now i know i get a new reconstruction
that's kinda interesting the the picture is actually a little different
all these numbers kind of changed actually so now we used to think that
we were equally likely to have a cold day on a hot day at the
start of the diary now we're pretty sure that it was a hot at the
sort of the diary
OK because when we go left here
we see the book it probably was hot then at the start of the diary
so we just really we we took those things with that them back
to that end we got a new picture
you you might wonder why this isn't circular
and the reason is that you know we're taking the output of the model were
feeding back in how can learn anything and the answer is that the data come
into it
so what we're getting a compromise between the model and the model is making some
it starts here
and i will try to join the limit cycle
well i mean by stability stability means that nearby guys
the guys start somewhere else eventually approach the limit cycle
regardless of whether they start from the outside or start from the inside so that
and unstable limit cycle but i'm not calling it a limit cycle of this unstable
and just going into a closed trajectory but let's draw one which is unstable OK
here's the way we look at its unstable guys which starred nearby will be repelled
driven somewhere else
or they start here
well go away from the thing
instead of going to war
so this is unstable
and i don't call it limit cycle is just just the closed trajectory
cycle because it's cycles around around limit because this is the limit of the nearby
the other case where it's unstable it's not the limit of course you could have
a case also where the curve outside spiraling toward it but the ones inside are
repelled this
then we can also be stable and you can make up all sorts of cases
and i think i one point drew them in the notes but
i'm not going to
the only interesting one of permanent importance people study of the actual limit cycles state
now was the stable close trajectories
notice by the way a closed trajectory is always a simple curves
remember what that means from eighteen o two
simple means it doesn't cross itself why doesn't across itself
it can cross itself because tried to
what's wrong with that point
at that point which which is the vector field goal
that way or that way
why the interest to limit cycle well
because there are systems in nature
which just this type of behaviour they have a certain periodic
and if you disturb
gradually returned to its original interior original periodic state a simple example is breathing
now i feel self-conscious all your breathing you really
well radar you breathing while you're unaware of of course except now
if you're sitting here
listening to
certain temperature certain air circulation in the room
not thinking of anything certainly not lecture
and the lecture is not a two weeks is not unduly exciting
that certain steady rate which
a little different for every person but
that's right now
you can artificially change that you can say OK and i'm going to brief as
to how
that you and indeed you can
but as soon as you stop being aware of what you're doing
the levels of various hormones and carbon dioxide your bloodstream and so on will return
your breathing to the natural state
with natural state
in other words it's behaving in the system
that system of your breathing
which is controlled by various chemicals and hormones
in the body of is
exhibiting exactly this type of behavior has a certain regular periodic motion is the system
and if the stir before officially set out somewhere else
it will gradually returned to its original state
now of course but if i'm running of course will be different short you're running
brief faster but that's because the parameters in the system
o BA's and the bees and the equation
yes in the x what the f of x y and g x y
parameters in those functions will be set at different levels you have different hormones different
amount of carbon dioxide and so on
now i'm not saying the breathing is modeled by a limit cycle
it's the sort of thing which one might look for limit cycle that that's of
course the question for biologists
in general any
type of periodic behavior nature of people try to see if there is
systems of differential equations which governs which perhaps there is a limit cycle
which can take to look like
well one of the problems the
in this sense limit cycles are easy to lecture about because so little is known
about at the end of the period if i have time i'll give you
also use the simplest possible questions you could answer is totally answer to it
good as is to the attitude is totally unknown
one hundred twenty years trying to study trying
OK but let's first talk about what sort of problems people address with limit cycle
first of all is the existence problem
if i give you a system like this is to be on the right-hand side
x squared plus two IQ minus three x y and
g is something similar i say OK
does this have limit cycles
well you know how to find the critical points
but how do you find out as limit cycles the
answer to that is nobody has any idea
so this problem is in general no in general
there are no no
not much in the way of method
not much
not much is known
there's one theorem that you find in the nodes the simple theorem called the parker
a benedictine theorem
for about sixty or seventy years was about the only result known which enable people
to find limit cycles
the theorem is use relatively little because people try to find limit cycle by computer
now the difficulty is you have to know where to look for them
in other words the computer screen shows that much you set the axes
and it doesn't show any limit cycles that doesn't mean there aren't any these are
over there
or means is the big one like this
and you're looking in the middle of don't see it
so in general people
don't look for limit cycles until less the physical system which gave rise to the
to the
it's a pair of differential equations