and then there is there
the second parameter which is the widest death rate for that which is the probability
that somebody gets so the effective low here is that this happens with probability that
and all pull all the question asking is
whether whether survive this this model is called SAS where
and this is this is like a state diagram right a note can be either
either of these two states it can be healthy and susceptible to the virus before
it can be effective in can fact people and with probability
enabling factors
and the probability that the BBC going here
get get well
and the question is
one thing i should say is we have these wires
which is the ratio of parameters like this would be highly infectious virus and this
is how easy it is to get
and the basic questions that people ask is that if you don't know what is
called the epidemic threshold so given the graph we want to have the value of
the epidemic threshold so that if the if the strength of the virus
it is below the threshold the virus get sixty even if you producing the network
and otherwise the stays alive for
so what is
is a graph
and we want to get this epidemic threshold
and the question is so just interested in what this epidemic threshold depends for example
the of the network sort of the higher this threshold should be started below threshold
should be higher the more people that connected these it should be for the virus
to take over and for example then the question is is the highest degree is
the average degree then
then the other thing would also they on the right the more the network is
sort of of spread out the
part of it would be for the virus to take over
and i don't want to go into too many details but it turns so the
answer is very simple and this is this is the answer so what he says
it if you go into take large the largest tiger of of the adjacency matrix
of the of the grand
that we are interested in what it says that one of the slides
i j largest eigen value of the adjacency matrix this is the epidemic threshold right
so if the ratio of the virus that is is over or below this value
this tell us the virus lies in the world
so what is here is that just seem to have a tie the lighter side
sort of a strong enough to capture all the properties of the graph to tell
us whether the widest survival nine
so i've said and here is an example of the of the simulation so we
have an autonomous systems can to be like the graph of thinking
it's sort of small but
right if we are above the epidemic threshold so we start with all the nodes
in fact and then if you are above the threshold this sort of reaches steady
state and the white space in the in the in the network for while if
we are below the threshold the virus dies thinking and if we are at the
threshold sort of that slow and and there are ways to quantify what what we
mean by quickly and what mean by slowly but this is just to give a
flavor of one line of research on
how things spread over the network
o this study these are the parameters
right so somebody comes and tells you this is the african is about so this
is the parameters of the model
i know the properties of the virus
so now i want to talk about the other line of the the diffusion that's
called the different models of diffusion in networks and you hear something similar going so
we have some nodes are should act and then this
nodes spread their influence on the network to other nodes and so on so for
example if nodes and are active what particular time then they can influence the them
know that gets influenced and so on and this continues and this will be the
processes that we are studying and there are two ways to think about it so
the first one that i will that point is the threshold models
and again so what we have we have a weighted graph where the weight
thirty seconds of by first piano concert played by going glenn gould
this is thirty seconds of silence
and the interesting thing is that while you're here to while you listen to music
than the auditory cortex contains some the senior field
it's just the queen incidents
so this was a very good test bed for us to to try to measure
the senior
if it's it's actually something very very difficult
two to measure
in fact the reason why people are interested in the senior fields is because in
also my green are any lesion
actually has the senior fields
and so stroke while my greenwood been lesions like that and given that you now
have established that that you actually able to reproduce so to say the paradigm on
sub in an unsupervised manner you can now use this technology for monitoring stroke patients
you could and things like that
that was the medical idea
behind that
so what are the conclusions that we can draw
so first of all we saw that this reliability assessment works
this allows us to select between algorithms or select
iteratively atively between algorithms so we take our favourite doesn't algorithms and we take the
one that is most able extract the first component
you know go to the subspace where the first component doesn't live and do this
over until we finish
so this actually makes a lot of this so this would be operating these algorithms
in some kind of hybrid deflation mode
and you can gain a lot from that
but also this has been used by the group of trouble money for assessing the
stability of clusters solutions
so but not asking questions
yesterday and so i had to you know get some slides
so i mean this is never told about this so far
this also has to do with ICA so this so to say the end of
the ICA a part of
so i i mentioned briefly that there are some
some signals
that you can use for
for the brain computer and facing like the slow cortical potentials to the dynamic features
like you're them
there was the third one which i don't forget but anyway the
the issue is that it is believed that synchronization in the brain synchronization between certain
ensembles of neurons is actually means for computation
and i think your used it also for BCI studies
and so
there was what what was worrying
as in this
work was actually t to be using this synchronisation between
you know ensembles of neurons as we can measure it with e in order to
to improve or BCI performance
of the BCI performance of system but there is a systematic problem that i will
show you and also show you the way to solve it so
imagine you have some dynamical system
and so this is very abstract but you could think of some ensembles that have
some some dynamics
the brain of neural assemblies
what you would be interested in
so so imagine these these ensembles they they make some they have some oscillations
and you would like to measure the
if you measure the core as they say there signal that that
that is as the phase difference of of
and like this
if you take the correlation it would be zero
but if you take the local phase so the local phase angle at every point
so the first so how do explain this into intuitively so if you define the
local phase
is like
how do you say this this thing from watch the hand watch that moves around
OK so you define your day it year oscillators like that by their local faces
and you have the same second oscillator like that and in this example that i
just made you see that the correlation of the phases will will be very
strong because they are fixed and
so there phase locked so to say and
it is believed that
synchronous oscillations of very good means for actually
computing with the brain
OK so let me just so if i would be this phase this local phase
this the definition of the
of the phase synchronization index which is the exponent of i and this is the
problem and this is a no sorry this is the
the difference between block faces of two sources OK
this is just numbers
so you would have say two dynamical systems that could go or go around some
attractor and you would
i have some phase locking between and you can can compute yourself come on
so you can measure the instantaneous phases by
handwaving or by
compute derivatives
and solve
four equal to zero
i'm pretty much all the calculations i'm doing here with this new example i'm going
to do them again
generality for log linear models and conditional random fields
what's the derivative of
so what i need is the
d by the state
say to to the age
one minus data
to the n minus h
and let me point out so this is the bottom of page three in the
notes and there's a typo in the notes
it says d by DP
but what we what actually means by the state
and i have an occasional question so this is the curly d
four derivative instead of the regular d for derivative and what's the difference in meaning
between curly DNA regular differ derivative
a single parameter so
if you have a function
say have
which is a function of a single argument say e
then that function is called one derivative the director with respect and you can call
that debate easy
but if a function which has more than one argument is going to derivative with
respect to each of its arguments and so on
the user could be t to indicate the derivative
with respect to any particular argument and something that is quite common phenomenon here when
we do dealing with maximum likelihood is that
there's some ambiguity about how many arguments your functions have
because you think of something you think of some arguments is being fixed and then
other and and if an argument is fixed is not really an argument but
you can always then say well suppose not fixed and then you could take the
derivative with respect to that so here
this likelihood
i was thinking of the exercise is being fixed so we're not gonna take the
derivative with respect to them
but you know there's something which is even more fixed and the excise which is
an because even before we
drew the training set
we knew that there was a constant and of how many training examples control
so in a sense
this function is a function of and it's a function of the axis through agents
the function of data
but and i'm thinking of was being totally fixed and h thinking of is being
fixed for the time being and really the only thing i'm thinking of is being
varying hero status i could write the by these data but i i chose to
write curly divide the
but it's always
you should always ask yourself so well what is what is fixed and what is
not fixed and they can be degrees of fix this
OK so now
and it's gonna work out this derivative
and you know the
the derivative of product
so the
the mnemonic is
FG prime is f prime g plus fifty prime
and then
as composer g prime
OK it's f of g prime
so now we have a prime of g
times g prime
so that was this is the chain rule for derivatives
product so what do i get here
and then so i want to the root of state of the age is just
a on
a monomial so that's h times stated age minus one so i get h times
stated to the age minus one
times one minus data to the and minus h
and then here the
data h stays fixed
and i get n minus h times
one minus stated to the n minus h minus one
and then i need a
minus one because i had a minus data here
i'm going to do so this is
the sum of two terms
i'm going to
right it a single term
stated to the power is minus one
times one minus data to the power and minors aged minus one
more age times one minus data
um and minus age
data so this is just rewriting this expression
and now it's got the derivative
now i want to
set it equal to zero
so the
during the
equals zero
and there are three cases
one of the three cases
the first cases stated equals zero
the second case is
one minus state equals zero
that case is
age times one minus data
and minus age data
these two cases
you know in these two cases the whole thing equals zero
this probably looks
maybe similar to what you've got no much but some the CCD cameras here
the spectrometers in here
we use
a fully functional light microscope
this allows us to
use all the optical options to visualize sample
so if you have a difficult samples to see if you need to use polarization
fluorescence was type of techniques you can use
this microscope by modifying goodbye makes them i optics for the microscope
you can get this already shown
as a company
spectroscopy is a small part of the range of about ten percent of the total
what high course the area and the company itself is metrology company and we manufacture
measuring two
these precision grating stages are all built by ourselves because we have a high precision
metal on metal to
metro metallurgical company not metrology mythological
we actually have a very accurate measurements and we actually can do this very very
and move the stages so these are all built into the system
a wide choice of excitation wavelengths standard system can run from
the two four for all the way out to a thirty using standard lasers and
we have no done some work ten sixty four doing some roman work in that
so the choice of is there we can get down with this my option here
two about ten wave numbers from the laser light
we have an option to image true imaging of raman not mapping
o point by point mapping is something by using dielectric filters you can filter twenty
twenty with number band from the sample and it because using a CCD
you can actually cause the roman image onto the CCD chip
for rapid looking at
the issues surface control
very useful thing to do
some put something we'll talk about it on the whole system i think comes as
it stands here
and that thing all you require is an electric clock you go into the means
and ready to go
because of the multi-user potential
we developed
an additional
alignment optimisation and automated calibration and automated execution search
everything is still be done in controlled manually
but in this we call college o here
we have to adopt so we can sample a white light source and any unsourced
and these can all be used to automatically set the system and also allows you
to validate the results and your results validated automatically if you choose to do so
the advantage here
is that you can in fact
like almost anyone using instruments
within reason we cannot break it
so what we're looking now is the multi-user system and we this was developed specifically
ITN really the pharmaceutical people who wanted to use running
but they don't want to have a high-level scientists spending all the time on the
twenty of the non-technical people running it
usually with a good education is good scientific background but basically somebody can go and
use these men get the results
the same goes no for all
a lot of academic institutions
because the publisher parish
the the guy is also a weak and run
you spend a week setting up your experiment getting samples
if you go to a traditional roman history you can spend two or three weeks
setting up i'm an instrument to do their analysis with this data samples and run
analysis one day all finished spend the rest of the ten rating of
for some students that starts an advantage for other the students that's an even bigger
advantage but more importantly for the these the simulator for the
supervisors it means we are getting results published
so everything is going and everything is actually being done
and in the modern science department that is critical is critical to the running of
the unit
everything here
it's fully motorized wavelengths as i see it can be changed automatically and
it automatically aligns itself all system like to do everything on its own
it would be
a top-of-the-range instrument with this is not at the moment we have three lasers on
box no
encloses the microscope
and the reason we put enclosures on
and it was set up with safety
yeah that was part of the reason for the most important reason was as i
the pharmaceutical industry they want to put this into the laboratory
they don't want to put it into the red
so with that don't do close to one of the problems with the roman it's
fluorescent lights give around
you close the door there's the fluorescent light you've got noise and interference here missing
the other reason is an addon remove you running along mapping experiments and you take
a long time to analyse the last thing you want someone walking instead of what's
happening in your switching on the lights
and interfering with the experiment so with these you can actually set it up i'm
going to run fully automatically
we can make up on
i understand the system can mode up to four ways of
just because you got four lasers doesn't mean you restricted to four wavelengths
if you take the system three two five five one four seventy five percent three
to five in the cat
so o five one four are good i and diode seventy eighty five
ninety CAD
three to five will give you three to five and four four two
so potentially you could have two wavelengths on their
the more than argon ions will give you four five seven forty eight o five
one four saying three wavelengths on this LST five a six wavelength one system
for the nanotechnology group particularly looking at the silicon wafers looking at the enhancement materials
looking national resident this can be very useful
if you wanted to then go down into the UV and having water cooled quiz
are with two forty four o two six in the movie you i would suggest
you might that separately and then fitted in
the system is a big water cool is very expensive movie about eighty thousand dollars
to fulfill is at the moment which is not an insignificant amount of money that
could also be added
to this this instrument understand the important thing is
quick change the
you to me
but more importantly
automated changeover
serious health effects now what is holding the fixed in this picture me well T
is equal to you plus so you plus is fixed is a constant in other
now where the curves along which you plus b is the constant well they are
these lines
these lines along which you want to be
equals a constant on tedious accounts for the reason I'm holding clear constant is because
the 1st integration only allows you to change years held fixed
OK you let you increase as you increase is held fixed
by traversing these lines in this direction that's the direction on which she was increasing
I integrate from the point from the you value where they leave the region intent
the region what's the value where they enter the region you is equal to
everybody would know that not so many people will be able to figure out what
to put forward leaves the region
what's you the value of you when it leaves the region well this is the
curve equals 0
but the equals 0 is
in another language
u equals to
the latest u equals 0 or you will equals in other words they enter the
region where u equals 0 and they leave where you with his team has led
this is the
and how about the other guys full which cheese do I wanna do this well
I wanted for all these values
well now the T. value here that's the starting line here t is 0 all
and here is not 0 and if I go out and cover the whole first-quarter
and I'll be going letting T increases to infinity the some of you in the
eye will be letting increasing so 0 3
so all this is an exercise in changing taking this double integral and UV coordinates
and changing it to this double integral an equivalent double integral over the same region
but now in
UT coordinates now that's the answer somewhere here is the answer because
because like if
since the 1st integration is with respect to you
can migrate outside
because it doesn't involve you
that only involves T and to is only caught by the 2nd integration
so I can put this outside where and upward the integral from 0 to infinity
of e to the negative st time what's left funny expression but you're under desert
island found
this funny expression integral from 0 to T of the minus you
the ensure the convolution exactly
so all you have to do is get the idea that there might be a
formula sit down
change variables a double integral that you formula well
it is
and I would like to spend much of the rest of the period
In other words so that's how it relates will plus transform that's how it comes
out of all plus transform here's how to use it you know calculating will plus
transform directly from the other and of course solve problems will plus transform problems differential
equation using the convolution but I have to tell you that most people convolution is
very important and most people who use it don't use it in connection with will
plus transform the uses for its own sake
1 of the 1st
place so learned that you know outside MIT people use the convolution with from my
daughter who knows she's environmental engineering consultant the environmental consultant she does risk assessment stuff
like that but anyway he had this paper on acid rain she was trying to
refer clients and
she said knows all about calculated acid rain falls on our soil from there you
will stuff leaches into a river but there are other things happen to it on
the way and soil combined in various ways reduces the acidity of the things that
chemical reactions take place of all anyway she said well that they calculated the and
how much the water again river gets polluted which it but it's a convolution
should that what what's the convolution so I told that she was too young to
learn about the convolutions and I should say I thought I'd better look it up
1st RBI you cost convolution with basil puzzle that applications so I read that there
interesting and I had been thinking about it I think other people come to be
you know some guy with problem about the drilled ice cores of the north pole
and the from the radioactive carbon and so on and with deducing various things about
the climate you 60 billion years ago and it was all convolution being asked me
if I can explain that to him so let me give you a sort of
an all-purpose state at a simple all-purpose model which can be adapted which is a
very good way of thinking of the convolution
is a problem of radioactive dumping
it notes by the way was so I'm just want take a chance on and
listen to what I'm saying relevant scribbling everything down maybe it's a available to figure
out the source
so problem is we have some factory or some nuclear plant or something like that
is producing nuclear material duo radioactive waste and certainly not always at the same rate
of and then it
Florida dumps it on a pile somewhere so radioactive waste
is dumb and there's a dumping function of goal-directed today don't right
that's the dumping rate let's say years and years you like that units and Quantity
kg either whatever value of
now what is the dumping rate means
the dumping rate means that
if I on the time axis
if I have 2 times which a close together for example 2 successive days
new midnight and 2 successive then there's a time interval between them all call that
delta T
to say the dumping rate is half of the means that
the amount Don
is that in this time interval
on the fifteenth
they're moving out of it so i mean maybe to mention a few things which
i have talked about this central dogma
i cannot really answer when it was because they not really educated about that very
few things happen now the first of all there's not only one m on e
what i mean generally that's not only one protein which can be generated from the
there are several ways to there
regulation point so i would like
now what
i think that for instance
to include what moving into is a certain decision and this can be regulated
and depending on external conditions or depending on other
i mean
conditions that might be the case this entrance is removed when i remove this allows
a lot of flexibility not only the transcription which is regulated as the
processing and also the translation is regulated we have a lot of different control points
leading not only to one protein but have
put into supporting it
i think
OK so maybe not thing to mention is that
nowadays it's not only the protein which are also a lot of on a on
courting on a lot at all on a translator forty
on may a just have a whole bunch of
and this might be considerably
so in particular for human known that only
in one of two percent of the human genome actually try to encode for protein
and all the rest
it seems like that and i mean the question what is the stuff and it
seems like it could be on a on eighty nine according to one
structure element
so it's interesting to look into
you mention a few popular types of measurement
what i talked about already there are sequences so
there are a lot of different people can sequenced genomes to be sequenced on a
and we get a big databases full of
what we also get a population data so this is
not only one sequence we have maybe different populations
organisms and have many variations
i talk about one
what also get factual they data like three d structure of proteins
expression data
so we can measure when a certain gene on the benefits of climate conditions
and we have protein networks could be interaction data what could be regulation
so when which protein regulates which
so one which protein interacts with which he
OK so we have actually network here
the corner
just text data compression we have arguments
OK let me mention a bit more on the way think
it was developed by sun nineteen seventy and nowadays because you can essentially stretches of
about a one thousand nucleotides long length
he essentially when would like to
sequence the genome we break it up into small pieces and sequence of these small
so and if the sequence enough
then we can overlap these pieces
and you can find out the full
so problematic of course is when you repeat sequence so one part which is repeated
several times then you cannot really we construct
how the original
you cannot sequence of the whole worldview
and these these repeats along the thousands really problematic so then you have to do
some specific sequencing
so that essentially to spread one of the human genome project with a look at
this small
they look at smaller parts may be
million base pairs or just KB and then sequenced only those parts only took random
part from these from this hundred KB sequence those that overlap
so that they could we can put forward cetera cetera just randomly sequence the lot
and then tried to reassemble the whole image
the cost for the human genome was like three billion dollars including the technology technology
and this has gotten much much cheaper it's cheaper by the house and recently the
you know what i think what have been sequenced by or what you think that
what's left millions
you are
so population data it's not just one genome which is so i mean that every
individual has its own you know and the you know might be different from from
the next video
what we really have to understand what are the differences between these different phenotypes whether
and the genomic information and related to genetic information like
how people look like
OK so and you the new sequencing technology one need new technology in general
allows us to determine the variation between populations and individuals
first of all there is so i mean that the
if you at the area
and the next generation sequencing techniques which are much more
what you get out there is
essentially sequences like those usually referencing
how well would be like if i classify this data pointing to all the possible
classes that i have
and then compare
each class with the total given by some world so that the form this distribution
has want you can work this out in a little bit more
i'm gonna skip this part of the softmax here
and i just when
one minute that this galaxy in
the naive bayes or bayesian classifier has a linear geometry if the covariance matrices are
the same
so the ratio
the posterior probability for any two classes is a linear function
of the inputs if the covariance matrices are equal
and what that means is that
all of this
thing that we do really
is giving us nothing more
then the same picture we had
at the beginning
it's just a linear
separation between the classes in other words you as reliable where you think it equally
probable to be class zero class one that's
surfaces is just the wind the covariance matrices equal
if the covariance matrices are different if you have a separate gases for each one
like this
the contour equal probability is a conic section
parabola or hyperbola or something like that
which by the way is linear
in the sufficient statistics based
i a conic section is linear in this case is
it's gone but many in space one
x squared
he festering in your mind
so i want to talk
so so that's just the link between the gas model and the and the linear
and this is just a slide to tell you
exponential family
class conditional models are linear in the sufficient statistics
so if you think of the sufficient statistic is an extended space
which augments the original feature vector having the class conditional model which is any exponential
family model
it is linear in the sufficient statistics based that exponential family model
you can think of these as just extended linear classifiers
all of the class conditional models is exponential
OK so the last thing i want to do here before you take a short
break is is the discrete equivalent of
this classifier
which is the discrete bayesian classifier
so if the inputs are categorical which can really fit together into the
what should we do well the simplest thing to do is to have a joint
which is the table so this is is
the conditional probability table conditioned on the class
and of course is conceptually correct but it has huge practical problem which is that
if you say a hundred binary inputs
then in two classes each class conditional model as like two to one hundred twenty
and there's no way to be able to to estimate that for any reasonable
so for example if you're sixteen by sixteen digits in two hundred fifty six grey
levels for each one each class conditional model as
sixteen time sixteen
that's the number
variables two hundred fifty six numbers setting two hundred fifty six to sixteen sixteen
and it has caused most of the entries in these tables will be zero
your probability of being in a particular class of zero zero and you want know
why are we going to do here
we're going to to regularisation just like i told you about the gases
we're going to use one or more of our three regularisation tracks which was factorizations
parameter tying and priors
OK and each of these tracks again leads to very common discrete classifiers
so let's first talk about the factorisation true
factorizations trace yields
classifier called naive bayes
eighty phase but despite the derogatory name i pretty predicted by our very seriously
it seems like a ridiculous idea but it works extremely well
if you're doing a paper in which you are studying classification
you are morally obligated to compare your method two
naive bayes and nearest neighbour
and verify for yourself that these seemingly foolish classifiers did not actually be here
could be surprised how often naive bayes nearest neighbour will actually be compared
but nonetheless there are many much much better than naive bayes
like like kernel classifiers are gaussian process
priors but let me tell you what naive bayes and the naive bayes assumption is
the attributes are the
OK this is clearly ridiculous assumption
let's take for example the naive bayes classifier for
so what the naive bayes classifiers say oh well let's say that the features are
just the binary presence of certain
he goes nigeria your email
does by
here in you know the stock appeared you know there's more to it appearing even those
by actor appearing in
about in other words publishing like
and this
the naive bayes assumption is that if you know instead the probability of each words
occurring independent
but it clearly true that if there were more in e-mail it's much more likely
to work approved is going to hurt you
or if were the average person was in other words that are more likely to
occur so it's not really the case that things are independent given the class but
that's the assumption we make the naive bayes and so the naive bayes
the world
in this graphical model you have the class year in conditioned on the class every
one of the attributes
are independent
so it's just a big
thing like this were all the attributes are independent in
training in naive bayes classifiers really really easy you just sort all the data into
classes all the data from glacier and one but all the data class one another
bucket for each class you estimate the distribution of the i th variable
completely independent
first of all you would just take email spam in measure how often in email
spam what fraction of the messages doesn't work nigeria occurs these three percent so the
parameter is point zero three the probability of nigeria on
given the email spam you take all the non spam email that's what fraction of
those messages containing the word nigeria
unless you have some legitimate existing relationship with nigeria probably is very low low
should choose by a simulation
the universe the
five this ago
or move from one thousand eight
which is the fastest growing
part of the
to be because we
be aware that
if you there
so far
o is
real world
by the way is not there
which try
they want
and you know by being in
you should be
it is
the job
so as you
one is dangerous
over here
so i will
that story is dangerous
there that are lot more
well all can be doing you
official my
and may be involved
there's no
they or
no more
you see four
on the other hand
march four or five
that you
say want to
wait wait
model is this
so o
i don't think
i think they are wrong
even a we are
the year that
did a lot
the idea is that it
i e
early in the
that season
you need to this is the neuron
is you is completion day components is the
he c
right or wrong it is who
you can
what is it if he were our well
there is which
it is
there is a POV fork out
for any
the area
we see is
more and more
born in that it is
is the problem we use we used to use
mechanical all the
new story of
damage or disease
so this
for more
he is
there is only one nation in
if you like can
so in the US
aidan accuracy is in his
you can use
the class of disease of
i mean that's
that's why
so this is a consequence
did the following this is really might
the primary goal
is is
i used
so she
the beginning of this is in
i'm going we have for
it's too
which is on
this is where
you might try
in the last year
i know that there is about as well for as
since it is
you should not all and then in my own
one is a
which is running
we use their
the role is
you use
this is
in such a setting so
i was very shy it seems to me there is no mention of TV well
sorry to all of the one that was going on this is
you may
the single was
it means that
there is no need to win
i will buy you a bit about
if you do
right and if the observed reward was small
you pretend as if
the other action was
the but their actions
so you assume that the other action was
good action to take so you tell your classifier
to take that action instead
the other actions and this is the importance weight
so this is the word is less than one-half here
and the importance weights similarly
as you do here
by one half minus or
over the probability so the importance weighted approach
was essentially this except that he used zero instead of one have
so there was no offset and here you can offset by any amount
between zero and one including zero which would give you the importance weighted approach
one half which is sort of the minimax solution
so this is what you do is to actions and let's see how and why
it helps and you were you feel that you feel this transformed data set into
your favourite importance weighted
binary classifier
you learn the classifier and then you should use it as your policy
i'm circa here
yes sure sure you can you if your actions are
you have to actions
but they can be either positive or negative here you're just looking at the single
and this is just the variable that the notes you're action that can be either
positive or negative
and you just invented the action in the observed reward was small
so if it was the positive you pretend that the true label is negative
if you observe
and acts
with the positive labels
but smaller reward
you pretend as if the true label is negative
union where it the there was a paper at KDD last year actually it's called
so how can the world be found
so this is a
this is this comes from your exploration so from the environment
right so you take an action and you assume that you get some really for
that action
so it depends on your application
and in the advertisment for example it can be either click and not as simple
as zero one
so we would not
really address this problem here
will you be talking about some experiment we can probe are
and then the draw an action from our action choosing distributions
and and this probability one over p where p is the probability of choosing that
action and this is the
absolute distance from the offset from one half
so you were larger than one have been generated
ax comedy so this is this
rejection sampling and that john talked about
right so probably well so you this
larger than one half which generated we using a is our actions otherwise we invert
the action
we use the other action is the true label
so the problem induced by
importance weighted
this importance weighted conversion
is noisy and this week the offset and the
can be used to decrease
the noise in the induced problem and i'll go through several examples to see why
it does so
what i missed
so should they go through the examples known OK
OK so let's say that we have an example axe
and they have two actions and these are
the words of these sections so the weight of the first actions one half and
the reward of the second action is one
and let's say that
there's some distribution
and so because this action left and call this action right
so what's the probability of and there are some distribution over the actions that the
user so what's the probability of generating
this binary example
versus this binary examples of what's the induced distribution
for the binary classification problems
i'm going talk about multi label problems
so it's just to slide about
previous work the
OK it turns out that
some of the techniques
it use in
works quite well with multi label
in fact
what you do
the graph
instead of
using a single variable for each
a single node in the graph for each variable
this this the graph is going to take multiple labels
you have to have some sort of encoding
of the variables
different values
in the graph so
the simplest way is just to have graph from different levels this would be
if you have label five five possible values for each label
right so you stack them up
disparity label
and x is just spatial
mentioned and you have
here is one
partition of the graph like this
corresponds to
once again
what the value of the
of one of the variables should be so in particular
if you
represent a single variable
like this
having zero
i want
the variable x that i'm talking about that i have failed to show called x
x one x two
and if my
of the graph
happens to
divided like this
and this means that i'm going to give
the label medical they should call is
label zero label one label two then
the variable x
it's the value held
the labels are generally held equals
zero up to
so each
these labels
corresponds to in
this gets cut
because you want that
the label
now this trick here in that you don't want
the cut come back again like that
so that's easily fixed
you want to make this so that each column corresponds get cut in any one
and so what you do is you put backward edges
these images have infinite weight
right so
if you've got this zero down here
this zero
and this is one in your your bias on the basis of binary probably cut
problem still
these will be
binary cut problem but each column represents in this way
more than one label
now if you've got
cut like that this is why
it's got to
it's got to do
got across three times released
could do something like this
because this this has to be in
and this one has to be
the zero
so this would be the all these would be zero these would be one
to not put the same distribution over words in every topic and i'm also notice
we have not even begun to discuss computation
there is no algorithm at play
this is just thinking about the
posterior distribution in this model
OK so one intuition is yes sparse priors help
encourage this but this can happens anyway
and you see this with the probabilistic latent semantic indexing model
this happens anyway
because it's
to the benefit of the posterior to divide up the words
with the exceptions of course like a word like bank has high probability and two
in two topical will will be captured by this
but it's in the posteriors interest to do that
OK so that's point number one
and i realize these are very organised points so i'm i'm still trying to think
about this
o point number two
in a mixture model
this is enough to find clusters of co occurring words now beginning to co occurrence
what's the mixture model somebody tell me into two sentences one mixture model is
or in one sentence that's fine
that's right sum of different distribution so and in in the context of of modelling
text the way we're doing here
i now understand why don't we get through my slides because
i prefer to ramble like this in the context of what we're doing here we've
let's call them topic proportions pi and zeta psi
and got in words
and got the document
and they all come from
one of these
OK it's this it's it's a very similar model except instead of each document getting
a distribution over terms each document only gets one topic assigned to it OK so
on the document i'm from topic thirty seven all
trillion of my words come from topic thirty seven
that's a mixture
it's like
every document belongs to this one topic
in a mixture model
topics are going to
by the way i don't expect you to understand that sentence because i don't understand
it seems
like you need some editing in a mixture model with this refers to in in
a mixture model
i think it may refer to model
that's a mixture model yes
this is a mixed membership model
and this is the next year
that's right they're both kind of mixture models so this is like an infinite well
information i mean something else now this is like a mixture model where mixing over
the over theta and this is the mixture model were mixing over the finite number
of topics k
no because there are k topics different documents can exhibit different topics so i'm the
yes we considering in the whole collection that's deeply
everybody on board with mixture modeling
so in a mixture model when you contemplate the posterior you're going to get co
occurring words this gets to the y co occurrence playsrole right because
because the if if if i come from one topic then the words in my
document all should have high probability in that topic and what words is going to
want to put in that topic with high probability the words that are all happy
together in in
in my document
and so those are words that co occur in the document
it's a mixture model
capture precisely the sets of
recurring co occurring words
so that clear
i'll say it again so if a mixture model assigns each document just one topic
what that means necessarily is that all of the words in each document came from
just one topic that means that it's in the
bayesian machinery interest to
place co occurring words together in one topic so they all have high probability if
two words that co occur lot were in different topics then we're totally
it's screwed because we are only allowed to be in one topic and so the
words that are in my document that co occur so that those two words co
occur document that probably zero and one of the topics
so when i know i'm being confusing
this is the rules of the model
in the midst of all of this to get you get something that kind of
look like topics yes so let me tell you when we get to the next
point thank you for
moving me to the next point OK
mixture model co occurrence
hopefully that same which has been made in your brain now
in LDA
so that's the second point in LDA directly on the topic proportions can encourage sparsity
in other words a document will be penalized for using too many topics
OK what i mean
if i go backwards got
i mean this
if i put a certain per hyperparameter on my dearest way
alpha equals
o point o one ten topics then the prior over the topic proportions seems to
topic proportions theta sparse the only place high probability with which are on
distribution that have
a small number of atoms with high probability
OK the distribution over distributions places high probability over these distributions that have a small
number of atoms that have high probability
clear j
here is alpha so small
that we we are essentially asking for a mixture model
if alpha gets pushed all the way down to zero
then we were we've got a mixture model on our hands more or less
and the posterior because this is saying every day i all i want is for
every document to be in one topic and notice that which topic it doesn't matter
so right
six minutes later just for the card
one the six minutes at the end
so i'm going to use the six minutes before talking about planning generative model so
we are
slide relaxing the condition of the the previous target the condition that was that
you should be able to create a transition probabilities
the densities and the rewards
and so what if if you can do that you can always sample and so
this is like an entry
two are the more interesting cares for and
you can only interact with the system and this is the way you get yourself
so that way we make and was saying so that the more that we use
you can
ask black box to return
around the next state from any given state for any given action
so there's more that you are going to use this is called the generative model
the purposes of again finding finding a good policy and the efficient
well the question is how to do that and so the obvious idea against two
to evaluation
maybe at this stage you you will are these start to understand why
we have to talk that much about dynamic programming and value creation all this stuff
many of these are given such is based on
and those ideas
here the idea is as follows
so this is very similar to that on the discretisation mentors
the only thing that changes that we can not compute approximate MDP so we have
to do approximate conquered
we have to use more samples he said i
just coming up is that approximate the so what you do is that
in a preprocessing step you just generating a bunch of sound policy generating base and
so that those the samples that are similar to
what we used in the on the discretisation method
and here will an arbitrary
distribution you see be just pick your favourite distribution you
and so there is some samples from the distribution
and then for each of these plants
you generate a bunch of next state so this is again monte carlo remembered by
the addition you want to compute an integral
are you want to compute anything for every action and so in order to be
able to compute intended
in approximate marriage is generated the next state
and generate the next it's but but from the transition from the current so this
is the assumption so we assume that you can do it so there is this
black box that returning
the samples you ask for is
next is given the current state and actions
and this black was just returns at on the next day
according to the transition probability kernel
the black box is also able to return immediately turns
immediate rewards
so there is this other guys
and then you just do value iteration so hard the iteration
so well
at the point at this specific point x of i
you can really constitute a good approximation to the
to target about to be
i updated values function we
what value iteration does
is that it's computing this into ground
what's what's the way of computing the center for the next four years
so the obvious way of computing this integral is to have a bunch of samples
generated from the transition probabilities
and use the same person among the countless the players in the
is an average
so this is what we do here
so we compute these values
and well of course the we take the max because in value iteration you take
the max
over the actions
and once you compute its value as well
what happens is that you have you have values
all our
a bunch of
so here is x one
is actually here is actually maybe you have three states only
very efficient in terms of computational
this would be the
maybe the true value is here the true value is here and the relies here
and then you compute ages this by this very so what do do
you set up a regression problem right so you have this
independent variables and you have this that and the very bottom up sorry
so these are the beat
the samples of the target
so this is just a regression problem so you want to come up
the function
that some whole
makes the behaviour of the optimal value function so you set up this regression problem
you have access to fly
and you have the targets
had offered i
this is a regression problem you saw
maybe you set up his first aggressions
so you pick a function space f
and so you
you are searching for the function
that minimizes this list are
this means that
what this function space could be so this could be space of network so
basically what you do here
most of the cases a year
optimizing some veins
or you could use support vector regression to solve this regression
and it will not be really discourse problem it would be
slightly different but it's all the same so that the procedure
and then
you have these two choices again that you could generate the first
in each of the traditions of traditional generate sample at the very beginning and we
use those samples
and what happens is that you can prove the nice things about this
it turns out that
well the reason i'm showing you respond OK if i should use screen
o who
it was five
going to right
and so
after computed
after this computation for k kappa decade relations you compute the greedy policy with respect
to your
o system by function
and you want to get the ball
on the difference between the optimal value function the best back from that you can
hope for
and the actual path that you are going to get
and this high high-quality come upon you can improve on this plant
so the nice thing about this bond again is that well and covered and then
let's let's give a specific example and specific example is
and silver chloride to a solution already containing sodium chloride
at silver chloride to a solution of point one molar
in ACL
so i really have chloride present is interesting if if i said that
instead of adding silver chloride
to pure water and at silver chloride to water that already contains some silver chloride
you say well that's obvious to contain some silver chloride can put as much as
they otherwise could but now i'm going to say
is that silver chloride sodium chloride does the presence of sodium chloride have any impact
on the dissolution of silver chloride so again look at
arrhenius theory of electrolytic dissociation so silver chloride will dissociate and go into solution of
cation and chloride anion and sodium chloride is present as
sodium ion
and chloride
so we've got now
no here
multiple sources of chloride ions
multiple sources
of chloride ions
get some chloride ions from silver chloride some chloride ions from
sodium chloride is so the consequence of that is that i know i can no
longer assume that the concentration of silver
i am equals the concentration of chloride that's no longer the case
because i've got some chloride ion that came from sodium
that's the problem
that's the problem so what do i do
i'm going to try to find the this
saturation solubility of silver chloride under these new circumstances so i'm going to go back
to my solubility product ksp
KSP KSP is going to equal the product of the silver ion concentration
concentration of chloride ions and i can take a stab at what this is
i'm told that this is on the order of zero point one molar
and we saw that in the case of pure silver chloride it's ten to the
minus five more
ten minus five before the magnitude lower even when we have full dissociation here so
i'm going to assume that ten minus one more is so much greater than
ten to the minus five or
which is what we got in pure silver chloride that i'm going to neglect the
contribution of chloride ions from silver chloride and say that the concentration of chloride is
simply equal to
zero point one because several point one is so much greater
what is
left over from the previous
calculation and now i can still make the
connection between the dissolution of silver chloride salt and the concentration of silver ion that
still exists is one to one so
this will then represent the sea of silver chloride times
zero point one and that's equal to this one point eight times ten to the
what is the ten to the minus ten
so i can solve for the concentration of
silver chloride
and that gives me
one point eight
times ten to the minus nine molar
so the presence of the chloride from sodium has had a tremendous
repressive effect on the dissolution of silver chloride
this is called
the common ion effect
because i have a common iron from both solitude someone influences the solubility of the
fact and we can use the common ion effect to our advantage if i want
to process something in order to cause precipitation very very fine particles i can load
solution with one song you introduce the second solitude and trigger the precipitation and doing
so control
particle size
and the shape
and thereby prepare material for subsequent processing in fact
you can use this if you want to determine if you've got water has been
simple thing you can do if you go back to that table eight seven
we all know that silver nitrate
silver nitrate is very very high
the solubility in water
so i introduced silver nitrate into water and the question is is there any chlorine
and if there's any chlorine present we know
that the saturation solubility of silver chloride is ten to the minus five molar what
will happen is if you've got chlorinated water you and silver nitrate
you all
cf a shower
a very very fine
which is the silver chloride
so this is a very good test for
now that's on the back of your hand out there this is not really because
we're not going to we're not going to collect it
you throw it away
it's here to intended to do two things one to show you something about the
method that we will be using here and two
to show you something of the level of this discourse the the level of the
the questions that i'm asking on this
the query is
questions asked on the quiz are the types of things we would expect you to
know at the end of the course not them
but at the end of the course some of these are difficult
if you find yourself getting most of these answers correct then don't take this course
be wasting your time with your money here so don't do this if you you
find the end of got sixteen seventeen eighteen these are alright let's start with a
little bit of classical music here and this
engages questions one and two
who is the composer of the piece that you're about to hear and what is
its title what's it called
so let's that's where i'm going to ask them to take you the next piece
here we talk about that just from moment the composer anybody know the composer of
this reader OK some people do some people don't gentleman over here dark doctor
OK that is beethoven ludwig van beethoven and you know the name of the piece
OK symphony number five now if you're sitting next to the church of god this
kind of so much
i'm not going down the tube in this course don't be intimidated by by this
as a saying we're going to build everybody up here together so that was beethoven's
fifth symphony the beginning of a famous passage in the history of classical music let's
listen to another composition here who is the composer of this
and what in what composition is this piece
that's probably enough for that so who is the composer of that anybody know the
fewer people do in linear integrated of your hand
again they
what's the what's new in what composition does beethoven used this particular
OK in the ninth symphony again it's a long really worried now don't be we
don't be worried here
OK so nice now
i believe
that music
a magical
potions magical spell
music gets to do a particular kinds of things gets us to feel particular kinds
of words and i think these two pieces by the same composer get
cause us to feel very
very different because different moods different psychological state to come over as one of them
it goes this way
and the other
i do a little experiment have never done this before never done this before but
i like to do the following
and that is to ask you
think about what each piece causes you to fall into and i've put some adjectives
up on the board of the group them by orson welles because i'm going to
ask you to raise your right hand if you respond one way to appease on
your left hand if you respond to others so on they are group there we've
got positive happy secure under the l group we've got negative anxious and settled
so i've chosen pieces maybe was slightly different fields here let's see let's see what
we do with this now
please number one
how do you feel about that now here's piece two
so here's one and play it again
if you raise your right hand or left hand as your response to that
here's piece one
right and left
all right
those of you that are raising your hand some more recent here but that's okay
those of you you know almost unanimously say
that's the beat of the fifth symphony sound somewhat ominous two is somewhat faithful to
this and the beethoven ninth symphony conversely has a different sort of feel to it
indeed does anybody know the title of the beethoven ninth symphony with the setting of
a poem by friedrich schiller recall
altered your
o to join so how does beethoven go about making the older joy joyful
what is he doing here this is what we're going to be doing our course
we're gonna be zeroing in on this music can anybody tell me why to a
person in this room we all responded positively to the ninth symphony and somewhat more
anxiously to the system
you tell me one thing
you're going to do is to look at all the social features of the two
strings to two big structures and you're going to in some way count the number
of social action that they have in common
the challenge now
once you have these general principle is is just to to know into to devise
efficient ways to do that
and know devising efficient ways means that you have to
identify what kind of substructures can be inherited efficiently
and can be
our and what kind of substructures carry enough information on the global structure
actually how how to do that and there's another idea
dating to the late nineties which is the idea of fisher kernels were you to
there's a process in two steps where you first learn generative models of your structured
data so generative models is directly connected to what acidic talk talk to talk to
you about yesterday and graphical models for instance you can when i say fisher kernels
the first use of fisher kernels
by a clan or slow was with
he then markov models
the use hidden markov models to model of the density of self of sequences protein
and they use that to to to to
to do the fisher kernels i'm going back to two
this example later
so they're remark that i did before is that there exists a tremendous amount of
work on building kernels for sequences i intentionally focus on research such kernels because i
don't have time and i have to have the whole knowledge about that but i
think that this idea
especially specifically this idea of comparing substructures of the whole structures into two to derive
a similarity function based on all the constitutions is very powerful idea
let's consider the problem of of of
deriving a carol for for sequences here you have a sequence
of amino acids
let's say that's amino acids acids and why you're going to do i'm going to
describe what is called the spectrum kernel something that was proposed by palestinian coauthors in
two thousand two
and the the strategy is very simple simple given two different sequences it just count
the number of common k mers cameras just like UK graph shows you you're going
to to look at subsequences of of
of size k
and you're looking to count the number of subsequences of size k that you have
in common the two subsequently in the two sequences
and computer value from this counts
in the first four four proteins you have an alphabet of twenty symbols they're all
amino acids and what you're going to be going to do is in some way
if you do in a very naive way you're going to
two two two will go through all your your words sequences and you will collect
all the numbers to the number of times or if you have a b and
then a BB in the BBC
you do that
it is that you that
i mean that each
three mirrors
each k mer corresponds to one coordinating in this long vector is different different
and then you do that for you sequences that for second sequence and then you
have vector your vector representation of your data and then you can do
everything you you you you want
so there's there's something that it's important
if you look at and that i don't know if it's the case
so it's twenty to the three
the this is the size of the vectors is very very big vector it's actually
it's a very sparse they use there there are very few nonzero entries in this
victory so explicitly constructing these kind of vectors given sequences and trying to explicitly constant
is that is is is is not very efficient
and the nice way
that leslie and her coco others found to to do that is to exploit the
structure of suffix trees
so i don't know if you're aware of specifics trees but there are those are
structure very efficient if you very efficient for instance if you want to you have
a whole dictionary and you want to find the word containing i don't know ABC
then this is precisely the kind of thing of things that travels on electronic dictionary
it is very easy to find words that contain some subsequence
and the reason why it's very efficient to do that is because they use suffix
trees suffix trees
are our structures
that are very compact and their help you
and organize all your data and help you
find a subset sequence of things
OK so the the thing is that they take the they have the they they
took advantage of this kind of structures and used it to compute to efficiently compute
the dot product between the the the the victorious that i showed you just before
i mean that i should have put it in in red because this is the
crux of
building kernels
four forest structured data again
very powerful idea for the literals to build kernels for for structured data is to
objects with respect to all the substructures that you have
and the
the real question is to do that very efficient
and doing that very efficiently makes you consider nice structure like a tree struck suffix
tree structures or dynamic programming or or things very very beautiful things that come for
computer science
from the ongoing point of view so my structures myself greetings and and again the
the the the thing is to find
the nice trade of
again between how
how informative are structures that you have and how easy it is to to make
computations on those substructures
so the results that they had protein classification problem where
just comparable to other methods but not better and
these pools the need of another sequence kernel they they propose another one a little
bit more involved
not not that very are different but they used what they call the mismatch string
if you want if you really want the details on these people i invite you
to just down the papers you can download them and so it's
what we learn is that shape varies across categories but not within categories in shape
is just behaves just like colored here but these other dimensions of texture colour and
size as you as you might guess
i don't know
and if we if we then go and apply this to the case of the
you know that there was actually tested the sort of transfer fees so now we
have a new object in a new category number five here
and a new shape
texture new color
so on
what's important in this simulation of course any models that to do something like this
for this task is that
we assume there's more possible shapes textures colors and so on then actually observed during
training may be a lot more but the key thing about this kind of hierarchical
bayesian model is it can learn expectations even for them the values of dimensions that
have been seen so even for example for shape
that has never been seen before
paired with the category labels and then we have these three test items this one
here corresponds to having the same shape
as as the as the dax but a different new texture and color
this one has a different shape
and the different color but the same texture and so on and what the model
tells us is that
this one is much more likely to have come from the same category this one
came from the these two so relatively this is the best choice for next so
even this very simple model is capable of of capturing this kind of abstract transfer
that the that children seem to show
now this model is is very simple and it's easy to come up with limitations
for example assuming that we have a a single dimension of shape maybe seems like
a limitation and there's lots of extensions which you can go through which i'm i'm
not going to go through here because i'm going to shift to a different topic
you know we can work with more
distributed representations of shape for example and get the same kind of effect of this
talk about one extension because it's it's again corresponds to an interesting developmental milestones and
it has a nice machine learning correlate which is interesting kind of selective transfer depending
on knowledge of ontological kinds
the shape bias that we saw was a phenomenon that takes into an h two
by age three
children know about the shape bias but they also know that other kinds of biases
for example and they restrict them appropriately to certain
large-scale categories so they apply the shape bias to solid object categories like ball book
toothbrush but
for non solid substances like for example toothpaste they apply material bias you can introduce
new weird gel nonsolid substance or if we had everything
and they will not care about the shape of the
of that entity but they will care about its material properties in generalizing and were
again that's correct bias so it takes a little bit longer to learn so how
can we model this kind of selective transfer well you might say
suppose we have we know the ontological kind whether something is solid object or nonsolid
that's the easy variable here then we could just learn a separate dirichlet multinomial model
for each
if for each ontological category you know this is just adding another level to the
bayesian hierarchy so here capturing variability in features for solid objects knowing that say all
all things in this category are solid but shape is variable
across objects although not within category and other features are variable within categories while the
cross-country and then the lower level learning specifics about what words refer to which shapes
and then we can we will learn something corresponding over here on the material side
but of course
this itself is already oversimplified because the data don't necessarily come labelled this way we
don't appear in know what the right ontological kinds are the this is chicken and
egg problem we don't know how to partition the object categories into
these these different parts of the of the hierarchical structure
a solution to this is just in to add inference at this higher level using
a nonparametric prior over this partition in particular using a chinese restaurant
process prior so we're saying that
each object category
belongs to some higher level ontological kind that's the easy vector but we don't know
how many ontological kinds are which object categories in which ontological kind but we can
do inference over that at the same time as we do inference about these two
levels of parameters and in fact the simple toy datasets recover the right kind of
structure here
so it's this is this is kind of nice it's certainly related to CRP mixtures
but instead of clustering objects or clustering categories of objects and the what the objects
in a conventional clustering model the objects
i have something in common here the categories of objects don't really have anything concrete
in common in fact the most distinctive feature which is the shape back of objects
in the category is totally different for every category but what they have in common
is that they draw on the same kind of prior
so it's this kind of
class in the sense clustering but you get an abstract level by combining a nonparametric
cluster prior with a hierarchical bayesian model is a powerful way to do selective transfer
and in fact very recently
some other researchers at MIT dan roy unless the cabling have to find a related
model for selected transfer task in in in in an applied setting where you're trying
to learn it's project where you're trying to learn whether user will accept meeting invitation
and they learn the naive bayes classifier for each user but then they define a
CRP prior
over the parameters of those naive bayes classifiers and they able to sort of improved
transfer by triggered by figuring out just exactly which users should be should be used
to transfer to which other users
so this kind of idea could have
i think a lot of implications
other applications of machine learning now what i want to do next is turned to
setting which is in some sense more knowledge rich in the in the previous setting
it was nice because the time it was very simple
elegant mathematical model of the very important developmental phenomenon but there wasn't much interesting structure
knowledge representation going on which i was arguing is so crucial for human learning so
to get that what we're going to switch to a different task which is another
one of these tasks generalizing from a few examples it's task that many psychologists have
really since the mid-seventies there's a lot of data here that you can model
and our models can get much more quantity
so here's the kind of task
it's in the form of evaluating the strength of an inductive argument but again it's
like generalizing a new concept from a few examples so these are the premises guerrillas
have t nine hormones seals have t nine hormones scrolls have t nine hormones and
you ask how likely is it that the conclusion is true given these premises how
likely is it that horses have t nine hormones given that these two so to
compare this with say the word learning case there's a new concept which is having
t nine hormones and you get a few examples of things and that concept and
you have to judge the probability that something else is in the concepts of the
same kind of task but it's it's in some sense easier to study
talk about something even more challenging than making these bots fight successfully and that is
to have a team AI
well it works not
you probably have the right codec if you want to go
that's a good idea
so it's quite clear that if you want to have a team behaving in in
some interesting ways in the video working together then you have these additional problems of
cooperation and coordination of the team effort
now there is essentially two approaches to this you can view the team as one
and this age is very complex beast and has to do all of this coordination
essentially from a centralized
the decision function point-of-view
and what have view that is of course much more elegant is to view this
as a distributed system we agents that have individual policies but certain ways of communicating
and thereby of cooperating
and i would just like to point out is probably most famous example
robocop where people have been studying these multiagent systems for quite awhile
we do i don't actually know which type of this is
the this thing works
well these are not my thing here i think
the nice thing is in robocup that's very very different leagues some of them i
think i do with some of them are real robots of course
and some of them follow this idea of
of the abstraction by just simulating a soccer games and also stimulating the inputs the
individual players get
and so this is very
very abstract version of of soccer of course and there is a huge literature on
how people have approach this problem that the typical approach goes
four nice approach if you like is to study subproblem you could have a
three attackers in front of the goal and two defenders and the goalie and then
you would have
policy is say parametrized by neural networks and you could for example copy of the
policy into each of the attacking players and you would have a different policy for
the two defenders and even different policy for the goalkeeper and then you would just
and you would get the reinforcement signals from the results of play you could imagine
that you get very positive feedback if for example the the attackers before they would
get the positive feedback and in that case this defenders would get a negative feedback
signal and
the interesting thing is that people never really succeeded in in generating corporation in this
way if only enough information of what the other agents were doing is made available
to any single agent and those are quite interesting pieces of work
so in this particular example of robocop the typical decisions that have to be made
are far field player if he should read the efficient if it should pass or
he he should shoot
for a goalkeeper as he has to predict whether ball might be going or if
the if the ball is passed in front of the goal then of course he
has to switch to another focus point and the really exciting thing is if by
training single agents here you can get emergence emergent behavior however there's a caveat again
this is not a game designer i mean it's not there are nasty guys but
they have this very strong focus on predictability and so they may not be very
happy with this emergent behavior so it's very important to test the limits of this
so well robocup is a relatively simple one
many constructive algorithm from it
and if you look at you know a space of possible features right in the
way that computer vision was done is in the last twenty years is that people
are trying to figure out what the right representations to use
based on images so if you look at different
there's things like sifts
so text arms and you know all kinds of stuff
that people are
i have been developing
if you look at the audio features again spectrograms them after he sees
flux and again all kinds of different features to use
right one question that's you know we're interested in and in general deploying communities interested
in is that how can we do feature learning can we actually figure out what
the right features to use from these data
and it turns out that's you know i've shown you some of the examples of
recognition it was actually a remarkable breakthrough because by using these models and in learning
the features themselves
right you can outperform basically the state of the art recognition systems that have been
used and know that the vision community has been using speech recognition community have been
using in the past ten fifteen years
so one particular model
this is sort of the oldest model ford for learning features is is sparse coding
model has been used a lot it's it's it's a very popular models one of
the building blocks of of many deep learning algorithms
and the idea is the following
you've have
a set of input data vectors x one to seven and you want to learn a dictionary of bases
and you want additional bases such that you can reconstruct the data
based on on these bases
right so it's a very simple formulation but the key thing here is that what you'd like to do
is you'd like these
these coefficients to be sparse
so what is essentially saying is that well each data object is gonna be represented
as a sparse linear combination of basis
so you know you can imagine that you have you know ten thousand bases but
you might wanna say well only ten of these vectors should be used for reconstructing
the data right
that's the idea
and this belongs to the class of so-called unsupervised learning algorithm there is no labels
are just trying to find the right basis so that can reconstruct the data is
as as
as much as you can
so for example for natural images if i take a natural images ethical patches from those natural images
then this is how these bases would look like so you can see a lot
of them look like little edges or r a little bit more like
that's seems like the right structure extract from images
at least when you talk to
neuroscientists they believe that that's actually something that's
happens in the visual area one human brain
if i give you a new example a new patch
then i can essentially
reconstructed is made is the sum of these three patches so can sort of see
that u u picks up by a
a sparse number or few number of these bases and can reconstruct an example and it turns out that these
the new representation that you get
despite the presentation that together what is one particular with the feature representation it turns
out to be much more useful to deal with
then the pixels themselves
right so working in this basis if you want for example classify
these images as turns out to be much more
has much better generalization performance
so how would you do training of of of these models well
u half an arm
inputs and you'd like to learn
the bases
so you have two different terms and one term is essentially saying well you'd want
to reconstruct the data as as
without introducing any years so you'd you'd like to have a small reconstruction error
on the other hand we also have a sparsity penalty you say well i don't
use a water-based reconstructed i just want use a few
basis to reconstruct this is kind of like controls so
the complexity of the model
and the optimization itself can be done fairly easily
it turns out that's you know for a fixed if you're fixing the basis phi why up to fight
and you solving forty coefficients in
then it turns out to be standard lasso problem problem right so just squared loss plus one penalty vicious lasso
and they can be solved fairly efficiently using quadratic programming so that's that's standard
you know machine learning one one
and then when you fix thee
activations you'd optimise for the dictionary basis and then again that's a convex optimization problem
is a quadratic programming problem and you can solve
so consider these alternating
minimization fixing the basis finding the activations
fixing the activations reflecting the new basis
so that's a pretty straightforward and now the best time
there's is also symmetric successive over relax asian which is you do every exotic combination
of upper and lower triangular diagonal parts of the original matrix and you put it
into a big messy thing and then you back solve OK so that's another classic
thing that people do OK so very classic
methods and can be thought of nothing more than preconditioned iterative methods are
and can
so these things still are to are too slow into an unreliable in the sense
of gauss i doubt if it converges great if it doesn't it's not so clear
you right so the problem is is that you know
our goal is to generate solvers for which they work systematically right what i would
like to be able to do is generated solver for which i can
put it into a program role into a doctor's office and have them music twenty
four seven and not phoned me up in the middle of the night and say
this already in the works
i mean there's other kind of solvers right to the big distinction here to make
the the reliability right
so i would imagine if all you we want to solver for which
you're going to go home and use it yourself personally
its sales one two hundred times about the failure rate of the shuttle that may
be just fine right i mean the spatial that's all you need
if that's the case you want to send this selling products
then failure rates one two hundred and a little bit is too high in the
lower failure rate so i would like to do is actually have our that always
so that's what i mean by unreliable most of the stuff works nice most of
the time but it will fail
and this the wrong OK
so so in order to be able to come up with a theory for which
we can claim that they are the works were systematically in other words we can
give guarantees unfortunately we have to start restricting the number of kind of matrices they
come up
fortunately if you look at most people in this room they think this is a
very natural restriction and so they're not unhappy at all
you're not happy but but nonetheless it is a major restriction on the types of
matrices we're going to be able to solve so let's talk about the graph plots
in which you all know
then we take a weighted undirected graph you some albeit weights are
strictly positive you define the incidence matrix you find the degree matrix which is just
simply the sum of the weights
giving you a diagonal matrix and from that and the la plata simply d minus
and so for what we're gonna do now for the next while then is we're
going to restrict ourself to
linear systems where the underlying system is as the graph of plus
so the graph plotting comes up and in many places
every every other talk here
let me just make this review some of the classic places it comes up
one of the reasons it's useful to do that is is that even if you
don't care about these applications
and you're still using graph of in is very useful to know that
the system you're solving has very other
and a multitude of other meanings
so you're solving the system for some other meeting
you know what's some marketing problem or something
but it may have some very natural meaning in terms resistors or in terms of
spring mass system other things right so let's go through some
so one idea is severely changes the conductor
with conductance w i j
so if you let v be a column vector of voltages
then lv
it will see
then c will be the residual current needed to maintain the given voltage
OK so
OK so in particular what it says then it is that in order to maintain
the voltage at those nodes are going to have to either inject current to remove
current them out you have to inject or are removed is precisely c
you can also turn this on its head if you know how much current you
want to inject
then what voltages will flow to in order to maintain to have those current
OK and so the classic way to an overview of the glaciers very useful
so another place this comes up that's basically the heat equation
and so that's the standard
places comes up
and other places comes up as a random walk
again here the transition matrix ends up being simply the inverse square diagonal matrix we
had before
times posterior
an interesting question and it is to compute the fundamental eigen vectors of these kind
of systems and one amazing thing here is that fast solvers which will talk about
this film and tanks over
is very theoretical
but it's it's interesting in the sense that says that the problem of getting harder
so i won't be able to prove that you could do that it takes more
what ends up happening is well maybe this is the wrong place for it in
the talk about
if you're interested in i can vectors of graph plus unions
so the standard theory would say you trying to do forward powers the way to
find cycles vectors
so we found both experimentally and theoretically actually doing inverse powering is the trick that
works much better if you in fact simply do take here
i initial guess for nike in vector and you simply then take the inverse power
that gas and repeat that process after log iterations will converge to something with very
small rayleigh quotient in practice something that looks like an idea to
OK so it's very powerful track which may be over that but
you know that
that's very nice idea OK
so to the other place that will questions come up is in spring mass systems
again suppose we have a weighted graph and suppose we view instead the constants
as spring constants
the w ideas spring constant
and suppose we let and
the diagonal matrix of mass constants
a standard results
is that if you look at the item pairs
to this system
part of speech information and syntactic information seems to be fairly relevant for reordering
some publication hope that a little bit more if you believe this text as building
models are talking about non surface forms part of part of speech tags
does it help to you
you could also use actually bigger blocks for part of speech tags if you might
have seen a seven
but part of speech text sequence very often
so does that help you with reordering
and the answers
yes but things get very complicated
so that that's one thing to do
there's also the idea to use some kind of shallow syntax two
not only have part of speech tags but have
you know
tax that span multiple births
so check there is
you actually want to have like two words subject there
and to do with that you can say well the first one is the beginning
of the noun phrase and the second was the continuation of the noun phrase that
allows you to label things chunk things into the syntactic chunks and maybe using these
kind of things helps as well
this is more than long range reordering
this is work that kind of finished at this point one
factor models that's it
any questions for us
so i mean a lot of the stuff available because it's one of the fundamental
problems of people work in natural language processing so for english
there are several part of speech tags you can get
that they basically all train on things like the penn treebank
so there are so the one tag are used for initial rules
tiger which is available from his webpage stone technology in the nineties
probably also the the possibility of a lot of maximum entropy tag as that can
be trained if you have a corpus annotated part of speech tags
so not
sure participation spanish but i think there are things that treebank and part of speech
so those things are available
so so you the way we got subject object possibility by passing things so if
you have a pass so you can get these things
what seems a bit harder to get but is something available is this real morphological
analyses that say this is the root for the word in this in this has
this property
again for german we have
some i know i mean we've been using things
are available
yeah i
mean you know spanish new work was shown
as the
so i think part of speech taggers exist for many many languages process exist
if there's a treebank
mean there's a lot of effort in many languages developed readings
morphological analyses it harder to get the space some people do research on
it just send an email asking if you can get the tool also time to
give it to us
it was
the core region
there's so much o OK
so i said about the two sides civil society
OK so this is just to get some results on this
papers written as we speak so the basic idea is that if you look at
the paris peace sequence
you can learn much larger patterns
then you if you just look at the surface for so the phrase we extract
the phrase expecially the phrase we used to be the average length two words
and given the input sentence
there might be seven part of speech tags and sequence of you know how to
you have whatever you probably for each
noun phrase and translate from spanish to english
you have seen that particular pattern of whatever action known as the adjective noun
determine you have now and into whatever the terminology tragedy using those kind of patterns
often enough
so you should learn to be able to learn
patterns on that level fairly frequently and there has been work on doing this in
in reordering
before according you learn all the ordering patterns and then
we use search tool
following this we are independent
here the idea is that you do this also in in the factor model as
well so you have
you do you
first translate
and this part of speech patterns
and then you fill in the noun phrase afterwards
so you
you kind of have
kind of the true level of phrase segmentation of the input one is segmented it
in a certain way on the part of speech for the part of speech in
any segment and it little bit finer
on the actual surface form of words
but does
make things a bit more complicated with the decoding because the way it is presented
according as the do all these segmentation in the same granularity
so if you if you have longer patterns for some factors that for others