identically distributed assumption it's just the product of these goes in
where each should the means corresponds to deterministic response of our model
so there is the likelihood function
and we can see that the likelihood depends on the model of the the model
parameters now
we should just remember here that
our model
correspond node corresponds to
not only the deterministic component
but also the stochastic component so we have a statistical
part of the model no which captures the uncertainty
and our observations
and this is winnow move forward from the least squares estimator just just giving up
which is just point addiction two
the fact that we have to find the statistical model which captures and the stochastic
component of our model means that
what we're going to be able to bit more
sensible in terms of characterising any residual uncertainty as far as predictions are made
what this means there is that we can use this function
to tune the parameters
of our model which no correspond to w and sigma
to make
the data to make our observations more likely under our model
so let's do that
and how do we do it
well we find the maximum of the likelihood function with respect to the model parameters
and we can use the logarithm of the likelihood the logarithm is are convex functions
so that argument which maximizes the likelihood will be the same argument which maximizes the
of the likelihood
and this is well there are a number of reasons why we use the log
so again we use the same school algebra we turn the crime we we need
to take derivatives of the log likelihood function
so let's do that
so what is the log likelihood
remember the likelihood is that this is the product of these individual components so we
know have the sum of the log of the components
some of one of these go since
you're introduced to go oceans by walking
i believe so our our log likelihood function corresponds to this was just constant terror
respectively the value of the parameters
river thames here
related to the statistical component of our model the noise variance and then we have
component here which
should look familiar to
those of you who are still awake
this is basically just the squared mismatch between deterministic
point the model and
the observations
we take the stationary points with respect to w
again for those of you familiar with this
very good for those of you who are not grabbed me and again i will
show you how we can
makes these derivations in the laboratory but basically the stationary point to the likelihood with
respect to the deterministic component of the
the model
it is defined as this
and the matrix of second order partial derivatives of the
log likelihood function
turns out to be
well the sex transpose x ten which is so previously i mean have one over
the noise variance
and this happens to be strictly negative so indeed by finding the stationary point
we find the maximum of the likelihood
and the maximum likelihood solution
is then just simply
this term here we get that in closed form
and that should look familiar
as it is indeed just the least squares
so for those of you again you are not familiar with this let me just
label the point that we have no have an equivalence between the maximum likelihood estimator
under linear model and the least squares
estimator under squared error loss
big deal
well that's a big deal and no one other thing of course we have to
do to still identify
our statistical model is get the stationary points of sigma
and and that means that as the tutorial exercise for you and i would even
those of you who know this
but the back of your hand i would
i would suggest that you just try to convince yourself that you are masters of
what does this buy is anything more
than a simple least squares estimator
one of the things that we
those of us who work in machine learning sleep voters assessing certainty
and uncertainty
more the case
and are maximum likelihood estimates
well it's w heart is the maximum likelihood estimate
then we want to know
what the variance
of that estimators
so what variability is there around
w height
so clearly the variability is low then we have high confidence to be built is
then we will be is confident
so can be characterized this
we can't
now let's just remember this is a vector w had is a vector so what
we want to do is we want to obtain
the covariance matrix associated
with the covariance
of this the system here
i'm saying remember that covariance vector is defined as
this here if if you don't remember then let me just remind you that we
the outer product of our maximum likelihood estimates minus the expected value of the maximum
likelihood estimator
we take the product of that and take expectation
of the density of body and here there was following all this you know acoustic
wave with do with it
the radiation and the dark matter
i must also feel gravity must somewhat displays in order to see how the veracity
of body and a better falling
this power spectrum of the galaxies which traces
basically the power spectrum of the dark matter should about tiny little empirical which is
this sort of bark reaction say
of the fact that much of this is that the bodies were displaced
and this is here this has been enhanced by simply dividing discovered by of a
flat curve without the oscillations and this installation were predicted to be there seems you
know the very beginning of all these story the cosmological perturbation we're actually detected only
about five years ago
and this is very interesting because with the cosmic background you have a standard ruler
the last scattering surveys and you can drive you can draw the larger triangle but
you can do only one triangle is only between you and the last couple of
but hey we can see galaxies we can see the power spectrum of the dark
matter as it is traced by galaxies
i thought i should we want as long as there are galaxies there and we
know that galaxies have to actually five remember most of the volume of the universe
anyway is between you are fifty or so
so hey we can all play the same game
over and over again and several different pressure
so imagine how much a learned from the cosmic microwave background the cosmic by accepted
except that i can repeat the name of the game again only if i could
have measurement like that but not just an issue zero like this measurement is about
the whole sort of the fresh
and there's a lot of effort going on in to try to devise experiment that
can actually do that
OK we're not there yet the proposers of a
OK so what are the latest constraints remember we've seen this plot before would not
probabilities constraint of the very latest constraints again omega omega lambda and surprise surprise nothing
really changed their about a little bit smaller cosmic background remember to tell you that
the universe is flat with very good approximation this is the line that the universe
is flat
so here this is the clustering properties of galaxies in distant supernovae and OK we
then again
the cosmic by still holds
so this is our cosmological model and the cosmological parameters have been determined
we do not percent precision so we say the now cosmology and the precision error
because until say
ten years ago
cosmology was the kind of science where you did can plot are about
because they were to be so why bother or what parameters were known within an
order of magnitude remember how would say that the hubble constant was five hundred we
know today that seventy
but now the parameters are known with percent precision so tell me that they have
in custody seventy five or sixty eight makes a difference
because now we can write we can compute the error bars and they are very
if you want to learn more about that and even play with the data except
that i just to give you this this website
so let me skip
noting also less somebody one two
ask me about that
and let me go through some passes of the cosmological model
so the standard cosmological model says that ninety six percent of the universe is missing
a lot of it is that kind of your cosmological constant and you know almost
a quarter of it is that so this leaves us with major questions
major questions that can be addressed exclusively by looking at the sky because these
o thing here
you can address it also by you know going underground and trying to do direct
this here
it's a little bit more
so major question what created the primordial perturbations
and what makes the universe today accelerate
this question may not be related
let me try to show you one
so the success of the big bang model the big my model is made in
general relativity plus the cosmological principle
and from that you can derive the hubble law
you can derive the cosmic microwave background which we have seen you can derive the
abundance of the light element and you can confirm that by looking at the the
universe very and banks region where starts were not form and did not polluted
and all these all together very nicely
but the standard big bang model also creates problems
that is called the flatness problem there is an problem in the monopole problem
and on top of that the origin of the perturbation
let try to see why that is
so what do i mean by the flatness problem again a little bit of magic
but they just write it here so you have
so remember when we write the friedmann equation we can write one minus omega this
summer guys everything
except curvature and we write curvature on side
so today we know that one minus this omega which is zero because it days
less than point o one
so it's very close to main flight
let's imagine that this quantity was point one
let's try to go back in the life of the universe and see what omega
would have to be
back in the past
so we can write this equation like these rewrite it in terms of a function
of time to do some modification
because i want to have you know i wanted to convey right here and this
omega got a function of time here
so for most of the life of the universe the universe was matter radiation only
so i can simplify my life by writing it this way
so this becomes something like that
so let's look at this equation here in the month domination eighty goes like t
to the tooth fairy
so this becomes like this
and so on
well let's look at this as i go into the past
the universe become flatter flat so if this is by no one
in the past
it was closer and closer to zero
so an exercise for you is what was days
but the matter radiation equality so here we have assumed that the universe for most
of his life was matter dominated but as you go in the past at some
point it was radiation dominated so this conclusion conclude by say it's matter dominated until
matter radiation equality and then they switch and states radiation dominated before then
so you can figure out what my tradition at the time of my traditional qualities
remembering that the shift it's about three thousand
and then after you do that you and the radiation domination remembering radiation domination things
changed his course like t
and so one minus on the gang radiation dominated is one minus omega quality
with this correction here because this because like t
so the exercise value is to ask
what was then this quantity that one second after the big bang
hey we need to run a steeplechase and that either involves doing the move or
jumping at this point we've done enough stepwise refinement that we've got the level of
primitive we don't need to go any further cause carol immediately understands move jump carol
doesn't understand so once we've written this we need to break it down to the
lower level steps and say what is jump for involved and that's where we actually
go down to find jumper and guess what we define jump there might be some
other things like ascending and descending which are the next steps down in the process
that we need to define we just keep doing this
OK so with that said let's actually do top-down design together let's start another program
from a blank slate and see if we can do top-down design together to see
how this process might actually go for writing code
OK so the problem that we want to try to solve
if we want all and don't look at the code we want to try to
get this is kind of funky problem it's carol doesn't matter if you didn't think
carol could do math in fact carol can do MAP carols a lot smarter than
we sometimes given credit for so this little problem called double b players
so i don't know you can see the number here but a five-year which means
there five people on this corner and when this program is done running what we
want to have happen is killed guaranteed starting position one one and there is guaranteed
to be a pilot people in front of them in a space after k when
he's done he should return back to the same position and the pilot people should
have exactly twice as many beekeepers on it as it had before which means carol
begins with the beeper bag that's full of as many beekeepers in each that infinity
prisoner so we can double the number of papers sofie speed up the program and
just running you can see the final state so let me just crank up the
speed here
and start the program and it looks like nothing happened but in fact number change
from five to attend double the number of people so two things should be going
off in right now one is thinking hey
that's kind of slick how do i do that what's the recipe for doing that
and the recipe for doing that this is the sort of general approach you want
to take a something that we call an algorithm
so the notion of an algorithm and this is just a fancy computer science term
an approach to something
actually comes from where anyone know where the word algorithm comes from
couple mumbling
the nineteenth century persian mathematician named if i can pronounce right alkali zero hour i
should be able to say that i'm actually persian al wiring is rising
reason why there reasoning which sounds like algorithm there you go
and hundred years to pronunciation it sounds like algorithm because it is from the nineteenth
century it your basic approaches that the at stanford years and years ago called the
algo rithms where this was like rhythm like a i got rhythm
i won't say how good they are not very high so
you want to think about your general approach and then you turn your general approach
into thinking in terms of stepwise refinement power you're going to solve this problem from
the top down that actually start with a blank slate let's close this puppy
and we'll start with a blank slate which we'll call o our double purse so
i just gave you the boilerplate stuff to begin with there little comment up at
the top that says file double be person should be called our double beeper is
actually in carol double the number of people on the corner directly in front of
the the world he returns to its original position orientation so we have the public
class stuff for our double first we have it to extend super carol we're not
going to run the run method can a so what do we want to do
to get carol to double the number of the present high level what what what
might be think about doing this
we need to figure out how many papers there in order to to do that
maybe we should move to the pile of papers right it's one avenue in front
of us so we do move and here's the part that almost seems like matching
the same move heyer on the pile the first now one you i hate double
the beavers in the pile
and you like
american i do that
sure why not
right you're going to write the program you can do whatever you want so i
would like to say move double of
and the pile and then actually what i wanna do is not move forward again
but i want to move backwards
what i want to move almost like kernel could go in reverse that we kind
of call to keep the same orientation that goes back to new like but now
i you didn't tell me about move backward super carol to move backward like know
like OK well alright well i guess i need to write some of these right
let's actually do move backward is that the easier one if i'm sitting on a
particular corner facing east what do i need to do to move backward one step
and face the same direction
i need so i mean define move backward here move backwards i need to turn
around which is the primitive that i can use the then what do i do
move and then what do i do
i turn around again so i have the same orientation when i'm done it when
i started and now guess what move backward something i understand how to do because
i've broken it all down into primitives i don't need to go any further in
terms of their funding from turn or from move backwards but now there's the magical
power either double b in pile and that's something that might be a little bit
more involved i come along and say OK need to define what double be present
pilots double pipas in pile at this point i need to think about my algorithm
what's going to be my approach for doubling the number of people is what's the
way that i could possibly think about the problem because carol cannot count right there's
is no way for carol to say hey count how many people are this corner
what's what's one where he might approach it
that would be nice if we had to counter but we don't have accounts
right so carol can count
how potentially going to do it all the way back
you my complaint
so you have to pick up one time and put it on the corner and
when he puts it and you can't put two it was for that one puts
so what we do i know it's not going to happen and i understand karen
and you realize that have been thinking about fifteen years and my shot never improved
so you're just you know at the random can mercy since we can count we
need to do something be provided for so wouldn't be interesting if we said hey
you're on a pile of the first pick up one b prof the pile and
take a step somewhere else and put to be first down and keep doing that
over and over pick up be prepared to down eventually ill exhaust everything on this
poll over here but you have twice as many on the next pile beside you
and then take the pile of twice as many people and move them all back
to the place we started and then you're done that's the algorithm let's write the
code to do that like OK now i'm i try do that in my garage
band is going to be easy right what we're going to do is we're just
going to say you're on the power of the purse as long as they are
still be first for you to pick up some and have a while here while
b pers
well what i want you to do is pick up the deeper you know how
to do that life is good
before i was misspelled before i don't know why i want you to put to
be person next door put two
the slope of this line is minus one over c
but the slope of the line element is going to be seen
those numbers minus one over c
and c
or negative receptacles
and you know the two lines
slopes the negative receptacles are perpendicular
so the line elements are always going to be perpendicular to these and therefore i
hardly even at the bottom calculating doing anymore calculation is going to be
well about this one that's his and controversial quite
then i see quite well aware
that doesn't correspond to anything looking like this
it would if i
multiply through by saying
and then we correspond to see being zero
in other words don't write like this multiply through by c will read c y
equals negative x and then when c is zero
i have x equals zero which is exactly the y axis so that really is
how about the x axis well
the x axis is not included on
however most people included anyway this is very common to be sort of sloppy bending
the edges corners a little bit you know hoping nobody will notice will say that
corresponds to see infinity
nobody wants to fight about that if you do go find somebody else so if
c is infinity
that means the line
willis said should have infinite slope and by common consent that means it should be
we could even count this is sort of a nice declining
not unlike the dashes smaller indicated has lower status than the others
put this in
do this easily thing of putting quotation marks to indicate that i'm not responsible for
OK now
we are now at the point in the integral curves will nothing could be easier
i'm looking for curvature everywhere perpendicular to these rains well
you know from geometry that those circles
so the integral curves are circles
and it's an elementary exercise i will which i will not deprive you of the
pleasure of cell
so all the body
by separation of variables
in other words we got the
so the articles are ones with the centre at the origin
calls some constant chord c one so it's not confused with this city of they
look like that and now
you should
solve this by separating variables and just confirm that the solutions are those circles
one interesting thing and can on this i will do it
because i want to do geometric and numerical things today
by separating variables one interesting thing to note is
if i write the solution is y equals y one of then x
well you look like something like the square root of c one minus
let's make the square because that's what people
my that square
so a solution typical solution looks like this
well what's the solution over here
that one solution only goes from here to here if you like it has a
negative side to it's all make the same cluster there's another solution which has a
negative value let's use of one of the positive value of the square root
my point is this that solution the domain of that solution
it only goes from here to here
it's not the whole x axis is just limited piece of the x axis where
the solution is defined
there's no way of extending it further
and there's no way of predicting by looking at the differential equation
that to typical solution was going to have a limited domain like that
in other words
you can find a solution but how far is it going to go sometimes it's
impossible to tell except by either finding it explicitly or by asking computer to draw
a picture of it and seeing that gives you some insight is one of the
many difficulties in handling differential equations you don't know what the domain of the solution
is going to be until you actually calculate
a slightly more complicated example
it's going to be let's see
why prime
equals one plus x minus one
it's not a lot more complicated and
as a computer exercise you work with still more complicated ones but here the isoclines
would be what well i said that equal to c
that is you can go around the loop
from those saying some potential
patterns that we probably won't point out here's body shape with already basically talked about
no shape that's pretty straightforward the year
basic arbiter shaped didn't really change from phase a through and they are we going
be owned by a little bit because it and wanted to interfere with the payload
bay door which was built by a different set of groups uh the Delta wing
we put a little crank and double delta and a a little more subsonic of
and we didn't have the body flap moving to start with but we found that
it was a very powerful control which assisted the
center of gravity movement
the full Pannella bonds that were needed to control the center of pressure for hypersonics
and there's other little things there and you can read those through at your convenience
for those just basic things that you that you have to be will comment on
some of those little bit later
the integrated vehicle logically the police over the program requirements nutrient well the orbiter was
so as far that payload bay weighted handling and depending on we knew the weights
pretty well uh 150 K pounder arbiter 65 k keypad pound payload dictated requirements of
the orator injected weight
Adam up you gotta get into orbit once around at the high nations and returned
to the large sites at the order performance requirements we had to have a certain
amount of energy available from the propulsion system from hardware reusability mixed with the cost
considerations yielded a stage and a half vehicle and talking about that in just a
minute but the cost constraints and there was a great move referred to have a
return to
alongside with Germany and the history if you please and but the costing constraints and
the size of the vehicle and got pretty
going vehicle loads
were significantly reduced by the parallel bars
you got the orbiter
between the solid rocket boosters and the external tank forces in order that would be
on the on of makes a great difference and the structural loads of the administrative
solid rocket booster mismatch decreased the odds dictated an increased baited aspersions typically
an Indian vehicle that you got everything can detect pretty timing on this 1 the
answer beaches spreading mismatch of burnout we had some big baited aspersions still house a
little bit today
a sulfur and requirement
the assumptions of its own Automated dispersion at home
yeah that angle of attack on angles and beta OK so alpha beta standard standard
that definition which by the way brings me to
coming up with media we've been asked to chase a rabbit with here I would
suggest very highly that you get you a Nasser dictionary
OK and where standard terms that year bosses have come up with use because they
been used for years that that you do that and not not not fascinated all
but but 2
and that that commitment and you can get this grade book and installed that's addition
you know what Alphas Betas are C Q proscenium amount adults although standard terms are
defined flutter
buffet and those can and you really that shop you know what he's saying that
using this model to decide what the best action is in the in guess about
the environment
produces these actions which go out to the to the world but they also come
around and their users training examples as well so here's our learning piece here's planning
piece deciding what to do and then there's another little exploration piece that may modify
it so so when you're learning this this model if you just have to get
some new learning algorithm just give you it's best guess that we need to be
modified someone you don't want to just act according to your best guess because if
you're wrong you might not be able to discover high value
the word someplace else and the environment so often and people find in practice it
is really necessary to add some kind of exploration component to what they're doing some
kind of thing that will cause the system to learn about actions that might not
otherwise have taken given its best guess about the transitions and rewards
this is not the beginning of the next block now when we talk about some
of the formal and experimental work we've done on trying to
show that we can learn
in some of these environments depending on various properties the traditions we can learn efficiently
we can learn with pollen polynomial number of samples
so to do that we have to define critical close to what we think the
problem is so
we're taking at the moment the reinforcement learning problem to be as follows we're gonna
we're learning in a kind of PAC setting probably approximately correct extended to reinforcement learning
by a bunch of researchers that says this follows where the our algorithm
is given epsilon and delta
as inputs
it knows in the world that there are k actions and states and it was
the discount factor but it doesn't know the transition and reward functions
we're going to say it now begins acting in the world begins taking actions learning
about state transitions and gathering rewards and we're going to say that each time in
the environment each time step t where q value doesn't know the real q function
but according to the real q function if the action that it took in that
state is more than epsilon away from the best the value of the best action
in that state where call that a mistake
now nothing in the environment is telling the agent of you know that was a
mistake it doesn't really know that but we as the ones evaluating how the algorithm
is performing we could imagine that were the were applying that rule to it
OK so so now we're going to go out there is going to tell which
can act and we can keep track of the number of mistakes it makes
i'm going to say
that algorithm is a good algorithm it's an efficient algorithm if there's some and that
bound the number of mistakes it makes that bound holds with some probability one minus
delta and that found itself is relatively small polynomial in the number of states and
actions that how close you want to be too it is epsilon parameter how sure
you want to be this delta parameter and the sort of effective horizon time how
much does future work out as measured by one over one minus gamma
so we're going to say that an algorithm is a good algorithm if it's
the number of mistakes it makes is small in an infinite
OK you know we're letting it she little bit by by having the epsilon delta
does not always work and by work it doesn't have to be perfect to set
to be close to perfect
the only way to actually solve this problem is by balancing exploration and exploitation to
some extent an algorithm can just go around taking the action that thinks is best
because it could be that there's some other high-scoring action out there but it needs
to know more about that would be pure
exploitation exploration doesn't work either that means just kind of running around trying things all
the time and that's going to lead to lots and lots of mistakes so it
has to make mistakes explore just enough to exploit the rest of the time
right so we're going to show what talk about is that there's a number of
algorithms that actually can achieve these kinds of bounds and even do it in the
face of various kinds of generalizations
if you know something about the
the function class from which transition probability matrices are constructed
so so to give you a sense of how this works
how might make this work so so let's imagine that we've got an endangered in
this really simple chain environment sometimes called the combination lock environment the start of over
here and has two choices you can take the black actions which moving gradually along
the chain and eventually to this data has really high reward considered here that twenty
there are each step along the way it has a choice you can take this
blue dashed action which has an immediate reward
not very large numbers bigger than zero
which resets back to the beginning of this change
OK so if we know this problem we know that the one depending on the
discount factor probably the optimal thing to do is to march down the chain and
then get twenties until the end of time
but learning algorithm is it's exploring this domain might be in a situation where
you know to explore these states knows what they do but it's never tried the
black action in this last stage
well now what's this is this is the model that's been learned so far it
knows that the black
randomized strategy it if you hold the one with the five six chance you should
run households with five six chance should pass
and of course the other guy that's your fault because you
but with the once extensive back right away
the ball
if you have it too
in with then we should do is you should pass
if the other guy that's the fifty fifty chance either folder call
if three
with a fifty fifty chance
you better chance to pass
and then if the other guy would that when you pass you should
so that it turns out to be the minimax optimal strategies to a little bit
of fluff here
little bit of under here
think unnecessary should always that of course you then three the person knows something about
you know the too much about himself
you're trying to you know
and then when you don't know that they know that they can
OK so
right so that anyway turns out to be minimax optimal strategy
has both bluffing and everything
and for being the minimax optimal strategy
is that
everyone of the guy that's coming to this falls going to lose but otherwise if
you pass coming to you with the two thirds chance to pass and what chance
but was again some bluffing
if you have two
let's see if the other guy that's coming to you
two thirds chance you fall
one third chance you call
two you might when you might not two-thirds twenty four one you call if the
other guy did that
coming to you just pass
it is
clearly you don't want to that is not as if you have two
the other guy we have one or three
and so he would know
so yes embedded fail to even if the second player to you don't want that
because the other guys one or three reasoned with these being
and on three show
this turns out to player b
it's just that
so of
that results
also back it's better to be be minimax optimal value this game is negative one
eighteen day
so on average a is going to lose
about four cents
so for the very b
good so you can see you can analyse simple game of poker a little bit
about some recent work has been going on CMU so
thomas and andrew gilpin
i have been able to solve
the minimax optimal strategy a small version of two player texas holdem small version called
rhode island hold'em this is picture of new united states texas is affixed a down
a small state
that somehow texas holdem is gonna be on TV united states i don't know if
it's on TV and other places to where people watch people playing poker
this game is a fifty two card deck is five dollar and the
one card face down is around the building and dollars something called flop card you
around batting called turn card and they are an impending showdown with a three-card hands
as in texas holdem you have seven
o cards totalling five cards
anyway for this thing they are able to solve the minimax optimality are they use
various methods big linear programming you get to solve the max
o thing a million rows and columns it took me a week
the solve using machine about twenty five megabytes of RAM
you can use these online learning techniques to get approximate member how these things work
there going if you play on both sides these online learning things the approach minimax
optimality because the extent you're not minimax optimal we're going to get you so
because these regret bounds are going to zero and what you can do is pretty
figure out they you don't want to be player two so in two hours using
one of these things you can solve exactly that fast you can figure out that
somewhere between eight and twenty nine forty six cents for
camera shake sensor dollars
i think it's twenty seven point two eight dollars to point four six somewhere in
that range for player one so the exact values could converted take away but you
you can
uses online learning methods to you pretty fast
approximate minimax off
so these you can
you can decide they should play
what you should feed
and it's actually there's a lot of interest in this of
poker competitions and so forth fun and this is now this year this minimax optimal
it only makes sense for two player games once you get the more than two
players then things get more complicated when they were complicated already because
it's not a zero-sum there's there's
zero sum game is kind of
you might want this other players to be that player in various things
this all the
so now i talk about general sum games
so general so
zero sum games are competitions in a very natural and you're analyzing like the worst
case analysis from our that you think it's you against the world in general sum
games not you against the world as you there's the world
you can all
well they're doing anything together
right so
zero sum games are good formalism for worst-case case now of algorithms general sum games
are models for systems where there are many participants
whose behavior affect each other's interests but not necessarily adversarial it's just they have their
own interests in mind that could be some cooperative could be somewhat competitive but they
hello everybody
hello body and will come back to the next session of machine learning summer school
it's a great pleasure to introduce to you know you to
and he's going to give lectures on online learning with a small party
included his phd in computer science at the university of london
when he visited in
you said it was one problem
and post of rods but what want
since two thousand four he is professor computer science university of london and his main
research area learning theory
statistical pattern recognition in new york machine learning or extra
his recent work includes a second order of which is responsible for them
and also you you're are going to be
so he is author of
book on on the internet for each learning in games hope some
of things of this book made with the you
very much looking forward to
i mean
my best known for the nice introduction so
this series of lectures is about learning
in the
online learning is
kind of a wide area and so on
not wanting to
trying to call her
all right so i will
try to focus on aspects are
more related to the fatal
a usual machine learning problem
this means that we learn mostly focusing on
binary classification problems
larger scale
why were you complaining
and the
i think it
july and later why
now it's
while in the world because that i'd like to
you know to focus on other
but like also focus on studying properties of the eiger so
there will be a fair amount of math
in my life
if you know the better technologies like hypnotized building
i think the border
it will give you the right to be the explanation
and then of impression that some work
it is not that it is fair
so as i said that we focus on binary classification and
we've been talking about are learned
and we will study the behavior of these organs to theorem by
you know in establishing improving and so that
explain properties of the brain and
whatever it can which we tried to recover
more general principles
from the
from what we
from the specific of so we tried to
capture a larger share of the of family of of all and a from american
i don't exactly what we have a bunch of no
but it's ongoing
i want to write all all of the beginning because i have the feeling that
got away some of them again because of
now to make it possible for a board
i i read the name
close to
so we will look better classification from an abstract viewpoint
so we
i assume that instances
we shall of data points
coming code as the real vectors
in reality dimensional space of the would be the size of our number of active
in our
and all right back the with bar
if i remember my baby later i will only the bar to get the wrecking
and then we have label me
this is probably
the high school
think about
with that
the three positive lobes of an SP two wavefunction function all in the same plane
and again i didn't draw a little part of the negative weight function in this
right with now
we also here is that two
he y function the two p wave function of the carbon that hasn't
oh and sorry
o with been hybridized right
it sticking out of the point of the war
right after the two p
orbital that you're used to seeing and that happened
is perpendicular here to the plane in which the
SP two wavefunctions are sitting
so now
what we're going to do
is i'm going to take this sp two hybridized carbon
positive blows
fifty two wavefunctions are all hundred and twenty degrees away from each other
and where you would say these
i wavefunctions hat-trick and all plainer configuration
i'm going to take this as the two function
i'm just going to rotate it
so that flow theories
parallel to the floor
i'm going to do that for convenience as you can see why in the moment
that's what happened here on the next slide
the image is rotated by ninety degrees
in particular so i could put the axis here along upon uniform
right so that the time you
let's look at what this looks like
on the fly
so from the side what it would look like something like that
carbon is right here at the centre
positive law the positive part of the wave function that's what this is here
this two PY functional hearing
right it's perpendicular to this plane that you're looking down and up here it's perpendicular
to the plane that the two PY weight function
positive part of the team
weight function negative part of the wave function
and this part of the way functional is just the projection of these two big
the parts of the weight function
i was just projects this way and now that way that's what it looks like
from the side
now what i'm going to do is i'm going to bring in
as the to hybridize higher up here
i'm going to bring it and it's going to look just like there
and here it comes
what i do that
what's going to happen right here
is that i'm going to allow
that two sp two wave function from the carbon
to overlap with the two people with the
two sp two wave function from the carbon
and i'm going form life
that's going to be a sigma bond
sigma because it's going to be
cylindrically symmetric around the carbon power the bond axis
and it's a sigma bond formed by the carbon two sp two hybrid wavefunctions
and the other carbon two sp two hybrid weight function
five formed a band here
and now
what i'm going to do
it is i'm going to
bring the
c two
this is the carbon
sp two hybridized wavefunction carbon
again but i'm going to bring it in
and we're going to watch this view
right what we're going to watch from the flight
and this time what i want you to see
is what's going to happen here to the two p y wave function
so here goes going to bring it in
and then there's two SP two is going to form a bond here between the
but now what happens
is that those two PY wavefunctions
all were where
constructively or destructively interfere
you want to watch it again and right
here it comes in
we're going to make this a sigma bond but now
there's these tools are going to interfere in these two worlds are going to interfere
interference this is going to be constructive interference there
because they both a positive sign a negative sign
right and so we're going to have a function up here
and wavefunction down there
we formed another bond right here
the bond that we form here
it's going to be called the private
it's part i because it's not cylindrically symmetric around the carbon carbon and the right
the weight function or electron density is we're up here
and we a function or electron density you we're down here
but right here
along the plane there's an old in at high weight function
right so this is the part
weight function
it's the car made out of
the atomic wavefunctions i have the what the atomic wavefunctions the ones that haven't participated
in this hybridization
is made out of carbon to the wind carbon PY
so what i got here
the i got here double bond
i got to bond between the carbons i got a sigma bond and pi
that's great
now let's bring in some hydrogen
i just yet
and when i brought in those hydrogens where you can recognise this is that the
right the hydrogens
former sigma bond
between the
carbon two sp two hybrid wavefunctions
and the hydrogen one atom wavefunctions that's what forms sigma bond sigma
because it
symmetric around the carbon hydrogen bond axis
and the molecule that we have here is that we
now let's look at that again because this is really very important
here i show you just those two
sp two hybridized carbons forming the act of sigma bond
and this is just represents here the energy levels as i bring them and so
in this case here we've got
two electrons in the best featu
here and we have one electron in each one of the two PY states
so this is this represents the sigma bond here
and then we made a pi bond and what is now from the top rate
we made a pi bond we let these two
two PY wave functions overlap
sure that can be solved because this is X times d z dx just put
z on the other side itself of the minus the
and now
this site is just a function of z
separated variables
and the only thing to watch out for is at the end
the z was your business you got with the answer back in terms of x and y
OK let's a working example of this
license I haven't done any modeling yet this period let's do it
I make a little model differential equations model and others a physical situations which will
be solved by an equation and guess what the equation will turn out to be
OK so the situation is as follows where in the
Caribbean somewhere
the little
isolated island the lighthouse on it at the origin and a beam of light that
shines from the lighthouse
the beam of light can rotate the way
White House these but this particular beam is being controlled by a guy in the
lighthouse at age where everyone's and the reason is interested naming it where everyone says
there's a drug boat
here and there is no difference
which is has just been caught in the beam of light source of trouble
we were just because of the alright and feels is better escapes now that the
lighthouse keeper wants to keep the drug both the light shining on so they are
US Coast Guard really copters consumer over and I do whatever they do drug both
sides of the same but the drug-loaded Meliaceae up follow an escape strategy and the
only 1 that occurs is to write wants to go further away of course from
the lighthouse on the other hand it doesn't seem sensible to do it in a
straight line because of the will keep shining on and so fixes the boat some
angle let's say and goes off so that the angle space 45 degrees so goes
so that the angle between the being and the
maybe draw the being a little less like a 45 degree angle
so the angle between the beings
and the bell
the boats pair is always 45 degrees
those at a constant 45 degree angle
at up to the having thereby to escape
on the other hand of course light keeps the the beam always on the boat
so it's not clear it's a good strategy but this is the differential equations class
the question is what's the path of the what's the what's the boats about that
cannot obvious question is why is this
a problem differential equations at all in other words looking at this so you might
scratch your head and try to think of different ways to solve it for y
what suggests that is going to be a problem differential equations the answer is you
looking for
a pack
I'm looking the answer is going to be a curve
occurred means of functions we're looking for an unknown function in other words
and what type of information do we have about the function of the only information
we have about the function is something about its slope
that is slow
it makes a constant 45 degree angle with the lighthouse
sort makes a constant angle makes unknown angle to the known angle
where if what you is you try to find a function and what you know
something about it so that is a problem differential equations
and therefore work out the structure of the protein
that's how x-ray diffraction they actually used
now i'm going to need the fact
this a little that
i can get those three all the way up to one number actually
so not only did time
demonstrate the interference phenomenon
but they also
got out of all of the
they got value for the
for the wavelength
and that was very important
and the reason why it was so important
it's because
a few years before
nineteen twenty four
there was prediction
what the wavelength of particle thought to be
and that prediction was made by this gentleman to avoid the brightly
the brightly
in his phd thesis nowhere
he made of prediction
what the wavelength particles ought to be
what he did
is he took
the relativistic equations of motion einstein the same identical equations he knew all of einstein's
phd thesis
and he realized
that those relativistic equations of motion
applied to matter
as well as to full-time to radiation
and so he said
if you
if you have of course then
a photon
which has the wavelength
course then the momentum of that photon is p
but since those equations also apply to manner
he then said well
if you have a particle with momentum p
particle ought to have a wavelength lambda
he turned
einstein's relativistic equations of relativistic equations of motion around
he said well you know
radiation at the wavelength lambda in order momentum p this is what i find that
rightly said well then
banner with the moment somebody
better than the wavelength lambda
deployed please
and an amazing
i think that's amazing
einstein realized that we're designed something like that
i don't know
but now let's say about this prediction here
what we know
is there that in the right way experiments
that we that electrons
fifty four e
that means that the kinetic energy this one and trying be square
you can write kinetic energy
and the square
over two and
you can convince yourself of this and this is
useful to know for these kinds of problems
right piece where over two and the kinetic energy
and therefore
again it's singular matrix
as had two
i'm looking for the old place that
what about the incident nodes by well
course of all life
so when i say the vector i'm not speaking directly visible line like vectors and
you i just want to be
for line one factor but
you could use some freedom in choosing one but she was reasonable
what what's the vector in the null space of the
well natural vector to pick
and the idea that we with would like to
my one
if i don't eliminate don't there
and so the free variables to be one i would get minus one
get that i
this is like
i vector
i can
for this for this matrix
and now
i think that i wanted to be reminded of
what is the relation between the problem
and the right just above
what we have here
a sequel
zero one one zero
in my
and i have to wonder what
i'm vector
what i want
twenty nine
how however the matrix related to that
our those
was like
three more than the prime
so my question one
they are
the idea is like the first we keep now in this chapter
if i find something to the matrix one
or you know something about
the reason was the the conclusion of which i think is an unlikely because
those i mean i was going to tell us important information about me
what what we see
what these i one minus one one three o
it just three to the i
i four
three or
what the
one might want
what want to still the
but useful
if i three i matrix
it's i don't change
and i read that this is one of the people
on the same
now i am really
you see one
the idea like this
other coming out
this is the other
i have a
which is
three and so on
three a
so i was three
the idea is to
is the same for both
so that's great
high resolution and often get a huge boost your computer performance
so that was after recognition
on one talk is
mobile manipulation
so doesn't two slides on
the the robot
navigate in those spaces open source schools and offices
which building on the work of ron parr on and developed the problems representation to
allow robot to reason simultaneously about the resolution course the
as was very high resolution models on
so it turns out that in those office buildings on
examples identical was designed that way and so that the if you build a model
of what went on the only by that not quite but also you have a
model for all the schools in the building
and so
you model the name about to
simultaneously in this house because you think work reasonably well
more space is of course paramount navigate across building sites spaces
as well as some of his the reason the meta level because you need to
grasp the handle
to couple millimeters position you want
so that's the idea of robot using this to and for this
one recent stab it is is if you take that idea but now combine it
with the affiliated computer vision so use division on to recognise the handles
what you see here are yes
well handles recognised by computer vision algorithm pipeline which
well recognised the door handle
on one elevator button on up the upper right
compute the frequencies to handle
using motion planner standard robotics two and a smooth trajectory for the robot arm
to reach out across the handle with without so without bumping into anything
the first
so we do that you can get the robot to on
open even previously unseen towards the interesting on different buildings for example
we do that we obtain ninety one point two percent overall performance chanters different tools
six make
one hundred dollars for those test so that's you that's such the robot going into
the men's room
so to patterns
so the final sequences shows in what the entire sequence of say robot uninstall
inside office
seen on this one
now on the on and around yes but not this one
not done limited amount of all we have to get that later but done much
more efficient although
well do next talk about the perception just take us into a discussion of stating
that's from a single still image so
so stop of the perception
in addition people like that
you the chancellor maybe less half things were from the camera when despite realistic
international olympic committee that
you can look at it and you can tell that you know the tree on
the left was probably further from the camera than the tree human right when this
page was
the problem of estimating distances from a single still image from a single image
has traditionally been considered an impossible problem in computer vision
and in the mathematical sense an impossible problem but one that you i actually saw
pretty well
and that the about similar ability so that they can get a sense of the
space around
this sense where the articles
so because there's less of i work in computer vision on on death construction from
this is work has focused on approaches like stereo vision and few others use multiple
images and i think we're all the actors on the ship for the many indices
like these are relatively textureless and even for many outdoor scenes was hard to find
responses similar to that
i say there's also contemporary works i was done by derek tricorn others CMU
the question is
given an image like that
how do you about estimate
how far we things were
so this is what we did
flying machine learning can collect the training set
comprising pairs of monocular images like that shown
and the ground truth that that's like the one shown on the right
so that that's shown on the right to officiate the different colours indicate different distances
and so
in the case caused by
on the other way and was very far away
and the collect the structure that houses sick laser scanner
and what that does is it sends pulses of light from the sensor island environment
and measures holland takes
the pulse of light emitted from the centre
to go this environment it's something about back to censor
and because you know the speed of light
time tells the whole party pixels in the image
well can do
it is then apply supervised learning
so that the mapping from monocular images
two these ground truth to that
so on the mapping and the idea was
to construct features for this thing out of actually first went to the psychological literature
on trying to understand what are the most popular
the single image cues used by humans to space that
so that people used use like texture variations in texture gradient where for example this
image patches you know both of the same stuff is all the same rules across
but the texture is very different because at different distances
on the use people using the things that he's color
patches that are in the distance tend to be slightly hazy and intensely because of
atmospheric light gallery
sexual people because
known object size
well that excites for example on the rectangles in the image frame
the rectangles may actually look about the same size as some of you because
because the human visual system is so good at correcting for distance of these rectangles
are actually somewhat different sizes and you have you know that people are roughly five
to six feet tall
when people appear smaller as further away and i see how tall someone here's picture
given this pattern how far away they are
each representation
to capture this texture and other features on the basically i think it's a good
if you've not seen this person
how can you predict his or her preferences
you can't write so even if you have made a rank one matrix and you
don't see a row or column then recovery is obviously not possible so we can
assume and you know it just strong modelling assumption we can assume that at least
for the purpose of this talk is well let's assume that the entries that are
revealed to you have been selected at random not because i believe in probability stick
sampling but because i'm interested in discussing what happens in most cases perhaps not in
all cases but in most cases
OK so we have a random subset of entries of of low rank matrix and
i say well
i don't know it's still a tough problem and the reason it's tough problem is
because well here's an example of the low rank matrix
it's very low rank matrix a matrix of rank one
and if i show you
well i don't know in netflix shows you point four percent of the entries something
ridiculous like this show even year ten percent of the entries
ninety percent of the time you can actually means this one and so you can
see only zero and you going to tell me that the matrix is
it has low rank you've only seen zeros
zero and then you would make a big mistake
now of course this matrix is very special for example in the case of the
netflix matrix i certainly do not believe that it looks like this because it would
look like if and only if nobody likes anything except that there's a guy that
likes movies
not the way it looks
or in the sense and application you would say
also sensors at exactly the same location
and one is far away
which is not reality
so this matrix is very peculiar
here's another example of the matrix which
obviously cannot be recovered from a small set of entries for the same reason is
i can refer to show you ten percent of the entries in the matrix has
rank two obviously show you ten percent of the entries are mess with very high
probability you're gonna miss one of these four entries and then what you do
you can recover them it's impossible
to me separate article purportedly called
the most basic example of low rank matrix then you cannot recover something like this
when i got here is i've got a data matrix where the rows which is
the vector x it's a rank one matrix obviously and everything else is zero
and then you samples is matrix at random i show you even half of the
and then of course going miss half of the entries upstairs and how can you
know what they are
he will not
so what i we learning through these things we learning that
somehow to be able to complete the matrix
like i think is a good example to complete the matrix if i have rules
that are orthogonal to all the rules that if i have singular rose
that are orthogonal to everybody else
there is no way on earth that can set in motion the principle of collaboratory
if somebody's rating
movies at random
such that this person's ratings are orthogonal to everybody else
how can i learn these ratings from other people like
this person they now
OK so another way to say what i just said is that he somehow they're
singular rows and columns that is what it meant in terms of the SVD is
is that even some singular vectors or if you like to speak like a statistician
is some principal components
happen to be very sparse
like in this case because look we see a singular vector the one it's extremely
sparse then they like to create a single rule
a single row then matrix completion is obviously impossible
here we have in the previous example we have very sparse singular vectors supported by
the first two basis vectors and matrices recovery is impossible so somehow the principal component
of these data matrix are sparse you're in big trouble
and i believe from my conversation ways
i forgot home that there are some
well in the netflix case there are some movies that are very hard to predict
exactly for this reason for example a good example is not fully on dynamite like
nobody knows whether they like or not these movies and the writing seems to be
a bit random
OK alright so what we're gonna do mathematically is we can try to quantify the
degree with which the singular vectors are sparse
and we're going to do this geometrically and that's almost my
my most technical slide here
which is that we cannot qualify as a
the degree of correlation between the basis vectors and the column and the row space
of your matrix so we can introduce a very simple definition we have a low
rank matrix which we think of it as the i singular value decomposition and can
introduce the coherence
and the coherence is simply what i'm going to do is i'm going to look
at these spaces factory i project them onto the column space of the matrix u
and i'm going to look at the norm of this vector is now is the
cost space is orthogonal to e either
of course the norm is zero is the columns space contains EIC norm is one
so what i'm going to do is i'm going to look at the maximum of
these projection and i'm going to introduce a parameter mu which quantifies
the degree with which the column space is aligned with the basis vector
by being essentially is the maximum norm of this projection
renormalized by
the dimension on which on the space you projecting onto on the rain divided by
simeon dimension
and so i'm going to skip the condition below look at focus at the top
condition the condition said that is mu is small then it seems like the kind
of the column space and the row space of a matrix are not well aligned
with the coordinate axes
if mu is large then the column space in the row space are well aligned
with the coordinate axis and if it's larger new institution that looks like this is
a situation where mu is maximum because as you can see the columns space contains
e one
so it's actually contains
this species
OK so another way to
think about this is to say
well we want a small music is we don't want to singular
sparse singular vectors OK and so on from now on we can think about singular
vectors are being not too sparse and mu essentially quantifies the sparsity of the singular
OK so the first result we've got in this field is something that has an
information theoretic in nature
and he said that essentially there's a fundamental role played by coherence and this rule
is that the number is the number of samples you get to see from this
use data matrix is smaller than this parameter mu
which essentially quantifies the correlation between the basis vectors and column and row spaces times
so here we have an n by n matrix times the number of degrees of
freedom because we've seen that the number of degrees of freedom is essentially dimension times
the rank times to log factor
the number of samples that is smaller than this quantity then no method whatsoever will
that's that's you know way know it's like a lower bound on what you can
do so in a really exemplifies the fundamental role played by coherence it so that
and then we form the by spectrum
is the definition of the
so common is this is what like
in particular the projected image of two
looks like on the dataset
so the bayes spectrum
just going to be these set of cubic polynomials and spherical harmonic coefficients
one thing that
i kind of
shoved under the carpet and the process is
what started as a bunch of matrices there
became vectors over here
so if you look carefully at this
what happens is that
OK so there's
if you know something about the
two spherical harmonics and you know that they are indexed by two numbers and which
is like the major index and them which is a minor index
the annals turn out to correspond to the irreducible representations so they're reducible representations of
the symmetric group returned to come in the sequence of the index by just integers
and canal corresponds to exactly that number like which representation in the sequence healing
and corresponds to the ruined so what happened to the column index what happened is
that in these matrices because
because we are now in the sphere and often the rotation group only one of
the columns of each matrix is actually going to be active
so the reason that the spherical harmonic expansion only has two indices and all three
is that each of the fourier matrices on the sphere
is going to have only one nonzero columns
so this is just the specialization of the general theory into this case
each matrix is really just the fact that makes things much simpler
the number of
invariance you end up with an excuse with the three two power
of your original data
and the amount of time that you need to compute the sums is not that
bad either it goes with the five over to power
so again from an algorithmic point of view what happens is that you start out
with say by and then by an image
that's and squared like the size of the data originates in square
this is what i call you
the new project on the sphere and then you to use the parameter like how
many fourier coefficients on the sphere do i wish to maintain this is something that
that you have to choose is a compromise between complexity
and computation time but if you want something reasonable it should be something that goes
through linearly with n
so i assume that you take something on the order of two n three and
or something like that
and that will lead to an algorithm which has complexity of finding two
and the size of your invariant representation was three over to power of the original
data so this is something that's
of course it takes time but it's doable in the case of the missing digits
that they actually try this out
started out with thirty but those images
i actually used by graph representation so i think i only went up to fifteen
free coefficients
doing that like on my desk machines or to about the tenth of a second
to process each image to do the whole fourier expansion by spectrum business
that the difference
invariant data wasn't too large and didn't cause any problems were and the results
well compared to
compared to not taking the invariants account
they were really spectacular
so with so
in this case of the perturbed data if you take only a few in number
training examples and obviously what you can do is
without knowing about invariances very limited
i started with the training set where i had about fifty examples from each class
there were ten classes corresponding to the ten digits
and then i tried to
distinguish between the pairwise so distinguish between two thousand seven times
but you know only had fifty two thousand fifty seven minutes and they were all
over the place and route is and what not so the baseline algorithm that i
tried really didn't do very well
on most of these problems this is on the left axis the air
so you expect to have more than fifty percent are binary classification task but many
of the cases many combinations of digits were actually right up there saying that basically
the classic like couldn't handle the sort of data
whereas if you do take the invariants account if you use these by special features
and then you get area always home most of the time to under fifteen percent
in many cases you can just now the problem completely so for example that the
first thing to remember is zero versus ones that sort of thing you can learn
perfectly just by using these by spectral features so this is quite nice because it
it literally over to this as straight out of the box i didn't begin the
parameters anything just push pushes straight into an SVM
on these binary classification tasks and at the beginning i had all sorts of doubts
about the various find things which are invariant but also you want to learn about
the sensitivity to noise and how they scale and respect to each other it seems
like this sort of thing at least in the
two dimensional pattern recognition cases robust
i should also say that there are natural extensions so one of the things i'm
the station
it costs one
three and this is what we do not know long vision such
you can
thank you
it is this one
i wish
seems to
this is
so these issues
creation with be
which actually use
this is
when is
at the same time
so the
this is the creation of the world
in the
phenomenal that is from the labelled data
and that
in real time
the system of the two most recent
this means that we need to be able to afford here
up date
in this setting
we have
and bond training set
dynamic models
but these models but evolve over time
so this is
the sequence
that's going a little bit
in two
data streams non
and the first
i think i would like to
give illustrative
what we have to go
that we that
the traditional approach
we have about the wells
that is
every time there is a new day survive
so i do when you want to
make wheaties to these data warehouse
we haven't we
the full twelve
and what then and
exactly that
the problem is
in most cases
this data allows can be
very low
there by
of the
running a single week
over the time they went out
can take days
we then an exact science
but it takes so long to of then against the
not used
so what is the
data streams approach
you have the document also and
they first data that is
women dying
of the data
whenever fresh data arrives
the summit is that of
when we have worked with
we can we
the sum
an approximate
yes it is not the
is an approximate
much faster
for example the addition of
they come out
it's iterative process
i had not really
of search results
we find we
need to go
of search results we find we and so on
is the prose
it's much more appropriate
most of the band's would not be
an exact answer
an approximate
and so we
it is that we know that we can
the defined
confidence interval for the
approximate answers
and it's much faster
the reason that the situation
the knowledge base
for example
TCP IP traffic
data is transient
it's never story
in relation in the database
this type of approach
it's most is appropriate for this kind of
so what is the difference
the traditional approach
and streaming approach
first of all
only one of four
instead of move people pass
the data training data about single we
we process
its observations one
processing time is history we have because the continuous flow of data we need to
an example
before the people of
next example
in traditional
that is i mean
the memory
is fixed
the of course assumes that everything can fit in memory
the type of result in that case security
the approximate
well the another point is
in streaming set
they is most of time distribution
it's not for
it's a simple one
what that approximate
boston it does this this for
the last thirty years
five thousand minutes one
probability like that one
this is what we call
x y del approximation
approximation factor
which corresponds to
measuring everything in implicit feature space which is low dimensional
and that gives you the opportunity to take training data and projected into the low
dimensional space and then have lower computational overhead both in terms of memory footprint and
time to search
so that's the that's the basic plan so
as a young mention this morning and been touched on in many of the talks
so far in the workshop you can i think of our goal as learning the
metric so in the second i'm going to sort of introduced the class of quadratic
metrics but for the moment imagine that we're going to measure things by a gaussian
type of metric mahalanobis distance you can i think of the goal is learning that
metric or as learning the square root of that metric
which is a transformation or projection or features
so there's a very strong link obviously between learning metrics and learning features and you
can make the link very explicit by saying whatever metric you weren't
i'm going to call that a feature
and i'm just going to measure distance using euclidean distance after that feature transformation
so you can ask the question for any features that you extract what would happen
if we just went into the feature space and then used the euclidean spherical distance
or you can say for any metric what's the implicit feature space such that measuring
things with this metric is equivalent that there's always an answer to the second
let's start off with the simplest possible thing you might think of doing
OK let's take k nearest neighbour
classification is your goal here
and that at what the right distance metric for k nearest neighbour classification and of
course the answer is the one that optimizes test error
OK that's not very useful
but let's try to approximate the
metric which optimizes the test error as the one which optimizes training error
defined using leave one out cross validation
so for each point in the dataset we pretend we don't know his label we
apply k nearest neighbour we vote the neighbours and we see that the majority vote
of those neighbours agree with the label or not leave one out cross validation
so if i gave you a finite set of distance metrics metric one metric to
metric three and as two which you prefer
my philosophy here is that you should measure the cross validation performance metric one cross
validation performance metric to the cross validation performance metrics three which everyone is lower that's
one you prefer
which one has a lower estimate by cross validation is going to be the preferred
metric and that will work for discrete set but what if i gave you a
continuous parameter continuously parameterized family of metrics
can you find the one which maximizes this
performance and what we can do that k
are we going to say k
here is the problem the problem is that cross validation performance is very hard to
why because leave one out error literally one out is it completely discontinuous function of
the distance metric imagine you neighborhood graph
so each node each training point is connected to its k nearest neighbors OK and
now i just the way that i measure distance of little bit so i changed
the distance metric slightly
maybe the neighborhood graph doesn't change at all
so then if the neighborhood graph doesn't change what will leave one out performance will
stay the same so now imagine graphing the leave one out performance as a function
of some parameter this distance metric is constant and making small changes constant and then
what's going to happen of course so make a small change in you know instead
of david being neighbour me
someone else becomes my neighbour and the distance met the leave one out performance going
to jump up a finite amount
so this function leave one out cross validation performance as a function of the distance
metric is basically flat and that it has these discontinuous jumps so that's
a very unpleasant function to to try and out
so we need some kind of smooth function or release the continuous cost function to
so this is the basic trick
most of you have probably seen this trick by now a lot of us have
been recycling this trick over and over again but it's a good trick so it's
worth recycling is the idea instead
thinking of a fixed number of k nearest neighbour
and then voting those we're going to consider randomise neighbour selection
so imagine that the way you're going to do classification is each point would randomly
pick one of the other points is his neighbour
with the probability that depended on the distance
so if the point is closer to have higher probability of picking it it's very
far we have very low probability and then we can ask what's the expected performance
of of this randomized nearest neighbour strategy
if we
averaged over random choices
so here's is the set of there's this quantity PIJ which is the probability that
point i select point j
as his neighbour
and that's just the exponential of the distance
maybe you would have preferred it if i put a square here
if you would prefer that then just add the square for all the days for
the rest of the talk
and normalized so this distribution sums to one for every i as a function of
j sums to one and there's no probability of picking yourself because that would be
cheating would-be be leave one out it would be leaving nothing out
so what's the fraction of the time that this point i will be correctly classified
under this randomized rule
well it's just the probability
of the point j
in the same class as i
because if i randomly choose point that has the same class as me i'm going
to get it right
and if i randomly choose the point that has a different clustering together so i
just add up the mass in the distribution p i j
summing over all of my friends j who are in the same class
that total probability is the chance the average
fraction of the time that randomized neighbour rule would have got a point i correct
under this we wanna
so you probably see we're going with this this is now the expected leave one
out classification performance i'm just going to average or sum over all the training points
OK so what i do i just converted leave one out which is the simplest
thing you could imagine into a sort of differentiable version of leave one out by
introducing this sort of stochastic neighbour selection
and now i'm going to take the derivative of the differentiable leave one out
that's it
so this is the objective function that we're going to try and optimize and it's
much smoother of course with respect to the distances than the actual leave one out
notice that there is no explicit parameter k
so talk more about this but in this randomise rule you don't have to pick
you just ask the expected fraction of the time that you would get the right
cluster OK is implicitly buried in the scale of these distances
and we're going to effectively learn that scale the same
c so i is the class of point i
so j in c by is all the points j in the same class as
and o
yeah sorry i didn't mean that
there is the distance for which this is exactly k nearest neighbour of course it's
soft weighting of the neighbors but just the size of the neighborhood
is controlled by the scale of
analytical processing aggregation and everything what one needs to solve this
problems which we mentioned before in this industrial sectors
if we talk about big data
so big data by itself is not such a big problem the problem are really
operations which you want to do on top of big data so if
we just do simple counting this is not to simply counting complicated accounting can be very more
complex but a simple accounting for his everybody could do with a little bit of
relative relatively trivial
piece of code
you don't need hadoop and so on
so simple counting let's is not a heavy
complex problem but let's it once we start modelling car reasoning with data
of different kinds and not just maybe structured and i are there block five but
once we have texts in signals sense
multimedia videos audio and so on then of course the edit operations and such a
date then this gets more complicated
and of course this
then requires another type of
and that's why big data is
we were doing big data already in the past four simple tasks
what's good news about big data is that
because of this huge amounts of data
modelling techniques can can get way simpler
let's say one
example from the semantic area is
a no times when we had just couple of assertions and couple of rules and so
some first order complicated first-order languages
of course then reasoning was
complicated so
since we have at
the everything store that all instances and the billions of
three percent so on suddenly
we don't need this heavy i may be needed but it's
fascinating that we can solve a lot of
hard problems just by
through look of with simple forms of a
reasoning so we don't need these heavy machinery from the past two fold almost the
same same problems seems through machine learning and data mining
so weights
machine learning on small amounts of data was very hard
estimating probabilities distributions and so on was way harder here
we we saw a lot of this problem just by
some kind of
simplified counting kind just because all the data is there
before we had to
assume that s
about the missing data about the missing non-materialized links and in the case of
so these big data
on one side it complicates life on the other side just because the size some of the problems are
are some development along methodological approaches are very simple
but we need to be able to deal with scale of
so here's one way
graph some of
you're already so this cube which i prepared a couple of years ago far planetdata but let's say
there's the
how these data
dataspaces kind of organized
this is one possible view
on one in one dimension we have data modalities
from heavy structured type of data like ontologies
structured data would be more like traditional databases
networks social networks for instance would fall here on this
texts so we are
that taking structure out now data from left to right
text multimedia and signals which is kind of reform
so this one dimensional
this is just data
so now here we have the mention of operators what we wanted to the data
operator obviously extremely important is collecting the data so
in the case of crawling for instance collecting wood crawling would fall under collect collected
preparing means transforming it somehow into from one form to another
how to represent the data so
elegy are
relational database are
something so
this is another
i before operation which we need to be able to it lists we need to
be aware what what we are using uh for each problem
reasoning can lead to visualizing would be so these are operators which we can apply
to each of these data modalities here
and then
so these are organised in a pipelined fashion
and here these are not really
organised in any particular order and these are these additional issues which we need to
be able to deal with it depends on the problem so scale obviously something
streaming which you mentioned before so
not all problems requires
response are not all problems have this
streaming multi
so but when we have it we need to be prepared to deal with this
context so much as the data itself which we observe but we need to sometimes they tend to be
then you can share representations you learning one
model one task with representations with another
table another task
so in the example here i have
the table
it has the features person
euro and events
and another one has euro words and history
in we have euro both places so if we learn in representation of your around
other words the mapping from the string corresponding to to the
to some vector
and we used up transformation with the same parameters in both tasks both joint distributions or conditional distributions
so we can get better generalization and you get a transfer of knowledge between those
this brings me
again back to
notion of disentangling of factors
these shared factors are trying to learn fore for learning representations
that's connected to a much older concept
that's been
the core of computer vision in particular
by that you find in many
areas of application and machine learning
where people are trying to design
features handcrafted features
and have so-called invariance properties so what is not
well if i'm trying to do computer vision and i wanted to detect ob jects
i would like to compute features four my classifier
that are invariant to things i don't care about light illumination
the position of the camera
and things like that
if i'm doing speech recognition
well i would like to extract features that are
insensitive to
these volume
after sound that are insensitive to the identity of the speaker
that are insensitive to the kind of microphone that is used so that's what we
mean by invariant features and people design these features by hand
remember which are we trying to replace those handcrafted features
learned features so how can we do not
and especially how can we do that's
if we're doing unsupervised learning
the thing with invariant features instead they are invariant to some specific factors that we
don't care about and they are sensitive to some specific factor we care about
i'm doing speech recognition
i don't care about speaker identity our approach out
however if i wanted to speaker recognition
i don't know who is speaking i don't care about what he said
i don't know
who he is
the same thing that's one problem i wanna throw away the thing i wanna keep
any other problem and vice versa
okay so how do we get around this
then what we wanna do is to extract features that capture both speaker identity ants and d
the phonetic content
without knowing the sicilian events that the task is maybe you are these
so i'd like to disentangle
the factors that explain the data and how can i possibly do that's it seems something that's impossible
but if we could would make the task
that come
downstream much easier
now there are some empirical observations suggesting got
these unsupervised learning procedures
learned features
some of which specialize some aspect of the task and others
two other aspects task and those that specialize to some
factors are
much less sensitive to other factors in other words
some features are
invariant to some factor another features are invariant to other factors and this is exactly
the kind of thing we want but they don't do it perfectly it seems that
it comes out as a side effect of training these autoencoders in this part quarters in particular
and i'm only true i'm only recently starting to understand why this is happening
but at the time when i did the slide i have no idea why this was happening
i'll tell you later if i have time
otherwise i'll tell you what to read
so it seems that it's almost as if it nobody tells you extra information
it seems that this is an impossible task with can we know
you know
what factors
you know different i mean what does it mean
if you don't know
anything about the problem
i think you need some extra
hints to help the system disentangle the factors
there is a family opinions that has a very long history in neonates literature
end it's the notion of coherence
both temporal coherence in spatial coherence
so i give as as an example
a something we can use as a prior again
that's would help us to
disentangle factors
the prime here
is not
different factors
at different scales
different temporal scales
different different spatial scales
for example
in the currency
there are things that change very rapidly
like the individual phonemes i'm pronouncing
there are things that don't change
whose presence in the room
thirty don't change too quickly
we can take advantage of
ends up i see a long series of papers people trying to take advantage of the
representations that's have this property
mostly people have been trying to find
presentations at captures slowly changing features that schools flow
slow features
but but more general you can think of multiple timescales in just separating out
factors that operate at different scales
thinking about this notion of priors help disentangle
come up with
this notion
but we should maybe
what all the prices are we could put in this big part
of priors
that could help to disentangle the factors of variation
well the first flyers that's there are multiple factors and that's the prior
that's behind the very notion of representation learning with
this to be representation so that's
you know i explain that this assumption that there are different factors and we can
learn about them kind of independently from each other
and so we can get this exponential statistical gain potentially compared to
things like
nearest neighbour methods and things like that and decision trees
and then there's the prior efforts is that these factors are organized at multiple levels of abstraction
and it doesn't have to be true
but if it is again we can get another big boost from a statistical point of view
there's a semi-supervised prior that i mentioned
but works well when there is a causal relationship between x and why