so we had to to get a sequence of one of the variables each
there is
independent and identically distributed according to g
then we can ask what is the marginal distribution of this sequence of random variables
when we integrate out g
so this
it turns out to so
most of the ways in which the dirichlet process is used in practice is
basically the way it interacts with the rest of the
i'm of the model is that we simply draw samples from g
so if we know what's the marginal distribution of samples drawn from g where g
is interviewed that we can know all about g that mean
so that we can only
the second thing is that
since g is this infinite sum of point masses then there is positive probability that
is a positive probability that sets of drawers so
sets of
the draws from g
can take on exactly the same value
so the probability that theta one is going take on value test one is going
to be pi one
and the probability that theta two is going to take on value of theta start
to is also going to be the test that one is going to be pi
one as well so that's a positive probability that theta one and theta two can
take on the same value
one the question we could ask is
if we put sets of that take on the same value
together into a cluster that how does this cluster structure look like
over as sequence
so so those i can represent patients of dirichlet processes which will get quickly before
we move on to different processes
of treaties
i can ask it this slide here
come back to this later way
the first representation where we describe the joint distribution of
the pies and the theta stars
it's called a stick breaking construction
this actually gives us a constructive
a construction for all all the data
and all the other data stars and all the pies together and goes as follows
the state has going to be drawn i i d from the
one of the parameters of or perhaps a shepherd
should introduced the parameters
in case a
she introduced to find the right
over here
i've described to the the dirichlet process in terms of this base measure in london
and what we can do is to normalize lambda so we're going to express lumber
as the product between the scalar alpha that
a oppose
and a probability measure h
so alpha is simply the total mass of lambda
and she's just lumber divided by
its total mass of
and usually people call alpha here the strength parameter or the concentration parameter
and it acts like some sort of inverse variance for the dirichlet process
while this
probability measure h is usually called the base distribution since it is the probability measure
and this turns out to be the mean of the dirichlet process
so yes so if we
look at any particular subset of all probability space e
there is pretty easy to work to see that the expectation of g of a
to g is so this is a
a random variable because g is random so we fixed a but you during the
soldier of is still random and we can look at it its expectation so that
this expectation is simply
h of a where h other is simply the mass
assigned to the subset a by the base distribution h
and we can also look at it's variance then the variance is going to be
some numerator which is
of times one message of
divided by alpha plus one so that's why we see that alpha is the inverse
variance right so the larger alpha is
the smaller the variance and vice versa
so coming back to the stick breaking construction
here's construction for g so at first we're gonna
take all the items and we're going to draw the i i d from our
base distribution h
so h is the distribution we can draw from the so we can draw infinite
from h
and then
this sequence of weights is drawn according to the following way so imagine that we're
going to start with this thing of length one
we're gonna break at some point
we're going to take this
the length of this stick
to be pi one
and then we're going to because so we're going to take
the rest of the thing now gonna break at some point
and then the length of this thing is going to be pi two
and then we're going to take the rest here
get some point and we're going to get poetry pay-for-play five and so on and
because we started off with the stick with the state of length one the total
length of all the spice pi one plus pi two plays poetry and so on
the sum to one
and the locations of the breakpoints here simply drawn from from from beta distribution so
beta one alpha
so this gives us a construction for both
pi and theta
and from past data we can construct a our
our drawn from a dirichlet process g
this is also sometimes known as the GM distribution so the distribution pi sometimes also
called GM distribution we can write it as
prior to the GM of sometimes people use pi
drawn from the stick alpha
there's also another notation that people in machine learning have used
this is actually the initials of
three of the tree
i guess they probably
i think richard's hanging mcclosky
this is a
this is a very direct construction of dirichlet processes and in fact
peter was talking about how
that's kind of difficulties with using
i come across the consistency theorem to construct this random probability measure we can construct
a random function that
i can look like a probability measures but we can
proof that the probability measure
but what's the theorem and it in his nineteen ninety four pp is that started
off with this construction
and proof that this construction satisfies all the problems
all the properties of the dirichlet process
and it's obviously a any draw from is going to be a probability measure is
actually a proper random probability measure
and this proves that
i dirichlet processes
does exist
OK so
the other
a way of looking at a dirichlet processes is using is what is called the
polya urn scheme so in this case
we look at the sequence of draws from
i i d draws from g
so each state has to be drawn from this distribution g
thank you very much for inviting me here
so there was works of yesterday on robust high dimensional statistics and we had a
last minute swarm
so for those of you that were there this this talk parts of this talk
we're presented there so my apologies and plan so i'm going to tell you
a story about similar to the last not just in the in the sense that
we have some corruption and we want to think about how to remove it but
it's in it's it's in a much simpler problem principal component analysis
so there's going to be two problems at all little
be able to talk about today if only briefly the first one is is looking
at the most basic one of the most basic statistical
that that you can use it's been very widely applied in a wide variety of
fields principal component analysis except i'm going to be interested in the case where we
have outliers a lot of our lives not just a few but a constant fraction
five percent one percent twenty percent in these outliers are give you a precise model
later for for the set up here but there are completely arbitrary so i struggled
with my
co-authors here on what word to use because we say outliers it means different things
to different people so we're not assuming that these have high variance or low variance
they're from a different distribution we're going to assume that these outliers are generated in
a completely arbitrary manner possibly even by a malicious adversary possibly by an adversary that
seen the other points and knows the algorithm that we're going to use so so
quite powerful not limited anyway
and then of course the number of outliers
so then i'm going to look at PCA again but look at a different application
show how short of this problem in fact is
kin is going to be the driver behind solving the collaborative filtering problem where you
have manipulators of the easiest way to describe collaborative filtering is is referenced by now
famous netflix problem so netflix has movies end users and the very interested in giving
to users based on very partial observation of movies if seen in rated about what
is they think the netflix thinks that you're going to like and so the question
of course is recommender systems are everywhere amazon uses this
relies on this
i'm interested in this in in this setting where you have a lot of
people that are trying to manipulate the system
so people that are given bogus ratings because they want to be able to give
one one restaurant better recommendation another they want amazon to say
if you look at this point you're going to like this other book or netflix
queues so these are the two problems that i'm going to look at it turns
out that there other quite related
and there's there's an underlying theme that ties these together and that's the regime that
that is particularly interesting
and the regime is challenging
is that the high dimensional data so this is this is featured prominently in all
all of that so many posters
that talked about this but let me just briefly go go over to what is
what is the high dimensional regime as opposed to what i call the classical regime
so the high dimensional regime is the setting where the dimensionality
is approximately equal to the number of observations so if you think about the basic
results you know about in statistics and probability even even the most simple things like
law of large numbers
you fix the dimension and you the number of points go to infinity
so that's not all what i'm what i'm interested in hearing interested in the case
where you have
maybe ten thousand points and maybe there fifty thousand dimensions
or maybe five hundred points and maybe there in five hundred dimensions so that that's
is the that's the regime
can we can obtain scaling results in this regime is well except that you just
scale those two numbers together
so there's many reasons why you why you care about why you might care about
this primarily application driven many examples from from biology and bioinformatics falls exactly into this
picture indeed any situation where you can look in
we're all you can do is is looking more in higher resolution at that something
you immediately fall into the high dimensional data so
for example
think about a patient with a rare disease now
OK so there's thousands of patients have some rare that some rare cancer it's
at one point we had very we had very limited amount of data we could
collect from patients like this but now you can sequence their DNA you can you
can look at proteins you can look at protein structure so while the number of
patients we hope is not increasing or not increasing faster than the population
the description of one of these data points
is now in the
many thousands millions or or or maybe or maybe more so this is why the
high dimensional data is is really prevalent in many different applications one particular application that
he was
the school
so that
in one to one
so i
so that
so what
this is a
one to
the moment
i must be
first one
so this
so what
he so that
that's what this
one is
it's hard to see
in the world
this was
that is
and so this is an instance of and that got me
that's what i
that is for all so
the story
the problem of
we've gone
the cells that line
so it
that's one show
for that
so what
suppose that the question is do you want to take an assistant implement ontology in
order to enhance it and implement it again so if the answer is not so
you don't need to do
engineering of this is the ontology and because of that you don't like the engineering
activity on the on the table so these kind of questions and this kind of
table can be used to select which one idea activities that you need for developing
after that based on the life cycle more than that you've already selected and based
on the application of the activities that you have
to make in the
in the previous table you can
great the ontology life cycle for your
four your ontology and it is important to mention that we can have the ontology
life cycle for the same of so here you can see that
from the requirements specification we go to the sign implementation maintenance or in that case
from the requirements definition we
do we have a use system resources we do some kind of modelling implementation and
maintenance or here we do we use reengineering the same model implementation
i mean these depends of the
d activities that
you have already selected him prove in the previous state
so now i
we know the activities we know about the life cycles more that we know how
about how to select the ontologies for our application and the next step is where
can i find ontologies with the goal of reusing them
so and that case we talk about the ontology metadata vocabulary about and also about
so for the
ontology the ontology metadata vocabulary is on an ontology
that allows us to describe to provide metadata for
the ontology is that we
i have already been so there
we can find information about the name of the ontology the number of classes in
in know
ontology the number of properties in which are linked to the ontologies implemented who is
the author so this is the information that appear in the ontology metadata vocabulary and
we have several ontology registries where we can find information about these ontologies like tony
that or
or what
so how we can search ontologies in that case you using honest so in that
case you will you will get an application in which you you can introduce here
the by the
the the the the the
the some parameters for instance i am looking for
an ontology everything in in RDFS for instance or retaining now
in the domain of travelling and so on and so forth
filling in these so you can get into trouble in domain for instance all these
ontologies which are
for in that case if you select one of the structure ontology is what you
get is some kind of RDF called with the
information about these these ontologies with a to the ontology so clicking there because you
can just download the
the ontology of the other systems and especially watson
which is the new
and your application built for searching on the web you can even though we import
some pieces of the ontologies if use the neon toolkit in by
so now
you have already
you have the ontologies you know about the process and
what thing going two percent now is an example of how we have built ontologies
and deployment mediators marketplace
OK case in order to provide us feedback of how to use or this is
stuff before
four billion application so in that case what we have is a person
these persons that introduced her CV
the city is for one two and it's one of employment services which she which
are in different countries so
these in that case they should be these in the information on the different the
so that the basis
the different companies use it is is is localized in the it is written in
different mediums this in the different kind in in the different primate centres do some
kind of
mapping between the city of the job first the different employment service provides so if
you so much i mean if there is eligible for for for the person then
an aggregated offer is sent to the to the first so in that case we
are working on with one
context and at the same time different companies have different databases and different schemas for
storing the information so they be in the domain of this application is really simple
i need to more than usual for CV so
class of people
so there are two ways of building these these this ontology first one
is trying to build a center using a centralized approach we can be to just
one centralized ontology one reference ontologies and to provide different types of mappings between the
ontologies and the different is key mass of the different employment services
the other
approaches to use the federated network of
he transitions are particular action
in a particular state right
it is many times
then you're estimates of the probability of the next is going to converge to the
and these estimates converge
very closely
then he dynamic programme
run on
these two mdps will be
almost the same
in terms of the value of the next next summer rewards in return
and this is the explore exploit lemma
explore exploit lemma says that
the value of the programming
none mdps of knowledge
but two times
divide programming and in piece about on average is greater than
the best you can do in the real world
OK so
these are the two fundamental and one of them says
the internal data structure of the down to to converge to the truth
cannot converge well enough that we can
estimate things
then they explore exploit them
this is something about
our beliefs
how well we can
o o
the sooner this is
the probability
you can actually reach an unknown state
because of the way we define things
and this is
what are maximum effect summary words is
none of h
in the real world
this sum is created and
the best the optimal policy can do
in the real world
OK so the way we use these dilemmas
if we say
we choose in
it's that the simulation and by pretty hard
so in particular
one over poly
it is very small
and then
for exploit lemma
so is implied the difference between
how well we can do in the real world
and how well we can do
in region
all right so this was the the
the by the if this difference is large
however we can do in the real world
and how well we can do
the notion of a ge MDP forever
because of the simulation and this
is also the same
as p none of age right
so the in how we can do in the real world
and how well they can do in the known of HMT
it's good enough on
as you imply
the probability
it's going to be greater than
some reasonable quantity
so the two possibilities
e there
the inequality goes this way
in which case were done because acting
according to innovate and if you want to be near optimal
or the inequality goes this way
in which case the probability of exploration has to be recently large
and of course it's probably a good exploration is reasonably large
well because
we can only
successfully explore
something like this many times
so the the the
this is a good exploration is we can have some state where there's some action
we have executed less than n times
we can some state
so there are times that we can and cannot state whether action is executed lesson
in times is something like
the second be elaborated in various ways
it's simply this object would have to be positive
mister here
the interstate actually
not actually stated that have a function alpha k
plus b if it is positive
then it's inside it is negative outside
well it's easiest to see from here the
there's bound because back in
if i saw
the hyperplane in in feature space on the data
these points actually lying back in in the input may actually on the page
this is guys on inside and but i do have a function which i don't
see it stated but it's basically when the function is positive or zero then OK
where it
negative and outside
so dense in the state of the art
right so other things
this is going to push it down with alex smola and now lives in order
see who
because god so passive learning
personnel in the learning machine receives examples so not sure those other things you can
do for active learning
why learning and indeed also on the show that the
svm framework as well set up for active learning so passive learning the learning machine
receives examples learns these and attempts to generalize to new instances active learning the learning
machine poses queries or questions to the oracle
so as to maximize returns she actually useful examples of this surely
now there are several types of active learning
the algorithm selects unlabeled examples for the human expert to label result we have this
family of handwritten characters
and what you would wish
what do you have these two hundred sixty thousand handwritten characters and some of so
let's go around and label always what i'm saying is the learning machine could have
all these unlabeled instances and ask OK
what is this handwritten character
presents a new one
what is this handwritten characters well so this is called membership queries algorithm selects unlabeled
examples there a second type of
query which is creating queries
this can be meaningless so context so for handwritten characters
i can obviously do the thing i've got a whole lot of handwritten characters and
the mountain can pick this one and say what what does one
and what is this it's a what's it has to be but if i offended
handwritten character can easily invent every character just makes no sense OK
so depending on the context so these makes sense it's not it's membership queries which
and the talk about now
i'm going skip some of this
and just get the essential points
support vector machines
they were set up in this context show you why
one thing i noted earlier on
is these points here than on support vectors
never appear in the decision function and support vectors are
in fact i therefore don't really need to know the labels of the don't support
vectors the
sort of an important for me because they were ultimately into the decision function so
what i could do
it is actually try and run a heuristic work on labelled data
and i was simply trying to ask the labels if i can of what going
to be the support vectors OK
so for the SVM scenarios will set up for
membership query
in fact we may as well therefore what is the best point to query the
unlabeled instances and mike algorithm can pick these what it turned out was the slides
called consi ways but basically
if let t plus the labeled instances where vast labelled square
the negative
so i've already asked the labels of these these red blobs are data points but
i don't know what the label is and i met office label OK it turns
out to prove the theorem that in fact this goes back a bit to what
in actually did in nineteen nineties and the contacts but it turns out that data
points which is closest to the current hyperplane is the best point query in fact
so makes sense because it's probably going to be maximally ambiguous
these guys here probably going to be negative and these are going to be positive
whereas this ones which and the marginal band and particularly those one to close to
the current hyperplane probably maximum ambiguous i do make the game from last president query
if the query faster label this one it was going to be negative supposedly negative
then this is going to have to waste my time
is going to be positive one something off is going to happen because it's going
to be hyperplane around a lot so it doesn't look too good
well what i imagine what happened here
is it possible is going to be a positive
my heart i might move that y can be negative news that way but relatively
little effects and
it's so consistent with what's been going on for
just show you an instance of the learning
let me just to come up with the damn rule which is the majority rule
which i created a string of zeroes and ones if i one zero then the
targets one more zeros and ones that the target is zero
OK now that is the rule
and i have to make most of learning
one is i check my SVM
just these samples and it passively learned examples i give it does this then this
is the curve it follows the k
and as even more samples
then the test error drops until eventually gets to zero
alternatively my learning machine could pick a string of his choosing
all string perhaps in the back of a lot of these strings they can ask
what's the answer
two the strings
generalized clause
which has exactly one formula on the positive side nothing on the negative side were
just asserting out
now at every step
we've got to set
generally have several
such clauses which may have left side right side positive and negative
and we're going to apply
one of the set of rules to simplify
and the rules are very straightforward
OK there come in
are there sort of like quite a lot of them because every connective can appear
on the positive side or on the negative side
but wherever
there is a formula with some
connected and it is going to have a main connective and there will be some
rule to simplify it
for example
if we have at any point
if we have at any point and negated formulas are not be
on the positive side
we've got general clause here
and this copy
with the not be in it
OK well let's let's just be a little bit more
formal about this
he is some people prime
together with
use a comma
not be
the negative
stuff maybe anything
we can transform that
without changing the
without changing the meaning
intuitively obviously we can transform back
in two well we're just leave
other stuff on the positive side
and will be
on the negative side
OK we'll just have to be is one more
negative sky and we got rid of the connective
OK here there was
and negative formula on the positive side here the inside that is on the negative
and it's the same thing the other way as well
OK if we had not be over here
we could fly
and for the be over here
and i
and we can do the same thing with other connectives also
if we have
here you that there's some stuff i mean it's this is
when i write the prime
not be
i mean the prime union
OK and this
this is one of the one of the general clauses the maybe bunch up OK
you leave everything else same
you can do the same
four other connectives for example for
suppose you have b and c
on the positive side
so this is
and the negative
then we what we're doing is we're sort of
we're asserting the positive stuff
and denying the negative stuff well asserted conjunction is the same as asserting the condoms
what happens to this
is it turns into well
we're setting the condoms but the whole thing is a sort of distraction and you
know it so this is going to turn into two disjunctions
one would be
one with
all right we're asserting this
disjunction and we're setting this distance
it's so
so there the and is it is here as it were
the connective disappeared here
and similar things happen on the
well do you think happens on the negative side
if we have
this IP
and some in private together with
b and c
we can transform that keep
and we just
but in the two
OK so
the thing
willing MCMC i want to simulate essentially i want to obtain samples
distributed according to the target distribution pi OK
essentially what i'm going to do it does the MCMC philosophy
i'm essentially
building the markov chain which is such that asymptotically
in the number of iterations by markov change i have some paul approximate is distributed
according to pi to do this i need to basically build markov process which admits
basically markov kernel which any bias involved distribution on a generic way to do this
i told you was metropolis hastings were essentially
you propose come the day basically according to proposal distribution that is potentially dependent on
the current state of the markov chain on then you accept or reject it could
this probability i five OK which is given by the ratio target time to raise
your proposal
it's a very very generic categories on we've seen that basically these guys
is a
it generates whatever being too
markov can we do i think the distribution so
does that as required i only know to know the target up to a normalizing
constant because it only appears basically we
in the algorithm
in the race still gamma of the current candidates gamma proposal divided by the cold
value so this is i don't need to know what exactly only have to what
constant that's quite
on you can be
x four major OK
as long as you can see from this guy
that's OK
basically you can basically are evaluated
simulate unevaluated then it's fine so you can crazy thing actually in the metropolis hastings
algorithm says basically on the current state
basically of
chromosome maps x
then say you could do something like one
say look cool optimisation algorithms like gradient type algorithms to find the real cool
maximum of the
called the target distribution
on then propose the candidate some further on this local maxima
that's valid you can do that
as long as deterministic algorithm to the local optimisation technique uses deterministic that's fine you
can all districts
you could do actually think even more complicated actually
yeah like value
the most his x
you could run actually is stochastic algorithm OK
that's kind of stochastic optimization algorithm that finds
look cool map maximum of the target
use ontologies footballer on that
it's a bit more complicated argument that you can show this is valid actually so
you can be proposing the very complicated way
you would initialize yo
you're basically you're optimisation
positive at according you sample that it
you can do that
so this is this is valid
so i was saying you use that to build
the the proposal on then you would or on this this this a local you
need to get the company in in this case
but you can use the stochastic so i resented it is still valid the argument
is a little bit more complex is called a quantum proposal mental processing that's from
quite a few use in the literature refer you to pay for these eichengreen peter
the spigot to mortar
so it is much more freedom that summer essentially with the gibbs sampler
because where in the gibbs sampling
essentially all only sample the candidate compared scale according to its conditional distribution given the
remaining components OK
so you need also to be able to sample from the conditional distribution we've discovered
processing algorithm you don't need that
OK this year we don't need that
OK let's good so let's consider
instead of continuing very content like complicated stuff for for us to start let's try
to kind consider a very simple
simple case so the first thing could be say well i would like to be
the proposal
which is independent proposals so it's a bit
very similar to rejection sampling essentially forget the concept of markov chain triple but the
county according to density qx is called independent proposals
in this case i was seductively employability
well this is the ratio of the target summary the proposal get simplified obviously because
the public independent of point anywhere on obviously this is the rate of the normalized
target on you can write it as the ratio of normalized proposal why did i
write in this way is just to make you should show you that essentially in
this case the image will be thing acceptance probability essentially you have completed that are
very very similar to what appears in rejection sampling
so it is very similar so compared to rejection sampling i don't this requirement that
i need
two have that gamma of the q
these upper bounded
over the wall space it that is actually
bush and i said with an aneurysm
whatever being she is going to have essentially
the white in the distribution while at the same point independent proposal you support
of pies including the support of q but that this condition on the tails okay
so that seems to be quite good
so one
delete looks so much like image processing and the rejection sampling algorithm you know you
might want to assess whether what's going to be the performance of the cycle reason
for different proposals OK so let's going to target
x OK are going to be some proposal which are essentially two case once we
basically independent proposal which have thicker tails
OK so it's we just want tell cannot tales in which case essentially private URI
is basically unbounded OK in which case you could apply
the rejection sampling but human you will be able to apply basically the middle possessing
of case where essentially she was fricatives OK in which case both metropolis hastings on
basically rejection sampling could be used so here is what happens when basically
you're trying to sample from simple univariate basically gaussian distribution
on you use a proposal distribution
Dirichlet distribution if we reorder them stochastically according to this process which is called size
biased permutation then we get a stick breaking construction okay and this process basically
goes as follows so what we're gonna first decide which cluster is gonna be our
first cluster and we're gonna pick cluster K to be the first cluster with probability
phi K okay so that will be our first cluster and we remove that cluster from
our list of clusters normalize our mixing proportions and repeat this so that we pick a
second cluster and the third cluster and so forth and we see that of course
this is this will give us a stochastic ordering where the phis are not
but they are on average decreasing okay and then after you've done this reordering we can now
take K to go to infinity and that gives us a stick breaking construction so
the nice thing with the stick breaking construction as a representation of the Dirichlet process
is that is actually very easy to work with and it's very easy to generalize
so I won't be go ing into details but I'll come back to to the
mixture models now and look at the different representations particularly the Chinese restaurant process
and the stick breaking construction and the reason for that is that the reason
I can't people always talk about the different representations of the Dirichlet processes is because it
turns out that the different representations tend to lead to different algorithms with for doing
inference in the Dirichlet process with different properties okay so what is a Dirichlet process mixture
model it's a defined in in the following way so as I said before G
is gonna be D P distributed and then theta I is gonna be are
gonna be IID draws from G and basically we can think of theta I as
the parameter of the cluster that data item I belongs to and so if theta I is the
parameter then data item I will be generated from a distribution parameterized by theta I okay
so this gives us our mixture model which is a DP mixture model so now
we can look at two things one one way is are the CRP and one way is the
stick breaking construction in the case of the CRP basically we say that
we know that the thetas are gonna be clustered according to the distinct values so we
can integrate our G and simply look at the partitioning of the clust of the
data items induced by the clustering of the thetas and that is described by a
Chinese restaurant process so our partitioning is gonna have a prior given by the CRP
for each cluster in our partition we'll have a prior distribution given by H and
then every data item XI is gonna be drawn from distribution parameterized by theta
star C where C is the unit cluster that data item I belongs to in the partition row
so here's a graphical model the nice thing with the CRP representation is that
it makes explicit that this is a clustering model is a model for clustering the
data items into different clusters okay and also another nice thing is that
using the CRP prior for row kind of obvious that need to limit the number of
clusters to a certain fixed number like K or something so this kind of leads us to what
are called marginal Markov chain Monte Carlo sampling is marginal in the sense that
we basically marginalize out G and we work only with the random partition that's induced on
the dataset and basically the the infinite limit of the Gibbs sampler that we
just derived earlier is the is the Gibbs sampler for is this marginal MCMC
sampler right where basically let me see yeah so the probability that data item I is gonna
belong to this cluster give in called row I is gonna be proportional to
this will be proportional to a conditional prior of over clusters that data I
can belong to and the conditional likelihood of data item XI given that it
belongs to cluster row I and this is kind of as we just derived it
as in the infinite limit of the finite mixture model case the tricky bit of this
this marginal samplers is in terms of dealing with new clusters
when we actually have to introduce new clusters and so there's this
nice paper by Radford Neal in about two thousand kind that kind of surveyed a number of marginal samplers
for this so yes sorry row is basically the way customers are assigned
to tables however this the whole seating arrangement of the of the restaurants
here's what the result looks like you have to do this on these six demonstrations we just looked at
so we have a new helicopter in picture the white one that's the one that's been recovered
trajectory that we think about any intent on the pile what he was trying to fly
flying is nose trajectory
butcher but this white trajectory you'll see is
a cleaner version of the other ones
we also see is that all the time line so a replying things here
if he timeline version of these over the trajectories
look is a little more
look cut
other demonstrations
this is double loop sequence
we have
three demonstration shown here
and this is what you get out
bring this process the white out the trajectory
so you get a much cleaner circles than any other demonstrations
the king in the purple one was likely
due to imperfect sensory measurements it's alive the helicopter actually flew acting but all those things get california's noise
and get
smoothed out in this denoising step
the black one is now a retired judge if a w
the next step to be able to control is defined dynamics model
to get standard helicopter dynamics of the might look something like this
these are
rigid body models for the helicopter so
catching everything about the aerodynamics
in two forces then
result on the helicopter
may not be familiar with the notation
but i think look at here is the capital sees
the capital sees are the free parameters in this model
everything else you gotta get from data collection
look at the capital see are factors they appear linearly in these equations
so you can run in linear regression defined those from there
and then if you didn't you collected data here you dot is the derivative of
the forward velocity vi don't do it
sideways lost in w the derivative on the vertical velocity
feature are angular rates the dollar version of the derivatives
collected data from a linear regression
and then design a controller based on the simulation model
you can have a helicopter
but if you try to do the same thing for his dynamic maneuvers doesn't work
let's look a little more careful about how could model you get from this dynamic maneuvers
here the horizontal axis
it's time
very boxes
these are the model makes in predicting acceleration of the helicopter
u have your data
based on their at the current time you predict the acceleration helicopter experience
they need do look at the data and then at the next time so that the actual acceleration was
you make a difference
is in meters per second squared
gravity is about ten meters per second squared we see here they you get up to
three cheese
of error in predicting actual relation helicopter
that's huge right that's being three times gravity in
anticipating what's going to happen makes it really hard to control helicopter
fact makes it impossible to do based on the mall five at
if you look more carefully
at all these demonstration trajectories
here's what they look like
same thing actually regime error as a function of time
and here's what they look like
after running the algorithm that extracts the
intent the pilot which this time alignment
so we see here is three j air
yes it's an area in the model
but is very consistent it's not noise it's not stochasticity
in the down the helicopter it's something and if you do the same thing over
and over and over you got over and over
get this additional three g's pushing on the helicopter
and you can anticipate this
so we should
so the key observation here the white helicopter dynamics is really complicated
it turns out
well not deterministic
it is fairly repeatable
and that's probably why how white house can learn the fly helicopter so well after a lot training
recovered the patterns the helicopter dynamics
you know how it works is not a big surprise them is just very complicated
but after a while the muscle memory has built up
the recognition of what will happen and be able to anticipate
so we wanted do is somehow
this variability
what models things like air flow
around the helicopter that's part the true state but it's not in our state space model
actuator delays
flapping of the blades
so it does say given the repeatability
we're going to still stay away from modeling flow is very expensive for similar flow
and we want to learn
laws that are specific to the trajectory we're trying to execute
and the idea here is rather than running a standard linear regression defined e vectors
the weighted linear regression so you get the data
for a particular slice of trajectory
and weighted data closest to current time most highly and there further away from the current time less
what happens then you want a model is fine tuned to we're currently in this trajectory
if you look at the model capture the entire pattern that we saw
was captured by the global model that was trying to one one set of coefficients
you will learn was very specific rejected trying to fly
and that's
this i think they do it this way you don't want the fly
just arbitrary things you learn fly
the your has been demonstrated to you
let's take a look at how well this works
experimental setup we had is one where we have cameras on the ground looking up at the helicopter
the last track position
our pilot can track orientation and position with his eyes
cameras we have visual process and we have
one zero
look this one is standing still
but this one is standing still
that's been
you see that the energy is transferred from one to the other
and that is a
the phenomenon that follows immediately from this
what would happen
if i moved the
spring up suppose i moved spring
higher halfway
anyone without
looking towards the blackboard
but you sure intuition
what would happen
with the same phenomenon happened
this been one
so what would say phenomena happening
but what is the
so it
now let's look at the blackboard
i really think
the certain
separation right you make that separation small you make the effect of the spring small
so the only good mines becomes even closer to the omega plus
so to be period will increase
take longer
i want to stop let's find that
so we're going to move this up
i put it roughly
OK ready for this
so we doing it again
and then you will see the same phenomena
accept it will take longer
for the first one to come to
so i have
decrease to cooperate
it's still swinging happily
is beginning to change its mind
now standing still
the longer
now to something mind-boggling something that you really want to see
suppose i bring this all the way to the top
that's an interesting because then omega minus
is exactly the same as only got plus
because look this term goes away
it's thomas s
cutting out the spring there's no spring anymore
will not happen if i start one year
three two one zero
one will string and the other ones
and that's shocking
it's shocking you have two pendulums
and they're not even connected anymore
you start this one straight
and the other one will never start to sway is an amazing four thirty thousand
dollars duration
something fantastic
except that the beta
it is infinitely more
the patient
so let's the for
so let's demonstrate
so there we go
six work
look at this equation
when only minus is omega plus
this story is always zero
so you see x two remain zero producing
and in omega minus is omega plus this cosine term is always plus one
hahaha that's what you see
isn't it amazing the power physics
so what is truly remarkable
that we can describe
for any initial conditions
the motion in terms of
the linear superposition
of the two normal modes
so what region they look like an impossibility
when i started
the first thirty seconds of my lecture was that demonstration
under these conditions so we
it gets left out so this is something that that you'll see
many times
all right so
w with the equilibrium constant
and it's the product of hydro near my and times hydroxide ion
it's always going to be one point zero times ten to the minus fourteen
at room temperature
we're going to
look at
definitions of ph and p o h
and come back to this KW
think of
that person here
so ph
PH equals minus log
of hydrogen ion
o h
he o h equals minus log
the hydroxide ion concentration
we just saw that w
the hydrogen ion concentration
times the hydroxide ion concentration
so now
if we take this expression
and we put logs on both sides and minus signs on both sides
we can come up with the minus log
the w
minus log
hydrogen ion concentration
ion concentration
i find that p
he o h
and that can equal
o point zero zero
room temperature
so you see there is a relationship
pkw ph np o wage this derived from this equation
from k w b equal to the hydroxide times the height
ion concentrations
these are all useful things to remember in doing the problems because if you're if
you're given appear waking ask for appear
room temperature you can use those equations to enter confer
it also turns out to be important in terms of thinking about the strength
of acids and bases
let's look at
the strength of acids and bases
in terms of phd relationship between ph
and as it some basis
so the ph of pure water
should be seven
and that's neutral seven neutral ph
and as the solution is anything less than a ph of seven
a basic solution is anything greater
and the EPA
defines corrosive
substances that yield ph is lower than three
or higher than twelve point five
represented by the DSM which is the matrix of the signal box derivative
should i really don't what the has them the hessian matrix is
thirty is symmetric
in the way the
sense of vectors x one
it is the
two value in r
the gradient of s
in the point x
is the vector that is made out of the partial derivative of x
of f
at point x
which means that
the x two
this vector has the coordinates one for each of the valuables
x one two x p
and this notation means that you consider
as for as a function of only one the first of all ball x one
you do you consider the function g
you fix x two
two eggs the
you could consider the function g that
to real number associates f x with x two and x the fixed
and that's a function of one variable that you can differentiate
and the partial derivative is the derivative of of this one dimensional function
now ninety is symmetric
if you're going to differentiate twice then you may
i want to differentiate twice
with the against the the same
the same valuable x one or you may want to differentiate and once with a
according to x one and the second time according to x two right so you
get you for which is the matrix of all these fulfilled
second order derivatives
think of that
so it's the matrix
we've done the end
they are going on the
the function that is twice differentiated into valuable
and you see take an
no rule i and column j
then you differentiate once according to x i and the second term according to x
and so this matrix
as nice
as an easy form is actually symmetric
you can verify you can actually see that you can
it's actually true that tissue differentiate from
with respect to x y and then existed then it's the same thing is that
it isn't as if you differentiate with respect to a then x i
so this matrix is a symmetric matrix
and it happens that if you have a local minimizer
then this matrix is semidefinite was
alright what happens is common for convex functions
so i figured that
so let before i go back to to convex functions here are the questions that
i haven't mentioned so far
one of you want to find the global minimizer but you want to rex restrict
the constraints x two living in
in an interview for example q
so if you have a construct of constrained optimisation problem how would you know that
whereas with very little additional wisdom
most mutations could be at least plausible
you could reduce the number of fatalities by factors of OCT aliens
by just a few heuristics
so it's so easy to improve evolution is not funny
of skip this one
but you know i was generally the trouble with evolution
is the genes operate on various levels
very few genes actually control particular details of particular structures
which means that in order to get an improvement in particular structure
you have to wait for
a series of coincidences
they give
which would never get rewarded all
unless they happen to have side effects that also promoted survival for
entirely different reasons
but the worst part of evolution is that it only remembers
what succeeded
and it doesn't keep records
so can only learn to avoid
five or ten thousand
serious mistakes
it has no way to remember
these genomes are size
we have no way to remember a million less common mistakes
however every culture teaches children very large numbers of common mistakes and that's why
so many
fairy tales are popular
o thing the stories we tell their children
are generally about things that you shouldn't do because
it will kill you
there's a psychologist named neuron
o believes that
so many cultures have the same legends that they must be
inherited or
placed in some mysterious racial unconscious
but the fact is that if you look at the legends that is
talking about
they involve
little stories about social
wonders that are liable to get you killed
every one of these popular legends
represent stories that are going to happen in any culture that has a lot of
people crowded together
we'll get inherited not as genes but as
means as
propagated beliefs in that structure
so the popularity of the on
it is very strange
because he doesn't have a plausible theory
of this very real phenomenon
the point is that evolution cannot remember a large number of
of slightly useful facts those will die out
and you'll only remember the big ones
another problem is this
when somebody builds a
computer program
that's going to manipulate some kind of data such as common sense
knowledge of a certain form
one of the first things you do is say
how am i going to represent that knowledge
should represented as sentences in natural language with syntactic parsing tree
sure i recognise it as a relational database
should i start the information as numerical coefficients in a neural network
or statistical probabilities in a hidden markov model or whatever
i used to hear students arguing about this
and the typical conversation would be
the best thing is to use logic because
logic is perfectly unambiguous and the rules of inference are perfectly clear
and it never makes any mistakes
and then somebody else
i will say yes but
you can represent most ordinary things in
predicate calculus
why not
what is predicate calculus
it's a language that has only three adjectives
sometimes always and never
you can say sort of or
this is similar to that
and nobody has ever successfully
done any kind of significant reasoning by analogy
using formal logic
so it's good for certain kinds of mathematics and other things
jolly good for certain kinds of business procedures
but there is no good for common sense thinking just too rigid
so we said why not use neural networks
and this would be my complaint
neural networks are actually more rigid than logic
because they don't have any adjectives at all
everything is represent or rather one
everything is represented as
as the number
with respect to minds
so here is where the root cars
definition comes into the picture of the fine
this guy here
this going to cause
so intuitively
what we are doing is just too
to six to see
are how similar is i on the average with respect to all other
elements in
except years
we are waiting in the sound with the red wings
OK once we have numbers then we can define
the total sum we can define the total weight of this of this set by
just some in all the contribution
now let me give you a very intuitive
interpretation of this number
it turns out that the sign of the site's importance
before defining the notion of dominance
let's try and see what happens in this two simple cases
consider this graph here
we have this three that is two three and four
they are highly similar to each other in fact the similarities is constant
what happens if i try
this here
this set to two three four
well intuitively i expect that the overall similarity this new set
sixteen one two three four will decrease because imagine something to the set which is
less similar
with respect to the intelligence
so this is reflected by the fact that
w one
with respect to one two three four is less than c
if i compare this number here and this number is less than zero what i
can conclude
this this is the basic intuition is that if i try and
one to the set
then i will decrease the internal similar to of the set
let's consider this other examples here we have six seven eight
they are highly scene they are seen which i can see higher of course because
there is another verdicts
five which is more similar
but if we just look at six seven eight
four mcclure coherent group
police at that scale
so what happens if i had this but it's here to the set i would
expect that you're similarity will increase
and this is reflected by the fact that w five
the the for the weight assigned to disguise here with respect to what is greater
than zero
OK so the size
this ways there's an interesting things about what happens when i try and that was
two groups of data
so this leads us to the main definition of dominance
we are in the symmetric case right now we are assuming
it's similar to semantic and they are nonnegative
we define
a subset of edges the the dominant set if these two conditions are satisfied we
require that
for all
in total there this world i in as
w s r is greater than zero which means that
this set as high
the internal coherence
but we know that turn on which it is not the only thing here
we need to do to care about that
we also we also need an external criteria so required for all i know along
with external to us
this number is less than zero which means that if i try to
i said i would agree
so in one sense a dominant set is the maximally coherent set of maximum in
the sense that as soon as i try to add something else
your personal
so this is our basic definition
no we formalize the notion of the cluster
so from now on our notion of a cluster coincide the dominant sets here is
a numerical example
here the set one two three is dominant and you can see
internally it's high coherence coherence and then outside
that is outside less similar to the
now let's
start from the beginning we
we started from the case where the magic of similarities with zero one
was my
and now we have introduced the notion
in that case in the binary case we we so that
the notion of the class actually is the notion of the maximal clique
now we are in the way the case and we introduce the notion of dominance
that and now the national question what is the relationship between the maximum clique and
or another way around if i have
an unweighted graph where the
edges are weighted by one zero then what is the dominant set so the answer
is that brazil one metastasis
dominant sets coincide with strictly maximum
OK actually
notice that here we have a strictly maximum clique if instead of eleven
less than zero here we have less than or equal to zero
so we relax this this condition then we would have maximal clique but as i
said before maximal cliques are a less stable in the sense that they can throw
away about x and the another one to get the next clue when we are
interested in stable solutions
so that's the reason why here
we have to stick to less than
the last thing we want
this one
OK this condition this is
now is the second condition in this is which makes this if i give you
a cluster i expect that every
subset of this cluster will be internal career
so in this sense i mean
the intuition behind this is just if
if you doubt that you wanted to gain you want to have this
this one correspondence
you will have a weaker notion which is that in one to one correspondence
OK now
now we have find the notion of the dominant set now let's put ourselves from
a computational perspective is how can i find the answer
and then we maybe we can ask of partition
a set of data into dimensions
OK in order to
find dominant set
actually we could for example we could derive agreed younger
for example finding maxima maxima with the maximal clique in a graph that i can
do a straightforward argument i just think about it just order
the vertices
and the graph by degree just just take the highest degree nodes and a
there is a oscillation itself
so that's what
that's right
so far all of
the goal is to these are the largest least squares problems
this is the forward stagewise optimisation
all these things
so can see how well
we will be
generation has to be because i was
so the problem is that you
thank you
that's that's a good thing
and this is what i propose is really a whole question that is currently just
right from the
the discrete loss function when they're not on this one because of the content be
and so
that's a question that is the only to the minimisation of structure for the expectation
of one
five years
does that mean that there is
what one of
so that we could special
and we
and how did you this
using this
for the last time
i mean this is something that
what is the probability distribution we have
as we know it it's like be the right off the bat is
it is possible
it was
in final question
see the relationship
the first annual
twenty two
it is
so let's look at the
right so that the whole of on these sorts of questions
the use of images is very
for instance there is
it is
one of the things that come from
all right
also has some
so this is also
it is easy to find
years as
the problem
also say
also is
characterizing the two tools to support
well characterised by loss which minimizes
the first thing i
the position of already
the reason to exist
we just the citation
so using the results of the research is part of
the threshold
that is different from one that will denote by s
so is the thing here is that almost all of this is that
if you click on probability distribution
right just choose
to label the first one is why
it is that they are more is different
the the problem
so class
and with this one is four
this cost function
it was easy to specify one
in response to that
it's a big role
measuring the
of course that can
he the smallest
recently she
it uses of distribution
so the station using
the conditional probability of y is one particular case
all the next
and that is
parameter five that because she
the last year the
it turns out also find
the optimal
more real to me like i was looking for
so so crucial decomposition what we do
he's right this river is the station is that this
so think
right so this expectation here we can write an expectation rates of conditional expectations of
phi one and that's
horizontal that it doesn't make a difference for the uniform data whether it's cluster
this how many clusters are recited some somewhat correct for this
and that's the idea what the gap statistic actually does
the trick is now
of course it's not so easy you can just say i divide by the number
of clusters or i've divided by the square root of the the number of clusters
it is not very clear how exactly
the influence of the number of clusters is aircraft so it's not the functional dependency
which is obvious
and what they get statistic analysis
we try to generate
essentially we do
in the previous slide
so assume that given the data set
we know the curve decreases like this now what we do is we generate another
second data set
we test which live in the same domain
but which is the data set which doesn't contain any cluster don't
and then we say OK now we look into this curve
divided by the square distance because here in this uniform case it shows us
how the number k how this curve decreases
independently of structure and then we just say can be used for normalization
and then hopefully what happened here is that this curve
still decreases if i
say two or three clusters but it increases if i want to take ten cluster
just because i divided out this effect
and that's what is what is it's called the gap statistics o
what you do is you run
with different numbers of k in the original data
and run it on this uniform data
and you take to the ratio between the two
if you want you can also take a look at it but it doesn't change
and then you say OK i minimize this quantity
the minimum gives me the number of k
and i think that's one of the method which is mostly used for selecting the
number of clusters
and there's one step which is not so trivial actually
the step of generating this uniform distribution
the data we here
to generate such a uniform distribution you could just say OK
look at the space in which my pillars
and i generate a uniform distribution center from a uniform distribution on this
on the same domain somehow
and of course
if you were not to be for example you can do that but if we
have data which is hundred dimensions it you can just it's very difficult to sample
or i mean of course you could try to sample from a hundred dimensional units
you but somehow it
it is very likely that the data you get this or the this reference distribution
you get in this case has nothing to do with the data so maybe data
submanifold in those hundred dimensional space and it actually only has three dimensions but if
the centre from this hundred dimensional unit cube
that probably won't be a good idea
so another approach which is often taking is
he just scramble your data so what you do is you have
you take
your data matrix
so you have
data point
o point one song to feature one feature two
so dave is described in such metrics
and what can i do with you
take each column in this matrix
and two randomly permuted
what happens is that
feature tool if you only look at future to the distribution of theta two is
still the same
in the data after scrambling but some of the features randomly distributed to some data
by this way so you do this for each column independently of each column to
OK so now that carries some colours and patterns and some basic definitions i'm going
to go and to into a little bit of detail and some of the tools
that we have
for graph mining
so some of the tools to look at is a matrix decomposition direct application that
principal component analysis
look at some random walks and ranking of algorithms and then co clustering and self
similarity into plots
so what one example of the matrices will want to work with as the adjacency
matrix but another common wires
documents and terms for clustering
so in this matrix here will have a set of papers and each of them
has never turned associated with people once it mentions the term data thirteen times
it and so on
so we want to be able to find patterns in groups and concepts from this
from this matrix
so in singular value decomposition we would take the document term matrix and decompose it
into three matrices the theorem is you then you can do this with any matrix
we want to be able to identify
CS concepts and medical concept because will have it's pretty obvious we update information retrieval
and then bring and lung is probably a medical concept so we want to be
able to
b b we all want to be able to tell which papers are which papers
go where
so for instance are
the the u eight u matrix is the document concept similarity matrix and we have
to be
the first paper has cs score of one point one eight
and then the sigma indicates the string to string of all the concepts that were
found with this decomposition so we see concepts
c is concept strength nine point six four
and then
this is the transpose gives the term concept similarity that is
how how strongly
certain terms
maps to concept
but the term data maps to CS concept
with the score point five a
so interpretation of this we could think of multiplying a with itself together
term similarity
term term similarity
or document to document similarity
and we may refer to this decomposition
with having you is the left singular vectors
sigma singular values and the transported as the right singular vectors of what we might
refer to
we write for these terms a little later
so what if we wanted to extend extend these
this decomposition to identify concepts over time
so to that we use the user tensor and that's the that's and in general
generalisation make me matrix so here we have three dimensional generalisation of matrix we take
what you want to take arthur's
o over time
over different conferences
and then look then now
the terms for each each
other and conference
so there's a tensor decomposition that corresponds to this
we have the author by keyword by conference tensor are here
and then
decomposing it would give us after by other groups
conference conference by conference groups and keyword by keyword groups
and then we would have a core interaction tensor
explains how the
how the
after groups the conference groups in the keyword groups
interact with each other
and this is discussed in detail in another tutorial by jamming sound and lyrical the
and it can be find this address
and that over a lot a lot of tensor methods and some of the applications
there that i'm not able to cover in this manner time
direct application of speedy is principal component analysis it's a method of dimensionality reduction
so in trivial case might have two dimensions we have we want to measure occurrences
of data compared to occurrences of the word information
so we know that these are often correlated with the weekend
projected onto the spectre he
factor here
and then we have for any point we will be able to the and map
it onto the one dimensional space
so i'm getting from SVD principal component analysis
we would take
however however k number dimensions we want to protect all the data on two
and then
take the first got the first k columns u
in the first
the first k entries sigma
and multiply together and that would be our principal component
in our going to go over some
random walks and ranking other algorithms which which may somebody's matrix methods
so the first first of all introduces climate algorithm hits
and the problem definition is that given a web graph that we have
and a query such as bicycles or singular value decomposition is some term we want
we want to look at the bottom and we want to find the most authoritative
webpages for this web query
the details can be found in quite kleinberg soda soda nineteen ninety eight
so the
the the way the algorithm works is that were given some graph
and the first step
is to find all pages containing the query terms
so we might find these three pages that have these terms in them
and then extend the next step is to expand by one move forward and one
backward and so these are going to be all the nodes that we want to
be able to rank
according to the to their authority on a certain subject
and so on the on the resulting
no that we take down will get a high score higher authority score to know
that have many important notes pointing to them
and then we'll give a high importance score happiness score
to know that point to the authorities
plus one half
and two
two prime square
two equations with two unknowns
and in principle you can solve for v one prime
and for the two prime
except that it could be time consuming
and so on exams what is normally done when you get a problem like that
number you get the problem by year and one thousand eight and two
or and one is much much larger than n two
or in one
is not much smaller than two
like banging a
basketball into a ping-pong ball or being able to basque
i will do it very
a simple example whereby i will take now for you
in one equals and two
will call that
and i will even simplified problem
by making the two zero so the second object is standing still
one dimensional collision
it's that object very special case
so to conservation of momentum now
becomes much simpler
and time be one
there is no v two
the one prime
class and
the two prime
conservation of kinetic energy
one half
ones created
the one prime squared
plus one half
two crime
notice that now i lose my and which is very convenient
i lose my one half and even
this is very easy to solve
if you square this equation
you get something look very similar to this if you square it
you could be one square
he one prime
plus the two prime squared
was two
he one prime
the prime
and compare this equation with this equation almost identical except for this term
so this term must be zero
we in order to be two prime is not zero
the kids
so it will go forward
so what that means that
one prime equals zero
and if v one prime equals zero
you see that FT two prime equals one
and this is that classic case
this one
has no speed
it's the basis of the velocity field one
they have the the same as
after the collision this one stands still and this one takes over the speed famous
newton's cradle
you see it often
we spend limbs
it is the logo
on the a to one home page and i showed you a demonstration here
when we discuss that elections
all right
let's move on
and that's something now
the works
and the momentum
and let's go
discussed at atwood machine
i atwood machine
clever device that allows you to measure
a reasonable degree of accuracy the gravitational acceleration
is supporting
forty mass and radius are
it's solid
solid disk
friction is about point p
really is or
and there's a rope here
new massless
we ignore them as
mass and two is here
mass and one this year
let's assume that two
the larger
and one
this will be accelerated in this direction
this will be accelerated this direction
this will start to rotate
the angular velocity omega
will be
of time
and now
the first thing we want to do is to make up
free body diagrams
everybody diagrams for this one
it's easy
and one g
the one up
this one
we have
two g down
are kind of cool is three other types of learning we haven't
mentioned reinforcement learning
it is more of a kind of artificial intelligence typesetting where you've got an agent
and some
world and trying to maximize rewards of some kind
and this very questions but
if your
if you're some kind of entity in some kind of world how much time she
spent exploring that world and how much time he spent exploiting the resources that you've
already found
so i think that's got some interesting things to say about
learning good behaviour patterns
transfer learning is
also very interesting i think it's the idea that different tasks might be related in
some way
you might be wanting to classification tasks
perhaps your learning
actually learning diagnose malaria from
from microscopic all images and you might have another test career trying to diagnose tuberculosis
the same types images and the
the things that you are doing both of them i have some overlap you know
there might be some underlying representation which makes it easy to solve but things and
if you've got both datasets you combine them in some way then perhaps that helps
to even better
i think also transfer learning is pretty interesting in the in the eyes sense
in is
something that people seem to do really well
you know
you may be
you may try to learn to ride a motorbike and perhaps you already know how
to ride a bicycle you had drive a car and somehow those skills can have
combined to to help you pick up the
the scale of by driving quickly you know this kind of
o thing that we can
we can
transfer the the representations that we've learned from one
from one problem and the
the kinds of
the decision making processes we used to another one that's a very interesting field
active learning
is the case where
you have
data which you actually have to pay for
and you can pay for data at different points in your input space
and you want to
get the points which give you
the most valuable
so this is like if you've got some budget for collecting data which you actually
almost always literally have where should you devote budget to collecting things
so this is for example i talked about crop disease
mapping so we've got exactly that situation
if you want to survey we've got some model
in space and time of where the
density of diseases
we want to know as much as possible about by where the disease
is this particular places were interested in
we're going to have
we want to collect data from the points that were not certain about
the deep space of input where that maximally informative about
about the
the quantity of interest
so we might look again at the error bars in our model we places that
if we've already had you know a thousand samples from
this point beside across that we might be more interested in a region where we're
not example
that's about it i've got one that's why just to wrap up with some comments
kind of some practical
it's called that
first my three practical tips visualize things whenever you can
you continue supporting tools try projecting down to low dimensions you can see
if it's a classification where the decision boundary is
you can see the relationship between the variables space three really big health
if you can incorporate background knowledge should by no
aspects of the input are more important than others think about the speech where we
took the raw data and we used to background knowledge of
different frequencies
being generated as part of the speech process you know we might already know that
kind of representation is more and more useful
any time you can reason about the
domain knowledge you have the skin has going to make it make it better
and you can do that either by
either by changing the representation of your data for example you might it by changing
the prior if using some kind of bayesian approach
good features beat fancy models if you find some clever representation of data
often the better than finding some
really complex state-of-the-art
a classifier or regression or one
here's quite interesting survey quite recent of a bunch of machine learning projects and how
much time people spend on the different stages so this can give you some
some sort of idea of what you're probably going to get involved in if you
if you decide to embark on one of these projects
and it's all about the data basically collecting the data and
dealing with missing values
getting you get someone's messy database and filtering and outliers and whatnot that something which
takes like half the size of the project
and actually
you know what we've talked about changing representation
learning the model of the data
you might think
when you first comes the
the field of this is going to be words for all about you you formulate
some model many learned from the data in your is not machine learning is well
actually it's only ten percent of what you're
actually doing if you have one of these projects in practice have found this to
be about the right
there's a whole bunch of