and actually they have going on
o technique
they have like
but the
when they right to
on election
for five
the change in the world but they
we should look like this for all possible
but the reality
and we are looking
this picture
we all try to distinguish moment and
changes the picture always
which for so if
i can tell you want this to be true
the home going with the
it's actually and
this paper
when i was in the first time
about the second part understand this
and if i could
like this
complete what
because this
well intentioned
what you see on the left
it's gone north with
the thing is i think all of these circles here but there are no actually
on line
so we're trying to
i think because it featured two additional
just to add additional part of the city
well she
and that was that
which also
four of the fact that have a lot of assumptions there is lot
the culture
environmental factors affect the way we things
if i describe the picture
how to describe
from top to bottom from the bottom
because i read from left to right
actually when they
how we are
which is derived from right to left the all the way from top to bottom
now mentioned our company based two of
you should know about your
cultural learnings about your personal experiences to retrieve images that reflect your vision
and it's not so
nobody can do that
another interesting is called
these lines
actually of equal length
but also seem
but this one is this one
i solution
but i
i have seen
there was
some information about now i want
for me
so the probability
i think does
actually a local solution the one
i removed from
this looks like the left side of the building
and this one looks like inside the building
we can
if we are able to see the anything like this one it means that have
o thing and you should see it
the small one
and if we had
usually these walls so much we and that there should be
a bit more serious
actually our visual perception is
really sophisticated
we have someone else
learn about how i more general books i actually think
can we do about our but i just don't have to be able to
we're becoming levels density
although the
so we can see what is happening in his life
we can
the same moment the time
so i that to
so can
this is always
i don't know
does the average level of intensity which we see no
another thing that is not the subject to write the first
the actual line so if you will
incremental amount of light
the perceived
although the logarithmic function
even if we actually created
all of labels which we can
one moment of time we can see a much smaller range of
and so on
we can show
just sort of like
in the beginning but after same time can distinguish
on average a book to
and so sounds like
how people understand
you are a
and he is on a function from the
so i suppose this may not be what you estimate suppose you have i tell
you had of termites decide just going to use a thousand samples
well maybe we should make it nicer number like nine hundred
so let's take three hundred samples and you can be very active and aggressive it's
lacking which
examples you'd like to get labeled from those first three hundred then the second group
of three hundred you just going to take them
randomly chosen randomly selected examples for labeling television two hypotheses one a one h tilde
and then with the final third of now you just wrote say OK well h
and h told agree on lots of areas
but they disagree in a certain region they have two
linear separators so you're just sample in that region where they disagree neutral state in
that region
who's better who's better in the area where they disagree and then you like that
one finally
so use a final three the thirty of your budget that way so you have
to decide ahead of time in the set-up how many total samples you used is
that they tend to the sick
another question
i mean
according to me depends on the algorithm in certain algorithm certainly would have
that capability if you have no noise in your your hypothesis is in your set
using something like al gore this generalized binary search and you have adequately rich set
of hypotheses you can actually serve to make some distinction among eral pull cool air
hypothesis space then
these algorithms will eventually find the correct one
but i mean the one of the problems with those algorithms is
sometimes it's not that easy in a given application to implement exactly that type of
process because maintaining this version space it could be a huge object that's you computationally
prohibitive to actually construct and maintain and so
a lot of
practical algorithms
could almost be viewed as approximations to these procedures and then
it's not so clear
whether or not though there always work so
so let me just have to go through these ideas so active learning for classification
and this is heart disease example one thing that you might do is you you
say OK i some data here's my
best linear classifier given the data i have so far
now here another
set of unlabeled examples i could ask for labels for and the typical thing that
you might see
which again is sort of like an approximation but we've been talking about those other
you might identify a point that seems to be you have the most uncertainty about
one way to measure uncertainty very simple heuristic would be well points their real close
to the decision boundary that's where i'm not so sure because i once i'm saying
it should be read and on the other side and saying it's blue so let's
try to query a point that is closest to the decision boundary that's one way
of the people
we try to
update linear classifiers and we get label for that point and that would allow us
to refine our notion of the decision boundary so the idea to to keep in
mind in this
classification cases that active learning is served narrowing down
the precise location of the best decision boundary
and this is an example
that illustrates this
which is motivated by sensor networking problem so
suppose that we had a sensor network so each of these black nodes is the
sensor network deployed over some area
and there are two environmental conditions the blue condition in the right conditions and we
don't know that but are sensors can report whether they measuring random measuring blows to
think of again is this oil spill or contaminant or something and let's suppose our
hypothesis is that the the boundary between these two is just a linear boundary to
keep things simple so we have a hundred sensors in this example that would give
us a total of about ninety nine hundred different possible linear separations of the sensors
and if you run an algorithm like this splitting algorithm is generalized binary search algorithm
these are the points
that the algorithm would select query and you can see as it goes along it
starts to begin to focus on those examples nearest to what turns out to be
the decision boundary in this case so it doesn't know
that this white line is the boundary but it starts
comment on that automatically so is doing a lot
emerged after
and this time we started on solving differential equations
this is the 3rd lecture of the
term I have yet solve single differential equation in this class of well there will
be rectified from now until the end of of the term or so once you
learn separation of variables which is the most elementary method there is the single I
think the single most important equation
is the 1 that's called first order linear equation but also because it occurs frequently
in models because it's all
I think that's a lot of the
if you drop the course that today you'll still have learned the most important methods
separation of variables and first order linear equations so what is such an equation works
quite well I'll write it in that there are several ways of writing it but
I think the most basic conditions and I'm going to use acts as the independent
variable because that's where your book does but in the applications it's often the time
that the independent variable and also try to to give you examples which show that
half of the equation looks like there's a problem of finding some function of X
times y prime plus some other function of X times Y is equal to yet
another function of X of obviously the X doesn't have the same status here that
why does the why is extremely limited how it can appear in the equations for
the x can be pretty much arbitrary like in those places so that's the equation
we're talking about and and I'll put up
this is the 1st version of it and will call them now
why is that called the linear equations the word linear is a very heavily used
word in mathematics science and engineering for the moment he
the best simple answer is because it's a linear
In variety
and why prime variables y and y primal white prime is not a variable well
you'll learn in a certain sense it helps us think of it as 1 not
right now perhaps but think of it as a linear
analogy the most closely analogous thing would be the equation of acquire a linear equation
that looked like a real linear equation the kind you studied in high school which
would look like this you have 2 variables and ideas constant coefficients and you'll see
that's linear equation and that's the sense in which this is linear it's linear and
why prime and which of the analogs of the variables Y 1 and y 2
a little bit of terminology of C is equal to 0 it's called homogeneous
the same way this equation is called homogeneous as you know from 1802 if the
right hand side is 0 sociolects I should write here but I won't that's called
homogeneous now this is of a common form the equation but it's not what's called
standard the standard form for the equation and since visibility of prime courses to primary
course of confusion which is probably completely correct but a prime source of confusion as
well as that of the standard
linear form and no underlying linear is the 1st coefficient of Y prime is taken
to be 1 so if I divide you can always convert that to a standard
form by simply dividing through by it and if I do that the equation will
look like why prime plus no it's common to not call be anymore the coefficient
because really be already and therefore it's common adopted yet and a letter for it
and the standard 1 that many people used to speak about the right hand side
we need a new letter for that to it's C overage but will call
Cuba so I talk about the standard linear form for for linear first-order equation is
absolutely that that I'm talking about now you immediately see there's a potential for confusion
here because what I call the standard form for a first-order equations so I'm not
the standard first-order forms
it was what would that be
well it would be why prime equals and everything else on the left hand side
so it would be white prime and now if I turn this into the standard
i'm afraid
graph cuts for image segmentation
so the image segmentation is
that's a very important issue in
computer vision
given an image
how do i break it up into bits have some
so really the application of graph cuts
in this area stems
boykov and jolly really but there have been people working on this somerfield tools results
later on
the question is how do you set this up
as a markov random field
when i get out of serial or show the markov random finding the
what you're trying to do with markov random field is the probability distribution but you're
trying to find the most probable
state to find most probable given that
it's turns out that's equivalent to just energy
minimisation problem as we'll see how do we how do we define
this energy minimisation so
here's an example i guess original paper
in fact
this was always in these
graph have
doing this
you have two types of energy
very similar to what i showed the hysteria as well
you have an energy which is just pixel by pixel
so OK you take you take a picture typically this is the way you do
things you take a picture
like here
the lights which dim down from the rules in one
OK well i guess you see
you take a picture typically
and often there is little bit of interaction here because you want to know what
you want to segment right so
person will come and sort of
do i
you can click on a few points or draw line
so the foreground object which in this case the bird
take some points on the background object
so far as to what i
however these are samples
the foreground and background so there you have some samples of what i consider to
be foreground i want to say without sample what i consider background
one of the wanted segments
and those give you
an empirical
and so you can then
user sort of two
two clusters
i know whatever you like the
support vector machine something i try work out given the pixel which class
fall into that gives us away
of giving the label
to every pixel OK
what you use
i said
you you you take samples what you take samples of probably not sufficient just take
the colour
that pixel might take the color neighborhood gets some texture descriptors
i things work out based on
based on the small neighborhood what pixel
each what which class each should belong to so the two classes here foreground
we want to label
before rounding the good ones
a little background
OK so that gives you the so-called
the pixel by pixel you returned cost function
which are the unitary like likelihood
first on the right in this expression
you also have
as i
shouldn't slide the beginning
as an image
each of these circles
represents the pixel
the track
and each of these i have
d stands about
this is the given this this pixel x
what is the cost of putting that in one class was the cost of putting
in class one
what the cost putting class europe
but you also have these terms
pixel up and down left and right
for each of those each of those years sign in terms of
depends on the pair
so so for instance this is the function of
x one
x two
this x one this is in the set zero and one
this is in the set
zero and one
in other words
what is the cost
the signing
this pixel in the foreground
and this piece foreground also cost finding this piece in the foreground
this pixel background
there are various things you can do here one of them is just sort of
say up front
pixels that
next to each other
belong together
that's very rough
but fairly useful
criterion so you signed cost
the cost
having zero one
some value
the cost
this is the pixel x i x j
the cost of having it
one zero
it's also value but the cost
of having them zero and zero
no cost
assigned that
one one so in other words
i assign
pixels to the same class
and can cost
i person card so that i think it is really worthwhile
assigned different classes right so this is known as
the potts model
markov random field is something which comes from the dynamics of that
o thing called the ising model which is similar to
but maybe this is the ising model in fact in this particular case
that's one type to doesn't actually look at the just sort of say OK things
which are
next to each other probably not the same class typically
you can also
have terms like the middle one so the right hand when we talk about the
middle one sort of
is are adopted driven
hello i'm from his university it's actually work with my peers otherwise professors cell
and today i'm going to talk about sailing ships studio factory in depth images
after hatching about the most fundamental problems in computer vision
it has is like give you like this for example
we want a computer to recognize objects and the categories automatically
so in this case is me and etiquette
and over the past decade they're all comedians actually work with corey's our detection especially
the current state of the art which used amazing people earning which is considered as
well the top ten greatest breakthrough in science
so just to see
how far we are from solving this problem let's do a little experiment
which are called the album only dataset
well take the sales are or fee from professor young and tested on the proper
they have proposed focus group and see how well it performs the off-the-shelf
so here is the input image
you can see inside the bounding box is clearly a char
and the if we think this image patch told off and here is the five most likely categories within predict
so you can see thousands many managed to financials and then you cable
let's try another one
this this chair is recognised support as well as well is not too bad
at least sounds make making crack that's both of them kind okay
so let's have another try
well this this attack is recognised as a special type of dog
so please tell me what is wrong here
absolutely no
most of these algorithms actually now you mention it
higher forty years ago
image now also adults otherwise is at the basis as otherwise has already told us
at this temple techniques we're not going to work for cinema analyzes for many reasons
for example
larger variations
will point difference
carter like my is room
and no cushion cos there's a little cute dog
and all the problems make already had to really really difficult
and that's we know all the deep learning godfather such as you really super genius
and professor can figure out how the brain works for many many fans
and you can now figure out how to solve this problem how appropiate is still like myself can do anything
so probably is the thing about the album because i thinking about another level you could
so maybe that's not help
absolutely no people care a lot more about playing games compared to going to the more of something has a
and that the market companies designs a lot of local citizens such as microsoft connect
and they have all citizens are you know was a lot of places in computer vision tasks
for example
the city reconstruction is the confusion
you can image inference
and popular human pose estimation which enable you to catch the for use body
so today i'm going to introduce initiatives a studio detector in depth images
so you put a lot of our system will be a single
can that's map and the output will be a set of city bombing boxes with object labels
by using that's or detector can significantly outperforms the current state of state-of-the-art algorithms based on colour image
and achieve about one percent improvement on the average precision
so now i'm going to talk about our first and then apply some analysis about the way this doesn't work
so given on category for example tower in this case where the first collect set
city can models from the internet
and therefore each of the can city can model
well rendered that's map from different viewpoints
just like this we continue this until color the typical will over object
and therefore each that's not projects to city point and compute on features and this
really point clouds and use this as the only positive examples and come out with
an active from labeled can that's my we try a linear example acid with hard
so now i'm going to talk about how we actually compute the features and is
if you still remember to case like the hough
because the image into cells and we compute the features for each cell and concatenate
to one feature vector which corresponding to the maximum weight
and this is is really
because the city space industry cells and compute the features we just is out and
can kind featured twenty vector and use them to learn the weight
and in order to capture swedish shape information with these unforeseeable features like supplying high density
surface normal
surface shape and the truncated signed distance function
and the comments whatsoever features a sort of unofficial vector
and use it to train unless lesbian
and the think we're sliding window is ready to you the score for each window
and use the example that use the training data streams
and we use the physical size of a typical territories that the size of a
sliding window so that we don't need to do the multiscale scanning like twenty case
so for each location
all the examples as we tell whether it is a town not if all them
know that is probably not here
and we continue to do this cover all the city space
and some of the example and so yes it is probably actually
and sometimes multiple detector get for the same location then we use non maxima suppression began the final detection score
here is the final detection result with the corresponding summer we used
here's another result
on the left is the current that's image and on the right is a playing how is this city models
o system all use that that's actually includes and carries only hope is registered with the data
and then you can see that in this case we use tentative unfolding tell with
which demonstrate the ability to generalize four model
here's another example is the better with the bat and the chair detected
yet another one you can see that the chair on the right
it's correctly detected but actually with the wrong orientation
we were all systems on the problem i
the following categories and twenty that's over the cable
and across different categories also detectors significantly outperforms the deviant and on various datasets and argentina haskell we'll see
and just to give you some intuition why we are better now as shown side-by-side
comparison with over said that's this shapes and the color-based if you
but in this case was about getting correct but artifact complexity bounding box
and in this case that if you fail to recognise the chair because it's too dark
however by using that's we are not we not influenced by the lighting conditions
and is it in this example that if you have a false positive with iran size of bounding box
however because we use the physical size of a chapter so this is also a
this is the integral in going from a to b
f of the or
and the only term that i have is the one
that deals with
the y direction the other terms
if nothing in it so it is the integral
in going from a to b
if f y
the y
and that
equals minus and g
as we have the
minus and g
while b
might violate sort of these miners and g
times age
what you see here
it is completely independent of the past that i have chosen
it doesn't matter how i move
the only thing that matters
is the difference in height between point a and point b
it could be
larger than zero if b is about eight could be smaller than zero
if b is below a it could be equal to zero if b has the
as a
whenever the work that is done by the force is independent of it passes only
determined by the starting point and end point that force is called a conservative force
it's a very important concept in physics i repeated whenever the work that is done
by a force
in going from one point to another
it is independent of the pass is only determined by the starting point in the
end point we call that a conservative forces gravity is a conservative force very clear
i suppose
do the work
i go from
a to b
in some very strange way
and is very clear
it to work
i would have done would be plus
and you because my force of course
it's exactly in the opposite direction
so whatever gravity is doing
positive work
i would be doing negative work
i hold in my hand when i'm doing
positive work gravity
is doing
negative work
again i'm going to concentrate now on the case where we deal with
when there's only gravity
we have the
minus and gh
is to work
done going from
a to b
miners and g
times y b
my widely
and that now is the kinetic energy
at point being
minus the kinetic energy
o point eight is it to work energy theorem
look closely here i can rearrange this and i can bring the bees on one
i can we be eight alongside
i don't get
and g
times y of b
the kinetic energy at point b
calls and g
times y a plus the kinetic energy one
and this is truly amazing results
we call
and g y
we give the name
and we call that
potential energy
often we write with that p e we write for that you
what you're seeing here is
that the sum
potential energy at point b
and the kinetic energy
at point
is the same
has the potential energy a kinetic energy at point a
one can be converted into the other and can be converted back kinetic energy can
be converted back to
potential energy and potential energy can be converted back but
the some of them which we call mechanical energy
this conserved
mechanical energy is only conserved
if the force
is a conservative force
it's extremely useful we'll use it many times which you have to be very careful
and standing around
so you have
these which decrease
can you have the number of regular support vectors which increases
in this area
so all here we have the deep you know what
a performance dip
and is the deep in terms of the number of support vectors
so she tuned c
actually what you see here is taken we set
a sequel one hundred
something this which is quite quite large
so here it is
because you have the number of features
i did i did we could also with the number of training documents
so it is recorded
now have so many viewpoints do i to six some
if you varies in both training documents
well i expect because you number is the number of features and of documents of
training documents so i expect the same but and i suspect the same sensing
then what i see when i take is pictures with it is in this case
where we have to the number of support vectors is taken here
here force equal one hundred so you have
train set of two thousand
one i the same
but in the just to show is that the deep in terms of sparsity of
the solution we move
together we set the number of documents
why i don't know
obviously the resulting together because
he has the maximum number of features
given the twenty two documents
so you have about
seven hundred different features
in twenty two documents and then it
it increases
united together smallest
the maximum number of
so the size of the bubble fourteen increase and you
so increase of few transit
f one measure
and if it gives out sparsity from user in good results
why is the gap between
my problem is the gap between regular techniques and
and SVM is not so huge
thank you here it is
thank you your one nearest neighbor
and then you have as yet made by is and can research more more labels
and then the gain is
when you just have twenty or ten percent again
is not a huge
thing to sparsity
so how you use it sees more sparse will be a new solution
that's what i see so as i will be seeing more sparse when the solution
but it's not like fifty percent less it's like a few percent less
the solution here
i'm more sparse than the ones
so obviously if you had to choose between two solution was the same performance i
which is the one which is more sparse because they in practice it will go
much faster to classify new documents
it's also nice to have more sparse solution representing the concept
so is higher see you get more sparse solutions
thank you
what is your question before because they couldn't get the
correct use
it is it's it's
the last time
so monitor the linear separability of the data
i had to try but i still because that's what i do now
and i'm not confident with it
what i see here
i was trying to explain it
at this moment
for me is the performance struck between
more sparse solution here
with high c a smaller one
solution was this one see value
it comes from there
from outlier points
which might be misclassified
and to suppose is i i d
we have a famous the classification task and twenty newsgroup which is about point that
against took point religion
so let's see you again
let's look at this picture
in this picture margin error would be appointed that some lies inside this region could
be on the wrong side of it could be just a little bit in the
margin until on the correct side so as soon as the distance to this
line here is nonzero we call it the marginal
one can actually show
quite straightforwardly using the KKT conditions
all margin errors will be support vectors all margin errors will have another five that's
non-zero in fact they would have another five it's as large as possible
so they the of five will increase until it is the football which
again this sort of
it makes intuitive sense from this kind of argument here
so back to the previous slide
margin errors
having non-zero i support vectors having non-zero five but i told you all margin errors
are support vectors
however the country is not true not all support vector to be mounted to support
that this could also lie exactly on the edge of the margin
and then they would not be marginal
and there's a lot so there is little difference between these two sets and those
are the points that lie exactly on the margin
now it turns out one can prove that
thank you
this is
but what about the case so the question is what is the intuition about the
mountain on
so in a way
let's go back to this picture
so the margin is still
this distance but the difference is not at some points by the market if you
want to the marginal so you no longer trying to separate all
points with maximum margin but you're saying i'm going to do some trade i will
try to have a large margin but i will all viewpoints don't that are alive
to fly inside this model even on the wrong side
trade is in the in in the sea has been characterized by c
which is some kind of creative constant that we don't really know how to interpret
other than saying it's the upper bound on the outside the maximum influence we will
give to one point
or in the new SVM the trade is characterized by new
in a way which
they now
here we go
so in the new SVM one can prove that the solution of the optimisation problem
satisfies the following proposition
new is an upper bound on the fraction of points
that all margin errors
and it's a lower bound on the fraction of points are support vectors
and remember the difference between these two sets
support vector modern rules where exactly the points that lie
at the edge of the margin so that exactly satisfy
the constraints
as equalities
with value of ci equal to zero
so that's the difference between these two sets and one can show that under certain
benign conditions
on the
the kernel and on the
a distribution generating the data
these two inequalities will become equality so asymptotically the fraction of points lie exactly
on the edge of the margin will be negligible
the sea
let's say i want to change
so as a as a as a run as a write-in opposition out of on
on have to respect the constraint that some of i alpha i y i
but can
so this is the only constraint and i didn't happen was talking about corners
suppose they might change just alpha one
then i know the alpha one
must be equal to sum i was two to n
alpha i
why i divided by y one
and so alpha one can actually be written exactly as a function of alpha two
alpha three and so on graph
and so if i hold alpha two alpha three of four
throughout thanks to the country alpha one because of was the the final radius these
whereas in contrast if i choose to change alpha one alpha two at the same
then on i saw the constraints i know alpha one alpha two
must must must satisfy
yes that linear constraints
but and this is where you can change alpha alpha one you also change alpha
two according to make sure to satisfy the constraint
the mix
so zeta was defined on its own to find
the back to support so on each iteration i have in some sense the parameters
alpha one alpha two and and so on
and i want to change alpha one alpha two say
so from the previous iteration on you know
let's say i have not violated constraints so that holds true and so on just
defining zeta to be equal to this because after one y one was two y
two must be equal to minus some from i was reading that some just defining
so to find this to be easy to to
so this is on
so in every iteration you choose maybe a different pair of alpha to update on
the way you do this is something i don't talk about the also it's a
couple were more about that but the basic outline of the algorithm is on on
every iteration of the algorithm you're going to select some alpha i alpha j to
update public life from the sport graceful XML file alpha j to update
by some heuristic and they use the procedure just described to
actually update alpha i alpha j
so this is what actually just about was the procedure
to optimize w respect alpha phi alpha j i didn't actually talk about the heuristic
for choosing alpha i alpha j
well the option
o and w is
this where i to be done about functions previously about this
you know this is all this is about solving the
and that
so this is about solving the optimisation problem for years and so this is the
objective function we had the best that's the about
this was which
change you
one of the one chain works
this is what are
let me the chancellor said differently so on
what we're trying to do is we're trying to optimize the objective function to be
available for
so the metric approaches that we care about is whether w alpha is getting better
at every iteration
and so what is true according to sense and for is on every iteration that
of alpha can only increase it may stay the same increase the content words are
as true that eventually the office converges some values true that intervening iterations the alpha
made one of the alphas moved further away and coast further closer to the final
value on that there will be some will be more about what really care about
is the w about is getting better every time which which which is true
six couple common words on
some of the phi wrap up on this one is that other diseases tourist she
just run has original algorithm talked about the heuristic
choosing which values for choosing which pair alpha i alpha j to obtain it was
a very complicated here it is is on is one of the things that sort
of not conceptually complicated is very complicated to explain your work so i will talk
about that here
if you want to learn about it you know can look out
john that paper
on the SMO algorithm is that the heuristic is pretty easy to read
and later on served for the world also posting a handle on the problem on
the course home page on with sort of simplified version of the service the in
the news problems
so you can see some of the courses meetings for more details
one of thing that in talk about was on how to update the parameter be
right so this solving all alphas
this also the alphas is lost get w getting it until was hard to compute
the parameter b and it turns out that again not actually not very difficult to
all that you read about yourself with the with the with the notes that will
that they will post along with the next problem
the last two to interact with to this lecture we want to do is just
tell you briefly about a couple of examples of of applications of so
last time
address piece you person addressed piece e eight by saying
and this also works for this he everything on
that's why so many periodicities in engineering are just applying piece e eight dataset on
so the person addressed by saying okay if i'm progressing from one region to another
time by regressing from your height to weight
i get different regression line
predicting your height given your weight
and if i predict your weight given your knowledge
he said that's clearly strange
should be fit data if we want the regression line to be the same
the answer
peace yet
you'll find the direction of maximum variance again
so that's how personal address that and it was later discovered that the question you
answered that question is the same thing as the of the hotelling's question by telling
was looking appreciate in the sense of factor analysis model where space and was just
answering a different question so i think very much if you should think about
people missus multiple algorithms in one because is just about to show
peace is also this distance matching algorithm
which one like classical multidimensional scaling which underpins a low dimensionality reduction work in statistics
we go
so the proof that this is a nice little lagrange multiplier based proof where you say
that's fine direction
in the data center data
rotation vector here this is the
i is constrained to be length one so it's giving us the direction of data
that gives as the largest variance so
i one is that maximize variance why times are one
now we can rewrite the variance in terms of the sample covariance and that's the
typical trait down here which is if we look at the variance
it's computed in this way the sum
all the values in the new dataset transpose
so this is
so each value in the new dataset multiplied by itself which i will always write
as a vector in the product
i can say the vector product and i conflict this guy around because its transpose
and write it in this way
the rotation times one over the
in the why transpose why perhaps which is basically the sample covariance times the rotation
on the other side so this variance that we're trying to maximize can be written
sample covariance vector
so we want to maximize the subject to the constraint
and that's the grande multiplier problem
and again we just by gradient methods so if we take the
i mean matrix-vector derivatives for me is the mainstay of machine learning so i'm assuming
you know that if you don't know that it doesn't matter but you know you
really need get on top for them to do all this linear algebra stuff
so be it
the grungy and has this form this is the ground multiply
dealing with the constraint
taking the derivative we get to sample covariance times are one minus two lambda one times are one
and we can rearrange this to in this format has the form and i can value problem
that's the first principal component the direction the largest variance
we've sort shown that actual variance is
and i can value problem with the result is the solution to like value problem
we don't know which i can value it is
but multiply both sides this by aaron transpose premultiplying it
tells us
the lambda one is equal to aaron transpose this so what so lambda one turns
out to be the variance we extract that's why withdrawing earlier
without explaining why drawn in which is always good
in these things it the variance the direction
the largest variance turned out to be the one that's all one in this notation
and the variance we extract is given by lambda one di died value there
yeah so that's what
this proof is showing
and that's the first principal component
the maximum variance is therefore necessarily the maximum igon value
so the principle
i can vector i tend to think of that's the first principal component
to the next principal component you need to impose the next direction should be orthogonal
so that you get the rotation right otherwise it's not a rotation matrix are extracting
and you apply the same thing again with this look around know one of those
magical mass things happens that you even though you've got this extra term here
if you know
premultiply this whole thing by
i transpose again
that's same trick we did find out the
variance what premultiplying at shows is the i transpose times archaic because they're different indexes is zero
um but also on my
transpose esskay archaic is also zero
and that's because
this guy is a previous i can vector we've extracted and substituting in
go through this too quickly i'm aware about substituting in this guy
shows that if you take place this is like
if people are two times this yeah
there are two times less
must be equal to because we've already said i want satisfies this must be equal
to lambda one hour to transpose all
which this constraint is forcing to be zero
so basically premultiplying by
eliminates and eliminates that's
and then just extracts
the element this which is equal to all right so gamma i times one is
equal to zero which implies that gamma i zero so
la grande multiplier constraint that just disappears if satisfied even without using it that's what it means
hands once step
things disappeared
it is rewriting the same thing yeah
you get for the k'th component is also a solution if the eigen value problem
so the principal components are just be i can vectors of the covariance matrix but
in this case we look for them by looking for directions of maximum variance which
indeed also minimizes the subjective
all looking at these distances in the latent space
so we can extract as many principal components that we like
but this is more the traditional way of looking at it rather than me
probabilistic piece you anyway i did beginning
a little bit about trigger because what i said is that we were gonna be
talking about non linear dimensionality reduction
and then i've solve the problem
by just applying a rotation
now the last time i checked is a rotation isn't a non linear
dimensionality reduction
what i've been proving here
that if you restrict yourself to rotations and scalings
then piece e eight is the minimizer of this
the problem with putting animations in your flight
this subjective here
if you restrict yourself to rotation and scaling that's a linear operation
that's the minimiser this objective
so that's actually known as classical
multidimensional scaling but there's one other odd aspect to it that i skipped over okay
so the results of applying the digits data festival
this is to
dimensions so this is the what you saw
the beginning
and then of course the current has reached the maximum value
which you can find ways on the floor
because the self inductance itself has no reason to think of the self inductance has
made of superconducting materials
no resistance
and so without knowing much about physics
you can make a lot
the current
that is going to flow as a function of time
you start out with zero
and then ultimately
if you wait long enough you reach maximum current
which is given by
law which is simply
divided by r
you slowly
approach that value
and how slowly depends on the value of the self inductance
if the self inductances very high
by climate like this is a high
value for l
the self inductances very
it is a low value for l
if the self inductance was zero
come up instantaneously
but i just convinced you
there is no such thing as zero self and there's always something finite no matter
how small
so this is qualitatively
what you would expect if you
use your stomach
and if you don't use your brains yet there's nothing wrong with using your stomach
now i want to do
this in a more civilized way
and i want to use
my brains
and when i use my brains i have to set up an equation
for the search
and if you read your book
you will find that
mister john coding
tells you to use case cells lutrol
mister john cole he doesn't understand for this law and he's not the only one
almost every college book that you read on physics
i do this wrong
they advise you to use it the rule which says that the closed loop integral
around the circuit is zero that of course is other nonsense
how can it be zero
because it is changing magnetic flux
and so it can only be minus the phi e
i advise you
go to the aid of two websites
and download
lectures supplement that
you will find in which i
address this issue
and it's very hard
so the closed loop in the role of the doctor l
if you go around the circuit
is not zero
is minus the phi beta
five days long
so is mine is l
so we have to go around the circuit and we have to apply for this
and knots
he of
literally thousands
applied here
this is the site of the battle and the minus side so electric field in
the batteries in this direction
electric field in the self inductances zero
because the self inductance has no resistance superconducting material
so the electric field in
if the current is in this direction which will be
electric field in the resistor
will be in this direction
now i am equipped
right down the closed loop integral
of the adult the l
i start here
and i always go in the direction of the current
and i advise you to do the same
i don't care that you guess
the wrong direction for the current that's fine
later minus signs will
correct that
they will tell you that you really guess the wrong direction
but always
go around to look in the direction of the current
because then the EMF
it's always minus LVI
if you go in directions of post to the current
this plus the identity
that could become confusing
so i always go in the direction of the current
and so
i first
for the self inductance
there is no electric field in the self inductance so don't only going from here
to here is zero this is where the books are wrong
it is zero
i go through the resistor so now i get plus
i r
and the other in the same direction
this law tells me is i or
in the battery
i go against the electric field so i get minus
that now equals minus l
the idea
this is
the only sane
and the only correct way
five these laws
in this
you can write it a little differently
which may give you some insight
for instance you could write
i can bring v in l
and l to one side so i can write down the
miners LVI pp
because i r
this the same equation when you look
and the nice thing about writing it this way
is that since the ITT is positive here
it's growing in time
the induced EMF which is this value
notice it's always opposing
the voltage of my battery and that's with manslaughter is all about
it's not until the ITT has become zero
that vehicles i are and that happens of course if you wait long enough
so we have to solve the differential equation
and one is often done
that to tom minka he invented EP and he can talk a lot about situations
in which but i know he's going to discuss the that that issue in great
length as well because it's in some situations yes multimodality people not work well in
use variational message passing instead to the whole suite of these possible algorithms you need
to choose the right one so leave tom to talk about that because that's really
is this lecture
no questions
all right so i the question what about still evolving through time so the other
thing that can happen so what described so far is we assume that everybody has
a fixed but unknown scale what happens of course is that you play lots of
chess your skill improves so again we can capture that by just drawing my graph
so here's a graph
which says players one and two have met and they had again and got a
game outcome and later they're going to meet and have another game meantime on this
scale may have evolved has a very simple model just as the skill is just
undergoing a sort of gas diffusion
so says the scale the next time is gas distribution centered on the scale of
the previous time
and then off go
sure well if you want to skip that distribution then by all means you go
ahead and put in a skewed distribution that's that's great
if you believe
if you believe skills should increase steadily with time
i don't know my skills are definitely
the decreased over the years
at age age should be in area
OK and
you don't want to mention that this is that this isn't just an academic study
but it's also been used on on line
four well since since two thousand five which processing these figures are quite out of
date actually so really processing millions of game outcomes but they worldwide twenty four hours
a day seven days a week so this is represents an enormous application
of bayesian methods are very large scale application of bayesian methods which i don't think
we could have contemplated doing you know ten years ago we didn't have this machinery
available to do this fast large-scale inference is one of the reasons why i think
this is a very exciting time for machine learning because as the you know the
quantity of data in the world is doubling every nine months is it or something
so we live in a world with its increasingly data rich and now we have
tools to do inference on very large data sets are exciting juncture
and actually i mentioned also mention just to prove this was sort of one-off flash-in-the-pan
there's no another application again is exactly the same kind of tools this time with
sixty advertisements in in search you're not google well actually there are many realizes there
are other search engines are not quite as popular
so the company based in seattle has one of them and just like google is
trying to model paying it with adverts so the problem is to pick pick the
right and that's you don't about these with adverts but irrelevant because that just knowing
you want to show you see on this is you can the ones which the
user actually clicks on so there is a very important inference problem to work out
which are to show
we showed that you should be shown to the user and again that you know
a real time online planet scale applications involving huge datasets and again also went
like a few months ago and now all of the
all of the advertisements served up by
by this particular company on search engine or all
chosen using this method
performance improvement over the previous method was was enormous that's been hugely beneficial
very practical sense
o thing ought to mention art schools of thought about this this wonderful framework of
graphical models and fast efficient local message passing algorithms so that you mentioned the work
of john winn this was his phd work and this was a system called five
so this is an academic study rather than a fully functional toolkit what he did
was to say well
let's really embrace this graphical framework and let's build an inference engine which start by
allowing you to draw a graph
so what you get is a sort of drawing package
and by pointing and clicking you can construct the graph and this is some
some kind of mixture of factor analyzers some bayesian mixture of factor analyzers each of
these nodes are very well these things can see these plates here this will be
are assumes this noise is zero what is not a hundred percent clear i think
what he's assuming about the noise and this proved about eighty people assuming noise machine
coming out machine learning is perfect but if you assume
your your data is linearly related to the
unobserved factors plus the mean plus some noise as we saw regression
so this multioutput regression in fact
and we've got similar noise thing again the noise is very
so this is the thing that's going on we've got some
two dimensional factor space this function mapping to what we observe this three-dimensional could be
much higher dimensional
what we can show is that we can write down a likelihood again as we
could before
and then i can write down the full likelihood of the data just by making
independence assumptions
and then using a prior over x this time instead of w
i can compute
the joint distribution
for why the marginal distribution for y and it has its gaussians with the meaning
given by mu
and this particular form of covariance this is why i said that
like factors they will a w factors and if you do the other way round
actions appear as factors in the actual
mathematical sense so ashamed he decided to call the components so it's a covariance
if the calcium the mean and the covariance this covariance has this particular fall which
is low rainfall and it captures the thing is the dimensionality reduction and basically chris
bishop and mike tipping proved
you could solve this problem
by looking at the eigen vectors of the sample covariance matrix so that i was
talking about the next two things together but
tipping and bishop is really close to the original paper apart from the addition of
the noise but you can show that things are solving this w by computing the
eigen values and i can vectors of the covariance matrix which is just what we
know as PCA
so a probabilistic interpretation has a slight advantage
of dealing with missing data so is famous artificial the pseudo real generated type dataset
called the oil data
and the three different regimes of flow in this data then you have the sense
i think there's twelve them in total which are measuring density across an oil pipeline
was it either flow flows all mixed together or in close in this layer way
or this annual away soil water and the gas and the sensors measuring density and
all you know about the senses right so you can in principle component analysis on
the original data and that's what you see these different flow regimes so this is
a different homogeneous flow regimes in one of these islam and many others and you
know which are much more similar to each other what's interesting if you've done the
probabilistic approaches where you could decide doing is throwaway data you can get rid of
use missing data
and you can do the same principal component analysis so what you actually get a
similar looking things as you throw away more data they start looking less similar
so that's the only thirty percent of the data
and that fifty percent of the data being thrown away it's probabilistic approach helps you
to do that and you can think of that
during that in the way of the EM algorithms that's one advantage of a probabilistic
interpretation of PCA which you don't have any original page
OK so that was just a slight sense the factor analysis is pretty much the
same model but with the diagonal boy
different noise for each output
so you can think of these these these methods is a viable method is very
closely related
so following the example of trying to leave time for that
questions and discussion
what i talked about is probabilistic interpretation
the learning has these are functions as negative log likelihoods
contrasting to learn
loss functions the expected losses you're trying to deal with
what then was talking about
so the bayes the controversy in the bayesian approach is treating parameters of random variables
is nothing controversial about using bayes rule
learning proceeds through this combination of prior and likelihood and then you can even do
it sequentially one day prior to posterior and the use your posterior for the prior
for the next eight point
the latent variables makes gaussians r
not bayesian but they're using bayes rule so that probabilistic methods in learning as well but that
they're not bayesian because
you're only placing prior distributions over things that everyone except to stochastic variable
these problems
as an optimisation problem
and then how could we
could we could and then
build system according to its principles
so i'm going do
is going through
a sort of the torah
and commentary on this
of how we're going about posing to these problems from a bayesian perspective
as an optimisation problem
and some of us now is in the last five years has become
more generally standards
in the computer vision
literature not not all computer vision people
actually to this day use a bayesian perspective
know people also will accept some of the assumptions were making here
for example one of the assumptions we make in this first part of our system
is that image segmentation
or shall we say in general the clustering problem
is your place that's not rocket science to say that i mean we all know
but what was saying in particular is terms like minimizing some energy function may have
no relevance to perception
i have no relevance to me my metadata to minimize some function who says that
functions way representative of what we do
we saw yesterday morning of course there is some in places where there is quite
nice intersection between some optimisation criteria like maximizing entropy
and the responses of cells that was interesting
but that's not necessarily always the case
minimizing a function of some forms that you think of
is is necessary right so we take a supervised learning approach
one of the main one actually fit how humans perform doing this task
this is what you
in other words
contrary to many people we say in segmentation is not done
without supervision
that is to ask the process
even the visual process in humans of being able to encode the same as the
single consisting of parts and relationship doesn't stop
after segmentation after feature extraction the knowledge plays the role even in the very early
in fact we neurophysiology indicates that
that's story in a way
neurophysiology the visual cortex not like number conversation
what we do is we pose the problem of image segmentation
and annotation as a single proper
and what's the single problem problem the problem is i want to be able to
two label
a pixel
as belonging to a certain class
like for example shadow ground aspen birch whatever
and that the invasion of that pixel label
better be dependent on its neighbours
how is a markov random field so that the random variable this pixel now
is there any failed but it is labels the panels neighbours
but also what determines my my my neighbors as aspen
what does my neighbour
but of course what i observed pixel level observed that pixel
red green and blue values in the next few weeks you could observe the whole
because they're getting this hyperspectral cameras
so you observe a lot of things that will so to sort things observation and
you have
a dependency between labels
and nothing goes right through all this work this two ways two components for inference
observation model
and the click
the the neighborhood dependencies
well how to you get a handle on my tractable anyway the first part how
to even get initial labeled pixels well done some pretty simple stuff which i think
is now
it depends on the application but i think of conditional
gas mixture models are
really perform reasonably well
we could well have used to support vector machine as well
the reason why like as mixture models is because they have to propel the conversation
i like having where i can understand the rules
in some sort of form some sort of explicit form
so in this work what we've done is used i class conditional gas mixture model
to get initial
to get initial labelling of all pixels for class
how do we do that we use supervised so expert photographer also yes that's an
aspen that to show that number of
and in that multi dimensional the colour space
the colour space
i have many places in the colour space
the correspond to
example as the
was many different regions
of the kind of people have different colour distribution and in many different regions of
the attribute space correspond to ground
we can assume that this one
cluster in be space and that's why i think you you were many classifiers don't
this is one
of evidence for him
that is because you have many sources of the same class
and of course what you're trying to do
is to derive a non-linear decision
that will tell you
at runtime
is this pixel belong to this class and a
so in the in the class conditional gasnet models of course use the best of
the best
you simply the nearest nearest neighbour mixture
as the the the main page
in the thing you build up your classifiers by con ditional trying
the different classes you fit mixture models we use bowman's MDL version of gas mixtures
is some criteria for deriving the number of fixtures and then for each class you
do that so because when you classify
you have you have classified simply give you the probability of class given the mixture
models the prior to this
and it's act
so it gives the way of of getting initial classification
but more important than that what it does is give us away the funding for
every pixel a probability vector
probability vector
so the input images but green blue
the output is false distance initial values is now probability that picture which is the
probability of being aspen birch ground or whatever
but i'm not going to make the hard decision about what it is now
because academics and now something else
and so on is something else
the something else is
now a richer structure
i said i mean going to something else was
my neighbourhood pixels by
and that was the traditional hough like of interface
rate of the universe and how it changes with time is determined by the energy
and pressure content of the universe so today dark energy if it exists is the
dominant energy content of the universe so in some sense it's driving the expansion of
the universe so on this important issue it's time to take sides we can't hide
from the data the data and the consistency of lambda CDM is overwhelming it's too
good to ignore and again it's not just supernovae it's all these other indicators also
and what we know is that what we know what we do know is that
H of Z is not given by the Einstein-de Sitter result so what the only thing
that we can say is that this equation does not work that G zero zero calculated
on the basis of the Robertson Walker metric is not equal to T zero zero
where the stress energy tensor is only matter so there are two things we
can do we only know an equation that doesn't work we can modify the right
hand side of Einstein's equations by adding a Delta T zero zero and we can
add something that's a constant to the right hand side that is just a cosmo
illogical constant I put just in quotes because it's a remarkable value it's a remarkable
result or you could add something that's not constant that has some dynamics and the
usual assumption is that the dynamics which has a change in time is driven by
a scalar field or you one might say you can modify the left side of the
Einstein equations and you can say that this the observations are the first indication that
gravity is something beyond Einstein's theory of gravity so you can add branes extra dimensions
strings I'll talk about models you'll understand what F of R means in a little while or
you can take the crazy approach that is just the Einstein equation and in fact
the friedmann homogeneous isotropic model is not a good description of our universe and
there's a back reaction on in in homogeneities that's adding another term to the left hand side
of the equation I'll talk about these possibilities so let's look at the right side
of Einstein's equations and ask what theoretical tools do we have to add something to
the right hand side of Einstein's equation now I think that I'd look out I see most
of you experimentalists so you might laugh when a theorist talks about tools right you
say well what does a theorist know about tools they only use a pencil a paper
and an eraser and if they're really good they don't need an eraser but in fact I
know a lot about tools the reason I know a lot about tools is in
my life I have owned two cars a British sports car and a fiat so for
twenty-five years I owned one of these cars and I had to work on the
damn things every week so I know a lot about tools and what I learned
after twenty years of using tools is that you really only need two tools there
are only two indispensable tools with two tools you can fix anything and the
two tools are are duct tape and WD forty and here's how you decide what to
use if something moves and it shouldn't you use duct tape I was very
relieved on my tour of atlas yesterday to see duct tape being used it keeps it from moving right otherwise
the detector would move around and if something doesn't move and it should you squirt it
with WD forty those two tools can fix anything now there are theoretical analogs to
duct tape and WD forty the theoretical analog to duct tape is the anthropic principle
or if you speak the language of string its called now the landscape the theoretical
analog to WD forty is scalar fields when you ever you want something to move
a little dynamics you squirt it with the scalar field in the language of dark energy the
scalar field is known as quintessence so let me talk about at the anthropic principle explanation
anthropic landscape duct tape or faith-based explanation of the cosmoillogical constant now this actually sounds much
better with a British accent but I can't do that I'm sorry the idea is
that we seen there are many sources of vacuum energy all of them tremendous
some positive and some negative perhaps why would they cancel to give something cancel
to a hundred and nineteen decimal places well the idea is that string theory has many and the
number that people will bandy about is ten to the five hundred vacua and the the
cancellations are different in all of these vacua some of these vacua correspond to cancellations
that lead lea yield a small cosmoillogical constant now to have such cancellations you might
expect that this cancellation would be exponentially uncommon but there are exponentially many vacua and the vacua
where the cancellation is almost exact or preferredbecause more common values of
a cosmological constant lea result in an inhospitable universe therefore string theory neatly explains the observations
by saying there's so many possible vacua we can't predict it so one of them must
have a value of the cosmoillogical constant of ten to the minus thirty grams per
cubic centimeter so you see like duct tape it's not an elegant solution to
the problem and it's probably not permanent so the other solution to the right hand side
is quintessence the WD forty approach that we're gonna squirt a scalar field and the idea is
that there are many possible contributions to the cosmological constant we have no theory that
this is just works
OK we can decide if
the question
it was just a
well with this is to this day
once you're OK so
this is the this thing here
is exactly that quantity
so so this thing is the kernel of the distribution but in fact is actually
also kernel between pairs as you can see
suppose is great
and obviously you would estimate this by just replacing these
by empirical averages so you just have double
ah yes we did
but actually sometimes of us can works slightly better so where is one of the
other i mean it doesn't make a huge difference but sometimes
but that's kind of work slightly better
the problem is attribute matching so that's what i told you before
so you have to companies which merge and you want to measure databases
this tool here will be just a tiny
ingredient in a big database merging two
so you have lots of other generating systems around
he one
to find the corresponding attributes between two thousand six
so what you do is you only use the distributions of random variables
just check whether those same
you want to match different sets of states of it
there is it's no good if you just taking that well they're all dates you
might want to have want to check whether they're evenly spaced and all that
you might want to match names
are but we can actually merged database at all
so the idea is well you just measure the distance between distributions of the coordinates
you find the best match
i'm going to to show you a little bit more
now with metric
different datasets and
well it works OK and many other tests are not too bad either
this is basically checking well how often
if the
if the attributes of the same does indeed say yeah that's OK and if they're
not the same how often does it say
it's still be OK to merge
it doesn't do an absolutely stellar job i mean
it still works better than the other but it's not really great
in some cases
uniform convergence this is actually not so bad
OK well
it's kind of reasonably
in this case it fails miserably
actually there
i think is above
it doesn't make any sense
the unbiased OK well
that's twenty five books and papers
there's something else that we can do so let's say i have got two
they all have ten attributes
i want to find the base pairing of the ten datasets of the one
ten ten attributes of the one that is it to the ten attributes of the
other parties
so in that case i know that i cannot assign one attribute to multiple instances
never it
well what i could do is i could just say well the cost of assigning
does it one me i to attribute j
yeah that's it just given by some CIJ
and the overall cost for matching one data set to the other will be just
the sum over
and this is another permutation
so in which permitted or the
entries will be near the opposite of the term CIJ
so in that case they want to minimize the cross this out to minimize instead
o the space of all the permutation matrices pi
so that sounds like a combinatorial optimization problem
the matching problems
but the good thing is that this is something that people have solved in the
the so-called linear assignment problem
and it turns out that you can
find the linear programming relaxation of this
and thereby solve the problem exactly
so obviously this problem here
so in all the right but for the moment
a relaxation of the upper problem
so the supply
i would just have zeros and ones
of course the only the rules some has to be one and the columns and
has to be one because i'm on a matching one term from one side to
the other
likewise only one term from the other side
so the first one
so that's basically a constraint on the first of the constraint on the second of
all distilled into spider have to be critical in zero
and if i were to impose the phi j's can only be zero one
and this will be formally called into the upper problem
OK any questions at that point at the moment so i've just done reformulation of
what would happen if i were to drop this
i'm basically relaxing my constraints
so therefore relax my constraints my solution can only get better
so let's
assume i just relax this constraint in which case it becomes a linear program
this is all linear constraints
and that's all it
and then it turns out that my solution point
has only zero one entries
what does it mean
what it means that i have found a solution
which is optimal
in the relaxed case but also in the for the constrained case
so it means that i have found a solution which is also optimal the more
tightly constrained case
and then you can start asking well is this coincidence or
can i always assume that i will find such a c one solution
and it turns out that for
this specific problem here
i will always find a solution
that will just consist of zeros and ones
like magic
well why is this so
well if you look at those constraints if you write them out it turns out
that those constraints can be viewed as a union modular constraint
and the model of constraints are particularly nice because if you take a submatrix of
the big matrix in inverted it'll turn out it will just having two interchanges
and if the inverse of a matrix is only integer
my right hand side contains only integers
then the solution of a linear system will also be only integers
and unimodular matrices do exactly that
this is one such case
this is what could among found
and they came up with the hungarian marriage there
so gay marriage theorem is basically in hungarian guys in hungarian women and they all
would like to get married in fact they will have to get married
but they don't all like each other equally well
and overall you want to find some assignment that will make everybody maximally happy
first i differentiate with respect to x o i get white squares
then i differentiate with respect to the other factory the y squared factor and i
get next time two y y prime
and then zero gives me zero so
one zero
right so there is the implicit differentiation step
and now
i just want to solve for y prime so i'm going to factor out for
y q and
o plus two x y that's the factor on why prime
and i'm going to put the white squares on the other side minus y squared
over here
and so the formula for y prime
the nice why squared divided by four like you don't want to fly
so that's the
the formula
the solution
the slope
give questions
so the question is for the why would we have to sort of put in
what we saw before an explicit
equation and the answer is absolutely yes that's exactly the point so this is not
a complete
the solution to all problems
we started with an implicit equation we differentiated and we got in the and also
an implicit equation doesn't tell us what y is a function of x we have
to go back to this formula
to get the formula for four x so for example let me give you
an example here so this is
this is the
hides a degree of complexity of the problem but it's a degree of complexity that
we must live with
here so for example
x equals one
you can see
that's why someone saw
that happens to be
so it's also one of the four x y where minus two zero that's why
i picked the two actually so it would be one plus one minus two equals
i just wanted to have a convenient solution there pull out of my head at
this point
so i did that and so we now know that when x equals one y
equals one so at
one one along the curve
the slope
is equal to one well i have to plug in here minus one squared divided
four times one cubed
two kinds one times one
that's just plugging in that formula over there which turns out to be minus one
right so i can get it on the other hand
we're stuck
this formula star
to find more
so let me let me just make two points about this which are just philosophical
point for you right now
the first is
one i promise you at the beginning of this class that we're going to be
able to differentiate any function you know
i meant it very literally what i meant is if you know the function
will be able to give a formula for the derivative you don't know how to
find the function you have a lot of trouble finding the derivative so we didn't
make any promises
but if you can't find the function you will be able to find the derivative
by some magic that will never happen and however complex the function is a root
of fourth degree polynomial is are can be pretty complicated function of the coefficients
we're stuck with this degree of complexity in the problem
but the big advantage of this method notice is that although we had to find
star we had to find its formal star
or and there are many other ways of doing these things numerically by the way
which will learn later
so there's a good method for doing it numerically
although we had to find that we never had differentiated
we had a fast way of getting the slope so we need to know what
x and y were but why primary got by an algebraic formula in terms of
the values here
so this is very fast forgetting the slope
once you know the the point
what's in parentheses are used this is well let's see if i can manage is
this this little
is this the parentheses you're talking about
this is say
well so maybe i should put commas around it was as a y
come come
well here was at
at x equals one
and here's but at say i'm just throwing out of value here
any other value actually there's one value my favorite value well this is easy to
evaluate right lexical zero i can i can do it there
that's the that maybe the only one which is
these are in use
other questions
now now we have to do something more here so i claimed to you that
that we
we can differentiate all the functions we know but really we can learn a tremendous
about about about some functions which are really hard to get at
i mean even though you've already seen this you still have to kind of figure
out each word piece by piece because you can use the larger structures of of
semantics the underlying meaning of the five this is expressing as well as the syntax
the rules about how
words go together in linear sequence to produce complex meaning
and i think this this helps to show you why we need if we're going
to you know we we want to apply statistical approaches to understanding passing and language
learning but they need to be sensitive to a lot more than current natural language
processing approaches are they need to be sensitive to the structure of syntax and they
need to be struck sensitive to meaning
sure why not
well sure that shannon said i mean a lot of what generated the early controversy
about statistics and language with chomsky was i i take it reading shannon's first paper
information theory which he showed how much you could do really cool you could do
with you know just on grounds for graphs right i mean everybody if you haven't
read shannon's classic paper on information they go back and read it he basically introduced
that idea that he didn't have the massive data that google had but i think
everybody would agree you have all the data in the world as we now have
that could work
on the this
yes i'm arguing that the basic technology of some of the information theory and finding
clusters that has been with that underlies a lot of machine learning since shannon can
solve this problem but that is not enough to solve this problem because it doesn't
capture meaning and it doesn't capture the rules by which meaning is projected into linear
sequences of words that would be syntax semantics and syntax that's not to say that
statistics information zero relevant that we need as as i think it was just need
to understand how those ideas for learning and inference operate over the kinds of representations
of meaning and syntactic structure that linguists have proposed and i think google would agree
that's why they're not really trying to solve this problem and that's why they kind
of laugh off start-up switch which claimed to threaten them like for example powerset was
hot start in the internet world for a little while say well we're going to
use actual now you know syntax for natural language processing we're going to be google
in natural language search and go to step how to the right when then i
think microsoft bought them for some what in that business is a paltry sum of
one hundred million or something y
well because google said we we just don't have the technology yet to solve that
problem so we're you know we're not even i'm going to try to do that
we're going to solve the problems we know how to do the ones that were
i would say
we don't have that we don't have the technology to solve in the we google
wants to sort which is you know very high accuracy instantaneous across the entire world
but for me while i'm excited about this coming together again in these fields is
that i do think we have these kinds of ideas and i want to try
to sketch out this is just as much it's not it is not a google
level engineering challenge it's more of basic scientific research in reverse engineering challenge
there are of course many other inductive problems in language and big focus which i
want to say much more about now but we'll definitely see this later on summer
schools acquisition so there's not just using your knowledge of language to pass sentence but
learning and knowledge of language how to learn the rules of syntax well that's that's
that's another place where there's a long long been study of how the mind goes
beyond the data that's given and
we hear a lot about that
just one last set of examples
which i'll start off with thinking from science and then moved to to children's cognitive
development the problem of representing and constructing a theory of the world so i think
about what might be the greatest moments of human learning about the greatest accomplishments of
wins when scientists or whatever you want to call them natural philosophers are just final
philosophers have have have come to fundamentally new and fundamentally more correct insights about how
the world works by in some sense looking at data observations it's so how did
darwin come to his theory of natural selection by looking at the finches on galapagos
or how did newton come his universal law of gravitation by looking at the orbits
of the planets and maybe some data about the moon and maybe a few apples
how did mendel glimpse the basics of genetics in his experiments with p parts was
based on finding clusters are correlations in masses of high dimensional data
it doesn't seem like
it was based on finding some kind of causal
model positing something about the the underlying but unseen causal structure of the world and
CNN comparing different kinds of causal theories and seeing which seems to best explain the
another way to think of it is urged to pose this challenge is to go
back to what i think that was talking about a fundamental challenge for any kind
of association all learning association of learning or statistical learning is
if you like the discovery of new concepts or new dimensions over which read the
statistics or the associations have to be computed so when we're talking about doing dimensionality
you always have a quadratic function whose only
exercise two
the weight
represents the graphs
represent could in that for
will see before you have many adverse effects
is linear terms class
these terms we have
OK i j x i
so far
right always do that by
so we have terms like excite xj
just replace x by
one minus six five our multiply
right you get in this form
i mean that
what do we do
we draw a graph
px i
is zero
this one is this is the key
the key construction
i take it take an edge
from excited xj going to put weight on what is that age me
what do you think of you think of
the head of this our main xj
the tail of the our
is excited by
because the tail you put a bar across
and i take this to
i i j
i may
put that value
on the page
what about a linear term so OK this so
all these for all the
six k
have a
i j k weight HAK
being here OK
what about the new maybe the term five
x i
if x i and x k
bring in the in the in the markov friends the neighbours in the markov random
field and there will be such
certainly there can potentially be
just between
no i mean typically is not an order left to right typically if this is
an image
you've got them into two-dimensional re-negotiate here one here
you can then they'll be edges here the edges
only between the
the neighbouring terms like that right
now officially on july
in the lot for like minded
if only
with graph cuts you
with the ordered edges
one is the special cluster here i guess
when adding spectral clustering here
well i'm sure you can could that form that
typically in the general case
you've got directed edges that's for sure
i mean from the point of view of
the flow
this very different very
big difference between edge going here
with five hundred and it's going abstraction five one means you can push things in
that direction
five using the world's first
so that the directed edges
from directed edges
what do we do with linear terms five exi
we can think of that if you like is being five
zero by
x y zero by
right so by my
that would be
five there
excise the head of the arrow zero tails
right so that be five there will be five x y
and so any
an element like that of an edge here three that will be for instance three
times one
times x y
in other words
x i
so any function like this
one that you
the edges weights correspond one-to-one with edges
weights on the graph
now the point what is the point
of this
the point is
if for instance
i now partition
and this comes up to zero
and this comes to be one
and that means
the x equals zero
equals one
so that means in fact that exi power
so this
that's one so this contribute
i i j to the way that is exactly
the edge
which is which is cut words
some of the edges chicago
these are exactly
value function
with this construction
how various it just to make partition
and just as edges which go from zero to one correspond to non-zero terms here
which have the corresponding weights
in this way
inside ref
which she gives you
the function so for instance
as well as a here
well there is no need to look at the example on the on the right
that gives you
he's your example of something
complex function
i'm going to break it by saying that well
i require that all the points here
the value of the linear function
less people than one one and here greater recall than one
so there's nothing
magic about two things one
as a matter of fact we can actually make this venerable of the optimisation problem
later as well
and then you will get
svm optimisation with a new trick which unfortunately won't be able to cover
in this talk just because of lack of time
basically i mean by the lookup or looks look for something called the new trick
when i wrote a paper on that
i think nineteen ninety eight
for two thousand and we up to the neural computation
and you'll find all sorts of ways how to adjust the way
now that we assume that well i can actually go and try to compute these
well without loss of childcare can assume that has to be at least one point
here and there which
o which the WTA but the obtained the value of one on one one
well why not because if it were not the case i could just extend the
margin until i hit one of the points of the other side
so therefore there must be at least one point to which the constraint is active
now if we do that well we it there must be some point it's one
whatever they want with these ones
o point x o which relates to put these minus one
taking the difference between the equations gives us w x one one x two
it was it
well something very nice happen he has gone away
we don't know what he really might be anyway so getting rid of it is
we therefore no
that the inner product between this connection here
and the normal vector to the hyperplane
unlike normal vector
it's the
now we almost
although now need to do is i just need to
we restrict this vector w unit link i need to replace w
but you want to by normal
take an approach that with x two one i think one
so in other words and predicting
o line here
on to the normal
that the product within tell me how
the two
trials are
if i do this
just you want everything but norm of w and find out that two of the
norm of w
is the the weight of the margin
so now
i can actually just
really take this problem and optimize away and i would get something that's not totally
so in other words
what i can do is i can require that for all the points which line
plus minus one
that that makes
but the
is less people than one one
for all the points which are in the positive class
and it well
great people than one
and i'm going to maximize two over the normal w
the question here
that is the geometry clear
what i'm projecting
onto this normal vector
this guy here that w
w is orthogonal
to the hyperplane just
as you define a hyperplane
it's normal vector
and this offset from the origin
they also be
the normal vector w
and i'm projecting this line which unfortunately i cannot really reach
in the following up onto
the small picture
this will give me constrained optimization problem and i could
just leave it at that the problem is
but this in an objective function to be maximized is particularly nasty
and we got the normal rather than the squared norm we have to do likewise
we need to maximise its that's not the knife optimisation problem
now we can actually turn it into a very nice convex optimisation problem that was
in way the genius of thinking germany is in the sixties to realize that you
could do it
and the way they did this by realising well rather than maximizing revenue over
two or w
you could minimize w with the right
the minute quantities so this is all white
OK this at least gives a convex optimisation problem
along with the kind of function
so that should be all right
well don't know
you know what the quality of it
most hands are around
not all of it quickly draw word
which is a piece of chalk
the draw
as a
so the convex function
in in are would simply be one where you take the points
take the line between them and the function values below that in general what you
will get is that
let's call the x x prime
let's assume that there is some land
and the said between zero and one
i have
lambda ix
one one lambda
it's less equal
then land
it will fix
one one lambda
at that point
now convex functions have a a whole bunch of really nice properties
by the way it's called strictly convex if this is in
if this is the strict
inequality for all and not being here and why
these functions have said the really nice properties amongst others
but if you want to minimize them
they all have a unique minimum value
provided that the domain in which i'm optimizing on its
the main is convex
it went on the main
if i can take any two points from line
like it
the next prime
and i draw a line between them
and the timeline is contained within the mine
to show that quite a constrained convex minimization problem has a unique minimum value
he will just go inside by contradiction
only with would say well let's assume that there are two local minima
x and x run by
and then you go
and look at the interpolation between the two points
that the interpolation between those two points after being inside the
it has to be a valid optimisation
secondly i know just like convexity
but any point on that interpolation is less equal the
a linear combination of the values of the two local minima
also less people than the smaller the
any of the points on that line
i will also be omitted
OK so get the contradiction
however no
that i just i was very careful talking about minimum value
not minimize
this is a convex function
and anyway here
i'm at a minimizer
it has a unique value but we end up i don't know
but this is a convex optimisation one one
leave out the bag is going to do a lot more of that
later in the week
so you have to believe again a couple of things
on face value
until he shows up and then he will teach a lot more about this should
help you understand what's going on here
so what we have is
a bunch of linear constraints
and those linear constraints