we're going to the ground network we create is going to require or the into
the sea
my memory
and you united states like a thousand which is not alive and you know that
your house are three which again is data like this is already a billion clauses
so this is too much
as it turns out however we're actually going to be able to do inference
in main memory or networks of the size and large
for the following using the following idea
we can exploit the sparseness of relational domains
what i mean by that
if you think about for example relation like friends x y
there are six billion people on earth
so there's thirty six billion billion possible groundings of friends x y
which is unmanageable but the vast majority of those are false because every person only
has enough few doesn't maybe a few hundred friends
OK so the vast majority of items false so we can do is
only explicitly represent a list of the true atoms and all the others are implicitly
assumed to be false
likewise because most systems are false
most clauses are satisfied because the preconditions on fire
as long as one of the preconditions is false the clause is satisfied
so again we can assume that all clauses are satisfied unless we have an explicit
list of the unsatisfied clauses
so we can we can do lazy inference well we don't know the whole model
in advance which is grounded out is needed as required by the inference
and with this the memory they use just goes down by orders and orders of
for example an entity resolution problem and on and on and on
bibliography database the
memory required when down by
on the other for a factor of four hundred thousand
in fact
so the algorithm that we developed for this is called lazysat and it's a variation
of walks
this actually turns out to be good for satisfiability
so for the for applications people have traditionally satisfiability in the non probabilistic for for
example planning take the blocksworld previously the largest that you could do was was blocks
schools with twenty blocks
with this kind of blocks world with one hundred blocks
and if you think about the fact that the size of the problem goes up
exponentially with the number of locks this is a huge feature
so this is one of the things that's that allows us to scale to real
type of stuff we want to do is computing probabilities
so we want to compute the probability that some formula holds in the most general
given an MLN and a set of constants or so this is the marginal polytope
this formula or we might want to compute the conditional probability of formula one given
formula two
OK now in principle
this is easy to do
because the probability of a formula is just the sum of the probabilities of the
world the formula holds so you can just go through all the world's check whether
the formula holds that the probabilities of those and that's what we want the problem
with this of course is that it's it's it's feasible computationally what we can do
though is use something like MCMC to sample worlds
and then in each other that we sample we check whether or not the formula
holds and then estimate for the probability of the formula is just the fraction of
runs where it holds
and for conditioning on another formula then although we need to do is as generates
candidate worlds
in the MCMC process first we check with the formula two holds
if it doesn't hold we ignore that world and we only counts
within the world's reformer two holds and again that the probability formula one is just
going to do the fraction of those were the formula holds
now if if the evidence is is the formula two is in the form of
the conjunction of ground atoms which is usually what it is because your evidence is
really set facts like you know the symptoms of the patient and how this person's
friends are and so forth we can actually something else which is to generalize the
of knowledge based model construction by only building the minimum network that we need to
answer the query
and then once network as an KBMC we can apply any probabilistic inference techniques like
and you can also do lifted inference meaning something like resolution but for these models
although i will be talking about that here
so how do we do that how do we construct the minimum ground that was
that we need to actually carry it out even though it's generalisation of KBMC they
actually turns out to be simple
in the same way
that the markov network can actually be simpler than than vision network in terms of
discovering what dependencies i
so here's what the algorithm is
you start with an empty network
and with the q
containing the query nodes
and then we just going to the following cycle
we taken from the front of the queue
remove it from the queue and added to the network
and then we check whether that no there is no evidence
it's in nodes reason the evidence we know its value and we can stop there
if the node is not the evidence that we need to do is we to
have its neighbours to the q and keep going
so what's going to happen is that the network is going to expand out from
the query until it bounces into evidence
and of course in the worst case is going to retrieve the whole network of
the whole universe and that's going to be bad but more often you know there's
often a very small subset of the number that's relevant for a query
like if i one as ensign suppression of value and it's not about you and
your friends but not about the other six billion people on
so this is another thing that can is a very very large increase in in
there's still a problem
i've got all of these two separate models and trying to the whole process so
i get i will pay
well in in i to get the information of the show
so that's colin it's general because i can basically synthesizes
in some nations of shape and appearance as well as i can recognise both are
inherently linked
there's an interesting papers by colleague of mine that same year of gross and he
did some work on all how well
for very very large datasets doing PCA
how well the show components and their parents components generalize
so what you are seeing here is the number of training images
so there's a lot we multiply
and they he chooses subset ninety
and i one have a very large tests evaluating this across the perhaps like a
thousand different images things and so if we use say one training image and i
try to reconstruct
that we construct a thousand shapes from this one training image this is my reconstruction
so it's quite a bit scalar scales can arbitrary thing is normalized every pixel things
and as you expect add more and more training data
i can do a pretty good job and so the interesting thing is that you
have got about ninety shapes also it starts to what we call reach saturation so
even though we try to represent perhaps one thousand thousand different shapes i can do
a good job in nineteen ninety images because the reconstruction error becomes very large and
we detest like across illumination
obviously elimination one how much change at all because
there's not much elimination is an elimination show
suppose suppose was one of the big ones and things but given that had enough
training data it would saturate and identity
and basically you can see here that includes plateaus out
the important thing is for period is that you don't get the same effect
you don't get a saturation economy reaches
a plateau
at quite a high level of
because what is basically indicates indicated to was that obviously PCA
it is special appearances on pixel appearances doesn't generalize well i mean that's very well
known that basically you kind get this effect that it's very good where we representing
training data but not so good especially if you try to do across the whole
a large class of images of trying to reconstruct on the test and so
and this is kind in grosses gross's he a couple other things in the article
what kind of put forward that essentially the fundamental problem with active appearance models is
that especially appearance part how
you're trying to do too much we try to synthesize and detect and
register but unfortunately your model can handle
and so
what happens is that so if we apply say sometimes that with i am
on the training set so this is this i like
seeing is seen these subjects before generate i am i know a really good job
nearly always lines
but if i go to a test set
but i have never seen before in terms of identity
a second very poor performance can kind see like the jaws anything and other things
going on and this is the side that when you see a lot of time
to practice but i show you the kind of show demo's according to assure them
of the same all its working life AC but if you try to make it
work across a large number of people by that's essentially because it's just a linear
and it's trying to do too much
o thing second policy and this is zero
scotland here
so what
what a lot of people have been trying to do is not just us
is essentially a
breaking generative duality assumption so do i have to have a generative model
in shape and appearance can perhaps have a generative shape model perhaps discriminative appearance model
hopefully like you guys have been like looking looking at a whole heap of different
machine learning techniques last last two weeks and the attractiveness of that is this is
that sometimes the generative model
as a kind of spectrum with PCA general models trying to do too much trying
to synthesize every possible five so it's when it's trying to basically along to face
it's the it's ability ability to align is inherently linked to how well can synthesize
so PCA synthesizer face well it's not a very good job attracted so perhaps better
what is data
is to perhaps try to work out well
how faces differently to other objects or other images things so that these images could
be like non by objects or they could be dismissed aligned face images for instance
and so
and we still keep the generative shape like because we assume there is a couple
of images with the general shape model that is continuous and and this is the
thing and you know that i want to solve so we want to keep this
general want to keep this linear linear model the appearance
well not so much caring about because i mean obviously the synthesis it's good to
keep the to the the
three genera but in terms of getting accurate alignment this is what i'm worried about
so if i can do a better job of it
differentiating aligned faces with misaligned faces let's what do that so that's that's kind like
the whole
philosophy of of of some this movement one the first goal to come to venture
into this was about a evidence and here had very interesting paper back and forth
called support vector tracking
and so he couple the whole idea of a support vector machine integrated that within
the lucas kanade equations
and he had some experiments showing some really cool expect some really cool results showing
contract so contracts and showing that you very good generalisation
after that there was a face is specifically a guy called david christian announces who's
post-doc of conclusions are free university manchester he came out with a technique called constrained
local models
and we'll get into a bit more
on what that is but this is another way to circumvent this problem but we'll
talk about why it's not really simple to do this and there's been some other
work by actually frontline shelling luke whose use that same year but now is general
and now we actually got to play another separate paper et CVPR this here on
this topic except to to
we can we cover classifiers and things like that and generally kind of think well
and this group up here is once again
this happens to be serious
this happens soon which is an amino acids this also happens to be quite hydrophilic
here's our old friend the basic amino group here's the carboxyl group
this is a bit hydrophobic c h two and then we once again have have
the hydrophilic head here
and therefore we imagine if we look at what's called a space filling models model
and the space filling model really is intended to show us what one imagines if
one had this vision which we don't have these what how much space each of
these atoms
would actually take up in if one were able to see them
and here we see the space filling models the the
this this
lipid molecule is actually slightly king
with its hydrophilic head tucked into the the water space
so here is actually the way that many biological membranes look in terms of the
way that they are constructed
now the fact of the matter is this also affords the cell the ability to
segregate content on one or the other side of whatever lipid bilayer it happens to
have constructed
and here we can see about the same i permeability
how permeable these membranes as are two different kinds of molecules
permeability obviously refers to the ability of
of this membrane to obstruct or to to allow
the migration of molecules from one side to the other
these ions we see right here are obviously highly hydrophilic
by virtue of their charge
that explains why for example table solved goes already in the solution because it readily
ionized sodium and a c
which then are rapidly taken up by the water molecules
so these are highly hydrophilic islands and the question is can they go from one
side of the membrane to the other and the answer is
absolutely not or highly improbably y
because these are so high highly hydrophilic the water molecules love gather around them and
form hydrogen bonds and electrostatic bonds with them
and if one of these ions ventures over here
it's going from an area where it's warmly embraced by the solvent molecules
to an area where these molecules intensely dislike
these ions and therefore thermodynamically the entrance any one of these ions into the membrane
into the hydrophobic portion membrane is highly disfavored which makes the membrane essentially for all
practical purposes impermeable
the same can be said of glucose which happens to be a carbohydrate we'll talk
about it shortly
but it's also nicely hydrophilic
it also can go in
water in fact can go through
and it's actually the case to my knowledge that one doesn't really understand to this
why lipid bilayers are reasonably permeable to water
you would say well that's this water should be able to go through it clearly
doesn't have to have connect the positive and negative charge but the physical chemist if
you ask them cut why does water what we are able to go through lipid
bilayers the say we've been working on that and will get an answer
in the next five or ten years and they said that forty years ago in
thirty years ago and they're still say we don't really understand why water goes through
which is embarrassment because here is one of the fundamental biochemical properties of living matter
that is poorly understood gases can go right through
and i mean all acids ATP glucose six phosphate highly hydrophilic and also not go
now the advantage of this
the that a cell can
accumulate large concentrations of these molecules either on the inside or can pump them to
the outside
in other words it can create great gradients in the concentrations of different kinds of
for example in many cells the concentration of calcium
see a plus plus
is a thousand times higher on the outside of the cell
then on the inside the cell
which gives you a testimonial to how impermeable
these lipid bilayer membranes are
the fact of the matter is i'm finding a little bit here because
in the lipid bilayers of of the plasma membrane of the cell the outer membrane
of the cell that we talked about it passing last time there pumps
which are constantly working away
pumping ions from one side to the other
overcoming a little a little bit of leakage which may have occurred in the calcium
ion happens to snap through in one direction or the other
and we end up expending a lot of energy
to keep these ion gradients
inappropriate concentrations on the outside and the inside
in fact virtually all the energy
the goes that is expended in our brain almost all of it is expended by
the use of to power the ion pumps
which are constantly ensuring
the concentrations of certain ions on the outside and inside of neurons are kept in
their proper respective the proper respective levels
it could therefore be that actually
more than half of our metabolic burden every day
is expended just keeping the iron segregated on the outside and inside of cells
for example potassium is at high levels inside cells sodium is high levels outside cells
just decide some arbitrary example
there are also by the way as i mentioned last time channels
and channels are actually just little doughnut shaped objects which are placed inserted into lipid
so in this case
each of the labels is coming from some state capital y and their let's take
a possible labels where k is bigger than two now
so there is a direct way of extending to boost to the multiclass case
so in that case the weak classifiers are just prediction rules which now predict for
every example one of these k labels
and we can use the same update rule
in this form
the multiclass case so again if the example is correctly classify multiplied by either mind
itself t otherwise multiply by either the alpha t that's unchanged in our final classifier
rather than taking majority vote
we would take a plurality vote are weighted plurality vote meaning you
choose the label
which gets the most weighted votes even though that might not be
a majority
so this is called
adaboost died in one
it turns out that this
version of adaboost we can prove the same bound on the training year across approach
things about margin that we can prove the same thing about the training year
provided that
all of the areas of the weak classifiers are at most half
so this is
the good news that we can prove this bound but it's bad news that we
need this requirement that we need the weak classifiers that are at most half
why is it bad
if you have let's say ten classes of doing so digit recognition
he just guess randomly your accuracy will be ten percent
and this is saying that we need an accuracy of at least fifty percent
so this is saying that we need accuracy which is much much better than random
guessing when you have more than two labels
so in practice this is usually not a problem if you're using a pretty strong
weak learning algorithm something like c four point five because it can usually get an
accuracy better than fifty percent
if you using something really we truly we because the weak learner something like decision
stumps then this will almost certainly
these significant problems
if you're in this case
and you want to use boosting the most common technique is to reduce to binary
so what do i mean by that so in multi class
prediction you're trying to predict whether a given example is one of let's say ten
so if you do in digit recognition you want to predict which digit it's
so the idea here
is to reduce that multiway question
in two a set of binary questions
so rather than asking what's the label
of this example
we instead ask is this example
zero or not is it o one or not
it's a bit too or not you get see a series of binary learning problems
so for instance in this case
may be the set of labels are a b c d and e
so we would replace
the single multi class problems by
five in this case binary
binary learning problems
so what happens is every example let's say here's an example which has label c
so for the first problem it would be labelled negative for the second problem it
would be labelled negative
the third one it would be positive and probably others would be labelled negative
so this is called the one against all
one against all cos your getting
one labelled against all of the other labels
and the idea is that when you get done
you predict with the label
so you've done your train these binary is
on this binary learning problem and that the end predict with the label which gets
the most votes the the most weighted votes
so this is called adaboost rmh
and so for instance in this case we can prove that the training year the
final classifier will be at most that same product diseased he is that we had
before timescale over two where k is the number of classes
this is good because the product of the zeta use will typically got an exponentially
fast but it is linear does depend linearly on the number of labels
and this is kind of an inevitable for this kind of methods
because because just a small number of errors
made by the on the underlying binary problems can cause the overall prediction to be
so it's not very robust this this kind of about
maybe i'll skip last point
OK i'll go ahead and mention it so this also extends to the multi label
case multi label means each example can have more than one correct label so you
can use the same method there
OK so an alternative approach is to use output code
so this is the method that student detrick can be carry
so the idea is to come up with a binary
learning problems
which in some ways are more interesting or more robust in some way than the
kind of binary problems that you get using this one against all reduction
so the idea is for each one of our labels in this case a b
c d e we associate codeword a binary code for each one
of these labels so a is associated with codeword minus plus minus plus and b
is associated with minus plus plus minus
and so on
now each one of these columns is now defining
a different binary learning problems
so in this binary learning problem in this first one for instance all of the
examples which are labeled a b
would be treated as negative examples
and all of the examples which are labeled c or d would be treated as
positive examples
likewise each one of these columns defines the different binary learning problem
so we can use we can train
this really a general method it's much more general than boosting we can use with
boosting so we can apply to train
a classifier for each one of these columns
and then when we get a new example and we want to classify that example
we just evaluate the classifiers we built for each one of these columns and we
can choose
the label which is most consistent with the predictions of those binary classifiers
so this is called the output coding one against all method is a special case
we just use the identity matrix here
no pluses on the diagonal minus everywhere else
but what's more interesting is to use
OK code like code used in information theory or even just filling this table with
i've never heard anyone use level three
but you know
you can imagine what
a very important
class or
distributions and priors is this
exponential family of distributions and the conjugate priors that go with them
so it's worth
just knowing about this
piiv excavators in the exponential family if can be written
in the following form
the key here is that the distribution of the data
can be written as
some some measurable over the data here
some term involving just the parameters in the way the data and the parameters interact is inside an exponential
e to the
five stated
transpose at a x
this is the linear expression
inside an exponential
is the vector of natural parameters
so it's a way of representing your parameters in its natural form those things that appear linearly inside the exponential
and yes
is a vector of sufficient statistics
have the data so for example calcium
galcians burnley's
plus songs whole bunch of common things that you've encountered
are members of the exponential family
fergal see in the natural parameters
so this event physics are
x and x squared
and the natural parameters
are a re-parametrization of the mean and the
now if you can write your distribution in the following exponential family form
then a conjugate prior
is a prior over theta
that has the same form as a function of data
asier exponential family
so this is now distribution over theta
and phi alpha status appearing inside the exponential with some parameters
and this gene data's appeared with some exploded
the nice thing about this is when you multiply a conjugate prior r by an
exponential family likelihood the posterior that you get is conjugate base with conjugate means
it's sort
it it interacts with the exponential family give you back a conjugate
and in particular r
the posterior of theta
given x one to x ann
written in this form which you can look at if you want later
it just increments
this hyperparameter are aided by adding into it and it increments the vector new
by adding the sum of these sufficient statistics
so why am i going on about exponential families and conjugate priors it's because if
you're doing bayesian modeling you need some tools to specify
the distributions over
the different parameters in your model
these tools are incredibly powerful
now some people say
you know i often use conjugate priors
in a complicated hierarchical models and they'll say
otherwise is the prior
and the answer to that is
you know
is computationally convenient
because these things
because the conjugate can do a lot of the computations analytically
and they say albert you're not being good bayesian because he using something computationally convenient
is that if your true beliefs
and i think that's
that's a little unfair
in the sense there
you know ultimately we are trying to be practical in what we do
so we do one use computationally convenient tools where we can
and remember the thing about the prior that really matters
is that it should be able to put
probability mass on
all reasonable values of the parameters in these conjugate priors are often really good at
spreading the probability mass over reasonable values
so they might not be exactly what i believe but
they might be just so incredibly convenient that there are has good is just playing
in what i believe but much more efficient
questions the question was and can only believe be arbitrarily closely approximated by a mixture of conjugate
far family distributions
i would say
i don't know of a particular result and therefore but i would say probably yes
anyway sickly what you can do is a mix ture these conjugacy can write down as
the conjugate exponential model over more latent variables
and so
basically every part of your model is then paraconjugate and exponentials and in general you
have a very rich class beliefs there
you know i mean that's a good argument for
using this
stepping back again so here it is the bayes rule applied to machine learning
i will go through this
anymore but i told you a little bit about how to choose the priors
now let me talk
this bit here
these that's integrals
so computationally
that's the thing that we need to worry about
so imagine in general there you have a model with some observed data why
some hidden variables x
some parameters theta
it's a model class am
the marginal likelihood can now be written in this form
the problem is these integrals
it can be very high dimensional integrals
and the presence of these hidden variables and many more models
results in additional dimensions that need to be marginalized out
like you know you need to marginalize out not only
the parameters but all these hidden variables as well
so i first went to think organisers for inviting me to talk about multiple sources
so i don't exactly know what notable sources means so i got to be multiple
kernel instead
community but considering just doing the resources in a supervised way
so if you have a lot of my talk i was just using examples from
computer vision to show that this is decent thing to do
because it multiple sources of the problem
present how you can do it using multiple kernel learning and we should different formulations
of the problem
and finally i will consider quickly some semantic analysis and i believe that the tools
have been using for that could be very useful for all the sittings of learning
with multiple sources and particularly in particular
using covariance operators is a very simple way to analyse what you do people use
and idea have more and more digital media have
it was you have pictures what seems industry also for or
and your own personal PCFG bytes of pictures
if you have kids
in every case when you get right so forgive forgot about
i would like to show you that all other stats also many tasks to be
to be sold for computer vision
they're all associated with the mission employment
you can really
a good way of relating images
then you can apply playing different
playing different measurement techniques we can have a sort of different tasks
so the first two thousand first task is one of the image retrieval system
is quite a long time
so you can see get pictures of london get to know
you get some them with from them
so here when i need those queries
well is only looking at some of the surrounding text they don't get the math
right now my time
here the goal is to look at the image to be able to output better
together but the output of classifier outputs
as pictures on my
and even worse
take paris
maximum get the pictures together map is again
in a sense this is triggering event
and then
you need to be able to get the image to separate paris paris this is
a simple examples
and the one going back to keep
OK so have many pictures usually they organised by my year in the end he
it's very tough to do to get them because have something
so will have to be able to do some clustering clustering by kids
well as all the pictures king one of the ways of key you might do
well to visualise i want to do
detection of new guinea
you can do it
so anyway have lots of stuff and all of them are can be framed as
national classification clustering outlier detection
we all those of complex locus
a massive so here we don't it was what in madrid is one image is
one that points which means that it's massive
it's very you have a lot of heterogeneity
a different yet sometimes even inside an image you have a lot of different lots
of different sources
and typically have different useful for for images you can look at shape so you
expecting some some object and you want to go to exchange important for the commission
cora is also important cue surface texture which is different q
i have image can be segmented into different q
interest point where they are located in the image at the end
we have a lot of different shoes and what
claiming that when you want to design a kernel
of course i would consider cannabis this stuff if you want to design a kernel
it's a lot easier if you focus on a single single source of the time
is any kind which is good straight both
shape colour texture and saying it was point is kind of difficult
but if you want to focus
only interest point
people have been doing that
for example they consider interest points so here we have too many nice
this is just corner to corner detector
people have used
four dollars it you can also view the i match kernel was essentially divided
imagine two pieces and they can still write the number of the histogram of
of SIFT features as interest points this is easy to do
and the good thing is that this is really fall interest points then if you
want to kernel for
for texture you again
people use it the conventional features like gradient of gabor wavelets and then you get
get histograms
well there's one so you can see that
it is easy to design fear
another way of designing kernel for simple one q
and finally on work with a national ways to look at segmented images
the assumption that usually segmentation does not work we never get
in two in two segments
one object in the middle siemens and the background is the signature was gets things
which are cut into pieces
if you look to consider that you are the same in the image
and make the assumption
you make and you have the
objects would be cut into pieces
no assignment will span
with the object of interest in the background so here
from los creek with so the images one big so
to a small graph your it goes for dozens or hundreds of regions so how
it works simply
two image going to the gradient watershed transform
the team from in and then you can reduce the number of the number of
now what you have done is designed a kernel on the on both types of
objects and they will present these these objects
is there a graph
this is the image this is the segmentation of the image is assigned to each
web one vertex the region
we connect especially neighbouring regions and then we put the labels in the region which
is a histogram of pixels in that region
so this we capture essentially traditions in kind so the way
of looking at the specific u example here we do not consider the texture of
its response OK it's kind of the single view if you wish
no we can design ever graphs can use the graph cannot technology to be able
to get away from that
and before i go on
OK assuming
every pixel in the image has three values the red green and blue
and each of those three values could be any one of two hundred fifty five
different values
then we've got two hundred fifty five times twenty five times two hundred fifty five
combinations that one pixel could have taken so we already have a huge number of
values that that than one pixel could take on now we we look at the
whole image it's a gigantic number
you know so the point here is that if we have
examples of the behavior we like that might still be covering a very small part
of the input space
this set of examples we have even if we think we have several
if you
look at the
the space the images can take in general very small so we can
obviously we can't just memorize images we can't just take examples and think OK i've
seen this image that's gotta parasites and it has seen this one is not going
to parasites and it because we're never going to get the same image twice so
we need to be able to deal with that
lack of specification of the problem
OK here's
the traffic in kampala which i would say is marginally more chaotic
cry even at least you guys don't tend to drive on the pavement and you
second thing i think a bit more organized if you
have a CCTV video streams
like this and you're getting the real-time feed from cameras around the
around the
centre of the city where you live
imagine if you are able to derive some high-level information from from this video stream
if you could tell how fast the traffic moving
is moving normally
is there some anomalous phenomenon which maybe maybe an accident or maybe something unusual happening
that would be useful things to work out and
you know pretty you know pretty tough kind of inference problem
if you are able to work workers from the video data
then a whole new set of questions arises which also have some uncertainty could you
predict the traffic characteristics
tomorrow at the particular junction how how much trust is going to be there
and i've been
trying to do this for my three years in kampala complete it always takes you
by surprise where there's a will there's gonna be congestion sometimes the rows are fine
when you're expecting it to be a nightmare you know i can't really figure it
out but if we had enough data then maybe we could do this automatically
all right here's an example which is you know not so specific to to here
but one that will will try to be later
we speech to text we may have an input recording some sounds so sound when
you recorded is just a sequence of numbers just it's several members
you know maybe forty four thousand times per second u
if you take a sample from the input signal
you get the sequence you could represent that has
time versus frequency plot here the spectrogram and from these
the spectral information here you could try to work out what being said
this is a recording of my favorite poems
ted hughes
that's an example which will look at it obviously you fairly complicated one partly because
of the
the size of the input space again we've got so many
so many
numbers here in five hundred thousand
numbers in sequence
i think a bit about
on in general terms how to deal with this
it's going to be a bit a vague here give some general notion of of
what we're doing and will go back to looking at some more examples of the
types of motivating applications were interested in
so one thing is immediately clear if we didn't make any assumptions about our problems
we can learn anything
if we white noise world where everything was completely random and we were continually surprised
by our senses
we have no idea what to expect at any time we wouldn't be able to
learn anything
it's only by
making assumption having some bias towards what you
already expect to be happening in the world
but you can begin to make headway on these problems
so humans have various kinds of biases about the things they expect to
expect to receive in their senses the things
biases about the types of ways they might represent the
external world
and we're so good at seeing patterns that quite often we see them even when
they're not really there
so usually this two kind of assumptions which are fundamental to pretty much all
machine learning work
which allow us to make a start on solving these problems the first one is
and this is
this is something you basically always assume that if you have some function
say a
images too
two label on
you would assume that if the input changes a little bit then the output by
change a little bit or not at all
so if you have some images perceived and you know the label
you know the output of the function
if you receive another image and it's almost the same
but just a little bit different than
then we just use the same kind of and that's one is simplicity
and basically models which are
which have
few were variables fewer kind of not to twiddle
we prefer those over-complicated cont
so we're biased towards
seeing those kind of patterns and
and things are looking up
just look at a few more kind of canonical
machine learning tasks
just to give us a few examples to work with later on
and it's a pretty exciting time to be working in machine learning incidentally we have
we have these problems around for a long time and i think
fields at the stage now where these are being robust defied well being able not
just to
face recognition and handwriting recognition
before being able to on this gigantic global scale use speech recognition is
pretty robust now when you
when when you try to
here's another example you might want to
have images of handwritten digits
there's a a great deal of variability in how someone might draw an image
and given a new image
let's try and work out which which digit the the person intended what do they
have in mind when they were making the shapes on the page
so there's a gigantic canonical database which a lot of people
considered to be a good
good testing ground for new algorithms
and if you think about how to go about this
or even just two class problem
where you get some
some input on this
in a little square and you want to know whether it's one or two
maybe you start to think about crafting crafting rules
we're going to look at something where we we basically
take a great deal of data and try to
as you may recall
let's roll yes let's roll
and by the way i admire your little finger
because most of the planet is this gifted as you are not everyone was guaranteed
so many brains
as you and i say seriously have been fortunate enough to have been given granted
let me just finish up discussing what we're talking about last time
which was the cell cycle
you may recall that we talked about oncogenes
we talked about rats and the rest oncoprotein which sends out mitogen it signals and
what it does just to
what we're talking about is it pushes cells from the beginning of the g one
phase of the cell cycle up to point here decision point in the life of
the cell it's called the restriction point
and here just by way of review the cell has to decide whether or not
going to commit itself essentially irreversibly to go to the rest of the cell cycle
or one with stay in g one
and may even retrieved from the cell cycle in g zero
and ras pushes this decision forward
the retinoblastoma protein which we talked about the last time stands as the guardian of
the gate right here the rb protein
and the retinoblastoma protein holds this shot unless and until certain preconditions have been satisfied
on which occasion the retinoblastoma protein opens up the restriction point k and allows the
cell to go through the rest of the cell cycle and now when viewed from
this perspective we can begin to understand how hyperactivity of rats
and how the inactivation of this rock are be this retinoblastoma tumor suppressor protein have
such disruptive the stabilizing effect on the proliferative controls of the cell
keep in mind this is a negative factor on cell proliferation
it's the two tumor suppressor gene which must be inactivated in many cancers this is
a proto oncogene oncogene which must become hyperactive did
now i want to move from that into the topic of today
and that's
the whole issue of immunity
and much of our immunity comes from understanding the way we deal with what violent
the fact is just to cite one arbitrary virus infection relatively few people died from
viral infections these days because we can come immunized against and the first immunizations are
really began
in the late eighteenth century believe it or not when a physician in england called
edward jenner
i first noticed
that women who would work
as milkmaid milking cows
and who got disease called cowpox
from milking the cows seem to be immune
two the disease of smallpox which was by that time realized to be spreading epidemics
are highly infectious agent and one which actually killed quite a few people and generate
into it correctly in retrospect that the experience of these milk maids
and their exposure cowpox virus somehow protected them gave them indeed lifelong protection from subsequent
smallpox infection
subsequently to that the the sources from the cowpox infection
or scraped and the day the fluid was used was scratched into wounds of people
in order to immunize them into immunization really began in the seventeenth ninety is taking
a sore from the skin of the cowpox infected patients injecting that into the
the skin of somebody who required immunizations and as a consequence hoping that this would
confirm the lifelong protection in some cases actually individuals who were infected in that way
actually came down with smallpox
in other cases or some variant form of the skull but in most other cases
these individuals actually acquired a lifelong immunity
in fact the very word vaccine
which was used already at the time
comes from the latin word about course which means cow
in the north side cambridge common there's the benjamin waterhouse
house which is still there
he was the first physician to
introduced smallpox vaccination into this country already in the end of the eighteenth century
if we fast-forward to situation like poliovirus we've situations in this country where in the
nineteen forties nineteen thirties and nineteen forties there were epidemics of poliovirus if one began
to examine who was susceptible who wasn't it was clear the people children who were
for example
born and raised in the middle and upper-middle-class and houses were very susceptible through much
of their lives for example in southern california there were dramatic examples where children who
grew across grew up across the border in let's say one mexico
really came down with a paralytic polio the polio virus
is one soon learned was the virus which infects not only the gastrointestinal tract
and creates a form of mild diarrhea but it may be one out of one
hundred persons
the virus escapes from the GI tract from the gastrointestinal tract invades into the central
nervous system and actually creates debilitating
paralysis which most of which is is not yield
and some people have lifelong paralysis other individuals whose paralytic paralysis
goes away actually when they grow older thirty forty fifty years later they began once
again to experience the paralytic symptoms is that arose as a consequence of the current
and this time one began to try to figure out why children
living in tijuana mexico really came down with polio virus infections whereas those who grew
up up north flights in southern california he did indeed do so and one came
to the conclusion that the children growing up in tijuana mexico are frequently exposed very
early in the life too contaminated water sewage contaminated water and they as a consequence
acquired a lifelong immunity without getting sick whereas children who grew up rather sterile conditions
for the north never had any exposure to the virus and when he hits them
as a young adult series teenagers it created devastating effect
so i would like to
two really
lead that the
paradigm where we have real movement
and divert into the
space of imagination so to say so
the second paradigm is
as i pointed out and use on the video early on
it is a paradigm where we
only sink about movements where we
imagine someone else
and one of the important point here is when measured movements we can imagine squeezing
a ball
playing piano or
the sensation of somebody talk hand or something like that it's very individual some people
can do one thing that they can do the other things that
again following a motive to push
the main
hard work to the machines and to have the subjects not learn a lot
we ready are
hearing people up with an EEG cap
we're ready after twenty minutes of calibration time
well they have to imagine
left and her right hand movement
we ready to go with that data and to infer the intention
although they're are not moving anything they're just imagine
and then we can go to the feedback session
typically this
which we take for
blocks of this calibration
and in the between the
the second and the third this small nor was to which means that you get
in a coffee or on your liking of class war
and then we go to
the feedback session
so maybe that getting the filters the spatial temporal filters
so maybe i'm just
the so so this means that we have a multi-channel ECG recording hundred twenty h
we do
low pass filtering to get the light of potential features as i explained
then we do some bandpass filtering
and to get the a are coefficients which describe the dynamics
of the system
for every channel
extract a
four to six they are
the fishing
these would the channel
and you have on hundred twenty eight
and then we have the subject specific
filters the CSP filters and they could be they could come s
CSP or CSSP host CSSP and you you know
its surrounding so we can have cs to the four one and so
and then there is the need to do artifact removal say with ICA all with
some of my removal
in the end of the day we have a large vector and we can
make that all care what's the difference between probability and degrees of membership probably clear
to everybody should but just to illustrate that one more time probability is describing you
have assigned numbers to the probability the likelihood of something to happen
so if you would have asked yesterday for example what's the probability of as not
having to listen to this boring tutorial michael berthold being sick today
the uniform said well we don't know the guy but right now there's going around
two of my neighbours sick and i have twenty two neighbours of the probability of
further study sick maybe something like five percent but that would have meant that today
i i would have been sick or healthy that's the outcome you're describing the likelihood
of something some crisp event by the happened on that track so the degree of
membership sort of of BBC not this one was right but today i can stand
here and say well that's the degree of membership of membership for me to the
set of sick people
well maybe here suggests that it probably is not one i mean otherwise be hospital
dying but i actually do have a little bit of the sabbath throat i can
tiny cold sneaking up so i wouldn't declare myself one hundred percent healthy either the
process on the degree of probably like points are five so that's what you want
to help
and it's not really sick OK so probability describes
events happening or not happening how likely it is
fuzzy sets describe the degree of membership describes how much he belong to a certain
set that's not something that will change i mean it will change ultimately i'm not
going to be that sick any more or maybe and we don't have the cold
tomorrow so may change but not for this specific
OK so i told you also to stuff new stretching wondering what does this have
to do with data analysis don't care about building fuzzy rules and describe what is
bizarre controllers cars we want analyse data and we want to build models that describe
so green fuzzy rules obviously would be wonderful way of doing that and in fact
very complicated data set for stock market prediction trying to figure out what's what's microsoft
stock going to do tomorrow would be wonderful if i got three fuzzy rules that
describe don't it was slow yesterday it's going high tomorrow something some easy relations that
i could use to trade stocks so trying to extract fuzzy rules from data that's
the beauty of actually if you manage to do that this would be very nice
and easy to understand rules right
OK so the the meant that the classes are rooms for the first
in germany call those hotel someone approach wooden hammer i don't support force approach building
fuzzy rules from data the fundamental which essentially does nothing more than saying well i'm
going to ask the use to please specify
membership functions that are meaningful to him here is going to give me membership functions
for for x y
one minus zero small medium large scissors this membership function triangular membership functions that's for
my mom and i were assumes that are also four membership functions for
the consequences are trying to model this kind of data that we saw here using
these membership sort of like to have a rule that says well if x is
then y is
well i don't know maybe also medium medium large something like that something right or
if if x is large then
why is small something like that so i'd like to derive these types of rules
automatically from from data using these predefined membership functions begin do that
we do that simply by dividing our space our two-dimensional input output space in rich
based on the maximum degree of fulfilment for all rules i mean if i had
a rule that started with x if x is zero then it would be
the one that sort of means that has the highest degree of fulfilment in this
area right that's where the degree of membership is the highest one but in this
area of will that would start with if x is small would be so these
are the four regions for possible antecedents of rules and the same is true here
are the possible consequences
so what you see here our sixteen possible rules that you can even write down
right can that's all i can do i can do if x is zero then
y is zero rated with x is zero then y is small so those of
sixteen possibles are goes my my data
and i want to cover the domain x so i'm going to go for just
find the patterns that fits
each of these possible rule antecedents the best
so i'm looking for patterns that has the maximum degree
of membership for my possible rule antecedents of this one is closest to the peak
of the
of the fuzzy sets for small this one is closest to the peak from medium
this one is closest to as you can see those two are actually wrong
the this this should be over here this is the one that has the highest
degree of membership for large and over here this one is the highest degree of
zero then change the types of rules so i'll do that which tells me OK
this pattern is going to
define what's going to be written in the rule as the consequent of the rule
if x is zero this one is going to define what they put in the
world if x is small and so on and then we'll just look for the
maximum degree of membership for our for y
fuzzy sets large medium are will see OK here this is medium
medium this largest and the so we'll see if x is zero then y is
if x is small then y is medium if x is medium then y is
large and if x is large then y is medium
this is the world i want to four extracted from the state of this they
are very very very vaguely describes what's going on in our data
but they have
we of course completely missing out that we have this minimum here this huge peak
and so
i will give it a spin here
so it may last a little longer
it can't last very long
so very shortly
it too will
full over and come to rest
and that kinetic energy will have been converted
into heat
all right so let's continue
now on another subject
and the one that i want to
talk to you about now is
i have a pendulum
the pendulum at time t equals zero
is angle
they know zero
and i know that angle is
five degrees
which is approximately
o point o nine
at the time t equals zero
the idea of this
a tangential speed
i call it v of b
because i call this point b
it's going to be like
i call this a
so this is it
and it comes to a halt let's say a year
at point c
and then is angle
is the maximum angle possible
the state of maximum
that's the length of the pendulum for simplicity simplicity
one meter
it is small angle approximation
the angles will never be very large as you will see later when we calculate
the maximum
and so we know
that we're going to get the simple harmonic oscillation
very good approximation
so theta
it's going to be that angle theta maximum
times the cosine or if you want to be my guest
you can make this sign
i always work was co-signed
omega god
class five
and omega
because it's clear
g overell l i'll give you some equations
during u example this one i will not give you
i assume that you remember this
and that the period of the pendulum
close to pi
square root of allergy g
so we know omega
because we know g and we know l
and now a reasonable question is what would be
if we know
then we would know what data maximum is
because this part here
he calls l
times the cosine
of the max
and so this
is l minus
l cosine
so it comes down to calculating
how high hide object comes above point eight
i will split this into two heights
this one which i call h one
and this one
which i call eight two
so the one that we really want to know
is one of eight one was eighty two
because h one
he was aged two
will be l
one minus the cosine
theta max
so the moment where h one because it's we immediately have the
h one is a piece of cake
because we know
o point b that this
object is at b
when theta zero is five degrees
so it's one
he calls l
and one minus
o thing is zero
you know theta zero
so you'll find and if you are interested in numbers but i don't bother if
don't like numbers for the numbers that i gave you is is o point o
o three eight meters is only three point eight millimetres
i think we need a little bit
put this on the other side
if you take the old y and the previous one and two if you at
age times and and what retailers and well the computer has to be told and
is the value of so now with that let's actually write the oiler program not
the program but the oiler
the oiler method equations let's just call it the oiler equations
while they
first of all
the new x is the old x
wallace h
the new y
it is
just what i've written there
the old y i was h times
a certain number and and finally
a and
as the value
it's the slope of the line element here and therefore by definition that f of
x and y
so it's these three equations which define oil is that
if i assume in one hundred surely must be
the first is
two at some point it acts as an exercise in the literary one point two
to calculate
to program the computer and see whatever they using java now i guess
to do either
oilers method and these are the equations you these would be the recursive equation you
wouldn't to do that
let's try an example then
well the good color for well well purple
i so nobody can see purple is correct
anyone the back room see that that's purple
what OK
the close
so let's calculate example
are use a simple example
it's not entirely trivial
i example is going to be the equation x squared
minus why square on the right-hand side
and what let's start with why have zero equals one let's say
and so this is my initial value problem
that pair of equations
and i have to specify step size let's
take the step size to be point one
you choose the step size of the computer does so will have to talk about
that in a few minutes
now what do you do well
i say this is a non-trivial equation because this equation as far as i know
cannot be solved in terms of elementary functions
so this equation will be in fact very good candidate for numerical
numerical methods like whalers
and you had to use it or maybe with the other way around i forget
on your problem set you
drew a picture of the direction field and answer some questions about the bicycle lights
all the solutions be
all right
the main thing i want you get this is not just for boilers
talk about oil is equations but in general
for the calculations you have to do in this course is extremely important to be
systematic because if you're not systematic you know if just real scribble scribble scribble scribble
you can do the work but it becomes impossible to find mistakes
we must do the work in the form in which you can check it which
it can be checked which you can look over it finding try to see where
mistakes or if in fact there are any
so i strongly suggest
there's no suggestion comment on that you make a little take
the dual loyalties method by hand i don't ask you first step or two
it says i'm just trying to make sure you
some idea of these equations are where they come from
so first the value of n then the value of x and
then the value of y and
and then a couple more columns which tell you what the calculate how to do
the calculation you're going to need the value of the slope
and it's probably a good idea also because otherwise you forget it to put in
a and because that occurs in the formula
all right let's start doing well the first value then is zero that's the starting
point at the starting point x zero y zero
x has the value zero
and why has the value one
so zero
and one
in other words i'm starting
carrying out
exactly what i drew pictorially only now i'm doing it arithmetically using a table and
substituting into the formulas
OK the next thing we have to calculators and well that's since and is the
value of the right hand side
at the point zero one you have to plug that in the right hand side
is x here x squared minus y square
so it's zero square minus one square the value of the slope there is minus
negative one
now i have to multiply that by age age is point one so it minus
sorry negative although that
the way you look at the talk in kindergarten is the way you learn to
talk to us fortunately
kindergarten we said minus
o point one
it is one now what's the value of x and well to the old one
i and one ten
what's the value y well at this point you have to do
it's the old value of y
to get this new value it's the old value
plus this number well that
what's that number is nine tenths
and now i have to calculate the new slope at this point OK
that is one ten square
minus nine ten square
that's point o one
so the mass goes right
square root of attention
and if the tension is very very high energy scale typically close to the planck
scale as we will discuss and explain that these are hyper mass index patients so
the only particles that we need to worry about these low-lying particles everything else would
be up to scale it's all being simply to make the theory well defined and
now i have done here the calculation for the open string where there are no
independent left and right moving excitations shy just had one kind of standing wave excitation
we can easily it's the same story full of a closed string
now there are independent left and right until down field excitations and there was a
condition remember that we had to have equal
total frequency on the left and the i th because this was fixed by the
so if you repeat the same short of calculation what you find well those again
like you not lowest level and and then at the first excited level of the
string spectrum you just apply one
raising operator on the left another of the i each has a vector index
transverse space and there is no particular seemed property of this object and the exchange
of j left
so we can separate the semantic graceless the symmetric and the trace part
this correspond to elementary excitations of fields which are the spin two graviton on something
called the
two index metric then sure
the scalar particle that phrase which is usually called the villa from
not this one thing here this being two is there that it's massless and there's
nothing we can do to get rid of it
yeah this is of course the crucial
the first important step in string theory gravitons are there whether we want them or
not and that's what had killed the early attempts at you models
no before saying more about fact what about the acllon obviously the document is in
new sense it's a negative mass squared particle it shouldn't be there
well i'm sorry i just missed the said sentence tries i said the clustering spectrum
includes this must list into state
and this is what prompted the reinterpretation in the mid seventies of string theory is
a theory of quantum gravity if you could make sense of it as a theory
of QCD
well it has a graviton let's make sense of it as a theory of quantum
now back to the accuracy so the acumen is in your sense but in order
to feel fear eats it's in use since we are happy to live with most
of the time because it simply
is you that you are using the wrong vacuum here it is for instance
a but then she and for some scalar fields say this higgs some things like
field and suppose around phi close to zero it has this invented for well as
all know when you expand it out it will start out with the minus number
times five squared
if you try to do perturbation theory around the own vacuum with no
symmetry breaking your find acllon that's not the problem is simply means you have to
go to the correct by and everything falls into place and gets q
so of course in string theory you would suspect the same is true that if
you find the correct vacuum everything will fall into place but actually people haven't managed
to find the correct viking members on existing theory
we're actually they have found viking about which are only in two dimensions therefore the
only available remedy we know for removing these for regaining stability spacetime supersymmetry and and
that's why should but symmetry is intimately tied with string theory without it we have
a psych theory that we don't know how to make sense
now what is the superstring well technically very little changes actually there are very different
mechanically different a different descriptions of it it but they are basically physically equivalent to
that for example the information that you know about you know your object itself
so this is good in some ways but it's problematic in others so what else
can we do
we cannot discriminate learning
discriminative learning is actually often a very good idea in its own right
and you know i mean these days people pretty much almost always the discriminative instead
of generative learning just because it gives better results
and the reason is that results is that it's actually trying to optimize the right
thing most of the time so what is the right thing
what we do in discriminative learning is that instead of maximizing the joint distribution of
all the variables
one thing to do is i'm going to maximize the conditional likelihood of query variables
given the evidence variables
course this requires knowing and learning time who's going to be clear and was going
to be evidence but most of the time we do know that so we can
you know so in some sense it would be silly not to use the information
and then by optimizing this right we're actually not going to waste any modeling effort
trying to model in model interactions between variables that we actually don't care about
and they could actually make us do the wrong thing because you know i can
make a change
improves the modelling of the things that don't care about the expenses making another modelling
of y given x worse
so this is what distance to give better results and you know the expression that
we get is pretty much the same except that now what we have is q
y given x instead of just the joint distribution of all the variables and i
can ignore all the clicks that only involve variables in x because at inference time
i'm going to know
the difference is that now i have another way to deal with this problem editor
which is the following
instead of computing this expectation over all possible states of y given x what i
can do is i can just look for the single most likely state of y
given x the counts those
opinion approximation for the council for everybody
the reason this works is that these distributions can have you know all sorts of
pixel over the place but as i condition on more and more information
on the exile most of those pixel disappear
and in the limit that should have all of my mass concentrated in one peak
so if i just use the peak
as my approximation in many cases that's actually a good enough approximation were just learning
here we know from noisy data so it's like i really care about getting exactly
the right thing
so this is a very simple idea but it can actually i mean it can
make life we use it first us because now instead of computing an exponential sum
with an exponential number of terms i just doing a maximization which can be a
lot faster
so there's a couple of other approaches to it learning that are was knowing about
the classical approach for landing weights in this model the something called iterative scaling it's
not used a lot these days because it's it's it's quite slow
a very recent method is max margin approaches
max margin approaches that the extension to markov networks of the ideas the support vector
so far there have only been used for restricted types of structures but it's a
method with the with a lot of promise
so what about structure learning
suppose i don't just want to learn the weights as you want to learn the
structure of the model
i e no longer model i want to figure out what the features are not
just what they should be
well we can think of doing so like a greedy search
approach to this
i i start with atomic features meaning the variables themselves
and then i greatly track and joining each feature with each atom
and i evaluate them according to likelihood posterior something i think the best ones and
i keep going
so this is a reasonable method to use there's a problem with that
the problem is that when i try new candidates feature
in order to evaluate its i ninety two potential we compute all the weights because
the features interact with each other
so for each candidate i need to deal with optimisation
you know often with optimisation take sometimes even if it takes a few minutes if
i'm going to try and millions of combinations that's going to be feasible
so we need something in some way to overcome this problem what people have typically
done you know reasonable thing to do
it is to assume
that when i create a new feature the weights of the previous feature stay constant
so now the only thing i have to compute is the weight for this new
and that can be done fast in some cases can be done in closed form
and then maybe once isolated the feature and i can do the optimisation for everybody
so again this is an approximation sometimes it's okay sometimes it doesn't give such good
results but it's it's it's what people
all right so let's talk a little bit about logical inference
so first order logic is very rich language that pretty much allows us to say
all the kinds of things that we're going to want to say here
formulas in first order logic are built up out to four types of symbols
constants representing objects in the domain like emma
variables like expert range over the objects in that domain
the take it to pull of objects as input and produce energy as output like
say mother x
and predicates they represent properties of objects or relations between objects like for example friends
x y
represents whether the x and y fronts
and i'm going to call a literal
predicate or its negation so for example friends are not friends
here is
what is the target values go back
what is the hard
in a in the next lookup table you replace value with the target what is
the target you you function approximation scheme
it's just you take the editor and you disagree
bates is just the squared getting thing inside square brackets as the squared error you
will get you will get the of these algorithms function approximation
i'm sure the sparse coding cells sort of this is my favorite everybody has their
favourite function approximation that was my favorite one
what we know what function approximation linear function approximation
worst case that what can happen in practice often works
nonlinear allowed to is not well developed
nearest neighbour method
are truly not divergent not very often use i don't think that there's not much
theoretical guidance in this in this in this
but i feel free to stop me and
ask anything than not saying anything terribly exciting just just review
one last bit of review and then i'll tell more interest
idea monte carlo has been
sykes has been
you know promoted here in this workshop but it has been very useful here is
an instance of monte carlo during really interesting things in reinforcement learning
and in fact i would say the current state of the art algorithms in reinforcement
learning basically sampling
tree based approaches for many many classes of applications
and here's the idea of sparse
is the foundational idea so suppose you want to find the best action on the
current state here in some current state you want to find the best action you
have a model that you can sample
action the next day so you imagine it to action the solid action and the
dot action you sample decided actually three times
he said the next day he settled the dashed actually three times
and in each of those states and political action the next action and in the
lower tree
sitting monte carlo tree
monte-carlo tree of trying every action every sample state
and then you will be have to some extent and then you back values you
take about the leaves could be zero
and you do
that's sort of the average of the values and utica max actually below the value
and you compute the value of reaction in the root note and you take the
the in the empirical example that's one
it turns out that this is an algorithm
who's coming whose complexity is completely independent
on the size of the state space
and produces with high probability
a near optimal action in the
in that state
now because you when you
getting a free lunch show all the other algorithms value function based algorithms have is
linear dependence on state space this has no dependence on state space in fact this
descended make markov assumption cigarette lighters in the non markov setting just as well
as non is in the markov setting so you can do in continuous state spaces
and non markov settings all results hold
because it's exponential in horizon
the discount factor is very close to one then the horizon has to be very
deep and that of course can be a problem
and so what being cited inside here's the obvious monte carlo one right monte-carlo beach
coast dimensionality
could be
the role of a
but the the most
could i could have the freedom
and have a rule of law
no i
because the dimensions
right the dimension
or are they the room
if i may
just by the follow that example
if you it
rose by one of the main of with
i mean are really
one one-dimensional rose from one five
what's the matter
what they did know
so what know
look like that
the road freight line
one of the y one
what's wrong
we have
what he
one or two
one way
well one
what's the what's the point
the one that not only are
right now well they
and so
so four
line line three one one
so what do i know
but with all now
one of the
the more
so far all are
part three
will be
my goal is is
here main
the main problem is that all the
this is very
i like all
you may
so that
the way
and what
a function that associates to every possible realization that lot of this function is the
function of interest is approach
in fact
and the basic properties of probabilities
you should remember that every parameter between zero and one
for all x
in set
and the facts
and the sum of all probabilities of the province of all elements in the sample
just normalize
and why the talk about probabilities because
we want to do
with uncertainty that's the essence of using probabilistic and statistical because in real life
when he was the so that's all
but you
no inference problems
i wanted to really remember this slide because this is essentially two rules that always
in the following lectures
the first one is condition
it is the joint probability
XA and XB
it's difficult to go back to a given the times for
this is basically the initial conditional probabilities
this debate the definition of conditional probabilities
you have this caution
where p of x we should like
one is
so this is something you need to keep in mind
well then you can define conditional probability p of mexico next because name
this year
well still has the probability well
now if you have continuous variables you cannot conditions in an event will not be
single element because there is no matter what stated that
you need to conditional into
what's the you know what's the probability have one
o point eighty one centimetres
of high is
i cannot define because
that's an unmanageable so i mean the measure of sensitivity
so there's no problem
i can not far but that's
the thing of practice
the marginalisation mentioned
so if i want to compute the marginal probability of a given
support vector of my entire perspective
of bibles i just need some the joint probability p
for the viable over the remaining by
and then this is something that you really need to
two had in mind
i want to know if you would like me to go
a little bit more detail it is my position
let's assume i have
two events
i will also point
two times
the first of all quite
the officer quite
that around five
the first coin toss then the second
for the first going task
the first coin toss i can have
hands are still
but the second quite fast i can add
heads or tails
so i can have had had
heads tails tails heads tails
assuming that these two
random variables are independent
just past this kind here
and passing is quite
what's the probability of each one of these
the end
what's the probability of each one so my sample space
is equal to
had had
at the tail
they had
tales tales
i want to know
this is my
i want to know what's the probability of heads heads
the probability of heads tails
the probability of tails heads
the probability of tails there
is it could
how much
why is that because i'm assuming
i'm assuming two things i'm assuming that p
h is equal to one
that's just
one of the few t will be one as as well
because this is equal to one month
if you take
the first assumption
the second something
is that these two
i think that
OK so we have to this stage
now i asked the following question what's the probability
that he
equals two heads
what's the probability one is equal to
how do you know this
but have them
tell you what you need
this is what you
the last lecture of graphical models it essentially the lecture was learning
which is the topic of these
summer school
let's see how the learning graphical models that is the very basics of how you
let's go
so what let's try to recompute relate
what we have so far
so far we assume that we have a probability distribution p of x
and we were learning how to manipulate
that probability distribution computing we is computing marginal distributions of source
and we call the probabilistic inference engine computing marginals conditional distributions most likely populations
but of course the big question is what this p in the first place
how do get these probability distribution there's no
and joe or core god gives us is we need to figure out what this
should be from
from first principles
finding these
distribution is
basically do this by saying that collect that you observe the world look at the
we measure things and then you were out what model should be
and this gone learning
estimation are statistically
these are all seen
in the case of graphical models what we have
we have that our joint probability distribution
now i'm writing it explicitly as a function of
where theta will be some brown that we just according to some criterion
is essentially even as factorized
well these functions here
in the case of markov random fields they are just potential functions over the cliques
in the case of bayesian networks the conditional probability distributions of children given parents
this set as is the subset of the variables of interest
sort of SSL
non negative real valued functions
we can write this expression in different ways
if we exponentially this side
and take logarithms
we all think things expression
essentially we take the logarithm of these and then we exponentially so essentially would change
the expression just rewrite in a different way
which is this way he
so again
well it's defined here
g is defined here so just the lord
some of this is has a particular name
the model that saw
investigate called exponential families
so the subject of learning some
induction is basically the problem of
inferring a model from observations from the
this is
the most fundamental problem national this is the problem of machine learning statistics and you
observe the ending science in general because you will observe the world we observed that
you want to come up with the model that describes
the upper right
it's just that is this new to the machine learning because there's so much that
that you can not think of building interiors individually or a particular type of that
so you know from the process
he grew up to model
so you observe is that
i have samples the images are
text or whatever it is that these
and we assume that every
individual observations
it is a sample from the same unknown
assume that there exists a distribution on that space
of objects
and we assume that every observation is
independent samples
the typical assumption is not wholly assumptions
the there much
developing without assumption but for our purposes will make use of this which is a
reasonable case
and we assume
different samples are drawn from the same distribution
an independent
for example for tossing coin toss coin now we get heads and then we went
past another quite again
and we assume that the next time we toss the coin
experiment has nothing to do with the first six is independent
this is what we call IID setting independently and identically distributed samples
why this is important because
israel allows do
all the
the mathematics will be much easier to make assumption
and it's reasonable for
OK so
if a observe
number of
random variables that have the same distribution in the end
what's the probability of joint outcome
it's the product
of the probabilities of individual outcomes
because they are independent as we saw today the definition of
independence meeting and viruses basically when
the joint distribution can be factorized as the margin
but the model
the problem the model
the probability of
claim iraqi prisoners
now i think technically gambling is illegal
not because you know
i sense
OK i to play rock
i was very
the one
OK so you're not avoid
OK i think
it was one of the three
for every structured so the point is if you know i'm going to do about
i uses that you know question what i want for advice if i was playing
the sickly
you know how to be
so i think this is worth concurrent the
agents move at the same time
you want to randomized strategy so if you know if you've heard of national
the national
this is the case where i choose the strategy
if five sanity
it still wouldn't change what they do
and this is is in some sense of optimal for a concurrent turned so by
if i say i want to play
one third rock one to one-third scissors
and a player games does anyone think they can be the house
dispute purely randomly i just i i i relied on rule of hair dye
three sons
i roll roll solid iron and
so purely random
does anyone think in one hundred games that they can be found vampire
around thirty
the many many
a very large number of the y three
the village
OK so on on average enough games OK you can be the house if you're
playing one wonder wonder what researchers
and the thing here is that it takes a randomized play optimally when you have
so this something i think about security is inherently harder than than also in alternation
because concurrency game theory is game theory is another section of this
summer school and that cover game theory so if we see anything we ought alternating
so OK so in in we're actions
i said all actually need not be under control your opponent in the game contains
the state of the world
but you can also exaggerate events that are under some adversarial agent
but does under control say
OK so
random arrival person waiting for elevator OK no one knows trying to screw you and
and make exactly the people period the floor which make it policy for over the
words right in this arrive randomly
OK or piece of equipment industrial violent fails we usually felt
so when you have exogenous events due to nature
you can always model that randomness
and and and that that a lot more easily than you can adapt to the
remnants of other agents which are really trying to think about how you can act
and beach
so let me just recap
you know it's crucial this point i don't so we have these three centuries of
observations of actions as set of states OK
this is the fundamental to describing what the problem is solved
OK but
once i had this it's important to know how observations
mapped to states if i get noisy sensor reading here
the wall and here the wall
here the law
well over some time i can start to build some pretty their beliefs about where
in the world so interesting
vp as if i'm standing in place
you know if you if you buy average GPS receiver it you know you know
how to properly you know
one to ten meters of accuracy
like a car you can hear cargo yes
it works really really well
ponders what
carr GPS or
moving gps workflow better
stationarity vs
right so there are constraints that how you read that way you are
and brain and you can always get back to the road
he says you're taking samples in different places
OK i want to combine all these samples together they each give you some high
variance estimate of where you are but you average examples to reduce the variance of
the estimate
so it so if you have lots of observations over time to help help to
just two disambiguator state now i see the same place that same observation but the
air is always constant
roughly things in place but air differs
where i and by the end of that and i can deterministic more accurately
OK but it's crucial to have some idea of how higher observations might maps here
OK so i i find that the at the activation function in sec
the next thing is
you don't know the state but your actions do affect the state of the world
OK so it's crucial no higher actions attacker state OK it's not the function
so the activation function really states observations of another three cases of of their building
cover so you've got a non-zero problems OK i'm completely blind i can't hear anything
i can see anything i just have to get to the door
in nineteen five by writing something i don't know i don't feel
OK i don't get any observations OK
it's very hard problem but i i i i i like to go through life
you you know you go through life you want to be a good person
but you know you don't talk to god directly released i don't so you know
you could probably going to SNP
it was a good person do i get to you know i mean
he said yes and OK that's the only time that you actually get reward or
and so this is a non-zero case OK you don't get any feedback
their actions there are problems upon this category but not probably have sensors we do
we can actually see this in the world
OK so i'm going to focus on
it is the case where is for example that is we fully observed state's a
fellow backgammon go we fully see the board what's going on
OK so the drug bijection between states in the observation so that
the state our observations
so games are the clearest example i think of this
now a lot of problems i can say well
of services
x transpose the squared
on and that's the quality
two that
on and so this kernel
corresponds to the feature mapping phi x is equal to
on the right is now for the for the case of a course for you
but i i i i
and so with this definition of five acts
you can see five yourself that this thing
becomes the inner product between five and six
five he is given in a product between two vectors
it is you can just take some of the corresponding elements of the vector is
multiply them right so
if this is five x
then the inner product between five x five will be
so the sum
over you know all the elements of this vector times the corresponding elements of five
what you get the support
so the cool thing about this is that
on in order to compute five x
so you need
although square time just to compute
five x-ray if if and only if n is the dimension of actions even
five axis that is the vector of all you know pairs i guess of x
i x j most of each other
and so the length of five x is in square is always square in order
in square time just to compute five x
but to compute
but to compute the kernel function
all you need is all in time
because of
the kernel function is defined as xtrans fuzzy square c just take the inner product
between x e which is the order in times square that
you've computer
this kernel function
on and stage is computed the inner product between two vectors where each vector has
discrete elements
we did in his great time
the final wonderful thing
u on
so what about who
it's raise your hand this makes sense
so i'm just discover small says in terms of the slide just described a couple
of quick generalizations to this on
one is that if you
nine khz to be equal to
x transpose z plus c square so again you can compute this kernel
in order in time
then that turns out to correspond to a feature vector where on
i just added fuel to the bottom
we had to
not sure that those two CX one to c exterior to see three
and c
and so on
this is the way of creating a feature vector with both the multinomial meaning the
first order terms as well as the as well the quadratic or the inner product
terms between x one x i x j
and the parameter c here
on allows you to control the relative weighting between you know the monomial terms so
the first order terms
and the quadratic terms
and again this is still
the product between length vectors of length n scritti compute
in order in time
more generally here's some other examples of kernels on
generalisation of the one i described it would be the con
and so this corresponds to
all using you know and please do you choose d each
on of polynomials
monomials just means the product of x i x j x k this is just
all the polynomial terms essentially a to b