being able on the table or one ball against a wall
these ten balls on the table
those options were popular
having identified those possible options as as the first plane
i've been asked the question what shall advise you to do
well shall we say
if you want to get the most information
on average out if your first weighing maybe should put it the first weighing
so should be outcome the way has the biggest possible entropy
and what we are about to do now is go through each of those six
possible cases and work out what the entropy
the outcome
if you choose
for example way
six again six that's the first case we now discuss
let's backtrack and let's imagine
thatwe way sixty six
then the possible outcomes
when weighing six against sex
and this
so that's out and the probabilities these three outcomes anyone
half the
and that's the entropy about probability distribution
and we then we all half of talk about
end you get
let's make a little note that's somewhere if we do
six against six then the first outcome
one bit
by this five and very popular
but if we had gone with five against five
and what's the probability that it would
five and fought against five to
on the table
was probably a bad outcome
one six
one six why was six
okay so
it will bounce one of his book on the table is available
and that's to balls out of a total of twelve
so it's a two twelfth temperatures once
by symmetry remaining probability shared reading ten twelve s
equally between these
i itself
five fold that's
andy and
the outcome in this case
if we wait five five
i have worked out
you one point four eight
so sentences that gives you more information
curious that no one went
well that's get it well we could wait for or against four
if we way
all against four
what's the probability
that will balance
someone else
can someone
can just four twelve
it doesn't balance if wonderful book on the table
is they are all
and the remaining twelve split
so far this is
gives you the entropy all
the third
which is
no place to three
which is one point five eight
if we wait
against three
then what's the probability that balances we've left six on the table
what's the probability that at one of
okay so there must be a equal entity to these
when you look at the entropy
you get
times to
that's half times one
it is one point five
anselme fill in the remaining
that's the easy way to get to
then there is one point two five bits
if you're one against one
and is the point
something that could be done
if we believe in shannon just say well the entropy for these different possible
actions we could take
let's just go with the one that maximizes the information content and not what a sentence
this choice which
maybe after some fall
all you have
arrived at
right let's go ahead and go without choice
so we've got some balls now which we could say or possibly like possibly like right
but possibly having if this outcome
here occurs
what should we call these um
these are good models gene
that's when possible thing that could happen or possible outcome assuming way forward in four
the left side goes up
the right side goes down
we've got falls on the table which we now know good balls
so you'd like to make a suggestion it's got a bunch of suggestions and what we do next is this
would be outcome have a chance to enable
let's get some suggestions what we do next
we would like to suggest
we want against each other
okay so that way
goods against
possibly lights
okay suggestion and the two
the median of your suggestion
the prior probability of the missing attribute values that's one possible approach
so if
value if attributes are not binary
the question is
whether we should split
the training set into just two binary
subsets or into as many subsets as the advantages of the attribute it turns out
in the development of the system learning algorithm it was shown that it is better
to always split the node into
two some nodes
because the classification accuracy in that case will be higher but then the question is
of course which led us to put here in which there is a subset of
values here so these are all open questions which are
implementation details four different variants of decision tree learning algorithms
then some of these some training examples can be can not be classified they can
also be the situation that once you have split three
in two sub
sup notes that some ground can lead
to the so called null leaf with no corresponding training
in that case you again assign majority class
of examples into that not so these are all the different implementation details which have
to be taken care of in the particular implementation of
for decision trees that can conclude
so this would stop the stop the decision tree induction part
i wouldn't start to lead the rule learning part now but to would make a
small break
so it's
six o'clock we have one more hour to go if you survive
predictive data mining
so we said the predictive data mining is characterized by
the fact that we would like to build a model
which will enable prediction and classification
it assumes that the training data we have available is labelled by class labels
and we've seen the decision tree
approach to building
a classification model now we will see
the approach of how to learn a set of
we will
describe the rule sets representation and
one approach we have already seen
but in the decision tree and then converting it into a set of rules
other is
building rules direct
either building a set of rules or this the rules
and we have already met in the rules can be either
that would be a set of rules or that can be a list of rules
or ordered list of rules which is in the form of if then s
so one rule is built
after the other and there are also interpreted into if then else
you will also see some heuristics
we will also deal with overfitting the data and we will
i mentioned some pruning of the set of rules
so heuristics will be slightly different from the heuristics so we have encountered in decision
tree learning a decision tree this heuristic which we have encountered was take the most
informative attributes such that the entropy of the set will decrease as much as possible
OK now again we have the same representation of data which are objects characterised with
attributes and they are are labelled with this are different class labels
if we look at the decision tree learning versus learning of a set of rules
decision tree learning
performances follows suppose we have a binary classification problem with some
instances of labelled with plus the other labelled with class label minus
the decision tree learning approaches as follows
suppose we have just two attributes one
on x x is the other is on the y axis and then
based on supposed the most informative activities the one on the x axis
find a way of splitting the set into a sort of subsets
this subset and this subset
this is the clean subset
with entropy zero
so this would be one live
and then in the other subset there are still examples of both classes
suppose we take another attribute split based on the values of these other attributes in
the way that we get clean subsets just minus
examples on the one hand side and what the others
with the class plus the other side so this is also quite called the splitting
because we always
split the set of all instances into subsets
it is also
top down induction of decision trees and the representative of the algorithms is i'd three
in the rule learning
we are taking a different approach for every class
we are building a set of rules so suppose we first building a set of
rules for class plus
with the first rule
we will cover some positive examples
which means that with the rule the rule will be such that a summary
descriptions of the examples
are satisfied with the satisfy the conditions of the rules and then
those examples covered by the first rule will be eliminated from set the remaining
a set of examples remain and we will build another rule
for the class plus then the two classes will
change then we will start building rules for the other class and in this case
as is shown in this
simplified slide that will be just one draw four plus minds
this is called the so-called called covering approach because with a certain rule we want
to cover as many examples of the class for which we are building the rule
so it's the covering approach with and we are building the so-called characteristic descriptions of
in this way
we go into the user requirements and then we go into the development cycle to
what must be developing software has always because we are talking about application but the
fork is of course on semantics over ontologies that we have to develop
there will be green background lights and like that others the blue one about the
tutorial the green one idea about background knowledge so about introduction to the semantic web
RDF technology and so far so those of you
that's why i'm not too
really interesting to you again and again the same basic topics can keep all the
green one so you can write emails and things like that during the green light
fixtures code is available you can download it and play with beautiful like it's for
free and you can just do whatever you like with it i'm not sure if
this is the last version here but that we make sure that the last version
is published by many cases there will be something here which is running
what's the semantic web so the greens lights according to the needham and i took
this life from him the semantic web is a way to address the very interesting
topics of the web is just a
it's time for humans so basically you have
this natural language pages plus many more media content and what you do
is tried to get an answer from the web by deducing faster creating mental situation
in using your experience and understanding of the pages to derive the information which is
needed to solve your problem
and in the end this is quite easy for humans even if you're a person
with disabilities but my not being that it's so easy
the problem is that
we always
merge information that comes from this finding pages
so we're not going to have to find the page and read it through and
that the answer no money the point is we go on one website we collect
some data using the knowledge that we call we go to another website with people
searching and bring in knowledge together in order to solve the problem we do that
when we organize it rather using the beautiful travel agency
then i will tell bookings solution and then train solution forth full of course is
done in many other cases like digital libraries for instance
and i mean this is
the easy because we are humans and we know how to do it and
the point is always is that we cannot expect the machine to do the same
because basically it's
so so difficult for a machine to work with partial information so you get a
couple of four from there are couple of from that you know a lot
are you able to derive the results but machine can not work like that
it is very difficult to make sense of multimedia for instance in image
if you have a very fancy will maps images useful for us but almost useless
for life
and then there is the program of drawing analogies this problem of linking information from
comes from two different sites if this is very very difficult it's difficult for us
to exactly know what we are
understanding and if it's really a link it's very difficult for much just to make
concrete is these stuck here so creative is same as another cut down the
how to yes of course and then they are the same word but values into
different XML schema maybe they mean the same maybe not what does it happen if
we believe that means the same
people are good at this machine so
going back to to our music event explorer what's the point
as i said the application is designed to sort of put to rest the user
need and the need is basically
to know which events are around the world about the given music style so i
don't want to
really to go to an event about one very famous artists
it's more and more in the mood to to know about events close to me
but i'm about to a given music style and i don't really care about the
performer i mean i do care but the point is given that i don't know
all the performance of the given music style especially for very unique music studies but
i like what kind of music i would like to know which events are out
there but are about this music style
and to do that what you do is really to go on the web and
then perform several tasks that we want to be is application next to do for
you so we want to the
application to find all the artists that play forty stands for music
so you go on database where you have the information about the artist and size
and you ask your creating
place for music and you got back a bunch of bands and artists that play
is this this time when you have is a bunch of artists so what you
want to do normally is to understand what they are so you go to a
database music archive
you could ask for each artist
what we did with the they for you have what rocks all their info about
them and when they are born with without from things like that
and then we all these very
good bunch of information
this is not just the static prediction problems but in fact this this predict there
will be in the big blue and it'll help decide
its own training data but because it will decide which ads actually get displayed and
then those will get click that will be fed back into the predictor so
we need some means of exploration
because of if we only ever show those ads that we already know are good
we were not ever find the opportunities for the for the interesting ones you can
see here how the how our probability over the probability of click beetle like probability
distributions can help us do that because we can for example instead of just taking
the expected peak click we can sample p clicks from these distributions so that in
this particular case
and here
is already a fairly established low variance probability of click here
which is greater than the one for this thing but this and will have the
chance of sam pling
p clicks that will be bigger than for this one so in fact we will
be able to collect information about it which in turn will reduce our belief variance
for it and so we can explore the entire pool of ads that we have
is the training work we know how this forward model works now
but we need to understand how we actually update the those weights
here's his the factor graph the basically does it we have belief distributions here and
and then
we view this as a message passing algorithm here so the messages come from the
prior go down are combined into the sum
a score through the nonlinearity and give us some kind of prediction
and i
of course when we observe either no click all the click event
that message flowing the other way around we get an updated belief distribution for this
quantity here and that is then distributed to these weight here
and the important effect here is
that a weight which already had a fairly small variance in its prior will only
receive a small update
and the way that will that has brought the variance in the prior will receive
the bigger so we'll have that assignment of responsibility so to speak to those ads
where we're all those features were really certain
here the update rules in detail
and if we quickly go through them because i think there are actually quite quite
elegant because they're are closed for you don't have to view it as as the
message passing so we basically collapsed the messages i was showing before and now this
is basically the closed form
and so this is the update equations for the mean of a feature weight i
and this is the update equation for the variance of weight i
and so the first thing is we see that this is an additive update here
for the mu
and the update is the scaled by the variance of the weights as you would
expect a very big you take big update step small small update step
the similar construction here this is a multiplicative update for the sigma
for the sigma square
and again the sigma i scored the old one act as scaling parameter is a
step size parameters you like
so that accounts for the fact that
weights with larger variance are updated more than weight smaller variance
and now we have these terms here
these functions here and they
basically encode the fact that if this some of the weights of the use of
the weights was negative
we're on this side here then there would be some kind of surprise we observed
click this is the these are the updates for the click event but the system
predicted no click so then we'll have a big update here
whereas if we if this one is already positive then we only have a small
so they all this comes out of an analysis of approximate bayesian inference using expectation
these are basically the the updates rules that we're using and now we can look
a little bit of what the what type of parameters come out of this
for example here we're looking at all the weights of the client IP client p
can be interesting the client APP can be interesting because it tells you about particular
users for example above maybe using a particular client IP so you want to know
that would be very good in explaining why the is always clicking or never clicking
you can see here that in fact this feature alone allows us to find local
these are probably bots that never click
and these are high clickers that will click with very high probability
and we also relayed this information to of fraud department because click clicks by clearly
on anything you want to charge customers for
and something that was very into important for us
it was to have a good calibration
and so
we were looking a lot of these calibration plot so what this basically is the
plot of the predicted probability of the first the empirical probability of click where of
course the empirical probability of think we can only get if we have
if we have some binning going on here so this is basically just pinning this
line here into one hundred or in this case maybe a thousand bins
and looking at all the impression seeing what prediction we make for them to decide
which been they end up here and then averaging for those bins what the empirical
probability of click was and you see here that this is a very nice to
calibrate system
which is not always something that you would automatically expect for example if you're using
a naive bayes classifier instead you will see alot of over prediction
going on here because those features will be highly correlated sometimes that you have inputs
and then you will have double counting in the in the naive bayes
so just to wrap up
one of the system gives as in production is an automatic learning rate per feature
it is highly calibrated which is very desirable q one charge your customers based on
on this estimate
we can use a lot of features even if they are correlated because we have
the the fact that in an update the presence of features are taking into account
by the updates are not assume independence and conditional independence in base
we model the uncertainty explicitly and the cost for that is basically since we assume
diagonal prior just twice as many parameters because instead of just waits we have the
means and variances for the weights and it turned out that that was what the
really good decision to enable these other things
it also gives us this natural exploration mode where we can really explore the pool
of ads in this dynamic system where the predictor is in the loop and decides
its own input data
aggression males
i mean i'm summarizing means not a technical term as females and in males are
more physically violent
there are more violence in the room in utero
there are more violent as children
and the more violent as adults
this is not to say
that you can find violent women
or nonviolent issues on average there is this difference became more
males kick more
in the uterus
i'm as children are more involved in play fighting and violence
combat like sports and as adults wherever you go
you will find prison
and wherever you go
you will find that prisoners mostly philip full of men
they are far more likely to kill one another and to harm one another male
sex hormones test by testosterone
artists or not the sort of thing one would want to inject and somebody
unless you want them to turn kind i mean
if they increased aggressiveness both in humans and other primates
what about sexual choosing this
two male humans and female humans differ
the extent to which
they will
favor anonymous sex
this is relevant from an evolutionary perspective because the parental investment theory predicts males should
be more receptive to anonymous sex because
four males
to impregnate somebody else
fortuitously lead to another offspring
it may be good for you
and doesn't carry the sort of
the females and then have very picky
because they have to choose carefully
remember these systems evolved before both birth control
and vasectomies and so on
so what do we know cross culturally and psychologically well
is a universally
near are near universally male
there are male prostitutes of course
but contrary to some
various fantasies and sitcoms they cater to male customers
pornography is a human universal
everything in every society
males have done some sort of depictions
the naked females for the purpose of arousal often a card them into trees
or to sort of sculptures
one of the weirdest findings in the last decade or so
is that extends as well the monkey points
and so
some scientists to set up a situation where monkeys could
fruit is by giving up through to look at the picture either the females hindquarters
or of a celebrity monkey
the socially dominant market
some sort of a combination of people magazine penthouse
and so there's some interest in this even by non-human primates
what about actual preference for sexual right
you can get this in different ways
there is what biologists describe
as and the coolidge effect of this here
and the coolidge effect is based on president calvin coolidge
and it's a story about calvin coolidge and his wife
who being shown around the separately
and the person showing around his wife pointed out
that there was a lot of hands she she noticed that there's a lot of
hands but only one was
and she yes the guy showing around is one renowned
i said well you know
the rooster to work very hard to resist sex dozens of times a day
and and she said well we should tell elected president
the story goes
president went around that the guy tells the story to the president
the present master has sex dozens of times each day
same hand every time
this is no different and every time he says tell it to missus coolidge
now there's two responses to this sort of story
and what kind of negative with it will everybody knows
males prefer anonymous sex with strange when the
other responses
that's sexist claptrap
you might think you might be email and say that's not me
you might know males and say the males i know i like that
so how do you find out what is indirect measures such as who go to
but is also fairly direct measures one fairly direct merger is used as people
an anonymous surveys
so in fact give you some anonymous surveys are not as people use disaster
so so
so for instance
i want everybody to consider this question
how many sexual partners you want to have in the next months
what is coming up to april
how many sexual partners you want to
to see
the next two years
think many through graduation
when you leave you only one i had x sexual partners and that's what i
your lifetime
we get people to answer these questions professor china
last year in this course had clickers got people than now
do it we are not so high tech soldiers do it in our heads
but here's the way the answers come out
women say less than one next month that doesn't mean they want
less than one it means many of them is that many of them say zero
some say one and so on
forty five
you can ask other questions
from this population to seagrass
when you have sex with the desirable partner you have now so really desirable
for a year
women say i
yes six months and sure we less now
well many we get a majority
going down
two to five minutes
this all q and a pen and pencil sort of things
some grave scientists have actually done experiments
and in one experiment
i don't you know this is sort thing which you probably wouldn't do nowadays is
more than ten years ago we have an incredibly attractive man incredibly attractive woman
and they approached people on campus
not from campus to actors brought
and they go to people to strangers and they say
what's the easiest way of actually finding a maximum
easier than doing hill climbing
that's that's what we were that
that's we worked out but sort of the the principle we used was said to
equal to zero
let's say OK
d by
debated j of log conditional likelihood equals zero
you know maybe will be able to solve this equals zero may we won't
what do we get
we get
so this is some of the i
of why i minus p i
x i j
so we get
some of the i
y i x i j
because some of the i
here i x i j
remember this is over the training data
and why is the training labels
and then the PRI's
the predictive probabilities for the
training examples
this equality is going to be true
for the trained model
y equals
training labels
p i
predicted probabilities
by the
fully trained model
somebody explain so in intuitively what it's saying
that the that this equals the sum
this is
this is the sum of all training examples
this is the sum of all the training examples so
this is not really saying anything about any individual training examples
it is only saying something about the training set
so what is it saying about the training set
here's my
interpretation it was a so
take any feature xj
total value in the training set
for the positive examples
so here
we're taking any feature xj
and then was summing over the training set would not have nine y y i
so we really only summing
some of the ice such that y equals one
x idea maybe
this is
most informative way of writing so the sum over the whole training set the sum
of all the positive training examples x i j
is the sum of all the training examples
of x i j times p i
yes so this is the
expected value
where the expectation is according to number
and this
it's a
x this is a
so the
the peas
the the
predicted probability to get the training set
that that typically they're non-zero every training example
they have to spread themselves out so that each feature
the the average value of that feature for the positive examples is the same as
the weighted average value
that feature for all the examples
using the predictive politics as the weights
his special case
some of
i such that y equals one
x y zero
some of the i
PRI times x i
and what we say x i zero equals
yes this ties in a little bit with what you're talking about
getting more users getting more people involved
i will talk so much about the details of what octave can do
you know features that has because you can go and downloaded around it and find
out for yourself
as before start though
how many people here use matlab how many people are more familiar with mental abnormalities
and how many people have you
so almost as many or more
OK well that's that's good enough
so a brief discussion of the history of octave
discussion of ways we might expand the community of developers and then discuss some some
of the challenges for the future of the project
but if i also
think some people who have made octave possible
the first is jim rawlings use my thesis adviser texas and and my is also
been my supervisor for
the last sixteen years and he he secured nearly all the funding to
employ me to work on active from that time so i'm really grateful
after had him as an adviser and someone who is a champion of active all
this time
all the volunteers who have worked on octave over the years there's no way it
would have been as successful as it is without them
and then i also have acknowledge
the canoe project richard stallman because that was my introduction to free software
and without that i don't think i would have become interested in
producing free software on my own
so what this is that
three system for numerical computations mostly compatible with matlab at the syntax level doesn't have
a fancy IDE
although some people don't like that very much anyway so i don't know if it's
a big loss
it does most of these things and more
in the last few years it's it's really changed quite a bit is does the
the number of people working on has really
can increased and i've seen a lot more activity and
for example
on this list of all these things
an emotional raise sparse matrices
mister the control theory functions on the improvements in graphics signal processing image almost all
these things are things that other people have done
and i things that i wrote
and that was true
i guess the first four five years working in october i was
if you look back in the change logs
my name
all the time
and that was not a very good model for developing a project like this
there are some reasons why that happened on going into a little bit
so why would you want to use active well there's no license manager is free
software so you can put it anywhere
black boxes so you can look at everything not just the
m files
you can look at
how do we do
you know
how do we solve linear equations
down to the level of
you know you know they say in in malabar uses was but you don't know
exactly what they do
before they call the hours routines are how they call an output sequence happens so
that portable opposing systems with standard c plus plus compiler so you can put it
any kind of system reported to mobile phones
there is a large support community and
it's it's growing more or less although
australia applied in one of the
we'll see if that trend will continue
i not
set out to write
alan clone
that's that's how it happened but
i started to write some software
my supervisor jim rawlings wanted to use as
software to go along with the textbook was writing
we this is about nineteen eighty nine
we started talking about this
at that point we were four can users
so we thought well we could write some fortran routines
target mapping shipment this get stuck in the back of the book
after thinking about that for a while we decided that that was not going to
be successful we saw other people try that
and the students can use the software it was worthless to them
and and we knew people who had started use mallory time and it seemed like
an easy system to use so we thought well maybe we can do something like
that it wouldn't be
now i have it would be sort of like it we we could distributed to
OK so this is the tutorial
so it's not just my material on presenting and it's on looking at a class
of models which can deal with recognition of object classes
and i'm going to cover
material from
myself but also
from other groups that focus group she
shimon ullman OK
in terms of objectives the get this work is to be able to recognise visual
like for example this motorbike which is the visual class
and in particular
ten is designed to be able to work from what's called semi unsupervised learning or
define what these two things are so
it means here
being able to identify the object class for example that it's a motorbike or a
plane or a person
and also as well as identifying what classes there
specifying the location coarsely
OK so here you see
the cars
the region of interest which is the car inside
in this talk i'm not going to go this far
and segmentation so this part of the bottom here
we're not demanding that we're demanding that the recognition method exactly gives the alpha matter
the object that's not necessary here
what we want is a rough localisation of the objects
semi unsupervised learning what that means is that the island and learned from a set
images which have been
objects in them in this case faces
that's all the information is provided a set of images which has the object in
them and then a set of what's called background images where the object is not
and in the training images here the
the position of the object is specified nor the features OK so the idea is
to learn from this type of data
that's what we by semi unsupervised
so here some of classes will be talking about
you look at the columns here
you see motorbikes airplanes faces
cars side cars rear spotted cats and some background images
now one thing to notice is that the cars went about cars objects which we've
got cars here twice because
the album so far
we have to have
a different recognition systems for the various visual aspects of the side of the car
the rear of the car
they can be recognised separately for the moment
because this is significantly different
OK now why is so difficult problem people aren't really computer vision people here these
are the typical vision things one has to do with have size variation you see
the cars here here very small or very large
so due perspective size variation
background clutter that's all this stuff which is the
OK that has to be that we don't know what's the foreground object which is
the background objects
also this partial occlusion here for example
so the object class were interested in might not be completely visible
and the key thing we have to deal with this is this intraclass variation
we're not looking at the same object were looking at a class of objects going
down the columns
now the class of model i'm going to talk about this troilus is what's called
a pictorial structure
this originated back in the early seventies
and is the schematic of the idea you have parts
the object surface this was the face should have hair
mouth eyes nose
that's one aspect of these parts which are going to turn out to be two
d image fragments
and then you have spatial relationships between these parts of the two component parts and
their spatial organisation configuration of these parts
that's what has to be learned
this class model very successful in the past five years also because i just recently
this class models being combined with learning techniques that's made it sufficiently powerful to recognise
all these different visual classes
and as you'll see
the reason it's powerful is it captures what's meant by visual class his
a few examples of the car
and we can identify things which in common this is
front wheel
the top of the windscreen
this is what this is defining what's in common between these instances of the car
and there are two things i had to see
if you if you try to put these in correspondence you've got the part like
this like mapping to this light
and you got the spatial configuration of these parts of the these three parts occur
in the same spatial configuration because that's what's capturing the visual class
and what you see is that you can build some generalisation into the definition of
parts and into the definition of this of the structure
one of the advantages of these parts methods is that
it allows
as you can see certain you can
controls defamation OK so a and b here
we would say faces
c and d are not and maybe we can learn this information what constitutes a
by having these parts rather than the global model
and what noise was and say to yourself philosophically what is it is it something
that is independent
non this definition this could be dependent areas
it's actually i think
for me the best definition noise is it
the piece if your system
that you're not counting poriginal
now very often we then assume it's independent because we can't do much if we
don't assume is independent we still have to do some more modelling the noise but
i think it's a nice when you think about the physics side of things
these are the bits in the system you are interested in and these are the
bits in the system you're not interested in yeah
that's one way of thinking about noise not saying is the only way it's probably
not the original definition noise because the way i like to think about noise
so the problem solved by sampling
these these values from some distribution and the person thought about this so much with le plus
but class and the class
i believed
so the maximum entropy like idea
solar plants
so instead what if i don't know something
i should assume is uniformly distributed
and that's kinda reasonable assumption that's actually this maximum entropy textile assumption
and it's great but it doesn't work very well on continuous systems so that apply
this discrete systems like coin tosses it applied to
justify his choice prior
and we feel justified prior distributions in his in bayesian inference
uh ceases about and i'm going assume uniform now people can argue against this assumption
there are many arguments against it but it some
however it is this principle of least
something rather
can't remember it's he
it's a reasonable thing to do and it's effectively what maximum is doing it problematically
though you can't assume uniform distributions across
uh infinite spaces
so he spent an enormous amount of effort trying to build
what they call error functions
which reflected these types of ideas that they will heavy tailed are functions they had quite complex forms
he said he said well it should be uniform across this interval and uniform across
this interval and spend a lot time constructing these things very difficult and when he
got them
beating them to data with virtually impossible because he just had a pen and paper
i guess is if it whoever it is whichever lower frenchman
he invented squares he comes along and says that minimize the squared error
and actually doesn't motivated from the error function point-of-view
why gauss is known for the calcium is all he does is plug these two
ideas together class if the error function man that says this is the principle what's
going on
the other frenchmen if they
person algorithmically is a reasonable way of doing it and gal says okay if you
make the error function this form the calcium
then you get least squares now ironically in gasses paper he does nothing to justify
the choice over a function other than saying
if you to error function you get least squares and we know least squares works
well so this must be good error function so it's still a circular
argument and of course i think it's plastic produces one of the earliest versions of
the central limit theorem which is the real
so the physical justification as to why this might be true
if you have a bunch of errors as long as there very limited and additive
you will eventually have a guassian air so that's a good at a reasonable justification
and gas in noise model i
and it
it's the plants that first arrives the
in distribution in the context bayesian inference
it's placid that doesn't notice that it's a sensible distribution forearm we are finally comes
up with the concept that the error function
and it's class
demonstrates in effect why the gas might be an error function
but we still call the distribution gaussians
and the class gets back one which is just the absolute value two things which
no one even knows called class in the
this shows you
you can't win them all
the importance distribution similarly using exactly the same reasoning and what i've done at the
time to you come up very close your question for the importance which is important
for the time and its importance weight at time n minus one time what i
call these increment or importance weights
that's it
so to summarize essentially the i is the kind of an important sampling type techniques
so as to approximate
the sequence of target distribution pi and on the associated to a normalizing constant palsied
as follows
five someone is so important capital
particles called a random sample so i here goes from one to capital and capitolhillmom
sample according to involve the distribution q on all the computer associated importance weight okay
for this expression
the following time index OK
when you have time and the only thing you need to do
is you need to solve for the component xn according to conditional distribution two and
which can be dependent on the past values of simulated before x one x two
x minus one on this thing something you pick up this is the degree of
freedom in your arteries of what you do want to solve all xn you have
data associated importance weight which is emerging which basically correct for the discrepancy between the
target on the the importance distribution
so essentially any time
you have essentially a collection of capital and one them so important distributed according to
the part of the solution to an on you have also the associated importance weight
so when you are once you've got basically those guys OK
then you can obviously
approximates the target distribution
by using one of the average of the unnormalized importance weight
o and you can approximate basically the target distribution of interest
but basically the weighted
convex combination
of the
that i don't like mass
which have been sampled according
two two in case
that's it this is what we've been doing so we have no boundaries
basically it was an important sampling is which is very glad to be obviously power
lies very easily
all provide us we've essentially multicolour estimate of the target distribution of interest on z
of the knowledge society normalizing constant so not obviously if you were to use that
in the real world applications
OK well
since she's going away because what i've been doing is that just basically
implemented importance sampling
in potentially high dimensional space because as an increasing basically
the dimension of the target distribution increases OK
well i told you about something i dimensional space it typically violence of the estimate
increases exponentially fast with the time in the show
because the algorithm implementing is just a very specific chase of importance sampling where i
use destructive structure sorry importance distribution i can expect to bypass this problem so that's
basically what i've been doing here i've been basically using the sequential importance sampling ategories
so as to approximate
target distribution the posterior distribution
in the state space model is a stochastic volatility model which
so this is an example that describe
yesterday it's summer of it relevant to our problem but
assume you're interested basically an approximating
the posterior distribution
of the campaign for all states
of the state space model given the first observation on assume use essentially the sequential
importance sampling ategories then what you will be observing when you're on this side is
is that after a very few times step then you're gonna have
essentially the normalized which was results such that essentially one of them full set index
i zero is very close to one or the other one
four g from fuzzy very close to zero on that's coming from the fact this
is the normalizing parliament that's coming from the fact that the violence of the unnormalized
importance weights is increasing over time so if you look at what i've displayed is
the nice to one essentially
the log of the normalized importance weight at the very first time index it's fine
importance something is no i mentioned it works kind of OK
the time index dimensional point increase so if i try to approximate the posterior distribution
of the fifty first state given the fifty first observation i see that essentially the
the histogram of the much more to disperse on basically if you basically any or
all of this is what you would upset say for a lot of the normalized
importance weights it means that if you go back to detect the exponential of these
changes but it doesn't have to be fixed
i could change my external pressure
the whole process and that's the we talked about the last being very important defining
the path
right so
we're my pressure
is changing
and i can go directly from
this large volume to the small i have to go in little steps
infinitely small steps
so instead of writing
the the negative of external turned out to be
i'm going to write
why this extra
this depends on the path and
on pattern is change as the change
i'm going to add a little thing here i'm going to put it will
all right here
o bar here means that this
dw that i'm putting it here
is not
the french what i mean
i mean that by taking into rule
of this to find out
how much work
i've done the system
i need to know the
that's what this means here
it's not enough to know
the initial state
in the final state to find w is
you also need to know
how you got it
this is very different from the from the functions of state like pressure and temperature
is the volume the temperature the pressure here
this the volume temperature and pressure here corresponding to the system here
and the bottom temperature and pressure doesn't care
how you got there
it is what it is
it defines the state of the system
the amount of work you put in to get here
depends on the it's not a function of the
it's not an exact differential so that
delta v here's an exact differential but this w is now
that's going to be really important
right so if you want to find out how much work done the integral
from the initial state to final state
twenty two
and you got to know what the pattern
so let's look at this path dependence
going to do
two different
see how the different
in terms of the work
ideal gas we can assume that it's idealistic are going forward
noninteracting gas
you do put compression
they are gone
with a certain
gas pressure one by one
in the final state oregon
he two
where v one
is greater than two
so if i draw this
on the PV diagram
it's this certain degree ofconditional independence here so you can do some multivariategaussian
updatesor in A and lambdathe dimension not more than a number of factors
so this this thisgoesquite well this thissix minuteson a laptop
about thisterrible oldlaptopI've got here andyou knowit was a few years ago
in fact when you when youconditionall sorts of thingsthat are fixedthe data
and somefixed hyperparameters these are the variableswe're having to update and it'sfairly
easy to organize theorganize thecomputationI'll just talk about a few issues
one oneproblem you always have with thefactor analysis is the
consequences of this lack ofidentifiability you know cause your're basically modelling X
as a product oftwo things that you don't know so youhave this you have some trading off
I've already talked about the variances and otherssort ofgeometrical degree of indeterminancy is
that if you have a rotation matrix in there than the model doesn't change if
you post multiplyA by R and pre multiply lambda by our inverse ofcancels out
actually that's true for any nonsingular matrixA R but in particular if you use a
rotation matrix it doesn't eventhe prior structure you know the the rotation ofmultivariate gaussian
with sphericalit's still asphericalgaussian so the rotation isn't evenidentified inthe Bayesian
analysis where we have we have priorssothere's some care needed and
we we've adopted various strategies essentially do withrotating aback to a standard
orientation to to to assist thingshere asmallerdimensional class oftransformations are leaving
under variantparticular case of rotationiswhatI callwe calla sign permutation
matrix so simply swapping the labelsalso the factorsand possibly reversingtheir sign that
those were examples ofof anonsingularR reflectionsand rotationsthat you need to look at so
it havebeen various devices used to to combat thatand what we do is to monitor rotation
and essentiallywe we use linear algebratototo sort ofstandardize the rotation
to to a standardviewsensitivity analysiswhat wedid we did
a big sensitivity analysisand I'm now gonna showa little bit of a herein particular
we cared about various aspects of this model those here I'm gonnatalk about the
variancesbut we also looked at sensitivity to the mixture parameters sowe've got thatmixture
model for thefactor loadingso that was something we do hereso the
the nonhierarchical version of this would put the inverse variances for the factor loading whenit's not
zero the variable J and and thethatL have thissort of
structurenotice index only by the factors soagain we're borrowing strength across the
variables within factors
and you can takefixed values of alpha and betathere and you you you
you you get something but then we we found variousboth numerical
but more importantly inferentialproblems have beeninterpreting inferentia inferencethat led us to
to question thatand so we thought welooked ata we look at the
hierarchical prior where thebeta turned the scalepart of that gamma has a has agamma
distributionand thisjustgive you some idea of how things change so this is
this visualizesthe factor loadingsundertwo different prior settings in the
nonhierarchical priorthese these are the values offactor loadingand how it shows
how they changewhen yougo fromone priorspecification to the other and theseare
freedomof factorsandso really quite big changesI meand asa as agraphical
wayof demonstrating the the knock-on effecttwo levelsfor thedown inthe hierarchy of this
change in the hyper hyperparameterswhereasin thehierarchicalsetting is much lessmuch less
sensitive so this is commonly found if you if you put you know if you putthe
the certainity on further one levelfurther away from the datathen you get lesssensitivity
that's just a small anecdote if you like aboutsensitivity and answers thet the the now the big
issue andone that we haven't solved is the whole question of model choice
so if Iwas listeningto myselfanhour ago andIwould now put aprior on
thebasically on the sparsitya structural prior of sparsity which allowed me to choose between
all right so now you have some understanding of the kinds of problems are interested
in solving and you have some understanding of the algorithms that we might use if
we had to actually make the prediction once the model but now let's spend the
rest of the time talking about learning
and when these models are gonna come from
OK so we've seen a bunch of the
OK so
a little more notation i'm going to refer to use told us to remind you
things are training data and that's when the test and although i i realize what
i was going over my slides almost never talk about the testing given here just
assume you have some and remember that are white so the
they didn't come from god
they came from they came from some people
who shows conventions that are up for debate and then they they are they pay
people to to mark down those conventions on real data and those people who wrote
down the conventions may have been lazy or may not agree on may have many
valid disagreements and so on so none of our data are perfect never ever assume
that are perfect
OK i'm going to bring back the loss function is kind of important for learning
l is going to be a a way of measuring the cost if i make
a prediction y but the correct answer is why starting give three arguments just in
case it's important to look at what the input was so why
the first why there is that is what i guess the white stars the correct
you know most machine learning algorithms that go going trying trying to model for us
we're only talking about linear models today but when we want to go to train
some kind of model we want to minimize
the loss of the training sample
and maybe add some term penalizes highly complex models and so this is this is
sort of maybe this doesn't cover everything but it covers a lot of things
there's been an awful lot of effort in machine learning and trying to make a
loss function using training look like the evaluation function that we care about on the
testing that we expect to do best if we can actually optimize loss
in the way that we're really going to measure it
nlp makes this really hard
so the the first thing is that the loss functions are usually very vague in
ill-defined i want to translate better i want to write better summaries i want to
generate better text or i want to pass better about passing maybe is a little
better but i want i want to correctly represent the meaning of the sentence
people don't agree about loss functions for a long time for a period of about
five years there were several papers year just on evaluating machine translation systems it was
an active area of research often we care about more than one thing classic case
of this is precision and recall we want both the things we recovered to be
correct but also we want to recover but we want to recover all the correct
things and sometimes you can have one without the other
often measuring measuring the loss function we really care about is is expensive because it
requires us to embed our models in real system and go you know through the
system and in the world or pay people to pretend to use it to use
it and see how well you know how well things work and you know the
differences you get when you change your part of speech tagger in some kind of
dialogue system may be very very very small hard to measure
we're always fighting over these things they change frequently and often they require people as
i mentioned before so if your evaluation requires you to higher thirty undergraduates to come
in and use it a piece of software
you're going to think very carefully about when you do that evaluation
OK more often though
for these reasons people tend to focus on intrinsic intrinsic measures of the quality of
a particular NLP model so we're tagging you can count the number of words wrongly
tagged chunking you can use maybe one minus one four different run types are passing
we often use sort of precision recall measures we want to minimize the number of
incorrect phrases in a parse tree or incorrect attachments of words there's an ocean of
precision recall for reference as well
we really rather see how these affect things in real systems
but for the purposes of making progress on modules in natural language processing and because
that's expensive we often settle for these kinds of loss functions
OK so the first thing to talk about
for structured prediction is the use of generative models
this was sort of
until maybe two thousand one or so this is pretty much what most people were
so the idea is that you are going to define some kind of stochastic process
that produces
the the cross product is texas script with different probabilities and we're going to use
maximum likelihood or maximum a posteriori estimation to choose the parameters of that of that
model and usually in NLP this means a hidden markov model or probabilistic context free
grammar or something very much like that
so the challenge of course
is that if you have some ideas if you if you want to start with
feature based you that i for when i talked about decoding and go to design
a generative model
the producers the data
like this you would have a really hard time the rules if you want if
you want to well well-formed generative model for which maximum likelihood estimation is going to
be straightforward you really want to make sure that you predict each piece of structure
in your output y exactly once and no more
and you really want to make sure that you know you you i guess that's
sort of the key rules so i'll give an example of this in the second
if you do it that way then then you can use very simple estimators that
just involve counting and normalizing although there are extensions that allow you to deal with
general features most predominantly this is a generative models work so so here i'm going
to go through what happens when an HMM generates a sequence and show how each
piece of structure history once we start at the start state and then in the
next round we we've randomly chosen the first the first eight y one and then
that model of course it's easy to proves that the age of 3 days of
motor function and if which which of the nice the but of course again at
the computer educated explicitly because if you want to conclude that you to compute injured
on done well to integrate with respect 55 but what you do is that you
are you you will lose Mr. Cosic approximation type of Corazon which means that you
can look at exists in Centennial system it as a noisy observation of age
of the decade in which you suggest suggested that laws so that that's too good
them to justify promises about is we still what you do is is that you
that digitization I wouldn't you in the year
my metropolis testing and poisoned
it's also just starting from game I do proposal according to do
identical once Patrick's budget by Beijing decade next thereby will exit the reject according to
exist probability and then because I want to implement my us couple commission posted here
I will choose now the skating of my egoism into June discarding of categories and
I we're computer decade exists so
and which is compatible with the weather and so before so is positively converged on
the average to Zoo routes
because all the other in the limits if every single word loses quantity will converge
XKA would be decision or a gym a Hideki we also converge sources was quantity
things and it would be a kind of doses of this
average over the decision we expected except in the case of that's what they called
a control top without poisoning which included the type of idea what to do with
it which is says the idea of trying to use the past simulation in order
to be able to adopt your glories as it is of course the simplest you
can imagine I would try to convince you that is of argument can be extended
to more general fatigue to just 2
To CLT it works so here he said it's so that's a metropolis of Gorazde
use about him scaling solos a skating which has been computed from optimizing the few
times the previous models and for that mobile and here's this citizens in the talk
was of course somewhere you learn Aziz skating during his arrest and considers it so
it's it's a pretty it's a pretty it works pretty nicely given it dimensions of
isn't it when we image large will stay in a reasonable cost
looking time flights like arrow ask so now all you can extend this uh soars
as the
you have said that the is very this extremely important is not general all because
you would pretend that you want to see it for distribution is the product of
ethics Eisler affairs in a recession
it is the less you that you want to target distribution is is not something
that exists that something which can be read and exist it's just transforming reality X
according to the inverse of this magic signaled the end biology is is a product
of the bonds which appear to have that kind of Candida symmetry here is it's
not generals crucified him most of them
is more general than the previous models later when you can analyze this is realized
by the Republican are very recently by a student of business shouldn't of Jeff frozen
pork homeland Utah which may be reduced to this topic and very very nice dozens
and she proved that the acceptance rate is still viewed 0 adults to free for
which seems to be robust number but a share
the shares that the the achievable marginal speedy strongly affected by a signal so and
sure assumes that you propose according to Swedish you do distribution is is the target
distribution business and is now exists and cause according to move which are still according
to their identity Maddox than the westernmost loss improve loss which is linked with the
Commission on the world's this covert tricks but cancels its use rather obvious that opposes
calls for what I call in which dimensional scaling which was the cause of which
were originally proposed by Ottawa and tax man
and legal exists
but they analyzes of poisoned with totally different in a way which is the very
different which is whether they did not obtain the type of results
it and will exist as AD when you have them and insincere egoism with
coolers that again became the target be as this type of behavior are what you
do you should propose you should put according to an introvert distribution which is a
Z Z is a distributed demarcate with a simple violence and the tiger distribution admitted
like getting guns
and the skinny goes that should be so what you wear of called director-general is
not known so what we read
split off certain common endings of words so for example important might not to import
which actually seems wrong if we're trying to understand the sentence is important and important
two very different meanings even if england angle without e seem like the that might
be plausible
another thing people do is they lemmatize introduce words to their simplest forms
we had an example cats becomes cat
this is mostly solved in short perl scripts this isn't really a difficult problem people
don't write papers about these these things anymore but they are instances of structured prediction
it's just that we make the prediction using rules using very simple methods
but there are other ways of reducing the vocabulary and some of them are
are much more challenging so
the next thing to talk about this is the sort of extreme former tokenisation or
map we map words into word classes are part of speech you've probably seen this
problem before it's kind of a canonical natural language processing problem so here i've taken
each word in the sentence and assigned it blew part of speech determiners nouns
these are these are the parts of speech as as decided by you know somebody
i think is these go back you know two terrorists toddler something in the beginning
but you know you can come if you can kind of agree on the convention
and you may be able to decide on a way to map parts of speech
and this is this is done almost universally known NLP and you might think you
why is this what's challenging here the the problem of course is that many words
are ambiguous
and so
you could independently classify each word on its own based on
based on what you've seen before and you can get close to ninety percent accuracy
on this problem if you've got enough data in terms of the fraction of words
you correctly tagged
but context actually is really important so for example the word leaves can be a
plural noun or singular that is probably a verb is followed by a noun
similarly the word varies
communicating in honor but if it has a determiner in front of it you can
but it's probably now so
these the sort of local interactions among the words tend to allow us to do
a lot better if we can model and so the best performance on part of
speech tagging i think these days is around ninety seven percent and these are based
on structured models where we make joint decisions about all the words at the same
OK so this is this is sort of the simplest example
where the current NLP paradigm took off and continues to be the dominant way of
doing things so the general
framework here is that you get some people who understand part of speech tagging or
whatever you linguistic structure is you get them to label some text
you probably pay them a little bit of money to do that
and then you go perform supervised learning
and that could be some kind of structured prediction model i would advocate here but
you should you should be a little bit wary this these part of speech
you know if you find the dataset gives you parts of speech you should remember
that this didn't come from god
this came from somebody who had some insight about what parts of speech are useful
for that language and then he paid adviser to sit down and write down what
the part speech words in text
this is this is a choice
somebody somebody had some thoughts and you might you know if you do the language
you might disagree with them personally i disagree with some of the conventions that were
chosen in the current standard datasets for part of speech further even once you've laid
down what the conventions are people who are annotating don't always agree with each other
so annotation is actually a major
efforts that usually requires you know bring in lots of different people making sure they
agree going through various phases two to measure inter annotator agreement building up the case
that we've got is actually real
let's go back to work again
for a long time and focused mainly mainly on english but of course not everyone
speaks english and we'd like to do natural language processing for other languages so here's
a sentence in korean
and the
the graph at the bottom is is a little light far as network that shows
you the different possible analysis of the screen speak korean
no OK i'm safe
each of these is this
each of these words many of the words in the in that sequence can be
analyzed more than one way so i think if you multiply this out there something
like forty different analyses of the sentence depending on how you break the words of
how you tagged
so this is sort of showing you different ways of
segmenting in tagging the morphemes in this sense
OK so this may be a surprise if you only speak english but morphological disambiguation
is really kind of crucial for NLP in other languages so again this is just
the sequence the sequence mapping problem you get a sequence of surface words or characters
maybe and you want to you want to break them into morphemes and possibly tag
as well
this is one of my favourite examples
does anyone know what language this is
this is the word in turkish
it's very long and it means something like behaving as if you are among those
whom we could not civilise
it's a single word
and if you wanted to you know if you could say this is kind of
weird this is like some weird fringe effect but there are more than sixty million
people in the world to speak this language and we wanted to provide intelligent software
they could manage their language for them we would have to break that word into
its parts and figure out what the sum of the parts mean
what makes things even more nasty with turkish is often the valves change throughout the
sequence to match each other there's this thing called the harmony
so the problem gets even heard it's almost as if they've conspired to make their
language hard
so this going to move up a little bit from words
a lot of people have built their careers on unjust handling the words in different
languages but we're gonna we're going to keep going so
one thing that often useful is defined specific kinds of substrings syntax from the call
these chucks so for example if we go back to our cat cat sentence this
sentence has two noun phrases into prepositional phrases which are marked two based on the
positions and so we can we can use structured prediction two
to find these important segments are interesting segments chunks using what well
the representation is usually used to turn this into a sequence labeling problem we label
the beginning in interior and exterior points for each chong so this is just another
string transduction problem you have sense coming in and what you're going to send out
of these i be labels possibly
unlimited with chunks so this means that this is the beginning of the noun phrase
the interior and now we're starting a prepositional phrase the interior the interior and our
outside and so the the encoding is really not that important it's very widely used
it's worth seeing
so this is this kind of this technique is used for base noun phrase chunking
also for other kinds of shallow parsing for
other types of phrases and most commonly named entity recognition so i think that's what
i want to show to here's the sentence
from the news not too long ago
and there are the named entities
and we might label this entities the first one is the place the second one
is the person and the third one
what is robocop i guess robocop is a fantastical person i would call that miscellaneous
depends on your convention
maybe robocop is a person
OK so if you take this idea finding interesting substrings two
two it's extreme
and imagine that we want to find all the interesting substrings and we believe that
they have a hierarchical structure then you get the passing problem
and this is this is a problem that has dominated and continues to dominate LP
it's one of the main areas if you go to computational linguistics conference there will
be tons of sessions on passing and this is this is sort of passing in
what what what
thank you
i don't know
the hi
this is
and for the time being
or you know what
so four very well
people like know
well was
we also know that one
i mean
one five
we have to use
so i i
as for minus
ions which i noted
current carrier inside this
it's going from the right
going from the right to the left
so why would as o four miners ions
travel through an electric field
that opposes them
that opposes them motion
and they do that because in doing so
they engage
in a chemical reaction
which yields more energy than it cost
to climb
the electric hill
and while a current is flowing
while the s four minus is going from the right to left
you get fewer as o four minus ions here
this liquid he remains neutral
so complex must disappear
and it precipitates onto this copper bar so like
copper plating
on this side you get an increase of as so for minors
therefore we also must get an increase of zinc plus
because again this
link with there remains neutral
and that means
that some of the same
is being dissolved
so you get increase
in the concentration
of the
so the charge carriers inside these better DSO for miners ions
travel through very and they go from here to here
so to travel through the electric field
that opposes the motion
and this happens at the expense of chemical energy
now in the copper solution
becomes very dilute because all the copper has
been plated onto copper
and when this becomes concentrated this implies the the better we stop
and now what you can do you can run the current in the opposite direction
so you can run the current now in this direction
you can force the current to run without external power supply
and now chemical reactions will reverse
so now
comparable go back into the solution
so it will
and now the zinc
will be
precipitated onto using
so now if you do this long enough you can run the better you get
in the way this here
a car battery
is exactly this kind of better except that you have led
and that oxide instead of zinc and copper
but you also have sulfuric acid
like you have here
nickel cadmium batteries well known
you can charge that too
the ones that are readily available
in the stories you can run your flashlights
with these nickel cadmium batteries
this symbol
for better way that we will be using in our circuits
is this
this is the positive side
and this is the negative side
this is the symbol the symbolized that we're dealing with a
with the battery
but at this point b
and is going to be a
and here
we have a resistor r
so we have the current going
the current is going
in this direction
the current i
this could be libeled
could be laptop
the hairdryer
that you supply
if these are isn't there
that means that the resistance is infinitely large
that means that the current it is running is zero
then the voltage that we would measure over this
battery which is
minus eight
for which i will simply write down
view of the battery
we call
curled e which stands for EMF which is electromotive force
i will show you that later
if i put a resistance are in here
which is not infinitely large
then the current will start to flow
we should never forget
between the points a and b invisible to the
human i
is always an internal resistance which i call little are of high
and so if the current starts to flow
it goes not only through capitol but it also goes through these little are
so according to ohms law
the EMF
is now i
extra resistance plus the internal one
before the age that you would measure between point b and a
it's not going to change
that voltage
according to ohms law is i r
to b and then you would have caused
OK let's
keep going
OK so
is this good for another we have the definition we could figure out what we
can do with it
what are the implications of that
well will discover new applications of the product throughout the entire semester but let me
tell you at least about rules that
are readily visible
so one is
to compute
and angles
let's do an example
let's say that
i have in space
you have a point
which is that one is the all whole
i have a point
that is the all ones are also it's distance one here
one here
they have point
see also tools so its height two
and let's say that i'm curious and i'm wondering
what is the angle
so if you have a triangle in space
i thing pq one
i'm wondering what is this angle
so of course one solution is to build a model and then you go and
measure the angle
but we can do better than that
we can just find the angle using the product
so how would we do that
if we look at this formula
we see
so let's say
but we want to find here
well let's look at the formula for
pq that
p r
when we say it should be
length q
times length p r
and the cosine of the angle
now what do we know what do we not know well something at this point
we don't know
the cosine of the angle that's what we would like to find
but the length
so we can compute we know how to find these legs
it's not for that we know how to compute because we have an easy formula
OK so we can compute everything else and then find the so what we do
as we will find theta
in this way
we take the dot product of the q with p r and then we divide
by four lengths
OK so
so we say cosine theta is a q
of length p q
next we we are
so let's try to figure out what is the topic you want to go from
he two q i should go
minus one unit along the x direction
plus one unit and on the way the actions
and i'm not moving visitor action
so to go from p to q i have to move
by minus one
to go from p two are
i call minus one on the x axis and press two along the axis
p are claimed is this
then the length of these vectors
we take
minus one squared plus one square sail square square and the same thing with the
so the denominator will become one as well true and this is well defined
what about the new night
so remember to do the product we multiply this by this
that that that by that and we have
minus one minus one makes
plus one and say that's still
so all things to is zero again
so we will get
one of those quotes
that's the cosine of the angle
and of course if we want the actual angle
what we have to take calculator
find the inverse cosine
and you'll find that it's about
seventy one point five
actually will be using mostly gradients that for today
i but certainly are not speaking
OK any questions about that
OK so in particular i should point out one thing that really need to about
the answer
c and we got this number we don't really know what it means exactly because
it makes to give over lands and the angle
but one thing interesting here it's the sign of the answer
the fact that we got positive number
so if you think about it
the land always positive
so the sign of the dot product is the same as the sign of
because i
in fact
the sign of the
is going to be positive
the angle is less than ninety degrees so that means dramatically
two vectors are growing more or less the same direction to to make an acute
it's going to be zero
the angle is exactly ninety degrees
OK because that's when the cosine will is
be negative if the angle is more than ninety
so that means they go
in opposite directions
OK so
one way to think about what the product measure measures how much the two vectors
going along each other
and that actually leads us to the next application
so we have another one
yes so if they had no when they must have number two
because a lot of the minimum wage
secondly it is not so far
so you can as well
what does the gas was that this is
compute the value of more likely
it provides
about two-and-a-half operator which means so this is how this
to the right is
then continue on two
two applications to that
show you
example of rank two
the fresh we think that
but this is exactly what i like to watch what it depends on the properties
of this in this case actually generated in this small
o thing until is to do real data
it's really question i think
the second
the function look like a lot more
right now
this really look stationary monitor talk station
but you and i regret not
you can ask questions like that
you use machinery
and the trail to you actually have
make some observations observations we
this is one
in one
with the same thing
you under and you get something data which not so well explained by this
is very smooth
first lesson
then the case
more like the trade for the same
how much
OK to come back to this
come back
it's not just the two sides we have of how to use the process direction
because of this
so first of all we have that
one of the boldest
after the training points these are
on unknown
my prior
non-zero values for
all the
then was
so as soon as
by wise function
just like the fact that
probably any of these y
only depends on the car
what you want to
so particular input
unknown latent value once get
that tells you all you could possible
what happens on the basis that
so the
like that
and also along
i need to to turn the reason that want to make inferences
he also
the like
and how the situation is
this is house and this is
so this
is the fact that the world is here
this is the as you why
that's what the gas in form
the expression to utilize this
when distance between
we use the fact that like
also function
this becomes way for me
OK so what do we do
well we
make predictions
to make predictions about now say something about
the location called start
also for example x dy
and so
what i need to do that is to say well
one is the
is this is the sort of the identification
so the joint
star cascade
the same
just that for the model that
these are goals which are linked by some control data flow
so into to booker trip and in this example there is a request for flight
request for hotel and then you put the two
i request comes in
why are some goal based invocation and then either at design time or runtime these
go request matched
two semantic descriptions of web services
so the flight request is matched to a flight web service and hotel request and
hotel bookings at to hotel web service descriptions and these descriptions have choreography
and maybe grounded i don't have time to talk about grounding to some deployed web
services out on the
on the on the web
OK so that's three of the components of the last one is the
mediators so this is the top-level element in with no which doesn't have a corresponding
component analysis
but there is an interesting paper from
two thousand four
i think by paolo
comparing OWL s and the way was my hands handles mediation
so here are some of the motivation for why we have native
mediation is the top level
so this is statistics that for every dollar spent on programming five to nine dollars
spent on integration
so integrating components of big
a big slice of any application
creating tasks so we assume that there always necessary and we call this our safe
sex principle whenever you stick one component to any other component with may you always
put a mediator in the middle and the type of mediated depends on the type
of components that you're trying to put together
the other confusing aspect of the mediation in with me is that this is a
description of the role
so you can have the same deployed web service and in some applications it plays
the role of the standard web service you invoke in you get a result
in other applications it may play in mediating function
so it's not it's the role it plays in a particular context
so here's a pictorial representation to types of mediators in which in was not so
in with no we have ontologies web services and goals that we want to put
together putting two ontologies together and some sort of mismatch
then we have another mediator
which may point to some component designed by natasha
or she right if we put web services together and there is a mismatch between
say the inputs of one and the in the outputs of another then we have
ww mediator some and mismatch between the goal
of some client and what functionality web service we may have WG mediator in the
so this allows
and more
web services to be used against specific functionality
here's what the mediator looks like underneath we have a source component one or more
of these which want to be which need to be linked to the target component
and then the mediator points to some description
for mediators there may be a set of rules
for if this the functionality we may put up a web service in here web
service description or goals
and then run time will designed time the goal of the match to an appropriate
web services can actually carry out the mediation that requires
OK so let me quickly go through
an example
one application to be built in the
did a larger european project on semantic web services using it although we have at
the open university called the IRS three
so i had this is the real story
the BBC websites people don't believe me if i tell the story so in the
end of january two thousand three one centimetre snow fell in southern england and brought
all the traffic and trains
and airports to stand still complete chaos so here's the story of the twenty hour
battle my allow the driver to the motorways literally became a lot of people spend
at least one night
the application we created in conjunction with essex county council
it was to use semantic web services to support emergency situations related to drastic weather
so in terms of the scenario this is part of the essex county county which
we have on the left there is a major motorway
the m eleven which runs near stansted airport
and there was
this is where the heavy snow
i felt
and then there is the requirement that we want to link to meteorological web services
which will tell us about the forthcoming
weatherevent and i'm planning emergency response
we also want to get various details of the type of event coming
and identify rest centres
so if we have people that maybe you may have a coach of children he
may have elderly people
they told the story that they once had fifty dogs
that needed to rest centres of the type of dress entity choose depends on the
type of people that stuck anything different types of of people citizens will require different
types of rest centres
they also have something called the viewessex spatial data to this is a large databases
can containing all the elements such as hotels
shops schools that can be required
so here with the ontologies to be created the application was called emerges we had
was no ontology top
we had a archetypes ontology so lay persons view of geographical data
we also had
ontologies for meteorological data ontologies for the also covered another application to do with
what happens if a lorry with toxic gases
four i show you in in a small video in the moment ontologies for emergency
GIS and then one for instant messaging system called body space
just before i i show you a quick video of the screencast of application to
this is the generic structure applications that we've been creating over number years and it's
similar to the diagram that david showed earlier so that viewers when you build applications
using semantic web services you have these legacy systems
and we found in in the e government context which you're working in any government
at least in the UK
the problem is that you have many many different parties involved so you have these
four tiers of government some
agencies like the police force controlled by the national government some controlled locally you have