but i want to give is with regard to the slides that you have compute
decide that you have are now really that old because they had to give them
about two months ago and since then i modified the good news is that most
of the mortgage modifications were
to remove slide because i realized that i gave you too much material and i
had to cut in order to be able to get that into three hours so
the other a better version of the slide here
you don't have to
you're on your life so you can copy them
and i'm going to follow this updated version and even then it might still be
too long i will see whether i can cut from what i have
i'm going to start another said you can interrupt me
whenever you want something is not clear
be my guest
the outline of the tutorial is he here i'm going first to introduce you to
the field of machine statistical machine learning
then i'm going to have to have the section of the
itself to statistical learning theory why
statistical learning should work
in general
and then there are many many
machine learning algorithms i'm not going to
to show you all of them i have decided to select only a couple of
the ones which are more suited to the task of multimodal processing
and these are based on graphical models and the expectation maximisation algorithms so i'm going
to start with the simplest example which is a gaussian mixture models
then i'm going to go into further with the
temporal extension of them which is the hidden markov models and afterward
in the last hour
i'm going to talk about specific models that have been designed for multimodal processing more
recently in
and more
in recent years
so this is the outline of the talk
so let's start by
learning anyway
what is machine learning
this is machine learning of course this is only new cartoon but basically the idea
there we
computer or items to try to learn a concept that are not so easy to
learn by computers
so what do we mean by such concepts
well first of all we we have the feeling of what is learning for human
we do learn every day and but what is it exactly well in general what
we mean is that we
we are
changing our state of mind our way of thinking in such a way that the
next time which is similar situation we're going to be better now what better means
of course is according to our criteria that we all have in our mind can
be anything having more money being more healthy
it's up to you to you to decide what your criteria but you do have
so what is important to understand that such learning is not
what we call learning by heart learning by heart is very easy for computers it's
very difficult for humans but for computer science only having a table and lots of
memory in this we are not going to talk about that we are going to
talk about learning things in order to to be able to to generalise to things
that we have not seen before
so why is this a difficult task
i'm going to try to
to convince you that it's not
it's not simple it's not at all related to learning by heart
basically you
you have in general when you start learning you have a finite amount of data
using that they tell you want to learn a relation
that is going to
the correct for an infinite amount of data we only have a small sample of
of what could happen and then you want to understand the direction to try to
generalise to the rest
of the domain
the problem is that such
such idea of being able to do
to generalise to do an infinite amount of of domain is is in fact a
complex because here i give you in this two-dimensional space a finite amount of point
and i tell you there is a line that goes by these points
which one is it can you try to to me please
there are many
many many
lines that goes true despite the fact there are many lives that don't go through
the point at all like that maybe the read the green one does not pass
through all these points but maybe that was the real one that i was expecting
because the points that you've seen may have been noisy somehow because you have a
machine that that record points and and then there's is is intrinsic noise in the
recording so
you're not even sure that you want to line to pass through the point that
you have
but you want the best line that's going to behave the best for points that
haven't even seen
we try to grasp why this is difficult
because now i show you the points of points some of the points that were
not available when you have to decide on the function on the line and i
showed them now to you
but when you have to decide what was the line you couldn't use the information
was not available you have to decide on the line
and then
i want to show you the points and you see all my god then i
was i try to do to to follow too much the the point on not
enough so
how do you decide on how well too much or not that
well we
basically follow
very simple principle
that data back from the fourteenth century so
very old stuff and it's called the principle of parsimony from william of occam
and did
the basic idea of this principle is that if you have many options to solve
your past
this there
even i i will discuss this these these columns of the data
SQL query and this will analyse this data and you just ask on it
and the task may require that the data comes in a particular way
and then you just another reason may be an open source rate
to perform this task and this implementation requires it to be in some particular way
and watch
this same apart seen text may have different semantics
so it's not clear that when you see the data is in the right format
to where have arisen it is in the right format
for the reason do what you wanted to to
this is a very complicated and let me just mention for instance some data many
many much data and machine learning almost always works only with this sort of thing
that is relational so that you can think of each observation
as value for each of a number of attributes like arrow
in this country
he yes the comma comma separated values is a very common
a way of storing it they for format was populated by work and they know
every two is able to reach out of
number three is not uncommon separated values is about the separator really at
so if you export from xl
and you don't want to say the opposite it will be some icons
and then if you find this into something that experts kumar then there are no
commercial there is only one field and science english stray and then you see what's
happening and takes
fifteen minutes to find out that some of the problem
but then
they are transactional data traditionally days where each observation is as it
it's not the same thing almost the same thing as having a binary sympathetic where
two main city seen before means it is out
almost the same thing but not quite because if you have the
this and knows
new kind of things with the nose
and if you have only sit
doing somehow meaning that they intend to the things i was positive information
so there are a number of the key points you can of course because the
section of four into
bit vectors not for CSV now
do you want them to be serious and once do you want them to be
F's and these
four centers
one and two in the workforce and there were two the you want them to
have a question mark in the force and that
being the true
all of these
it tells us
it is one format that there is some tool out there that expects that form
i'm not making them up is this this is the one that happened after the
and then do you have any column headers
then there is one road that you don't have to have to skip because its
columns to help us
or you don't have kids and then you don't have to skip this first observation
or do you happen to have an end of file character as part of the
value nice one strain somewhere along the data and then your system stop there
this has happened to me
only one portion of the data was being fed and nobody knew why
and it turns out that one of these things
that we can that we got from this ecclesiastical secretly
i have a set of
she tells it
so what
anything of many many
but these approaches each of them is to be to so
there are many
and and they are sometimes difficult to
so most eight i like to say that it in this way has low sophistication
it's role with
a new have there as you other that best people was filling forms
and what they can mine at that is find some more sophisticated way of
telling me the same things
of course the change
the to the truth as i do that
five to present something to me has to be somehow correct
don't tell me that all the veterans of the vietnam war
are by now
i know what is
don't tell me that if i could go to the moon enabling a lot of
extra money off with this business
i cannot go to the moon
so there's a adjectives are very common in the definition of data mining object lines
a new changes every variable in to be a product and factor node
will be a product
with the factor not something the parent some recipe very simple
the structure of the graph so simply is not any variable node yukon yukon back into a product
and forty factor nor convert back into a product of everything that's coming in with the factor
plus some
some mission of everything other than the parent
if you just do this
that's really the most efficient execution of distributive law
it takes a little bit of time to get used to this
but i just summarize the main observation is that the structure of the graph
actually includes the algorithm
right so this is what you getting the first claims of
of why we're so excited about graphical models you didn't have come up with yet
another algorithm if you've written a graphical model in a suitable way
you've already got efficient algorithm for this particular problem is
sometimes called the sum product algorithm because you're pushing some insight products and that's one of the most difficult problems
you could be pushing individuals inside products high dimensional integration is a hard problem and
this is what we trying to solve
so i'll give you a hint of
why this has been rediscovered so so many times is that in markov models is just a very popular algorithm
it is a popular model
you have a sequence of states latent states you know that minus one easy plus one
they can take values in a finite number of states
and many are in a certain state in the transition probability with which you are
giving an observation x this is hidden markov models
the most basic form of government filters is essentially the same structure
but you you are dealing with real vectors and you know it
minus one plus we why did i models
so it's essentially the same structure the whole thing or
he then markov models have been studied extensively they have been applied extensively over the
i think starting from the early seventies
and the core algorithms you can go take a hidden markov model and this is
a good exercise to do if you already know the algorithms are therefore hidden markov
so i understand why this is a special case of what i'm saying
is that you want but each one of them the transition probability matrix sixty minus
one given that minus one is a factor
zeta given city minus one is a factory introduce those factors you already know the transition provided tables
just what i told you which is the sum product message passing and you're going to get the solution
so the petri problems people worry about in markov models is computing
the likelihood of an observation you've been given an observation may maybe a phoneme sequence
or something like that you're trying to figure out how likely is is
a set of observations the probability of the latent variable you know what is the
likelihood that the city is a certain value
and then finding the most likely sequence of states given the sequence o observations
apart from these two things you use something called the forward backward algorithm that's a
special case so what i just told you about
but this one use something called viterbi decoding which is also a special case of something i told you about
he was saying that
well these two i can see how they are marginalization problem because you are given
a joint distribution over all the axes enzi's
and you marginalize out all these and that's how get it
how can you support the maximization what these things into the same problems as well
the reason you can do this is that the distributive law works on any symmetry
right it has nothing to do with real numbers
so the max product is valid semiring so you can push max's inside products and better walk
and now you know this
you can back to the literature and find out how many times this algorithm has been rediscovered and distance forms
one of the core components in some of the more fancy algorithms we develop belief
propagation in bayes net map inference in
it humans
common featuring the basic forms and correcting codes and low-density parity-check codes turbo codes used in
wireless telephones and so on
they use this on a routine basis right so
are know message passing in general graphs is a bit more complicated i was talking about trees
this is very much a walking properties
and mostly we have good news coming from many quarters and i'm going to show you one example of fat
um but to sort of give you a sense of
this is not like a theoretical exercise of a bunch of people excited about semirings and distributive law
when it
when i want to play in x box live you go online and you are
matched with somebody who of equal skill
this algorithm is being used
and the people who put it in inside experts have had extensive conversations with them
it's used so so so that's one good example
and this is a very big problem for online gaming companies because if you are
matched up with supremely but there are really
bacteria are not just interested in playing the game
and these you know they are on the run on
hundreds of thousands of variables and they pull this off
records which are which are using fizzy forty forms
ah satellite communication much evidence that many of them have these algorithms embedded in them
says this is not just one algorithm
four one class it extensively using graphical models and all of these are actually applications of graphical models
and actually skip some of the
a couple of these discussions this is one of my favourite slides among with what
i'm not going to discuss today
are still
so caution process is another class of
graphical models
which means that
bayesian models which means priors over functions
right so the way the police of essentially is there
if you're trying to do god's bidding right so one approach is used by the
for the straight line and things like that the second approach is the u
actually maintain distributions over
all functions in finite human right it may be straight lines it may be second order it maybe other things
and then you maintain a prior over them there's a way to do that and that's what washing processes do
and then when you get observations left in this case you got some observations you
compute the posterior which functions are doing their land across them more
and then you get something like this right so so
so that that's one of functions used to maintaining non-zero weight on all of them
but you are getting your sharpening your posterior based on the observations you have and
this is a very rich class of models
we actually actively worked on these things i'm not going to get into this in
and this is again an example of of
duty version of it
i am going to get into the discrete versions also got washing processes are very good for continuous data
model random fields undirected models
graphical models far for a discrete data i'm going to give you an example of
what i'm not another thing i'm not going to talk about today is
how to learn the structure of this graphical models right i'm i'm talking about that
or you'll know about you know make false alarm goes off and so on and
so we made the wire like this and then we have a tension and then
worked out the
the math and then we found
but in that case
the two y x squared
was one of these grids
time two widely discredited
and we found by
substituting the
solution into the wave equation
that the speed of propagation
what's the square root of p divided by mu t being tension new was the
mass per unit length
in this
is no k
there's no megan
so to non dispersive medium
it says that
you tell me what omega guys
and this is going to be to speed you tell me what omega is that's
going to be the speed is independent of frequency it's in all
dispersive medium
the reason for that is
because we only took into account
that attention
in the string was responsible
forty restoring force
so that favours then
was vk
that came out of this
wave equation
and so we found that omega square
is this great times case group
that is the result
of the calculation when the tension is exclusively responsible for the restoring force
you get a non dispersive medium
there is something that we did not take into account
and that is the business of the wire
imagine for now that attention is zero
you take a piano string or you take the string from the violin
and so there is no tension at all
you take your hand the you bend it
no tension just bend it
it wants to straighten out
that's the result of stiffness
and it is due to the stiffness now
but you get an extra restoring force which we have
ignored we didn't take that into account
and the restoring force due to stiffness
turns out to be proportional to k two the power for inversely proportional
two wavelengths to the power forwards an approximation
in other words are wave equation that we had is no longer valid
because this wave equation
only took into account
the tension
if not you
go through the whole
procedure again which is
a slightly more complicated
you will find no
but you get the different relation between omega and k
and now you see that the
really becomes
this person now you get that omega squared
he call these grids
times case credit
of five
times k two the power four
this is the result of that stiffness
back affine invariant
cold is all far a square that's fine of course it's just a matter of
eight is a positive number
and what this tells you is that the higher the frequency
the higher the speed of propagation i can make for USA
omega k diagram
so let's have here
let's have k
so what we had before when we only took tension into account we had this
this case
that slope is the phase velocity
it's also to group velocity all wavelengths at the same speed
but now because of this term
it's going to curve up because of the positive
so now you're going to get this
now you see in front of your lies that the higher the frequency
when you're here
the phase velocity
is higher than at low frequency here
this slope
lower that's
so now we have a dispersive medium
and also the group velocity
right here
is even higher than the phase velocity because this slope which is the tangent
is higher
the connection
two zero
piano string is this person
is actually useful in application in some modest number of steps couple hundred or something
like that i mean that's kind of what you're hoping right so so this is
not about
worst case complexity is OK
OK so let's look at some common patterns are the idea is this then let
let's think about abstractly what this is meant like to think about not is as
an optimisation algorithm but is sort of the meta algorithm because in an optimisation algorithm
you were you end up working with primitives like evaluating gradients or subgradients or something
like that you do some linear algebra and stuff like that and also have an
algorithm right so these are a very low level operators here the operators actually are
higher level
they require this
they require you to minimize a function was the quadratic quadratically augmented function
right now
so the higher level concepts now i mean only in some cases this will reduce
to doing gradient calculation or something like that something like a gradient calculation
but in general this could be something much more complicated right well this this could
this you could actually requires some heavy lifting actually solving
real convex optimization problem
so what we do is we look now at
to actually by the way what this is you only have to implement one method
for f right and i mean it's just you have to be able to
to carry out this practice quadratically augmented minimization but i want some special cases and
things where the split because they put it like the other library these and all
of a sudden this looks interesting the first one this is like kind of obvious
if f is block separable and a transpose a is blocked several by the way
will see the light of applications a is like i or minus i u we'll
see what we see applications
then i will of course minimizing if you have to minimize there's you know take
equals i
you have to minimize this an AB splits then of course the whole thing split
so you can immediately target you can run that section in parallel
and that's that's do
distributed optimisation OK so i mean this is kind of just like completely obvious
another case occurs when equals i
this occurs so frequently has a name
and long history
so this is called the proximal operator associated with f
and he basically admitted later with that minimizes f plus a quadratic cost of deviating
from v
OK and you can by the way you can also see certain things here if
you make
rho super-high
very large
then you can kind and that is quadratic you'll see that this return something which
is the gradient it's a gradient step it's exactly gradient step
if rho is small i mean you get all the other things and i'll explain
some these but these you can these you can work out
depending on what f is
i mean one example let's look at some special cases if f is the indicator
function so f is zero off some on some convex set and plus infinity outside
and this really simple this just as minimize this norm the rose totally irrelevant this
so in fact the idea is the proximal operator is a is a generalization of
projection operators
and reduces to projection operator when f is an indicator function
if f is any separable function the whole thing becomes completely trivial because you
you minimize it actually absolute you certainly don't need to sum of absolute value any
separable functions completely trivial
because you're doing scalar approximate calculations how long does it take to minimize the scalar
convex function the answer zero mean because you put it all done in little registers
and things like that so it's all it's it's zero basically it costume or to
move the data in and out OK so
but you know you have pretty formulas for not that that matters but for example
for the l one norm the proximal operator is the soft thresholding right which looks
like let's for you because i like this is all flat chunk and then it
goes back up again OK
and there's lots and lots of others
quadratic objective will be minimize the quadratic objective
well then of course
you know if you are to quadratic objective with the quadratic is still quadratic minimiza
quadratic you that's you can solve this by just calculated by linear algebra i mean
you just
he the set of linear equations right so you get something like this
there's a lot you can say about how to do this well for one thing
depending on sparsity patterns and things like that you may want to arrange for this
this thing you may want to use something like the matrix inversion lemma something like
that and the rough ideas if in the dense case you want to be absolutely
that the cost of computing this is the big dimension times small square
right i mean
the big dimensions squared times small and being wrong
so and the big big dimension q being very wrong but that's the worst implementation
so if you're using the direct method
we also see something interesting that this
when you
well if you have to do this repeatedly what changes in each iteration is v
what it says it all kasha factorizations if you catch the factorizations of this in
the dense case you get a if diffuser direct method right in the first time
you solve it you pay factories asian and back solve
OK thereafter you only pay back solve and you get a discount
on the on the method
on computing the least squares problem which is on the order of this may which
is the small dimension
right so and work course we intend to do this for large problems so
the small dimension is a pretty good discount so by the way this also means
that this
business counting iterations is not going to be to irrelevant because what it says is
that after the first iteration of ADMM when you're doing
if doing direct method and factorisation caching
it is actually the first iteration thereafter iterations cost one five hundred to one one
thousand of the first one and you see in regime like that you know
really who cares whether you take two hundred or or for that matter ten thousand
steps i mean it's just not relevant
OK let using iterative method here
like LSQ are some CG type thing then there's other tricks
you don't catch anymore but what you do is you do warm start and you
the minimum a LSQR minimisation of the quadratic from for example the previous point as
you converge means you start take you start doing better and better OK so there
are lots of tricks are not going to go into them but these are these
are these are serious there obvious ones
and they can for you know huge advantage
OK oh i should say something else
that will see the statistical data fitting
context this is a quadratic update is going to correspond to just ridge regression
so this says that in those cases you do rich regression and if you the
first ridge regression thereafter you get a huge discount for the
you get a substantial discount for for further iterations right
now if f is smooth use whatever you like
we we've we've aligned sort of similar has in the lattice and we've
can then
with posterior probabilities that we get on the individual art we can then do do
decoding this revised lattice structure
and so
having having done that you know we can basically obtained this
this is combined lattice
this process of compressing it into a confusion network we get this network that is
has the same ordering properties
but we have now posterior
probabilities associated with the
sort of confusion areas along these alignment points and then we can re score by
just taking the
the each candidate at these alignment points that have the largest posterior probability
and then we get some very significant increase in performance you know roughly five or
six percent depending on the the scenario
and so we we get so that the underlying thing is that these things really
are something very different we get something much more
then we get if we take a single
the distinctive feature streams and then combine it with our our system so these these
different systems really do contain sort of different usable information
that we can use to sort of combined with our traditional ASR systems
any questions and
so i'm going to make the argument for
how good it is we've we've got another fifteen minutes or so and
quickly make the argument for what a great idea is to try and design adaptation
normalisation algorithms that
physiologically plausible in terms of of
possible in terms of speech production models
very quickly
my speech production really is a bunch of impulses here this is what everything we
do is is based on the simple thing we have a bunch of for voiced
sounds we have an impulse train
and it excites a bunch of linear systems cascaded together produce
sound pressure at the output and generally we can model the the shape being associated
with the glottis
we can model the spectral shaping associated with the shape of the vocal tract and
that that
occurs as the result of you know the are this baffle we have an inner
sphere called baffle here which is our mouth
in the coming out of our heads so
i'm going to rush because i'm running out of time
what is the idea of those with so far we've been talking about speech production
and distinctive features in terms of speech production we can quickly relate that to
the acoustics and we can do that by
making some very simple assumptions one is that we have sort of steady state flow
coming from the
from the larynx into the vocal tract and the other is that we have a
plane wave propagation
through this these basically this model of our vocal tract which is this sequence of
concatenated to use
plane wave propagation assumes the cross section of these tubes is much
let the area there's much less
then the
then the wavelength of speech and we could basically so that our wavelength is given
by the speed of sound over over the frequency
fundamental frequency of male speakers about one hundred hertz so we have the wavelength is
a few meters there is a few centimeters so laminar flow or plane wave propagation
is reasonable
i'm going to a little bit too much effort just to justify the connection between
vocal tract shape and acoustic and i'll just very quickly go through here too quickly
to make any sense of we can assume that we have are vocal tract is
modelled by an acoustic two and we have this acoustic tube that has a certain
there's density of air in the two we have the
volume velocity of the air flowing in and out and we have the the sound
the results from that so
we can
as engineers love this because we can describe this physical
in terms of an electrical circuit
it's about the yes
or yes tour OK
well i guess
we need the feedback
i guess we assume that
you see that in terms of acoustic feedback score
OK i'm going
o that's certainly true and i think basically how coarticulation phenomenon i guess is what
you're kind of referring to there is that it
and i guess this this is this is basically assuming that we have basically short-time
stationary condition and i think you can make that assumption
you know we assume that speech is sort of roughly stationary over all say
ten or twenty millisecond intervals and and the
the effects of coarticulation
generally occur over sort of hundreds of millisecond
you will
they have no
too to mean
so what to give lot
just to use the or
no more of
we're seeing
four years ago
propose more
one one
one of them three
what you see the i
of course
because they want
you may just more
i mean
what kind
this is
one or more of what was
well i think that we're trying
one one
other than that
saying how
it's a very simple method
or in the case where all the conditional distributions
ah gasolines
and you might say well how can it possibly be interesting if all conditional distributions
and that means that you know working with is a very simple the vision
well no not necessarily they're doing interesting distributions
all the conditional we can out and yet the joint distribution is
they well sample of so this is an interesting that you have
so let me show you a listener that all the deaths in this region
so we don't know anything about
and this is what if something looks like
all the same
the problem is exactly the same data and we were just playing with
the company will follow
it uses sampling there's no parameter that all
but the typical you take
when you draw from the conditional distribution this way
all that we can this way
because the
so are the activity that will always be a weighted
similar to the with
then would be
so you're never gonna be taking size be dealt narrowly missed by little out
which is
that means that you got random walk of the you
video on the elsewhere on in an example using the sampling
so i admit that that
that we draw
deliberately from the opposite side
of the distribution in one way
and then we get the available in royal mail decided be
the result is shown here in red they seem to run and run along the contour wobble down
we do men on this individuals
what this is going to
the average wait time when people revert anyway let's imagine that we started from the bottom left here
we've got a little bit
above the green pond or that they won't let
and then the of the of the site
a little bit about green
and then with let you again about all of the world
and that means that we don't know that every other
what the red line and then you wander along the contour of in this two-dimensional problem
you can do it in high dimensions
and all many problems
it turns out that we can eliminate does reduce random walk behavior
and there are various ways the revealingly
improvement in performance
and one is to invent the simple just keep track of and
fluctuations in the and
if they feel the correlation time
it's very short proof that
an indication that the good
now that anything
eight quantity x one
to be available on it
one wandering around on a regular old get sampling shown in and the orange
and in red is the rotation that one anything that i was so you want that moving around
but on the
and another called you can look at the world where
and on the sampling
the aged around being in the middle being one of three
think of the elements that
one where they're going
up and down but
that's a crude indication that
at least on the problem they are limited
it better
for those of you
that's over-relaxation all conditional distributions that are destined
you might say well that's not gonna help me because my problem doesn't involve any
initial that we after problem more interesting than
and this good news or even a new article that you can still do
using other methods
and it's all ordered
and ordered overrelaxation was invented by rapid male
and it works like this
imagine that's your doing gibbs sampling and you have other methods which will draw u
a new point
conditional distribution
they are at the current point
and you have the capability because they think draw one view on this this be
you know draw
eight times from but we
eight times
you hold on the point my life
all right
maybe i'm more interested in the world
what about an option that seven
drawn them and green points
the total seven point we have there is a set of eight point including the one we are currently
and ordered over measurement across one two three or
by the
you're at that point
oriented features and so forth exception mechanisms
and so on
and so people are willing to pay a factor three in performance so that's why
you want performance
because you can use it to pay for these other things that you want
OK and that's why in some sense it's on the bottom of the heap
OK because it's the universal thing that everybody is they you quantified you wanna spend
a factor of two on this suspended factor three and security
and in addition the lessons generalize to other resource measures like communication like memory and
so forth
in the last reason we study out performances
there is tons of fun
OK you know speed is always fun right
like why do people unified fast cars raise racehorses you know
you know whatever OK it out rockets et cetera what do that has been this
far in case he likes to ski i lot
i was going fast schemes are going on
OK hockey passports right
we all like the fast sports
not all of us and some people say
it's not talking to me
so let's move on
so that's a little bit of a notion as to why we study this is
that it does in some sense former common basis for all these other things we
care about
so we want to understand how can we generate money for ourselves
in computation
so we start out with a very simple problem
twenty oldest problems it has been studied in
as the problem of sort
OK we're actually study this for several lectures
OK so we're we're going to because sorting contains many algorithmic techniques
so the sorting problem is the following
in the sequence
a one
o two
up to and
of numbers
as input
the output
is a permutation of the numbers
OK permutation is a rearrangement of the numbers
however number appears exactly once in the rearrangement such that so i sometimes use dollar
sign to mean such that
k such that
anyone who wants to become a two
such that their monotonically increasing
OK so take bunch numbers
put them in order
so his algorithm to do is called insertion sort
right this algorithm
what we call
it's sort of programming language except it's got english and often
OK and just a shorthand for writing
the for being precise
OK so this sort
a from one
here's the code for it
this is what we call
if you don't understand the pseudocode then
you should ask questions about an notations you start to get used to it as
we go on one thing is that in the pseudo code we use indentation where
in most languages they have some kind of begin and the limiters like curly braces
or something in java see for example OK we just use indentation the whole idea
of the pseudocode is to try to get the algorithms the shortest possible
while still understanding what the individual steps are
in practice there actually been languages that use indentation as a means of showing
the nesting of things is generally a bad idea because when you page from one
if things go over one page to another for example
OK you can tell
what level of nesting it is
whereas with with explicit braces it's much easier to tell so whether the reasons why
this is a bad notation
OK if you writing if you're doing software engineering but good one for us because
it just keeps things short makes fewer
fewer things to write down
so this is insertion sort let's try to figure out a little bit what this
it basically takes array a
at any point
the thing to understand is so we're going to switch setting basically running the outer
loop from j is to to and in the inner loop that starts at
j minus one
and then goes down until its
until it's
so basically
so if we look at any point in the algorithm we essentially you're looking at
some element here j
a j
j element
what we do is essentially as we pull value out here that we call the
and at this point
the important thing to understand is and we'll talk more about this in recitation on
is that there is an invariant that's being maintained
why this loop
each time through
the invariant used this part of the you re
is sorted
and the goal is time through the loop
is to increase
is to increase is to add one to the length of things that are sorted
the way we do that as we pull out the key
and we just copy
values up like this
keep popping up
OK until we find the place where this key
so long as
so is see four
easy to the code
is it uniquely decodable
what we're trying to do here is so sail close to where you want to
make all codewords as short as possible because that's good news but we don't sail
to close and
have problems if you need the code ability
so a
is this uniquely decodable
you could stare hard lessons and try figure out
is some other interpretations so really long a zero one how could we get a zero one
it has to be a sea doesn't say something can't i see
and we look at this this and
there are what could be its thinking hard looking the codebook
and we say and well maybe
well there's a zero hey could be an animal eh
am then
but it could have been
maybe it was there
i hear
and no one zero maybe other dehaan
and then there's a zero
from somewhere
it is difficult to decode because i'm not quite sure especially if we haven't
reached the end yet
it's not clear what's going on
can anyone gives a proof that it's actually not uniquely decodable
preferred mainly find two strings that have exactly the same
these say
okay so if you
in code
do see
it gives you a zero one zero sorry
this is
as you one zero
zero one zero okay
it had got another string that also encodes
do you
zero zero
one zero world
so if we call this x
and this why
different but they've got the same encoding so it's not uniquely notable okay
so this is useless or not
uniquely decodable
what's going on
let's get ourselves one more example
sixty five
is fee five
zero zero
zero one
one zero
on what
can explain it like this
rolling stones
so that's not has
good has this one
i felt give you a few more
so i'm gonna further ideas
anyway we can improve yeah
various suggesting takes it to
andy between the last word surrogacy six
using one
there are lot
zero zero one
but you're saying you don't actually need the final punctuation character because once you've seen three zeros
if you're using theta you know what is coming next
so you can get rid of it
all right
okay so the length of one two three hand three
which incidentally
are the same as the shannon information content let's scholars age i
one bit two bits three bits and prevents
so the expected length
which is the average length is gonna be the same as we
average share information content which is
which is already worked back
so that's one and three quarter
which is the entropy
right so that's a fun idea we've got a symbol code whose expected length is the entropy
if we encode see eh
then we get
there's a long
zero one
there so simple
procedure in fact we can try this
on some real data which is what kamal mangan who was here just moments ago
ah giving a talk to use your second speaker today
in fact his phd thesis was on this very topic
and here's from his work
ah the algorithm and this is just what we said it would be that is
given the set of labelled documents
and some other on labelled documents
the first step is to build an initial classify
from the labelled documents only
this he EM process where on the east that we use the current trained class
of fire
but stayed here to indicate the set of parameters that we've learned for the naive
bayes fire
to estimate
membership the beach on labelled document in each class that is the probability
that um
the document will
belong to that class so assigning probabilistic labels these documents and then on the m
step really estimate the class of fire that is retrain it using those probabilistic will
applied labels
can make sense
right so long
and we did that how long will we do it until the status stop changing
from one iteration to the next or the change becomes very small
and that on
we know that's going to happen eventually because this procedure is guaranteed to increase the
expected data likelihood on each iteration so eventually
something the step size is large enough eventually it's going to reach a local optimum
and at that point it will stop changing and then will be done
OK so now let's look at what happens in practice if we tried this gonna
skip over some equations but
if you're interested you can look at the paper the citation to the papers in
your notes and here the equations but they basically are just saying what
what i said is an equation forgetting the priors on the class label y
i'm sorry not the priors but this is the probability of the class being the
y value being a particular class given the document high
and just like you talked already
about naive bayes that involves looking at
the individual words w
and the probability of those words showing up conditioned on the class label
and then in the m step we retrain
the two main parameters from the naive bayes class fire that is the probability distribution
on each word
given the class
in the problem prior probabilities of the classes
and i think you covered that already right in previous
so those the equations for especially
and step are little bit more
ah complicated than the first version of naive bayes you saw
why because now we have to
modify this to deal with probabilistic labels the labels aren't just
yes or no spam or not instead we get these probabilistic labels
point eight spam point two nine
but other than that it's very straightforward
i maybe more interestingly given the amount of time we have to look at what
really happens
in the class of fire from one iteration to the next
so this will show this shows some results of running the CN process
on a set of data which is web pages
these web pages were being classified either as
our web pages home pages of
academic course
we're not
and in this particular set of data there i remember there are very few oh
is one labelled example per class
so there's one example just one document which is the course home page
i recall there were many but i don't remember how many on labelled documents but
it was on the order of the thousand
so now what do we do this season now is we apply the CN procedure
what we do is
was the first step we take that one
labelled document that we have we train a naive bayes classify around
in doing that we're gonna do is we're going to learn these parameters of the
class of that is what's the probability that the word shoe
i will occur given that it is
of course
page was the probability of the word shoe will occur given that it's not of
course page and similarly for the other fifty thousand words of english
OK now having training
just on their first iteration suppose we stop in now we have the program print
this topic
twenty words
ah that it has learned are the most
i the best discriminator is of course pages from not course pages
that is we could do is we could print out each we could rank order
the words by the probability
the odds ratio the probability of the word will occur given
ah there it's part of course page divided by the probability of the word occurring
given that it's not of course page
if we do that these are the words we get on the left
so now if you look at those words you see
you can probably guess what that single training example course page was about
the derivative with respect to a lot of blocks
to the one hand
whatever it is
right so that's the first factor that we're going to use rather than actually
right out of variable for it
and and pat passed through as i did previously with this y and x variable
here i'm just going to skip that step
and i'm going to let you imagine it as being a placeholder for a variable
so this variables now
and then i have to multiply that by the rate of change of what's inside
with respect to x and that is going to be a minus two
right the derivative of one minus x squared is
this minus two x
and now again
our arming everything together here we could have done this example two
before example one
because we needed to know
the power rule worked
not just for a integer but also for a equals the half
we're using the case equals the half right here is one half times
and this minus half here is
a minus one
right so this
it is the case a equals one half a minus one happens to be minus
OK so i'm putting all those things together and you know
within a week you have to be doing this very automatically so we're going to
do it at the speed now you want to do it even faster ultimately yes
the question is could i have done it implicitly without these square roots and the
answer is yes that's what i'm about to do
so this is an illustration of what's called the explicit
solutions of this guy
is what's called explicit
i want to contrast it with the method that we're gonna now use today so
it involves a lot of complications of of the chain rule as we'll see if
it can get messier and messier
and then there's the implicit method
which i claim is easier
all right so let's see what happens if you do it implicitly
the implicit method
instead of writing the function in this relatively complicated with with the square root
it involves leaving it alone
don't do anything to it
in this previous case we were left with something which was complicated say
next to the one for x one have something complicated we had to simplify it
we use we had in equation one which is more complicated we simplified and then
and so that was the simpler case we'll hear the simplest thing for us to
simplest equation for to differentiate
is the one we started with
because squares to be practically the easiest thing after first powers or maybe zero power
to differentiate
so we're leaving along this is the simplest possible form for an hour going to
so what happens we get so again what's the matter let me remind you your
applying by dx to the equations you have to differentiate the left side of the
and differentiate the right side of the equation so it's this
and what you get is
two acts loss
why why
is equal to
derivative of one is it
right so
this is the chain rule again i did
a different way and try to get used to many different notations at once
well really just to just the prime notation in the d y dx notation
and this is what i get
all right
so now
i have to do is solve for y prime
so that y prime if i put the two x on the other side is
minus two as and then divide by
two y
which is minus x y
all right so let's compare are solutions
i apologize and going to have to raise something to to do that
so let's compare two solutions
i'm going to put this underneath and simplified so what was our solution over here
it was passed
one minus x squared to the miners to have
times minus two acts
that was what what we got over here
and that is the same thing if i cancel the to use
and i change it back to looking like a square root that's the same thing
as minus x divided by square root of one minus x square
right so this is the
formula for the derivative what i do with the explicit way
and i'll just compare them
these two expressions here
and then notice that they are the same
all right there the same because y
is equal to
where one minus
the question is why did the implicit method not give the bottom half of the
very good question
c one to c and
you must as is demanding property
all these
so what does this double sum
there's be superior to zero
so this is the definition of this family of functions which are called positive if
you can
so i was for that and the symmetry
you have
also you need those cells the symmetry
so why i'm talking about this
class of functions
in fact this family of functions prison
the property that
we were looking for so for any
was it even if you can indicate on the set x
there exist
and in that space
and so in nineteen five
four x
two s
such that
k of x and i x prior can be written
as you know product in this
in the space f
as the scalar product inner product between five
x five
exp right
we have the characterisation
we have the addition of the sun
which presents protein
and what we are doing now
instead of deleting like mad two lectures in pattern recognition
searching for some function phi
we're going to call that is probably too such
for some
cannot function k
which are nice properties which the we result
what events which gives we didn't insights in our data data presentation
so remember that
in any problem where we have such
the function k
it will be
as if we were able to work in the feature space is
it is
transform the was five
in this case any learning algorithm should sit in optimisation and the reason is that
in fact in the reasons that only involves
the product between data
can benefit
for these properties of chemical
since it was to canada
and this property is called the kernel trick is this one
it is corsican create because was in skeleton creek
one not
it's not necessary to work in the future might can just work these
so affectionately
so so far
we have two spaces of interest
this the first
space can be all set
we have no restriction on that
we have an input space to an output space and we have also feature space
now we are going to consider and space of interest and maybe this is the
most important part of course issue we need
two if you really want to understand can
you need not only to consider
data point of view but you also need to consider the
estimation point of
so i'm going to give you three or four slide
some information
about ten years ago but i think that's page
which is linked with the yours
user spaces which we've looked at
it will become clear unclear
during the course
how how much
this sport but diffusion properties and so on so on
so for the moment just have to trust trust
let's consider that we have some candidate k
associated with space x
and now we are looking at the following set of functions
we look as set h
a function s
from x
and this function is a linear combination of the
gamma cannot functions but
with some six scalar functions are fixed here with some
o point o point in the index
so x
so let's consider functions that can be written like this
you combination
let's consider
the following no
so we are we going to define the
it was this is space
and we have the tools
was just as the city that is the following
the scaffolding
in fact
as the said i'm talking about this class of a function f
these are the best space
there is an inner product
the final
as follows
and so the norm
can defined from this kind of for
and in this address space
you have very nice properties so i just w two y
do you have some reminder
vote i space
OK sorry
i thought it was
and before
OK so what is about space
you have two things you have
algebraic properties of topological properties sorry i'm going to first
well is a little more
all right
it turns out
o five one
o fire
one of my own
know what mean
are people
here he is
all of that
it was really about
they are
you load
when was
one these
the rest
on the in
one one
think they are
well what is
well designed
o it
one of
this error
in this
the only one
i this is my
well i was
so anyway
we have to
you are
my where
the error
one of
it we
well if we
o o o
you are very often
i think that is
also the
thank you
one piece of glass
if you are in
one of the
two years
we should look like
and that was what
he wrote to
the last here so what
look we take nondeterministic objects for given input i
several possible culprits
my input if
this is exactly like nondeterministic
o automaton musical automata automata
ultimate and
the reach financing
OK so i think nondeterministic automata in general but it's even more important that
for the case of the determinisation c one that tells you that every time i
the general setting would be nondeterministic objects and you have to to keep your expressiveness
as usual
they have transition on a full binary tree
so it's very easy
i read the label
on the current node
o tree
what do i do try to transition
all about time goes on the left to something on the right to some states
c tree with my computation
so imagine i start with an input
i stay here
the sort of thing in the system at the for
so you forget about this for the moment and this is my talk where he
and i a
then this is the two used that in every it
this is the two states i will consider so let me get this is the
tree in you
so it's an infinite tree
and what i have is that b and under these
and i just didn't i mean i didn't just the beginning so how history
i give to my it q
right so what is the current situation to i put
let's say this tree
and my
current state the current state of
i refer to the
and you will be
the fault
on the left you will do
so my computation forms the true to form a binary tree
well now
here in make predictions is pointing to simple this has
as we did
that is reason the difference is that here OK
i will branch as before because this was here reads a
i have school now define it QA and every AI branch
but i brushed and i will tell you is
now here if you have a look whatever when
i think the
some of the top top now so it means that here whatever i had
could average stop and now that the only subtrees of a tree with where
to understand the principle of the common interest across states your original input i tells
continue as the tree
and you keep going input so here as you say you see
if n
this is that in general
and i'm going to me i don't deterministic tree automata
i mean it you either i just
the main branch and
a little girl to all other states
and you will be in this direction
in one of those two cases
the radiation will go straight through
so i'll hold it in there and the receiver
in a situation the radiation will not go through with will be reflected
i'm asking you
to make a prediction
i really think that if i hold the call like this
in the b that means like this
the radiation will go through will the radiation to be reflected
what do you think that in this case
the radiation will go through
or whether they reflect so let's have a vote on that
but first i want to ask class
if i hold
in the brain
like this
do you think that the wave will be reflected who thinks that the wave will
be reflected
o thing is that the way to go straight through
o thing that in this case
the way go straight through
o things that will be reflected in this case
actually quite impressed by your answers most of the time i get
more wrong answers the correct answers
it is in this case
that's the way is practically four hundred percent reflected
and it is in this case
that the way go through
and if you have a a good understanding about the currents running in these
at the surfaces
to make sure that you meet the boundary conditions you will be able to give
the answer for yourself
if you can
then see me
or write the email what i want you to think about it a little bit
for yourself
so i will demonstrate now
so we have this
ten gigahertz signals modulated with five hundred and fifty
this sounds so you can hear it
the only reason why we
modulated you can hear it's that's the sound
the first like
i can
i wrote it
this situation goes this way
my hand is not the best not of one very i think
i think or even in the con was conducted
with flash flood information through
this experiment
to give you some insight
into the secret behind edwin land
linear polarizer for
we never discussed
that the radiation
that it's this displayed
is not linearly polarized but is completely unpolarized
then the component in this direction will be reflected
but only the component in this direction will be allowed through
that becomes a linear polarizer that's the whole idea behind the linear polarizer so this
in no way for radar a linear polarizer shine only on polar radar
and all components in this direction will be gone only this component will go through
so linearly radar light to come out
so it may give you some thoughts about how the optical
arises work
what they do is they aligned strings of molecules in such a way that
get the behavior
not like
these metal bars
i want to change gears
and i want to talk
for any kind of odd radiation pressure
in modern physics
we don't think of electromagnetic radiation this plane parallel ways which are infinite in all
but we think of them as bullets
spectators waves
called photons
photos can be produced by for instance atoms or molecules
if there in an excited state
and then the KDD k two lower energy state they can radiate
just one photo
but for adults
in our modern physics
have momentum if you throw to mate with me
and it goes it's a rotten tomatoes goal
i feel obliged not to make a lot of you know me
so i feel the force
and in that same way
the lights
when it hits me
push only
and that's what i want to discuss
as you
first of all
the energy
we have so many nice today even any off and
and we have e which was effective now we have for energy to all righty
and here
this there's no for energy
energy in a photon is mark strong's constant times the frequency of the photon
not and constant course plays a key role in quantum
six point six three
times ten to the minus thirty four
joel seconds
you tell me what the frequency is
i'll tell you what the energies which is very different from the classic idea that
we always said well the energy is proportional
thirty electric field strength square
and we have plane waves would infinite in this direction infinite in this direction so
as always an infinite energy into a wave of plane waves
take an example take radio waves
the only one example
so we take ten megahertz ten to seven
also relations per second sort it would be a wavelength of about thirty metres
one photo
contains an
and these radio photo was this frequency has exactly the same energy is quantized amount
of energy
and if you substitute
for this we consider you put multiplied by eight
you get that the energy
is about six
o point six times ten to the minus
twenty seven joules
in physics we
i don't like to work with so very small numbers so often converted into what
we call electron volts
clearly this includes erdos-renyi as a as a special cases, if all I care about is just the number of edges
but we can throw in many different things, so what is different here is that this this model has no analytical solution, so you can't analyze
analyze it and you you can't
or people you can't make statements, how how how the graphs will look like, but what you can do is you can fit it to the data
how how do you do if the fitting is to use some kind of simulation, so you have sort of doing local moves on the graph
like you you are adding or removing edges, you are moving edges or you are and you are basically doing edge swaps and you do parameter estimation through maximum likelihood and how the parameter estimation would look like is something like this, right, you say so this is my parameter, this is my my property and this is the the the value of that parameter in this
linear sum here here that would get me the probability of observing that graph
this is very nice but what's the problem is, for example
we can't solve it for for transitivity, so what would happen is that, so what I mean by transitivity is that there are triangles in the network, right , so this would mean what's the probability that my friends know each other
right and in social networks this is something that
occurs very often, but this model even if you are able to
to to count the number of suck such structures is not able to
to say
to to spread them around the networks, so as soon as you start caring about the triangles, it would
pretty much just group all of them in some particular part of the network, right, because all you care about is the number of them, not that they are evenly split around
here is
here's another
famous model that just cares about modeling this transitivity
right modeling
how how my f whe whether my friends know each other or not and this is by watts and strogatz from ninety-eight
and we can think
you can think of this as the network is on some kind of
lives in some kind of space, so we have some kind of network distance between the nodes and how this model will work is that we'll start with a low-dimensional regular lattice like a grid or something and then we will have this rewiring operation where we'll add and remove edges
at random to to
to remo to join nodes that are farther apart in the network
and what I mean by that is is the following right, so if you start with some regular network, right, so here every node is connected to to their immediate neighbors, right
to to neighbors each each way, right, and what we can do now is we can start picking nod edges nodes uniformly at random and start swaping the edges
and as we as we as we as we are doing this is at one side we have this completely regular network, I don't know, a grid or something or a things thing like this and on the other end of the spectrum we have a random network right, as we go and permit swap all the edges, all all this regular
structure is lost
and here somewhere in the middle
we will have as it turns out we will have
small diameter and we will also have clustering and what I mean by that is the following
what I'm plotting here is, so here I have the rewiring probability, right, on this side
you can think of this as being a regular graph
a grid and here
this is a erdos-renyi random graph, right
and this what I'm showing here, so this is the mean distance between the nodes right on a grid the distance is large
I'll I when the graph gets completely random, the distance is small
and what I'm showing here is
clustering coefficient, which which you can think of as how many triangles in the network are closed
right, so how many wha or you can think of it as what's what's the probability that two of my friends know each other, right
and if two of my friends know each other, now we are forming a triangle
and what this shows is that
he scored
not at all
now they
he all
and this
much more my
more efficient
and provision
on three
people of the
o you're not
so you
it has to be
and this
we have three
when the first of
of main
all the species or old
it was
i one a
the o station of
it is
the first
i was very
well that
one all
you know
right now
the vision
and they were
in the
one of the number
mark this
set x
that capture the so-called extension of such
anything is
it is true that if you have
so it's in x
something belongs
the set of all can example
and that's something very intuitive unfortunately lead to problem
if we let
a little are being
the set of all
x such that
doesn't belong to itself going and problems trouble right
use and here
so that's the formula right with lyon
formula y
say seven
so for all y y
they have
why does not
belong to one
so that so far as as in problem exactly is all what we can say
x belong
if and only if
x not long
x does not belong to access is put that in this was engaged
this can be a problem right
i don't think twice and survey
that wouldn't be a problem
now to problem can
and if we assume the middle temple we know that
perhaps it belongs to itself or doesn't but if it doesn't it doesn't
parents at contradiction
OK so that's kind of bad press box
one reply
it's popular here in australia trust is to say well maybe there's some sets that
have contradictory properties properties
and this is an extremely rare c called bility
direly theism
holds that
formulas in both balls not all
some of
both false
the last set valley business site of for a lot
contradictions around
although that it was called naive comprehension scheme
say that
for a start this idea that
i had to set that corresponds to a that sounds nice
like this well things worse even for the daily atheist
some well currys paradox
and efficient air using the sequent style calculus and not going do that
instead of the russell said take
and the curries
it is accessed
in fact he was paid the moon is made of green cheese
we don't want to derive
as the moon is not made of green cheese
we don't want to prove falsities
but also remember p could be anything in chesapeake pick whatever he wants
so what was the problem as well
now we do the same sort of thing we did before
we instantiate the and it looks harmless enough
and then we instance y to x
i mean look let's start a little bit scary
from this
we can do that
this called
sorry from this we can derive that that the whole contraction that's just
and elimination this this means that the simple as that and this implies that it's
just an abomination that sort of noun we contract
this has to do w we had before
shouldn't everest
he says that
if a then if a then b
just as a and b
i think if if twice the
present at any
and that's to move you can recognise recognizes
but in classical logic you can do the truth is if you want this also
valid and the relevant logic r one with
i told you about four
look at this we have the
on the classic that to date
build the web of data by applying these principles
we all know about the shortcomings of the classic web so content is not about
structured just text
this text you can only do certain things you can't do other things like expressive
and you can't
process stuff from the that in the applications like important data into your address book
compared the end of course and things like that
so what we actually would like to do under that is used to cook
complete that as a single global data
we don't want to just three
separate data sources like we do today we don't want just query you may agree
with a lot of data sources i would say you want to query all data
sources without
all data sources all
other structured information that has been published so want end up as a situation where
we can use the complete that like a single global data
so how do you get there
but publishing structured information on the web
in addition to classic HTML page
as information is publisher structured we can do some other things with it
so currently different approaches around for doing this is that API is the microformat and
this is kind of
new concept of linked data
i don't know why you're machine
changes my numbering
o starts usually starts with two
so that if you eyes see or or knows this of that keeps a list
of all available be so
basically all the major that data sources have published API by now
people are writing interesting mashups based on these API
so if you also go to pull glamour that you get a couple hundred
mash ups combining elements of this stuff is that
the interesting thing about the positive things about these ABI's is that they expose structured
so we can do lot things as the state
and the new applications
the negative thing about that API is is that each API has its own puppetry
as have the property interfaces
you as an application developer of us have to decide which API i want to
use for application and then program against this proprietary interface
i usually based on a fixed set of data
they're not
and based on the complete
some things that linked data is aiming to change
and that's the problem this
this API is is that
you can not set hyperlinks between data items and the different data
so kind of
the hyperlinks that the things that
the glue that kept the complete that together that made it into a single information
space and you can't do this this is the classic web API
so that the API kind of slice of that into separate data silos
and the cool applications by programming against the silos but they they stay silent
i'm not going to talk about michael pollan
OK so linked data
the idea is to overcome his silencing
by using semantic web technologies ontology is to publish structured data on the web
and to set links between data items from different data sources
so what we want to end up this is an as single information space this
time not for documents but for data built on the same principle some content standards
some universality the mechanism and the idea of links said lose all the published data
to together interesting information
this is all based on
this idea is based on the linked data principles that had been has been
lined out by tim berners-lee in two thousand seven so kind of the technical guidelines
to build this global information space
use URI is to identify things all kinds of things we wrote things online things
use http wires
so that people can look up things
meanings that
every URI on the semantic that has to be two references
if somebody is interested in what's in a URI refers to just
he just put it into
the semantic web browser just you reference it always about
he says that he doesn't want HTML is on so he says that he wants
RDF is not so much he gets information
this is the
and of the
the main difference between what has been done
the momenta community for quite awhile
all these applications working with this
rdf in their local storms
now is this requirement two
really use HTTP URI is and make these URI
the reference
if someone looks up a URI provide useful RDF information source of something
in the stuff that you give back to include links to other data sources
this is the part that connects everything
two the semantic web
so how does it work in practice we have some
small RDF graph describing the sky occurred
saying that he is the person
and his name and he is based on the goal
we look at the name space here we see that both namespaces
this is something only counts so before into his profile full profile this is the
URI in the BPR namespace
both URI is at the reference above so you can look up look out for
more date
so if somebody is interested now in
this was sort of billion
more information about
he just the references URI on semantic web says give me data about poland is
give it to me in in you
so what happens