situation where your algorithm
you know it
you don't really need to clustering it's OK to have three
then will be able to say a lot more about that
OK so this is natural because
melodic itself if you want to cluster search results so you do have very good
about advantage mccluster very naturally cluster them by tree and then you can click you
know you can see our because support versus science science this victory is click on
elsewhere in the math and physics OK of course you they click on it and
then let the user decide you know how they click so they want to have
specific to
and then another and so not required clustering of figure
so the claim is if we allow the clustering outcome this little bit more flexibility
then will be able to say more
properties that we can use
but in the end you you could go all the way down to
document so
but still that doesn't make it trivial problem because
you still need to be and someone thinking it should be afraid to find if
i was thinking of
basketball physics is one topic baseball union methods that topic that's not printing industry
OK because
we're five you know
maybe to be a little more
suppose i think baseball one topic everything else in the world is another topic
there are people like that
that's also another printing industry
it's not
baseball america also so printing is is setting some of these points to the we
i said this to believe that after that the
so this would be that would not be consistent with this property in fact if
you think about baseball for everything else
then the problem is this basketball things are not actually more similar
everything overall topic and everything because it was based on
so so the claim is actually if we relax gold this way we can start
to china
person thinks of as
as theoretician so that that's the the
my mind trying to say if you would like to know what proper fish we
can get into trouble if we require our actually output clustering was approximately correct but
if we allowed happen we can say all the more so for example
this property turns out to be sufficient and actually this property only is sufficient but
sufficient to cluster with extremely simple out across schools algorithm or single linkage basically the
algorithm is you take the two points are most similar you join them so in
general you've got some collection of clusters
and the point time find the pair of documents that are most similar but are
in different clusters and merge the two clusters
OK so this is the same as cross schools
minimum spanning tree algorithm except for using most similar instead of police this
merge and claim if you do this then this will in fact find the right
answer and
just because you picture man the right
so the claims will produce trees to the right answer is in fact the printing
tree in one way to see that the to this example let's imagine that the
right answer is this one and the other and so far arguments produced these blocks
so right now are going to start merging so we start so we start with
everybody in their own cluster
i should have said that we started in their own cluster step one and then
we repeatedly find most similar pair points in different clusters merge those clusters to
i suppose in this process we now have this this this this and this is
the claim is it or merging could be this or this or this would never
merged for instance this
so why is that well together picking the most similar pair by definition enough EX
here y here the sex is actually more similar to all these
why was more more to the so we would never have the case that these
two are the most
so you're guaranteed emerging that you're clusters are either pieces of the right answer with
are you collections of clusters
OK so this is nice because it means really
a very strong simple property or to imply
a simple our
here's another condition which is kind of fun
but you can also show sufficient to scurvy condition
so this one or instead we're not required everybody is strictly more similar to everybody
else cluster anybody for establishing require stability condition is kind of like the stable marriage
problem so using the stable marriage problem this is kind of like that for clusters
the condition if you have a vacuum so
condition we want here is for all pairs of clusters c and c prime
for all subsets a cluster c and a primary clusters prime it's not the case
i want not to be the case with these two
its approximation for the euclidean distance and it allows us to reduce the dimension chris
what's interesting it's very efficient search for the hamming distance
and the very few people and those of very complex operations comparison and reduces also
the the memory access so actually in the end it's times faster than the standard
bag of features approach
and so it's interesting how do we obtain
hamming embedding
so first of all we have to
we have to draw
we have to define
the projection directions so here would be dropped if we use we can either learn
them from data or we can just use
randomly chosen are orthogonal projections
we then use these matrices to protect our descriptor vectors down into some
this representative space
they determine the median
of descriptors which line itself
this is the point for comparison
and then
depending of of if the point lies on the left or the right bigger smaller
than the median value is either zero or one
OK so this allows us to obtain binary coding of the vectors in the cell
and these vectors can then be
compared with the hamming distance we can again use the threshold suppose you can say
we have to some threshold similar so they don't have to follow it have to
find exactly the self-same cell but they can fall into similar
i mean this part
which is similar right
and then for online computation compute the binary signature if given the script director protecting
in into according to coordinate system and finding one about development three million value the
way zero
OK so now we have representation in this space
and you can look at the trade between
memory usage x currency
and here what we do is like comparing the number of people right number of
projection directions so the maximum would be twenty to twenty eight which is the maximum
size of our descriptor which is the size of our descriptor
and it would be very very very small representation right and what you can see
the rate of cell points retrieved
and here the rate of five nearest neighbors retrieved we can actually see it obviously
the more
my dimensions you
we use the better results get
you can also see that even if the presentation is pretty small much better than
arbitrary filtering we do actually really improve the matching accuracy of our selves basically this
would be just mexico city of cells and then back the
systems on top of it really improves the accuracy of our matching so anybody doing
now be getting much closer to matching really retrieve the closest descriptors directly from set
of descriptors
and so depending on
if you want to favor memory or a security you can
you can either use the lower higher dimensions were used for the experiments we forty
sixty eight sixty four bit is the representation
and if you compare it here
because she had initially seen
for the k nearest neighbour for the k
vocabulary based on k means you can see here so basically read the curve obtained
by bag of words
and the blue ones by adding the hamming
hamming embedding right and what's changed on this blue curve is the distance so if
the distance is the for
number of different this to obtain the same results just obtain the results of the
points that fall into the cell without filtering and then then by
making the distance smaller and smaller we filled out more and more points we can
see here
and if you look at the current for example if you look at the curve
k equals
the point k one hundred that the blue curve you can see that for
for the same level of recall
people retrieve ten times less points right so we really improve the performance of our
so it really performs provide a much better trade off between recall and ambiguity of
what's really interesting effects
four very low cost so all you have to do is to start this additional
by these band signatures for descriptor and compare them
based on the bit comparison this was you have missed to still ones
and if you look at the example you can see here
OK this is this is the result obtained the hamming embedding
further vocabulary of twenty
this but you know word
and here is are the hamming embedding and you can really see that by adding
the hamming embedding
it allows to remove
four of script false matches without removing correct ones right
so these ones are the ones obtained just by finding descriptive words and this one
is the ones obtained if you to compare this to the hamming distance
and another example
again this same example if you look
and the much larger village of vocabulary so here two hundred thousand visual words you
can see that actually compared to the one to obtain embedding you don't remove was
may descriptors right
if you increase the size of the vocabulary of more more more was that
OK and so the second contribution
is the geometric consistency constraints
so the state of the art systems they are based
on the ranking with full geometric verification so what you do once the system has
returned to short list of images is take for example if a hundred best retrieved
images when you verify the german consistency between the query image and the returned images
example by estimating homography based on the matches between the two images right and this
is pretty costly
so you can
definitely not familiar images people can i add to four hundred but you could also
go straight up two thousand
however if you look at the graph here so when you look what you see
on the x axis you see the size of the dataset right and the the
more increases
the more
the rate of relevant images in the shortlist decreases right so here you can see
here if you have one million of images images which are in the short list
here if you take a short list of one hundred images only twenty percent
of the correct t twenty images in the short list
so basically here even if you user the geometric verification many nice
image is missing so basically the ones which are in here we can move them
in the in the shortest ranking but all the others you won't find them even
if you go up to one thousand images you can see still see
only fifty percent of the images have returned so many of them missing right so
you have to
so what thought about how can improve this without going up to the full
geometric verification so the idea of
is to introduce
some very simple german quite quite consistency checks
which can be implemented all images and not just for short list of images so
in the military for the millions of images and so what is our approach based
so yes initially that we extract effect of invariant image regions right so for each
region we have for example
seven find information scale and rotation angle associated with you can see actually the size
of the region is the scale
the rotation angle is the is some some angle which gives the rotation of the
innovation to x-rays and so you need the different tools and carbon ions
i think it's which today are considered to be the best
numbers of potential patients now i ask you to read this number into scale
two your own country likely enough you can have so many accounts so you can
compute how many
potential applications that are in your country folk cultures and down on the first those
number that you should not forget every ten million inhabitants in the which was twenty
thousand patients a year can exploit
is after all the people getting accounts for forty thousand pounds of ten million inhabitants
per year after them are treated with x-rays together with
chemotherapy and surgery many that's what that according to studies made in the framework of
the light bulb mentioned but later for percentage of the should get protontherapy today this
is that made in this country two thousand four hundred
and with carbon ions four assistant you should be three percent of them so six
so you see there are three thousand pages and
if i you remember to do that
normally in that case one thousand five hundred patients per year
he began sentech the complete two thousand patients but you means that one needs at
least today
the centre of the type issued new every ten million inhabitants which is very far
from what we have in hand in the world
one of the centres for carbon ion therapy centers for company said the one is
this a high or
the center in fact is not new it started in two thousand seven but for
carbon ions only treated patients for a couple of years
it is made by mitsubishi is a single from twenty five metres lin
as you
think and and focal tools and tools for carbon c
his ontology particularly inclined to this is the centre the second sentence in japan then
come back there
of carbon and so p is expanding the facility to add new facility with the
minimum standards so this will be working very so so in japan it would be
and there is this such thing to be three sentence to sentence in two years
and in four years three centres for carbon ions in the good design has pushed
the construction heidelberg obvious center which is called heat hydrogen ions have been
this is close to the ospital in heidelberg
the medical that they always looked to the user should utility doctor other physicists techniques
like this is synchrotron the that
and again to in almost and because
the band
carbon ions from this energy take three times more field
or use then to bend problems
both treatment so you need much more again much larger much larger and issued this
this again this is the same
the center this building
you see this again is twenty four metres
it's not as complicated as CMS but it is quite a complicated object to put
a gnostic tendency is not to put this in their all space so the just
is large to put such again in hospital then the jump to put to sea
it's the
the patient is sitting here and siemens medical is
taken all those
knowledge from just built you see
this global system in which the patients who received very soon because the first patient
treated within months and this is the same of carbon ions which showed set of
course the patient
come for carbon ions to be less than four total ten twenty times only to
the center but we see all
there is zero which is not very different from an
because you see here
the foundation there which i created with friends in nineteen two
has done two things
we have proposed and designed the dual national center will is the when you accelerate
carbon ions can also photos
which is being built in the south of milan long as also and then designing
new works type of accelerator call cyclinac football also carbon ions something about this
this is a project which i started when i was at
all right
last but not least a few things about writing
writing one of the those things that you might be able to tell from this
little board over here is something if i didn't have to do i wouldn't do
it because i honestly as corn is the sound i just believe in the love
of learning like i think it's passion about something just go do it you learning
but i'm naive and so that's not the way learning always works sometimes we actually
need grading to make sure the learning takes place in the desired rate breaks down
forty five percent of your great is on the programme this time k
fifteen percent in the mid term which is called the media because we like to
abbreviate everything thirty percent in the final
it's a three hour final exam in the regular final time slot for this class
if you think you are under the delusion that you should take two classes the
same time that bad idea because their final exams at the same time OK so
you should not take the exact two classes the same time and because the final
exam is scheduled for i believe it's december thirteenth which is the thursday twelve fifteen
to three fifteen that's the regular final exams slot for this class in any other
cluster the same time will conflict with that slide thirty percent generated the final and
that if you add it all up
it's not just that map it's because ten percent of the great is actually participation
and this is things like did you go to your interactive training sessions did you
regularly attend section did you participate in section they do participate in class right and
so in order to help you participate in class
there is little incentive to participate in class which is sugar in the afternoon so
someone raised their hand
all right
yeah i sometimes i'm not a good shot and this will tell you if you're
sitting in the back of i i tend to kick back because there are little
outside it is in the back of the room the roof prevents me from actually
being able to hear you so if you want to food come up but if
you ask questions in class
and that's a good time it's just a way to be able to reward you
for actually participating in class or to keep your blood sugar up if you need
all right so that's participation attempt any random and effective end the quarter i ask
everyone your section leaders to actually tell me how much to participate in class and
some of them you know to salespersons wonderful became every time he participated it's just
great thing and that helps you great out a lot
now the final thing and as you can can tell most of the time not
the most serious person in the world i would like to have fun things i
think it's important for you to have one thing there's just one place where i
get real serious and it's one place where stanford real serious and we want to
guess what that is
plagiarism and the honor code that fact that's what we call social so we have
someone down here
and then all the people who i don't know
we just spread
the honor code
in terms of the honor code the question comes up is what is the code
all about how does that affect working in you know groups in computer science et
cetera the i mean we shouldn't talk each each other no
the answer to all those is no OK if you look at hand i number
four which is all about the honor code we encourage you to talk to each
other we encourage you to talk about concepts in the class talk about different strategies
to problems to think about the way that you could potentially approach some problem or
the way different control construction and eventually get them work in the class and discussion
is perfectly fine especially among the core staff but also amongst yourself that's the great
thing so where do we draw the line we try to make a bright line
for where you've crossed the line for the honor code which is
i don't know
share code
plain and simple
in any respect
OK don't give a file to someone else's car code don't get code from someone
else to look at someone else's print out don't give them print out if you
have two people who were sitting looking at the same screen together that code can
belong to both of you it belongs to one of you i don't know which
one but it becomes an honor code violation so you should both you know two
people should be staring at the monitor together if it ever gets the point where
you're looking at someone else's code that's where you're going to reach an issue hey
discusses much as you want that's great
write your own code that's all we care about and you're like well what is
called now what that would mean code is speak for your program so when you
program the program that write is what we affectionately referred to as cold and the
idea of programming is what we refer to as coding strangely enough we just you
know we computer i need to make everything more complicated than it really is so
we can get people under the illusion that they should pay lots of money to
do what we do and you're like i just write programs like i actually pay
you have you know i write code now like i certainly it's much more impressive
they don't jericho code the other thing is if you talk to other people like
the other study group to talk about solution approaches or you go to talk to
the tears section leader to how you should approach to problem and they give you
a lot of hints as to how to do it say collaboration
so citing collaboration gets you out of trouble any collaboration that you say you cannot
be held responsible for the honor code you can actually copy someone else's program and
say i copied this program for mary smith and look at the same
they cited and i will warm the cockles of my heart and marry smith will
get full credit you get a zero because you copied your program from mary smith
but it's not an honor code violation because you cited one
the bottom line is cheap yourself safe and secure collaborations and i guarantee you most
of the time will be just fine now you might wonder why do i make
a big deal about this and the reason i make a big deal about this
is for a while thankfully it's not sure anymore before while the computer science department
actually had more honor code violations than the rest of the university combined taken every
everything else in the universe university put them all together they like over like work
which is not fine distinction have and you might wonder why is that the the
science people just mischievious and dishonest you know
it's because it's easier to catch honor code violations in computer science we have a
whole bunch of tools that allows the we take all your programs and run through
this tool on comparison not only to everyone else in here but like to everyone
from the last like x years where x is the large number of people have
ever gone through the classes
right and it's an extremely good tool from finding where honor code violations happen from
where they don't know that's find you know spurious violations to be you know be
honest i've never lost another key coast what i find not OK honor code case
simply here t
and that requires the integration is basically the integration of this distribution is an almighty
to make sure there's no my one
we have to perform this integration
integration can't be done analytically
certainly should say
the choices of priors that will be realistic to use
could use some contrived prize which might work but they wouldn't be sensible
in this application we can't do this and
so a little bit later will look actually doing is numerically shape that still has
some value
mister success we can't do this idealized procedure
look at how
if we contact is precisely how we might approximate
this is sort of pragmatic deviation from the true path if you like
someone david so as we well i talked about being practically pragmatic
when being bayesian inference and this is an example of that
we can't get back full posterior distribution that we want
so we need an approximation
there is
there are number approximation methods this kind of problem
i'm using a particular one
it's called type two maximum likelihood
it's kind of motivated by the idea
that one should
a bit of this distribution
you can calculate
and then do something about the count
so we decompose it so this is
follows on from the other rule of probability
this is an identity we get these two terms
you recognise this one perhaps this is the posterior distribution over the weights looked at
we know we can calculate
at least the second term in the product and that's the bit can't calculate
so we can actually
work at the numerator this distribution but we can't normalise
so is this has to be
approximated i'm calling it the hyperparameter posterior
the joint posterior distribution over the hyperparameter alpha and the noise variance sigma
so this is where the idea type two maximum likelihood comes in this is an
established idea statistics
we start off by
looking at what this actually distribution and we can explain it
by bayes rule
so this is based rules
to give us this
and we have to specify
obviously users coming
prior over alpha the prior sigma squared
this goes back to the question i was at the end
but how we specify
high price and could keep going on and on
one thing we can do
we can express what i call
uninformative or non informative priors on the hyperparameters
and we can simply make them uniform so we can say
we don't actually care
what value these take on going to do in my prior
it just simply say have a uniform probability distribution
not adding any information into the problem
now you'll notice that have actually
it's going to be uniform distribution logarithmic space
and this
one of two possible reasons for doing that
because these
well of called scale parameters that actually variances in this area here
space on which the model
probabilistically is the logarithmic space
and the practical explanation of why that's the case is
sign data t that we measured
was being measurements of length and we were measuring eighteen metres
but then someone else could some data which is exactly the same but they measured
in inches
some reasons for this reason
if we don't make these
prize uniform over long scale
we find that are and we get a different answer to the problem according to
the units of measurement
because any other priors wouldn't be invariant to scale
after rescaling t
so if you believe in your problem but it doesn't matter what the units of
measurement are
then in principle you should choose
i priors over these variables
that are uniform logarithmic scale
just a little bit of an aside
so once we have agreed
these can be uniform
they don't affect the shape of the distribution
in logarithmic space
the key term is therefore this
type two maximum likelihood
we want to maximize find the most probable values under this posterior distribution so we
don't calculate the whole posterior
we simply do this rather non bayesian thing
and calculate the maximum so that we do the MAP estimate the weights
doing something similar
i the hyperparameters here
if we want to maximize this we maximize this to
and this term is called the marginal likelihood
that's really what the phrase type two maximum likelihood comes from
because robert doing maximum likelihood of the parameters
we integrate out the parameters and we do maximum likelihood over this marginal likelihood
the the ninth of
what does it look like less i said
it's simply the likelihood of the data this
appeared earlier was gassing life data
this is the gas in private the weights we had earlier
so we integrate out the weights
that gives this marginal likelihood
which is no longer conditioned on the weights those have been integrated and the nuisance
but it still depends on the hyperparameters
OK so
let's start our development fails to have a document
we need to define what is documented what
the document has
and what we're going to do with this document
usually information world
in march
all the books that are at the root of this topic
which is pretty simple
i have a collection of documents and documents can be divided into work
but in real life i haven't seen any search engine that really used such a
very simple approach
so usually have collection and collection simply sat of all documents that we are going
to put into our search engine
what usually we can divide this collection subcollection even if internet
we can for example divided into that
based on geography which in turn different countries and we can treat it differently so
some somehow we need to
collect this information
but the document is not very simple all
is so what is the current document looking a document is usually divided into the
and you know search engine will have document that is divided into few
and every field campaign
contains work
so what about this field
title of the document a good example of a few
command of what script if we are indifferent email and and subject to another huge
for male lead for for email
why do we need all this stuff why do we need to cover the document
something more complex like we need to extract few and died or tighter or other
uses separate part of the document and we need to
this particular war belongs to this field
for our relevant for our judgement going to do
the result
it could be a little
and we discovered that we need to extract features
and this is feature
and war belongs to
title this is the feature
that can be used in the system for all processes can be used for ranking
it can be used simply for because the user can
type the query i needed documentary this particular word in the title
and therefore we need to extract all this information
and extraction information
from documents
there are many more for extraction in for extraction was from documents
the one before that
mind it may be the most popular artistic innovation canonization rendering have text and get
to work
but i don't like this for the canonization
i like more innovation
because for the canonization real information full innovation we get information about the document and
what we get from the news station the kind of our
our document from some form
in two linear least of
some attributes
for all search engine is is this
the feature set
this is the official said that we are extracted from the
on the left on this slide this is not
comment from shakespeare
but imagine that
it is
these of our
and on the right is something that should be extracted from from these documents so
to be or not to be
and what we see what we can see here
i imagine that it was document after
optical character recognition therefore b is OK so what we have we have
to be or not to be
and for this for for every word we extracted this road i want to remind
you for search so expected to work
the exact position
the extracted fields
and the extracted some idea of documents in this case it will would be example
all the information in order linear
OK so it sounds great pretty simple but what are the features we can extract
from it
for specific single state
you can do it in time independent of size of state space
can anybody think of equivalent algorithm for
the optimal control problem
support i told you
find for me
the optimal action state five
how can i any state
can you think of the way
the optimal action state five
in time
independent aside the state space
it's more challenging but let's see if somebody can
think with this
i'm saying i don't care about any interstate justified
public reaction to that state five
and give so no direct method
and giving him more can
do whatever you want with the model
this is the higher one
the montecarlo
that and
in is really really straightforward in hindsight is really straightforward the the interesting interesting idea
is not the algorithm somebody analysis but
it's out by bikers shaman and during its called sparse sampling out idea
starting state five
and try every action state five
say ten times
each time the next day
we should states
try every five every action ten times
keep doing this
for certain death
you've been our
and back at the values from the leaves of the tree
signs zero values in the leaves of the tree
and assume that tree
is the model and is do
backwards value induction already
and big the action of the root which is state five
it looks the best industry
they were able to show
the number of times the for try every action
in each state
completely independent
four thousand state space
by the same
monte carlo
invariance property
so there to prove it you get near optimal action the root state
in time independent of the size of the state space of course
in kind of exponential
on the horizon
what's the horizon sort of gammas gammas point nine the norris and will be whatever
power your career began becomes
in you know in fact very small
by the time horizon termite i gamma discount factor smaller the discount factor close to
zero small but exponential right
by the base of the expert the number of action yes
and it should be fairly clear right why does make sense let me just say
one more thing answer question what makes sense is because we take samples
multiple samples of an action
the number of samples you need in order to get a good estimate of the
is going to be independent of the number of possible xt
but as a monte carlo approach
mean make sure you understand because of that beautiful result if you don't notice
right now if i were take
estimate the expectation of random variable
and do the obvious thing to do the sample average by the draw eighty samples
of the random variable and average them
the number of samples i need
you get data a lot got and so the square who would look something like
this as it rotates that or scales would you get is shifts along either axis
if you then realigned that the center of mass you have scale the rotation variance
in afforded space which is translation vary you just get in in various space so
these are some of the properties your brain uses for seeing this goes a lot
deeper into her other things the brains doing to compressed so scales spaces a reducing
images by filtering city of the gals in pyramid and and it's reverse to generate
the image back which gives you the pyramid of edges that's all of these adjust
functions and their there's all kinds of threshold including adaptive threshold so this images to
darken light for anyone threshold to pick up the black and white squares as you
can see here but this adaptive local thresholding can pick out all the squares this
is a picture I took of Yellowstone those all washed out by Haiti's that the
histogram equalization makes it clear justice smattering of routines contour operators so how you might
extract by thresholding or other considerations contours and we have contour operators that you know
you're you're working in a in a a year and squared world pixels here too
late to when you convert to come tourist you converted to linear problem only operating
on the region's the linear regions of interest morphological operators that pick out parts of
an image these very fast local operators and by recombined them in in certain ways
their Maxim and operators that that crawl around the image that can be done very
efficiently and then by Ray combining them and in different ways you can get all
kinds of effects picking out data eliminating kinds of data that the different frequencies here's
a inpainting so this is just more more the techniques this is actually written in
the image of the pixels have all but turned agreeing here and then this is
restoring that image from from this damaged image it just tells it to restore you
know those areas of attacks that here it is unique IAC that EU there has
it has a happiness not quite restored correctly this red pen on the screen it
can touch but but this so this is useful for a lot of things including
blending things into images by it does a texture in filling this is something I
use in the DARPA Grand challenge this robot race across the desert so there's a
segmentation algorithm that that watershed transform that sort of like creating hills and valleys and
the gradients in the image and then if you can tell something is outside and
something is inside it'll do the segmentation you so that we that was 1 of
the techniques we tried and segmenting roads from injury ultimately we did a modeling a
color space and that in work on a robot that ran for 7 hours across
the desert never fail division never failed the lasers fell 3 times but it so
it is also the segmentation energy base segmentation years of separating myself from the background
and the robots by giving hints so you can have hints and depth and other
hands that's getting the segmentation grab cut it is a graph that algorithm energy minimization
technique but what it does is it starts over the EMU just give the overall
box and say I want to pull out that and then you can give other
hints of what's inside and outside you can give hot and soft hands these motions
templates this is just a normal optical flow soaking get area so wet that stamp
together in time and take gradients and you get so I I did this a
long time ago and and somehow these are gone around the Internet see set to
music but at that but it felt that because there's optical flow which is the
emotion tracking as the basis of a lot of things struck structure promotion and movies
use densely his structured optical flow of constraint to be on a faced this was
a year I mean shift algorithm which I expect that applied this robust statistic to
tracking and now it's a fairly common technique but here we used it for controlling
game turns out using your head to control the game is a really bad idea
that it's not that you do this for a few who bit for a couple
of minutes and then you stand with a neck brace for the week but the
feel that prospective transform so are fine and and full perspective from warping the plane
that are used for fitting that we have a whole section of stereo so the
this is
so you should
one the
so we want to
one the things that matter
they want
how old
so that
and so are actually
the situation which
all approach
then when we want to to share
should say that
so we
this is one of those things
prior over all possible linear separators
and we just take all of the linear separators that
classifier training set
and we can we take what would be the average prediction variance average of hyperplanes
your effectively get everything tilted that way
and the intuition behind this is that i have that i have an angle of
hyperplanes so i can have a hyperplane that's mostly flat which metric class for the
data correctly a hyperplane which is
angle this direction which would also classified data correctly and the angle between would also
class correctly and so the average solution is essentially the minimal angle the mid angle
between those two extremes
and in a sense this also has a maximum margin property you could argue because
it tries to stay away from that point as well as interest try to stay
away from these points having at that point in the first step away from that
even though the
in theory the actual margin way people normally compute margin has increased by tiny tiny
amounts by having this
as the fight using this your solution you actually gain a lot more in terms
of representing a posterior better
OK so so what i'm going to do is going to challenge the idea that
that that the marginal economic candidate is really the right thing to use instead we
should consider the posterior over hyperplanes has being the correct criteria and most of the
time it to coincide quite well the margin may disagree by tiny tiny bit
so you can also think of this problem in parameter space
so what i've done years i have mapped the
data that i had in the previous slide
in two into what looks like an paris-based when you think about what the posterior
looks like
let me just describe what what the posterior looks like so mathematically if we think
of what a linear classification problem is
it's that we have some feature vectors XII which are two-dimensional in the previous case
and we have this weight vector w
and the linear classifiers one is simply says know i think the inner product of
the weights with the feature vector to the gradients are less than zero with great
endurance in class one trillion classes
the magnitude of that w vectors irrelevant skilled w vectors irrelevant so well also generally
i can just say to point on the sphere
i consider the norm w was one
and so in two dimensions
if i buy impose a constraint i said you get a point on the sphere
being my primary factors so basically any set of weights
corresponds to some point on the sphere
and actually so
let me just correct myself so w is actually three dimensional because i'm including a
bias term
so you're allowed to shift the boundary as well
so in other words the
data points implicitly have featured there's always one
and that gives me the ability to shift the voluntary
and so that's w is actually three dimensional vector when imposed the norm constraint i
have two degrees of freedom left and that's why the point on the surface of
the sphere
so this fear is basically my prior space i'm going to have a posterior distribution
now where these hyperplanes come from where each of the data points turns into a
hyperplane that because this sphere
and we can see that is again by looking at these constraints of i know
that have the classifier certain point as class one
then looking at this equation i can interpret that as a constraint on w that
saying that the w has live in a certain half space
so the set of all of these were w transpose x is greater than zero
corresponds to some have placed have
half space and no
well i think
i have it because it is a
half of the space covered by hyperplane so
so he basically each data point is a hyperplane and have to be on one
side or other of the hyperplane
is a three data points have three hyperplanes are cutting the sphere
and the intersection of all of those constraints is this
weirdly shaped region on the surface of the sphere
yes well was
so if your data is not linearly separable then
then these hard constraints can be satisfied and you would have you wouldn't you wouldn't
have any region where they would intersect in that case you can soften is constrained
you can obviously softener you'd have to soften it and you would say that that
instead of requiring this be exactly positive you can have some soft nonlinearity making the
positive the reason i don't think that is because you don't have nice pictures so
and i'm sure you can you can do everything about the say
with those kinds of soft likelihood as well
but you get the nice pictures with the hard likely going to stick with the
higher likelihood for now
OK so
a posterior distribution over hyperplanes is weirdly shaped
what i plotted years i've plotted plotted point
corresponding the hyperplanes i showed you in the previous slide so the hyperplane chosen by
the SVM which is the
which is the maximum margin hyperplane response to this particular point
on the sphere
and the point that i was calling the bayes optimal solution response to this point
and in terms of private space you can see why
the bayes optimal is it is essentially the average solution
symmetry and yes you can you can do it on graph paper doesn't doesn't take
much more stable as a result but nevertheless this is the stylized version were these
prototypes that reflective symmetry and you can see very clearly that if you draw reflection
it's definitely not a reflection line
of the whole
and so he could and this is the only way these birds go together
you can't
you can put them together and the other way so can clear these types of
symmetric tiles that is the tiles
has symmetry
that is not present in any translation by them
and it's still not known today
what kinds of
but symmetry groups admit i symmetric tiles and which ones do
what this where the lines of symmetry can be
whether they lines or with centers symmetry because you it's possible to have rotation symmetry
but not is that is not a symmetry of the whole tiling so then you
have this global
question of symmetry
so issues work has actually
i presented some very interesting mathematical problems
with regard
two symmetry this whole question of local
versus global
explored some different symmetry groups not just plane symmetry groups here we have an icosahedron
of that was printed with some very beautiful arrangements of shells
and these are printed so they pick up
some of the cemeteries not all symmetries but the rotation symmetries of the icosahedron
he also did this in hard spheres
the twelve fish on this sphere
o a range beautiful asymmetrically so that this actually has the symmetry group of the
the rotation symmetry group of the tetrahedron
he also explored
the hyperbolic plane symmetry there
this was not that the blue
but rather the result
receiving the paper on symmetry that was written by the mathematician
HSM coxeter
the paper was written in nineteen fifty seven and coxeter
requested actually permission to use
some of ashes tests relations to illustrate plane symmetry
and then as a courtesy
coxeter sent the paper to asher
so he could see
how his
test solutions to period and
that the paper was a complete survey not just players symmetry but spherical and hyperbolic
and on this page shows all for the first time a hyperbolic cancellation of triangles
and some of you may be able to see there's actually some pencil markings this
is actually actual copy of the paper and he clearly to compress and tried to
figure out
how to get the scaffolding so that you can make these circles
and he figured this out he did correspond with coxeter
and as can
four how do this and
the are other kinds and what coxeter back actually called hocus pocus
and it really is
but it was not trying to be
snobbish he was not trying to be unhelpful
but just being a mathematician he was speaking
that you can
and the technical language and so
he really wasn't much help at all as you really have to figure this out
on his own
and to try something like that into something like this
it's quite amazing
so he did four different circle prince
which of course all given
illustrations of some hyperbolic symmetry groups
he also exploit similarity
you have a nice print will you have this rotation symmetry but you also have
shrinking towards the centre
dilation is
and here is another example of one that has for symmetry but again towards the
centre you have similarity or dilation symmetry
this is one
has four fold rotation symmetry
does not fit into the category
have any of the
what we require is that true
four point groups in the plane
each of these fish
is related to a small one
and in fact they all of
you can see this this year smaller and smaller and smaller
they are true similar images but there is no similarity there's no dilation
that will take this fish on to this fish
and the fish on to its image here and so on
this print was made
in this scheme completely divided by asher
but he wrote to coxeter explaining
this is as own picture of explaining how to begin with the central square
cut into four triangles and then this gets come into two and this small square
cut into two and so on and so forth and rhythmic so similar
we could serve
of producing
similar figures
and not related to any symmetry group at all
so although
we have this symmetry is invariant
what kind of invariance is this it's not it's not a group in the usual
sense of the word and that's to another
i might say mystery or problem or challenge the asher brings to us
it's possible to have regular repetition
it's possible to have without symmetry groups
no one yet has really figured out
or presented any kind of theory
four really repetition
without symmetry groups and that's a real challenge and particularly in light today of things
like a periodic tiling which have a lot of repetition in a very orderly manner
we really need to look for the new series beyond symmetry groups
there was one other
idea that's esther had that was quite original
and that is
the symmetry
should be compatible
with the following the symmetry of the tiling if you were not colored should be
compatible with the coloring this is the
and they explain
the high higher level
these considerations are generally yes
and so
you can really argue
the computer finds only finitely many configurations
because of the way the generation has been set up
you know those are all the possible cases
you can imagine how many cases are going to have and you have to let
the computer
but the way the computer program
and the principles by which you get these considerations completely understandable
but you don't know
that the computer search will come in a
when it does terminate realized that
the proof is in
so i think that's a perfectly adequate idea of proof
because we we have to be examined
computer programs basis of them we that no
there's a lot of graphs background goes into that to understand these configurations come from
the same
you mention there
it has to do
with things like
prime checking this
we can
if fact
in this machine
two in the war from mathematica you ask about primes the probabilistic
well some boring
the pretty certain
that are
examples perfectly accurate
yes but there is a nagging possibility there
this probabilistic prime tracking we could be wrong
yes so
i think
the graph that can be true
this is somewhat similar to that we use some kind of man search
in to find things and if we say well
we didn't find anything
because the random searches we're a random
because i know something about what we're looking for in the article
the two
conjecture is
and then conductors can
given the interesting says
with the conjecture holds then a lot of other things after all the
but i think we have to be left with the
possibility there because there is another version of the conjecture is true but it could
be a very interesting method of discovery
so this is the first new
in addition to is that the
you will be a lot of the people that people have the
the opposite that of humans
you must
it doesn't
this is the case is this
however what about the way that this is due to
it is solution that
or more likely to
he is
why do you think the it is the world so it is that there is
a possibility that you see something about this is not to be extremely complex that
so easy to see
six months
the mathematics applied to the physical world
yes and so
that's only based on all kinds of assumptions for example
i like to ask people to come in and sit down
and is an empty seat next to you may want to slide over a kind
of problem with the
the person nearby you so make space for the people
so i
for those of you who don't know me
and william cohen the general chair for the conference this year
and general chair of course to get the delegate almost every responsibility
either the local organizers who does a fantastic job
four to the program chair scientific elements generally so unfortunately can you say
and they did great job i get just sort of reserve a few of the
prestigious enjoyable activity so i decided to introduce michael
so i don't like all currently known michael for
i'll be ten or twelve years
so i remember when michael was a graduate student
having a conversation with the point of my colleagues eighteen he labs
ask them what was interesting and exciting and sort of the recent concerts they've been
and everybody mentioned this fantastic results in the computational linguistics community so apparently so
some new graduate student one really heard of on built this
brand new statistical pasture that was very elegant and did better on the treebank data
anybody else it ever done in the history of the world so they were very
impressed with this really trying hard to get that
a graduate student different internship so they were very excited about the possibility which
it's not for the the usual thing you usually excited about that in order for
more than anything else
sorry graduate students
so we are actually very lucky and i remember whether it came as an intern
but a few years later
graduated from the university of pennsylvania device which market
and he came to eighteen t
and i had the pleasure of working with them for a couple of years and
he immediately jumped in and although
he came out the computational linguistics community
this clearly immediately you can't contributing in all sorts of interesting ways
so what she might
and he's been working in this intersection of language proc
for machine learning
basically everything that he said very what is
at eighteen he was part of the civil war i would say sixty people
the people in the lab
b twenty five percent machine learning
michael was honoured in two thousand two in one of the three people in machine
learning that
i believe that i have AIDS and
i give you a slight sense of despair since then
in two thousand two he kind of people would be constant empirical methods in natural
language processing which is
i actually
the main
so are very
in all he was the first one he was or or
especially and you get best paper award in two thousand two young people one thousand
know you're doing the same thing
one thousand three
and to two thousand three he was the
he was the program chair for the middle east so we can use paper what
people work
but he did it to pay for additional people were two thousand
in two thousand five
so you have to for a lot of really work
very effective action
and the the number of
i saw we thanks
so pretty much all the outcome can be talking about today is a joint work
with this group to clear and it goes on to accuse i just wanted to
acknowledge them first
so structured prediction problem so this can be the topic of today's talk social explain
what these are
so without considering supervised learning setting setting so as usual goal is to learn a
function from some set x to some set why assume that we have a set
of labelled examples of that desired mapping
OK very well understood problem or very well studied problem at least as binary classification
with a set y
is simply a set of two possible labels is called minus one plus one
generalisation of binary classification and multiclass classification in this case the set is for k
labels k is generally a fairly small number
so in recent years structured prediction problems have shown
quite a bit of work in machine learning community
these are the following characteristics of the set y possible labels for any input is
typically very large set
so wasn't not it will grow exponentially fast with the size of the input x
OK so it's a very large set
in addition each member of the set has internal structure
OK can we can leverage this internal structure in a couple of ways one in
terms of how we represent these objects or labels
and secondly in the algorithms we use in formulating its prediction problems so let me
maybe more concrete to give you some examples of structured prediction problems arise in many
fields here's an example of a speech recognition so
so the problem is to map an acoustic input
two sentence OK so each label in a sense is an entire sentence in computer
vision we might want to map images to underlying segmentations for example using a markov
random fields
i will come back to that later when we analyse the running time but there's
some data structure we're going on here again
i'm using notation a bit
OK so here's a graph
with edge weights
OK and i want my parents here
animals are going to drop my estimates can you don't cheat
we're going to run the algorithm on this graph as will be
a and one of the shortest path from a to everyone else
so you can check OK there paths exist
so hopefully everything should end up to a finite value body and all the weights
are nonnegative so this argument should work
in the algorithm doesn't even need can activity but it does need all the weights
are nonnegative
so we run the algorithm for the initialisation we set the distance estimates for source
to be zero because in fact there is only one path from a a that's
to do nothing the empty pass i'm going to put a key zero over here
and for everyone else we're just going to put infinity because we don't know any
better at this point
so i'll put he's of infinity everyone else
OK so now you can see
i mean what the algorithm does is extract the minimum from the queue and given
our setup will definitely choose as or in this case
so it has always zero everyone else has a larger quite a bit larger way
OK so we look at s
four of his here
so we look at a we add a two are set as on square something
when it it's now removed from the queue will never go back in because we
never had anything to the queue start with all the verses and extracting decrease keys
but we never answer
so a is gone
OK now i want to update the keys of all of the
vertices and the claim is i only need to look at the vertices that have
edges from a to z to a to b
and that has way ten
and so i compare well is it a good idea to go from eighty a
which cost nothing and then to go along z a b which cost ten for
seems like a pretty good idea because that has the total weight of surplus ten
which is ten
which is much more than infinity so not a racist infinity right ten
and over over in the queue as well that's the decrease cooperation
so now i know a path from a to be good
the only other edge as zero plus three
it is less than infinity so cool put three
here for c
c is there
OK the other vertices i don't touch i'm going to rewrite them here but the
algorithm doesn't have to copy them those keys are already there it's just touching the
that was pretty boring now we
look at
rq and we extract the minimum element so is no longer in there so the
minimum key
here is three
so the claim is that this is a shortest path from a to c
here is a shortest path from a to c there's no other shorter where you
can check that will prove it in a moment
i call so remove see from the list is gone and then we look at
all of the outgoing edges from c so there is one that goes up to
which has weight for
four plus three which is the shortest path way from a to c grade c
and c to be sure cost three was for which is seven which is less
than ten so we found an even better path to get to be better to
go like this is to go like that
we write seven for b
and there not going to d cost eight three-plus decades is eleven eleven is less
infinity i checked so we write a letter g then we looked at e we
have three
plus two is five which is less than infinity
so we write five
for the new kiefer at this point we have financial past everywhere
but they may not be the best ones
so we have to keep looking
OK we just next to the next round of the algorithm we extract the minimum
key among all these can not be which we've seen and probably know the answer
to but it's the he has the smallest key
so we take this we now declared this to be a shortest path all the
way we got to e
on this path agency
c d e
clear that to be shortest where they were done with e but we still have
to update what about all the outgoing edges from e there's only one here because
five plus nine which is fourteen which is bigger than eleven so
no go that's not an interesting pattern our previous path which would like this in
a cost eleven is better than the one we are considering now drawing the whole
after the album's only adding these two numbers
OK go
so don't change anything
five is removed or is removed or new keys are seven eleven so we take
the key seven here
which is for element be vertex p we declare the shortest path we currently have
in our hands from a to b which happens to be this one algorithm can
actually tell this by the way but we're drawing it anyway the the spanish ACB
is there
candidate shortest path claims that it is indeed shortest now we look call all the
outgoing edges one that goes back to c
the cost seven plus one which is eight which is bigger than three
which is good
but we are declared seem to be done but the algorithm checks this says that's
not better and then we look at this other end from b to d that
cost plus two which is nine
which is better than less so we in fact have an even shorter path
so the shortest path weight now d
it is nine because there's this path because a a c b
for total cost of three plus four plus two is not
cornell is only one element in the queue will remove it d
we look at the outgoing edges there is one going here which cost nine percent
which is sixteen which is way bigger than five so we're done
do anything
this despite the queue is empty
and the claim is that all these numbers that are written here the final values
the shortest path weights
this not like five minutes as
and now you need to
really work hard and do some strange things so again i just one
let you know
these things exist what you do
because you partition the set of worlds into two types some called normal something called
create as you can see that this was not very politically correct in the seventies
that you get away with those terms there but then again normal and non normal
right so creators the natural thing that you might say and the idea of the
create world
is that
every query world has to make diamond phi true for every formula five
that's it that's is requirement so what you do is you build the kripke frames
in a particular way
so that that's always true
and then what happens is
getting no longer make every voxel military
OK because from every world you will always be able to see
and and that something is actually an inconsistent world
i don't want to go into the details but
it allows you to break necessitation
so you get weaker logics
these are found some applications in computer science
because in computer science and artificial intelligence
i want to talk about
box five they want to interpret box five as something like
you know the agent knows
what the agent believes five
if you have necessitation
right was station
by five those two box five
from guam
then in this situation what you're saying is that the agent has perfect
deducibility power but if it can deduce gamma
then it can then it knows and believes all the things
they it can deduce of course we know that
agents don't have perfect conductors
look dropping this
and replacing it with that we corrects him
now here we go back and say well right there with the shapes that we
they were the first order conditions like your reflexivity
which we couldn't
find the shape for
so that was the gap
where the
cricket e
semantics but the first order conditions
i wasn't able to be captured by shape so how do we close the gap
people look
nominal tense logics and there's a whole area
of these now which is called hybrid logic
type hybrid logic into google and there should be a conference called highlights which is
associated with this area
what's the difference
all that i'm doing
is i'm any an extra set of atomic formulae
called i know up to i one and i allowed me to be intermingled with
the formula on the left to build formula with
OK so what am i doing and saying
he is my
well w nor his mind the world w on his my world w two
and i have my
assignment of pain or p one
and p two that are
that's the traditional assignment and we can assign true and false arbitrarily
what you also do is you say well i'm also going to assign values to
i know i want and i two which is a disjoint set of atomic formulae
i have a global condition
the global condition is that
this guy
is allowed to be given the value true
and only one world
right so
this guy is true here
now it may also be in that this disguise tree that's OK as long as
it's not true or anywhere else
and then
now we can't have these two guys tree here so maybe this guy is true
and over here maybe it's something out here
can you see that
i not being true tells us that we're at w two
in know language you now formula language we are now able to talk about being
at the point
in the old days remember
the itemset here
in the syntax
and the world set here in the semantic
OK what these normals do is they allow you to bring the names of the
world back into the syntax
and now i claim
after this
captures the reflexivity the shape
let's just see why
so i suppose
that a particular i say i'm let's make it
whatever this one was let's make it i three showing let's say this is i
so i three is true at w no
what the shapes is is that
you're not allowed to have a diamond i true here
so what is time and i said well diamond i can go some way
and where i end up i have to say the same i is where i
started i have to have i three true
if i go anywhere else i three is not going to be true because i
three is only true at this point
so the time and i see is
this error has to go back to itself
and if you say that can hold
then you saying that you can't have managed to yourself
this is true one particular world and whether that's true
it's not the case
that you can see your world which makes it true
there's only one world series i tree is sitting in his you can't see yourself
and these are a bit more complicated
i'll let you that
all right
any questions about everything that we've done
because this is now
the end of
the semantics and calculating terms of hilbert calculi and i want to get on to
another of calculate
call tableau calculi
which are useful for automated reasoning
the questions
something that not
clear about correspondence theory
so was
it gets nasty very quickly
OK so
basic nominal tense logic is decidable
once you start adding any sort of operators that allow you to say well i
can go somewhere else
so they have operators like
seven operators like an operator at i five
right what it says is
i'm somewhere i don't know where i am or what i do know is that
the world i five street
OK and then have another one called down which says
take me to the world where i string
i based on shadows
based on a fraction
based on reflection
a lot has no legs
it's purely based on matrix
there are single general i designed compound design
and the human eye is
in this small car
and cameras are basically mimicking this particular optical configuration
so this whole space to explore
and each of them must task specific and feature
well because of the thinking about all this
issues of
land system optics and flash and so on
if you go back and ask the consumer
there going saying what i really don't care about that
just give me a camera
that's just a big black box
with a big red part
nor lands no flash
and also
not censored
that's all i want
and when i press the red button
you know if i'm if i'm in in front of
i for power
you know i do
therefore with my own camera
because if i have device like this
despite the loss of but also the back
it just goes on flickr
and trolls
for my current GPS coordinates which is in front of the our roughly in the
same direction is roughly the same time of day after the same season and brings
me back from the border from flickr which is taken by some other guy with
fancy camera with a lot of time
and bring it back to me so despite all this great what we're doing
all the consumer wants
it's just a blind camera it's really disappointing
thank you
any questions
so you use those coding techniques to take
are you already discuss with people from MIT lincoln lab for instance works on redound
this configurations
the principle this conclusion is that there
so define many cuts many the first according to optimize
structure function you have already with
OK i'm not i'm not
as you are in boston you can also with rest
you know very well going to be for radar applications
for this competition for i in range with solutions are also refer reprocessing
and i agree with you i think optics as we know very well is the
workers in
lots of other foods especially telecommunications
and so on the optics is almost thirty forty years behind all fees and i
would say photography is even more far behind from the rest of the scientific image
so what's happening in this field now
islam of the ideas that were explored in signal processing and different analysis and so
on that was
that was done in other fields is slowly filtering down
two something that can be done at optical wavelengths of devices that are
that portable and so on so you know where there's a lot of beautiful research
a lot of beautiful literature available as well
for example the notion of core temperature is very very well known in astronomy since
the sixties and seventies and and only now
it's possible to think about that
all we
and if you use
this is right
he only
number of people
one year
you will not
the world
o thing
here are the ones who want
so even if you
o in
he also
he or
in this way
there is one
that's all i j
okay let's not limited to
reasoning are gonna have
with but that's a nice suggestions or any other suggestions
and then we will have a think about
probabilities in due course
how many of
to everyone right
on one side and then
and like okay
around so in this case we are leaving on the table a possible life and four possibly
and you're suggesting leaving both lights on the table
how long will be the goods
so that's a nice suggestions let's now have i think about them and think about the possible
things that's good
if we went over this strategy
as a second way
well it builds on one side and all the possible relied on our
what could happen
could it looked like that's
could happen
could the right hand side go down
why not
so this is the possibly live
and anyway that's i could go down given the left hand
although good is it
one of his followers
notable and heavy but really no that's not
possible these guys can only be available in light so this has probability zero
is it possible like a balance
is one heavy possibly have you guys
what's the probability that being the case
what's the probability of
that's happening
so that's the probability distribution whose entropy is
one day
okay let's talk through
this one here
it's an asymmetric situation and
talk about the symmetric outcome was the probability
now that balancing
because if you to
then for balance
by symmetry
the remaining probability has to be
split between nodes are happy with the symmetry argument
for example
this could happen
this guy is available
and is therefore lighter than normal
if only even does is
and the heavy
so that's the
action and the probability distribution
and action
we could
three good three lights
so what's the probability that this will
this because as far as we all balls
but we've left on the table and if any of them is doable
and it's balance
what's the probability that's
he will be
down on left hand up on the right
what's hot climates
is the
zero probability of getting this
come here
the cos there's no way that they possibly like i can be heavier
and the good
right so that a whole bunch a possible thing can do and everyone misleading to
a different probability distribution is one probability distribution
is another
and this one
the that's me
that's is actually a little less than one that's
this one has entropy
one that
and i wonder if i can dig out
what it is
one of and
simply using this permission
in general if you know that you have one can you
there are also a rule that allows you to co-star can from or they can
for example you gave can and alpha is the first then you know that i
fucking keep last time also can or if you have to learn to some of
the candidates is that you can learn the product of the camera
he sought to catch
i show you some application where support vector machine has been important for you
i would say one of the application that
well the support vector machine has been
widely recognised as
good means the is
it is optical character recognition
it is that it's nice that contains sixty thousand training samples and ten thousand test
there are images and that is to recognise the on
and the people use their own pizza
and also some preprocessing on the menu
four like in two thousand two the course and short course show that we of
water can they can reach very good performance that has been for years state of
the art on benchmark
like and they try for linear SVM and they got this eight percent the polynomials
can and they got
one percent then they say
which is something that we
we designed cannot taking into account their translations of the pixel
and they
do that and they got an improvement of
i think now
not the best result on these datasets but close to
the best result and it is one of the applications made
and i guess you
they want to
face detection
by was one
the consumer faces different schemes and they decide
nineteen times nineteen eighty so they do some preprocessing on the images and
the classifier with SVM
with polynomial kernel fifty thousand at point
this is one of the first them to apply
so i support vector machine to computer vision fifty thousand at the point is not
that much but at that time was
quite kind of the results
in fact the support vector machine has been using computer vision for many other applications
and i would say
this is after resulting pedestrian detection of being the support vector machine
we clever features that are used for the guardian proposed by the police
by a simple linear can they get very good results but
my classifier in and student proposal is the gram intersection can therefore
this kind of the k
they have more to scale representation of the data
and they
i got a very
good results with respect to
that the sunday
he said the
they also provide a faster way to compute the again because
usually you can allow the linear support vector machine widely used because they are fast
to train nineteen
the machine i'm not that fast so if you want to use it and you
want to be able to scale with a lot of you have to have some
and i think in this paper and i think to compute the disease
intersection can be proposed
another application is the
i mean match by ground
the context is object category recognition feature that uses scale invariant feature
this is
kind of
or maybe about these ideas have been used by
many by many more or and also
they propose a fast evaluation of these can function and they go to very good
results on the dataset
he then in the example shown before
and that were some knowledge
about the application domain give assistance in defining
april similarity measure
but in many application we don't have a clue to the signing to choose the
can so as i told you before the first of all like i ocean putting
on her getting but very often you need to design something that even if you
use a simple solution can
you are required to choose the value for the we don't look at the results
of the regularisation parameter that you need to say so
or you could also cause evaluation validation or you
make some doubt as validation set
otherwise very difficult to to this but i mean without regularly knowledge
i want to show you that this is very important and adds the model selection
it's really quality of it's very important to make something work
that is not say that
very family KTH dataset for action classification
the united states in one of two thousand seven one two thousand five that they
use exactly the same feature exactly the same game but in the end
when i was in
t and i think that factors what should well you know the people by
some really knowledge and you can see
he performance like the two point five per cent
o point five percent simply
being able to do and i suppose we should so i
it's so time-consuming but i think it's really
so if you want to know what selection so in the end the choice of
the so it's important to people started to
to think
OK can we do something that
can we let the cat
together with
learning our economy
i think that the first world came into being
done by
in two thousand two and this has been by
pioneering work from the manual approach has been proposed for learning can occur chemical combination
i think it's quite nice idea
what do we would do they do is the following they they can as matrix
and they considered as the same thing so they have some because the label at
the top of the training set up and funded living that the that's the
let's assume for now that we have just the training center so does the labelled
and data two
two lambda divided by age and so on that's where you find
you're minimum
and if you convert that into
where they actually fall on the screen
well the next one
it will be
the small angle approximations l
times lambda
divided by a
that's no different
so now what i o u
it is
the pattern what will depend on like when i look on the screen they will
i really seem
well it's looking is going to look very different from what you may think of
applying now in terms of x i could have thought of it in terms of
i decided to plotted in terms of x
so here
x equals zero
there is
one mistake able on negotiable is the maximum that's
they coincide with theta equals zero
and then here
and land that
divided by
completely destructive interference that's that angle theta one
at times l
and then here
two lambda
divided by a
destructive interference and the same is true of course on the other side
and what you're going to see now in terms of
intensity that i showed you there was a square metres is the curve that looks
like this
broad maximum
absolutely zero here
very small maximum absolutely zero there
very small maximum and zero there and this continues for a long time
and this is very different from anything we've seen with multiple
if the intensity here is i zero
then the maximum here which i didn't even calculate where it is it is somewhere
in between these two minima
but i didn't calculate precisely where this
the maximum is very low
is only four point five percent
in strength
one of my zero and this is even lower this is only one point six
of i zero
so when you look at a diffraction pattern we call this the diffraction pattern like
this you'll see a very
broad sense maximum
and then you see
the dark spots on the site
you see light coming up again in between the sort of sup maximum
and so the weights of this center maximum
this is where it
which is really
x one
which is then l and divided by eight
and if you want to be picky you say well this centre maximum really twice
that much fun be my guest but this is clearly a measure for how wide
the center spot will be
when you see it on a screen
and now come something that is completely nonintuitive for you as well as for me
and that is
if you make a very small
that means that the lights go for an extremely narrow slit
then this is
what you see on the wall
extremely wide
the small it is
the wide it will be exactly opposed to what you would predict you would think
if you make
the opening through which put like very small
you would think that what you see on the screen is also very small it's
exactly the opposite
and this what i want to demonstrate to you
i have here
demonstration which variables that i can very a
and we will use
the brightest
they so that we have
a beam of green laser lights five thousand four hundred angstroms
and what i will do is i will make this opening never never never
and as i make the opening i start very large start with a large opening
of maybe five millimeters
and large opening
n is so large
that this
is negligibly small because a is very large then this is not very large is
very small but as i make a smaller and smaller and and smaller and smaller
there comes the time that the diffraction with
it's going to be dominating the whole scene
and what you will see them on the screen there that the
bright spot will get wider and wider wider wider
and that for me is always so enormously fascinating because it goes so strongly against
our intuition
so this is what i
next on the menu
i have here this
so it's i must make sure that i
i have my
and i'll turn on this
laser that i really
i accidentally turned on
i hope is coming on the as it is
and so you see there
this list is not very white
and so the size of that so that you see there
the size of the of the bright spot is now entirely dictated
by the divergence of my laser beam
the fraction with
is negligibly small because a is very large
now what's now i'm going to
make a small
i'm doing that now
making it smaller and and smaller the faction which is still