you should click
so we get things like professor in HCI
and lecturer taking four courses these new terms in the computer science ontology
and also i want to
it's like the type of computer science students
i actually communities across individually was selected something press this button here
i can add it to the list of selected items
on the
right hand side
and now i want to add in
so classes of students and classes as students so we've got CS students and i
students system taking courses and a students
and one of them this
first continue this is going to be my signature from my module
could actually have properties if i wanted to
and other items but were just like terms from concepts now
so i press continue and it computes
module for me
it is updated with appreciate what you see here on the left hand side is
the signature that was selected with some check boxes and we can experiment with this
new moment and on the right-hand side you see all the axioms of a preview
of the axioms that will end up in the
much also he was saying look got for thirty three axioms
if you recall
the original ontology
i can't see how the solutions that have about fifty axioms and this corresponds in
our case two fifty eight percent of the at the ontology
now if i wasn't so sure about what i wanted i could experiments at this
stage and checking this checkbox is here so if you didn't want to talk about
his students taking courses
i could uncheck any we compute module
and now you see some axioms of cross-taiwan this shows the effect of taking turns
out the signature was chosen you could maybe have little players out sometime and see
how this is the actual module
that's affected by signature
so i'm fairly happy with that just before carry on the whole just to show
you that it's not just doing something stupid and pulling in the
you have to follow is but just to show is that this means stupid and
point in the whole subtree if just selects one term here faculty
we compute module and we actually get an empty module here
so where no entailments because just like the ones here was nine thomas will be
ninety amazon this model any questions about that
OK so i just restored the submission i wanted
so continue OK i'm happy with much now
continuing now i just have to be a few mechanics to specify what wants to
so i want to put these axioms into a new ontology
and going to call this ontology cs modules all ontologies in out of your eyes
this will be used to identify ontology and then imported into university bench ontology
so continue again
we can specify what i want to say that skip over that now
and now can either like to copy axioms from the source ontologies into OWL module
could actually pull out axioms in case you actually might want to be facts pull
out the module completely but will go with the default option which is copy axioms
so i click finish
and the marginal extracted and you can see here
that we've got a new ontology alister ontologies top and this is a module
you want to go and browse the ontology
and you see we've got the terms that wanted
and a small part of the ontology
so now
one simple this module back into university
bench ontology
so i go back university styles
now i go down to the pain at the bottom here
i want to add an important
we've already got the ontology and memories of it already loaded so it selects the
second option here importantly be loaded
press continue make sure let's the CS module that was just created
and when it and found
the system of checks and things that are loaded
i do that and then it's imported
these class counts going to become more active
in ontology
any questions so far
right so that was passed modularity and the tools
you can use to extract modules and now we're going to go into explanation
OK so
what i want you to do now
it is with the on univ bench ontology
and the
are imported module
i want you to now selective is for the purposes of this demo are going
to select palates
so from the reason menu choose power
this will classify the ontology
computer class hierarchy in computer any in unsatisfiable classes
if you switch over to the entities top
and then you can switch over to the for class hierarchy
if we expand it we notice actually ontology contains some unsatisfiable classes
so you recall from ralph said this morning
this usually is the modelling error
unsatisfiable classes are interpreters and that in all models
and usually don't want them your ontology
it would be nice to find out the reasons why
these classes unsatisfiable
and take some action
to repair the ontology
here is the classifier ontology which is the reason to classify the
and come up with some unsatisfiable classes
and we want to know why this is the case
but first of all you notice several unsatisfiable classes in the ontology and if you
want to start preparing the ontology
they work
very differently
hose or pipe
and there's every year
as a certain length
and on one side i blow air
later we can discuss how you have to blow
but as for now think of it that we have here
a five rating
the changes its frequency from very low
very high
something similar will happen
happened to restrain
at certain frequencies it will do nothing
and then all of a sudden
it's very happy
it produces the tongue
recall that the first harmonic
higher frequency second harmonic even higher frequency
come on
you may think now
that's the part
that is vibrating
because the strings vibrating so you think it's the
that is not true because the air inside the park
it starts to oscillate in a way that is extremely hard to imagine not only
for you but also for me
but except for now
that is the air column inside that is actually going to post it so to
and it is then at certain frequencies
you will
here the
harmonics the resonance frequencies and i'll give you an example
if the length of this by
it is one fought
and two inches
notice how precise i am
the first harmonic
it would be five hundred hertz
and that's it
you cannot change that
you don't have the
strange you can change the attention you can change the length there's no such thing
as changing attention
he is no such a thing as changing the weight
per unit length you can do that here
so you really stuck
with length
is common however is also very happy
to produce a second harmonic
which i will do a thousand hertz
and it is very happy producing a third harmonic which it will do
fifteen hundred
similar to the string
remember one two
if you make
twice as short as this one
to make it shorter now
exactly half the length
then the first harmonic
go up
become thousand her
so the second will become two thousand
and the third one will become three thousand
the length is the crucial thing
no longer the instruments
surely the
the higher the fruit
very short
which is very high tones to be produced is very low to
notice the complication
the complication is the following
you can
design an instrument
you close it on one end
provides not open on both ends
and when you do that
if the length of the two are the same
you first harmonic
is half this frequency
so it becomes two hundred fifty
so you have exactly the same length one foot
and two
and i use this symbol now
now you get here two hundred and fifty
what do you think you're going to get you know
that's what i call you would say that's not true
centre run for this
i told you that is really a complication here
it turns out it now
the next one is three times this which is seven fifty and the next one
is five times this
which is twelve
so now you don't get the sequence one two three four five six seven but
you get one three five seven and some you may forget that if you prefer
since we are going to release in three installments and since we want to get
the feeling now
four what tones one can produce
wind instruments
i give you here
the scheme which will help you for the rest
all this talk
you see there in white
only the first harmonic
and the numbers given in hertz
and this is the length
of the instrument is open open
and this is closed open
now notice if you have one inch
this short only
then you will be able to produce
sixty seven hundred hertz
and you're
second harmonic
i would then be twice that
if you make it for instance
the frequency goes down by exactly factor for is four times more than that
twelve inches
three times slower
forty inches was be ten times lower than four inches you see that is the
one hundred inches of course is amongst the
it is this big
you'll get sixty seven hits and this will be the second harmonic only put the
second harmonic
in the first and the last is now
with the same length you go to this system notice that these values half
is half
this is half is half this half
and two police this gentleman
the second harmonic is three times higher so this number is three times this this
are not incoherent
and as a result they yield instabilities when you want to do classification out of
this sparse per out
now there may be way around but let's say that that is the state of
the art
so the question is what to do when
when you look at the current location vision you observe that people now begin to
be able to do some kind of classification and they use the scriptures
and these descriptors are constructed by grouping coefficients out of
basic wavelet representations
so what is this idea of SIFT bag of features also called back for OK
it is the following
you have your original image
and the first stage you make decomposition in wavelet basis and then you get some
sparse right corresponds to zero emissions
these are four different ways that orientation
which basically extracts four
directions of your
and then the key idea is to say i'm not going to work on independent
wavelet coefficients a lot of algorithms in the nineties for texture discrimination
try to build the vectors of single-track wavelet coefficients and that didn't really work so
the idea here is instead of looking up with the sufficient independently you look at
the block of with fish
so these small loops where simultaneously in all directions
so these this are
i love
now in each of these blocks
you have something like sixteen by sixteen crayfish
one never be
the need for also
sixty six different one by
so present problem or or is it can be by this sense
in two thousand and the idea of these elementary cells is that you want to
have some kind of robustness with respect to translation
and they get one measurement these
elementary cells and in this case
to get simply the energy this summer in which each other
so that for each other
now you get this picture which has sixty four coefficients OK
now this the scriptures lives in a space of dimension sixty four hours
and what you want is to group
these scriptures in our sixty four
if you count the number of descriptors you have to became this image is of
the order of two thousand four thousand two translated all of
you do your came in algorithm so you try to find clusters and the centre
of the clusters
and then you do basic histogram
which counts how many elements you have each of the clusters
and people have been trying to to classify images out of this histogram
and it works
really pretty nice
it works nicely but there is something of a bit of black magic because look
that's our sixty four
you have very few
i mean these four points they're completely lonely in this huge space and building clusters
in this huge based on its
something which is not so
clear to understand
let me
try to get the different interpretation of
that kind of file great and i'm going to make it link
with respect to these
presentation of money for that well done yesterday
so one review
of how to structure dates
is to say well
if there is some structure these data should belong to some kind of manifold now
think of these patches vectors in dimension are sixty four hopefully these patches belong to
some kind of benefit
and the very beautiful tools that were presented show that you may look at this
manifold by
looking at the heat kernel which is associated with the legislation try to define the
idea of function of the form
the difficulty at least from my understanding of these techniques is that it's difficult to
work in the space of dimension sixty four which is absolutely huge when you have
a very very very sparse data only four thousand in very very large so
this may be a little bit ambitious
when you have so little
another thing that you could do is to think OK something very
i'm going to take my data
project my data of a linear space and let me choose almost randomly my space
and try to find a new space
which absorbs a maximum energy when i do this projection
well in two d how does it look like well if you find the linear
space which is of the most energy
it looks like the tangent space
but the problem is that the number of linear space i have is a tremendous
something to constraints on the choice of the space but that's the idea the the
idea is let's try to optimize the energy of the projection and they may not
be too far too notion of space
and the idea is therefore identified indirectly the manifold through projections on the inner space
OK so let me relate that
and that's the work done by john blown up and you said one
the company
so let me relate that to what i just said so
i had these vectors
of sixty four energy
maybe long hopefully to some kind of
and let me make projection
on this manifold now what do i know i know that my representation is sparks
the fact that it's means that may be able to do projection in the low
dimensional space
and still carry most of the image
so how does the project
the project trajectory based keeps energy
one cells and removed from the
so project or around the projector
dimension p is equivalent to the
one out of sixty four in around the way
so far to project
however the project you just have have to do to select only the white element
to some of the energy and you get the amount of two project
now if i look use these blocks space projectors harmony the i
in nineteen sixty four and a huge number
let's signposted are spots and as far as a teacher
sixty four
sixty four that people stand for example you have about ten to the pahlavi project
is this is still quite
now of course you don't want to use one project to another one which looks
too much like so if you impose a little bit of differences between these projectors
for example that three of the damage and should be different then you go back
to to the managing member like fifty thousand project OK
the idea is basically to do that
same kind of spirit of what i described and how does it relate to what
i described
what i'm going here basically what i'm going to do is to learn the dictionary
of block spaces by doing these random projection
let me show
a simple example
this is a texture
in the use of for forty eight hours
the learning are there
it's called the
even ecological and learning are there
if don't the w
which is the
you time in the input time allen
the money he
think is large
if minus one is large
and more if ten minus one at specification and you more
is easier to see if it applies equal to add because then the
weight is just proportional to
with the money
what you had
i think the normalisation
and then think the according to to these the
for any fixed and over here and that is the probability distribution because it is
the normalized
it is linear combination
all of the
experts portfolio selection
is large
it is OK and performed well and the small
actually zero otherwise
but it has a much better interpretation might should be very proficient but it means
that the you know the the of the your your training but not in fact
the you just show me each of you have a monitor and i can see
or you want to make an aggregation
according to the minus one OK
it has a better interpretation let's calculate the
aggregated amount of money what i
it is the the
the product of you know product for my portfolio selection and i stopped it towards
the end of the piece of i
the definition of the aggregate it portfolio selection
it is the definition
and the product
of s i minus one
the inner product
if you just s
so by
and then if you look at these product then we ought to err
cancers are
if the initial capital is one dollar
combination combined
amount of money
is the theme of
what is the interpretation of these results
it means
that at the very beginning
the kind of the intuition that we
we carried out here as well to see if we can get a whole bunch
of these weak use
and have the computer guess
the elimination for the scene so this is our upcoming ICC paper
and here basically we are producing a probability map of where
all that kind of viewing hemisphere the sun might be so this is the
because of the map the way you look at it you just look up into
the sky
the black frame is basically frame of the image and this is your whole hemisphere
of the sky
and you can see the red is is where the sound is more likely to
so it's a kind of a very very soft probabilistic map of where do we
think the elimination might be coming from and of course once we have that we
could actually synthesized
synthetic sky using a parametric model that we have and then use that in in
computer graphics framework to insert a synthetic three d object in the scene so that
we insert the statue that that is three d
three d object all that with the environment map that we have just recovered and
you can see that it looks mostly mostly OK within the city
OK so what's the algorithm for doing this well first we compute
a bunch of very weak cues from three sources
first the sky
the shadows on the ground and the shading on vertical surfaces
second we integrate all of these information with a data driven prior on
basically what
types of images what types of photos people take
and first third step is hoping for the best because all of these cues again
very very weak so you're not going to get anything anything definite definitive but what
we have seen is that
it seems that
more for most of the image is one of those cues is is able to
give us something something useful at least as useful as something that a human would
be able to to infer from and image again this is really all we are
interesting in here is interesting here is that the idea for this project it is
the follow-up to this project is to see if we can use this illumination estimation
as the way to
to help you see interpretation two two two
help us understand
better the objects in the and services within the city right then and for that
we probably don't need to be very exact
OK so here's here's some of the
some of the queue so that
the first cue is the sky
we have a parametric model of the sky and basically the idea is that we
we the size of parametric more parametric sky at every
possible some position over there
the hemisphere and then we see which one of those
parametric skies words are better and better explain our our data
and then basically we have that those that
the position of the best explains the data is the ones that get a high
probability if this of course was only for clear sky images if you have a
kind of an english an overcast sky than it's it's very easy you just have
a classifier this overcast you don't need to do do is some prediction the tricky
bit is is what if you have some sky some
sky and some clouds at the same time so we have no a mechanism for
segmenting out a sky cloud layer and that only working on the clear sky pixels
for OK so this is this is this kind information that we're using
the second cue is shadows on the ground so here we are
try to detect shadows on the ground plane and then hoping that the shadows actually
are coming from vertical objects and then using that to basically boat using kind of
half transformed i think vote for possible some directions and of course you know here
because it's going to be symmetric we don't know where the sound is coming from
it could be you know from the left or the right of that of the
line and of course a lot of the time the
they the lines on the ground will not be shadow lines and some of the
time the shadow lines will be
in fact not from vertical objects so is a lot of noise in this process
also but again we are kind of combining it all together and forming a kind
of the distribution of where the elimination could be
and the third q is
shading from objects so here we are looking at
again all of this is of course comes from the the scene layout work the
the sky
horizontal services vertical services here we're looking at the different vertical services of different orientations
and looking very coarsely whether one services are rendered in one way are much brighter
and services or another way and that information if there's a huge variation in brightness
that cannot be explained by just albedo changes if there's a huge variation in brightness
there might be a possibility that you know the element comes from that particular direction
OK again it's very very coarse in very rough but that's what all we're looking
for so we here we get a bunch of estimates for for where the sun
could be the budget probability maps were combined together with a prior one what
what are the sun positions are more likely for for human photographs and you we
use a data set of six million geotagged flickr images
so we have the geo tagged with at the time of day
and the data so we are able to predict exactly where the sun is so
we basically statistics of where the sun is in
people's photos OK unfortunately we don't have the compass direction now that is i and
we're looking forward to using that so here this is only for the elevation information
to get the prior like this
OK for that so basically it says that there are very very few photos with
them with the sun on the disease OK
and we combine it all together this multiply all this probability map and here's here's
some of the qualitative results really quickly and you can we render little red stick
with the shadows so you can see if you agree with
with them
with illumination direction that that we guess and look at some quantitative results as well
and you're welcome to see the paper the papers online already and will be presented
to you
for your cellphones you have parallel processing what people do is is not the serial
order what they do is every round every processors just updating all the time
this is nice because it's a completely distributed algorithm and it's inherently parallel
but in some ways it's wasteful on the tree because you're sending more messages than
you have to there's
you know every round everybody is sending a message on on every edge actually two
two messages per edge
so that's the choice
the other reason the parallel muscle message scheduling sort of interesting to someone was asking
yesterday if you have a graph with cycles how do you apply this algorithm
right that's actually where a lot of the modern interest is is applying this algorithm
to graph with cycles
if you have cycles then
so if you look for instance like this then there is no natural way of
defining the route but there's no route if you have a graph with cycles
so there is no natural way of having to pass sweep up and down you
can talk about leaves and roots but if you don't think of the two past
form if you just think of the parallel form everybody just doing their own thing
right the parallel form doesn't care to happen to be an extra edge there
yes this node will pass messages along that edge but it's you know there's nothing
in the parallel form that that needs to know to tree
that's a good question so when you've cycles
OK so i'm getting a bit ahead of myself let me just say the basic
stuff first come back to this in one minute OK so the basic stuff is
that on the tree
whatever ordering of messages use use any reasonable ordering this algorithm will converge in essentially
the diameter of the tree iterations most diameter this means the length of the longest
path in the tree
right so you need a number of iterations if i had a long path here
i need enough iterations this guy can reach the sky that they have to be
able to talk
right but it's a finite number of iterations to find a number of steps if
you implemented the messages will be fixed they won't change any more
right so it means if you're running this update
exactly this local update here
it will be such that you have a set of messages and starring put them
in here you do this operation you get back and start fixed point
and an entry there's only one of those fixed points it's you can show that
is always unique and they always find it
and when you find it a you plug it into
this other equation here
then you always compute the correct marginal distributions it's always exact on the tree
right so that's that's a very important result because
if you remember when we spoke about the
you know the naive complexity of solving these problems is exponential
because you have to be something or exponentially many
whereas if we look at the complexity of this algorithm that we've done
right so that the naive complexity of some asian and marginalization
as we've discussed would be order
and two the and were and is number of nodes
and am if we're looking at discrete variables is the number of states with the
number of different types
number of levels of the discrete variable
right so that's huge message passing complexity let's just as a little calculation
what would the message passing complexity be how much does it cost me to do
one of these updates
right so and here is the number of states be maximizing over
so how much would it cost to compute this vector this is an you have
to compute
just roughly order of magnitude
as an exponential is cubic
what is a
close i think it's if you think about it m squared
because you have to do this
you fix an access you have to do this operation
this is like a matrix multiply roughly so
it's going to be order and for each one of these order m squared per
and you have to do is roughly the number of edges that are tree so
how many edges we have an entry
as a function of and the number of nodes
it's always n minus one so
the complexity of
of message passing is order m squared times and roughly
right so that's that's significant that linear in the number of nodes
quadratic in the number of states
sometimes the quadratic can be a problem if you do problems in computer vision let's
people will discretize if you had continuous things
a natural thing to do would be to discretize the to break the continuous space
into many bends into bins
so if i was like ten thousand square could be problematic and sometimes the techniques
to even make it faster than m squared
but what you want to take away initially is that this is the key that
the thing the and the number of nodes drop down from the exponent to being
i mean that's really why this algorithm is used all the time linear time is
is nice
oup sorry guys can't see that
should let me know if it's not properly right so what i was saying is
the key is that the the number of nodes has dropped from exponential to linear
OK so that's for trees it's all this exact stuff so far for trees
but getting back to his question a lot of the modern interest in this algorithm
just because it's such a simple algorithm you can in principle apply to any graphical
and historically i think the first person to do that one of the first was
probably bob gallagher in the nineteen fifties
in his thesis work at MIT he worked on those codes that i showed yesterday
member that that sort of image denoising coding problem that i showed you
he invented those codes
i guess in the nineteen sixties nineteen sixty two
but sort of history's funny back then people didn't have powerful enough computers to actually
you know simulator look at these things behaved in practice
so everybody basically just ignore his work from a b thirty plus years
until turbo codes are we were rediscovered in the nineties
and then people realized oh this is all very connected and these ideas were were
deciding what
another class of quality that are
look at in the literature are actually i think i models from physics
i'm not going to talk about those essentially the idea there is that there is
some inherent energy in the system in the system
essentially goes to distribution that minimizes the energy
so this probabilistic models the important advantages that they have or sometimes an advantage is
that predictive compared to the game theoretic models and again and again to model usually
look at the concept of equilibrium and are often more than one could
which is sometimes good sometimes bad
the systems often have more than one could for example
weather yahoo messenger becomes popular with gold park
becomes popular both of these you could think of us two different conceivable that could
be afterward
if you just have to model you can predict which of the two is going
to have a probabilistic models are more predictive in the sense that
given that you make about the model about the system
you're going to get the distribution for what happens in the
and as a result we can try to do optimisation for example if you want
to do marketing can find the best seed set two
fine to coarse cynical on tools that in order to maximize the yield of your
marketing campaign
or you could also allows you to fit the data in order to estimate parameters
of the the system is also an important feature of c so the model that
i'm going to talk about
it's going to be a probabilistic model and also includes the element of time
so the the
a few models that i mentioned in the previous
it's like the
i don't really consider the element of time is essentially is essentially static models but
with the because the element of time because one feature that we have in our
maybe a little more precise
i'm assuming that i have a social network that schema as a graph g
and i'm observing
the social network over time period from year o to t and discretizing
at any time period a number of agents can become active
and at the end of the time period of time t
we let w be the set of factor eight
so not
for influence models
we assume that in each time
each agent becomes active
with probability with some probability p of a where a is the number of active
friends that this agent already
the probability of an agent becoming active is going to depend on number of factors
and notice that i'm assuming here that this is done independently in time times so
essentially i mean if you say if the number of for this guy doesn't have
that this guy has doesn't change over time
essentially this is going to be like apply process to determine what the name of
that this is going come
and one
choice to be used for the function p of a is the logistic regression function
which is the kind of thing
estimating problem
that means that the estimating log after the larger function of p of a which
is a lot of one
as a linear function of the
explanatory value but you have and valuable
are taking here is the log of the number of active friends plus one
there is an you're taking logo sort of like number of active friends itself is
that this is providing a better fit slightly benefit relatively consis that's not going to
make much of a difference
essentially all of the extra funding from the linear function of the same words
because that means that are assuming that the function p of a set of this
form of funding two
and essentially this coefficient of
it's something that measure social
correlation because if alpha is larger that means that if you have more
friends that increases the likelihood of becoming active
OK so
in order to estimate the
social correlation the systemic just
compute maximum likelihood estimates for the parameters of the data and alpha is going to
somehow indicate how much social correlation having system
to be more precise
but the maximum like problem
and why of denote the number of pairs of the user and i'm pretty user
this came from
writing that this is
you will log of one minus
but we're assuming you know that b is
minor constituent here select is a small number
so this is roughly equal to minus
and that's just
over and a plus
and b
and since then b is much smaller than in a this is approximately equal to
and the
so we're going to make this substitution
this quantity the smaller volume of a at at the over
the pure liquid
since then since
the concentration of b is low
we can assume that this is just the molar volume of
a general so in other words we can write
a a
star we can just write it is
the a bar that that is we're not going to worry about changes in the
molar volume either as a function of pressure a function of concentration at the low
concentrations that were working
and then
note that in a times
the eighty per mole
it's just the total mileage
not far
not optimal query this is the more quantity multiplied by the number of rules
so just gives a the total volume occupied by a
all right
and using
these two
then we have that our
can't negative and b
over a
this result
b over a
times clause i
is equal to zero
and they will cancel
and finally
almost all the volume is due to a again because b is the minor constituent
we can approximate further that the a is approximately equal to the
all right
so finally getting rid of the
and a on the denominators
so we're left with
a simple expression
finds the
these are
and b
so in a very simple expression
which is called the band harvick equation and expression in and look at how it
resembles the ideal gas law right this is the pressure times volume equals the number
of moles times RT
of course really it's the change in pressure
and this number of moles is the number of moles of gas constituent in solution
but it has the same form familiar with
we also sometimes it's convenient
since and b
over the
that's just the concentration
burn yes sir well then but
1st of all of this is for those of you who were working on June
C 4 year project I spoke with
feel hiatus from draper lab who's going to be giving the lecture hall and you
can see but he's not giving a lecture until the 3rd of November no that's
the kind of late and so I asked him if he would be willing to
meet with all of you who were working on June just so you could talk
with him and ask questions
you know if you want to give you the short version of his presentation is
can be given November you can do that but I don't think he's our in-house
resident expert and I figured it's better if you get a chance to talk to
early so he is he has time freedom moral and here's sometime next week is
out of 10 through today but if I know we have 2 teams working you
and see if if you guys wanna get together and find out of their sometimes
when you control
it fill I'll give his contact information systems happy to do it would be much
more convenient from his point of view if you could
seem at the same time and talk about it OK
I cylinder would you come up but I can say things happen and the 2nd
thing want
there was an interview printed in USA Today which posted on the class website with
microphone the administrator of it says administrator says spatial was a mistake and so the
question was you know what what do we intend to do about that in this
class will let me actually
read this specific words that Griffin uses because I think that's important Griffin said my
opinion is that the shuttle was a design which was extremely aggressive and just barely
possible and and and that's actually I think a slightly different way of looking at
this meeting I would also say that Apollo was that was a project which was
extremely aggressive and just barely possible and I think that it's actually NASA's business to
do things which are aggressive and just barely possible now whether whether it was the
right decisions for the country to abandon the exploration program after Apollo and and do
the shovel and then later on the space station that's more in the thinking the
political realm and as I think you've heard of both from Myers and and John
long that of it in fact there were political determining factors which in fact which
didn't really give us a lot of choices of just to remind you the the
basic point of this course is is not the political and economic history of the
show it's a technical exploration of how we did the shall also
I think we would all agree that the concept of the show was extremely aggressive
and the technology was being structures to it and it was just barely possible and
yet we didn't have
the the idea of this course is to understand how we didn't how the systems
work I think it will be interesting when we get towards the end of the
course that will sit down and relax and instead of having people there's there's to
kind of open sessions towards the end of the thinking about what we want to
do this in 1 of them I think we would maybe just talk a little
bit of reflect on what we've learned and that'll give us an opportunity to discuss
issues like this so that's all you can say about the site propose that we
will discuss this further today because we really
fortunate to have readily and code is going to introduce informally I'll just say that
when I was at Johnson Space Center last spring and and that 1 of the
older managers there and I was telling about our plans for this course and hardware
and was going to be a visiting professor here and we inviting some of the
the experts in the early design of the shuttle and he said well there's 1
guy you absolutely have to get past well we've gotten were very very fortunate the
error all 3 you and let you explain a little bit more why we're so
what that same problem have found inside of our time find best lives in a
place called Smithfield Texas and Splitsville Texas he said when people ask until Texas is
he said it's it's about a few minutes after you pass reasons speak so it's
not it's not overall the place I finally fell best and he is truly an
outstanding character in the thing that's so important is that Annex to me is from
my vantage point is really the linchpin you might say putting the system together aerodynamics
and makes the system come alive and as you can hear from the various speakers
from tom moser and from the you and we we talked about about the guides
navigation control it's important for the structures evidences brought for the structures that support for
the hydrophilic space
this is called the lipid bilayer and obviously it's highly effective
separating these two aqueous compartments
in eukaryotic cells as i mentioned last time
there's an enormous
premium placed on separating and segregating different aqueous compartments
which is invariably achieve
through the device of constructing these lipid bilayers
here's the vesicle
the vesicle is more complicated than myself because if you look at the membrane lining
the vesicle
you see it's actually lipid bilayer but one in three dimensional space is actually a
in the case of this vesicle we can well imagine that on the inside of
the vesicle
water is kept can be stored on the outside of vesicle water can be stored
in many of the membranes that we see
within the cytoplasm of cells are actually constructed on this kind of design
so here we could so when we draw for example in this case the gold
apparatus which i mentioned you in passing last time we met
each one of these membranes here it's obviously drawn double line but whenever you see
a membrane indicated implicit in that drawing
it is the fact that each one of these membranes is actually a bilayer
they're not there are never any monolayers of lipids in living cells
each one of these vesicles you see here is actually lipid bilayer with an aqueous
inside and once again aqueous on the outside
again much to of the thermodynamic stability that allows these vesicles to remain intact rather
than just few support
it is created by these hydrophilic and hydrophobic phobic forces which ties such molecules together
or will rip them apart
now in truth there are yet other kinds of forces that govern the affinity of
molecules to one another
for example
let's imagine a situation where we have a and ionize
i had a city group of the so we just talked about before
by the way here but still draw the negative charge on one of these two
oxygen is if you can see that
but the truth is that the electrons are swarming back and forth
so the negative charge is is shared equally the net negative one electron charge is
shared equally between these two oxygen atoms
and this is obviously an area of great electoral negativity
independent of that let's imagine up here we have a basic group
let's see and the mean group over here
and the fact of the matter is a main groups
NH two groups that's what i mean is
here's the main group this is the carboxylic group and the main group which is
used very often in biochemistry
it actually has an affinity it has an unpaired set of electrons on the nitrogen
and so he likes to attract protons to it
which makes it cause it to be called basic
and this attraction scavenging of protons
perhaps from the water will obviously give this
the whole group here
and that positive charge charge equal to the charge of one
here once again we can imagine this is hydrophilic because
charge group can once again also associate quite intimately with aqueous solvent
now independent of
any other forces that might exist here
indeed one could imagine situations where there is the sharing of the proton and therefore
hydrogen bonds form between these two
independent of that is the simple electrostatic interaction of these two groups
that is the charge the mutual attraction of positive and negative groups one to the
and electrostatic interactions you can quantify
exactly how many killer calories them all there is because
the the energetic value electrostatic interactions
sixty is the first support group which is not a crime
so i mean you can be fooled
but i mean i you know that now you get going to an IQ test
well you answer sixty one sixty
sixty one
i mean this case because of the much more familiar concepts and you would say
OK i mean
the the guy who came up with a sequence probably thought about prime numbers and
simple groups
if i have time i mean so so there we have some bias towards culture
or maybe not maybe prime numbers are much more fundamental than groups
but maybe it's just because of our culture
and i will tell you briefly how to put this cultural bias in this universe
OK so this nice website
they can
just type in the beginning of some sequences and it is the rule
large rule
based on some seem is my algorithms
for finding the patron behind the sequence and are often if you do research
you it a force for any one two two three four you get some numbers
and you want to find the general rule behind it which can be quite complex
if you had the rule to prove it is much easier to find the rules
so you can just type in the numbers five two rules and then afterwards to
prove what you want to prove often much easier
i mean it's sort of smart because i mean if you look twice the prime
i mean very recognised first from
after this example the question
this is there a unique principle
which allows us to formally arrive
if the prediction which
they coincide
most of the time with our intuitive guess
or even better
which gives us in some sense
most likely the best or correct answer whatever that means
and luckily the answer is yes and this is a common phrase
and all countries is a very simple principle it just tells you
you have many explanations for your data which are equally good take the most simple
so and
amazing things the work
and you can prove that
and i mean if you look at the previous example
makes sense
in all cases
maybe the sunrise the tricky
so actually
occam's razor can serve as a foundation of machine learning
some would disagree
i think you could go even further it
the fundamental principle in science
i would even go
further i would say that the definition of science straight from the what we try
to do we try to understand our world understanding our world means collecting data
and finding regularities in them
regularities means finding models which are simple that simpler than the data themselves
the symbol the model as long as it equally good
always finished so the symbol the model that
the more typically got attracted to it so you live
o comes
maybe even unconsciously
but what you
what you could do
you know just just to we camera
and place it wherever you want to
and i mean take i mean it in physics and chemistry i mean small molecules
or something i special measures by biology medicine or whatever say
let's be out in the optical space take the camera and move around and just
sequence of data
without any pre processing and then you ask you know built simple models from that
with which
i you typically doing in a uniform way but you are use think deeply about
the data to try to extract and so on but you can ask i mean
is there a formal way
what is what's behind what you're doing
no no no no no you can do that and if it makes things simpler
so for instance
so what i mean here so now think about the
the o's as the output at each timestep as representing a probability
distribution for example the probabilities for each of the symbols
that x can take at each timestep and then what we can be
doing is we can be able to use a recurrent net to generate a sequence
so the daughter arrows here this figure mean that we can sample
when we use a recurrent net in its generative mode
his to be just free-running it's going to produce its own inputs
so at time t is going to produce a probability distribution
over the random variable x t plus one given hold previous ones
and we can be able to draw samples for example pick a a a the
next character given the distribution represented by t so
you can imagine achieving a softmax overall a the
symbol values and we drop particular symbol now that becomes
the next input now i talked about symbols but
could be vectors real vectors it could be kind random variables
so what we doing here when we train this with maximum likelihood
is saying we're given a sequence x one to xt and would like
that are network gives a high probability that sequence we can
decompose the joint probability of the sequence x one to xt as a
product of conditionals so that's what you see on
on the right hand side of the equation on top
and each conditional is of the form p of the next symbol or the
next observation that have the symbol
given all previous ones of course we multiply all these probabilities
and you know it's just the standard the composition of joint
into a product of conditionals where the order here
is that temporal order that is usually the natural thing to consider
for sequential data so the training objective will just be
minus the log of the the thing on the top which means that it's
some of negative log probabilities for these conditionals
so we're trying to predict that actually observed next
symbol given all the previous symbols
and and we maximize the probability of of getting that thing
right so it's just like a classification problem
at each timestep and of course replace classification by regression
if it's real valued or any other kind of of types of random
variable so that's the that's the sense in which recurrent nets
can be thought about as a generative
model and if you think about it now in terms of graphical models
for those of you who know bit about that
we're thinking what you see is that there are no latent variables
are least know stochastically variables you can think of the s
is as a very special kinds of latent variables
but they're determinist the functions of of
everything else so the esses are deterministic functions of the
previous as of the previous x's through the equation we saw in the
previous slide right so the s t here's a completely deterministic
function of all previous x's and so you can actually think of
this as as in different ways from graphical model point of view
but if we ignore as is as as latent variables because they're
kind of deterministic then it's a fully observed
model where which means that we can just apply max like you very
ways and compute the tractable gradient and everything is easy and
simple and we can model the joint distribution
you can also think of s as latent variables but as i said there
are deterministic and the the role to play a is to make the
graphical model both statistically and computationally
more tractable so what you notice is that through this
through this equation defines as in terms of the previous x's
you you actually have a full dependency
of all the previous x's conditioning the next one so you
know it's not a graph model where we have removed any of the
arcs is fully connected directed graph model right so there's
no assumption know in the conditional independence assumption
you can model and this bution however in general for graphical
model you think that if you have this fully connected thing it
would be very expensive the number of parameters could blow up
to welcome to my mighty
tom friedman
who you know the foreign affairs columnist for the new york times
i will admit up front that's one of the few columns i read with great regularity
finding the content always stimulating whether or not i agree with one hundred percent
but as i told him earlier today
his titles are the best in the world
anybody who could write
dancing alone
war last week broccoli
all which enables you to remember brussels sprouts
whatever it is
i thought
i think it is you know he has won three pulitzer prizes
three blocks that's all the snow very well from beirut to jerusalem
the lexus and the olive tree which i remember alex darvill of introduced me to a couple years ago
a little more recently
longitude and latitude
he is a graduate the hour neighboring institution brand ice university
in mediterranean studies
and then got a master's degree in middle east studies at oxford university
so the reason is here today
i'm going to tell you the truth
i was in a hotel somewhere rather late at night
doing what i usually do hotels is lying in bed flipping through channels
anne i came across the last few minutes for the charlie rose show
and charlie was
interviewing tom they are having a great discussion these are talking about all these flatness and listening
and also i recognised with a star
here is really important
powerful public voice
in a very articulate manner
speaking the things that are very important to us here at the mighty
things such as these values of openness
andy things such as the importance of science and technology
and the importance of young men and women being educated in these fields to the future of this country
in addition of course
to the fundamental hypothesis fundamental mission
helping us to understand
a little more clearly some of the most important trends going on in the world he was of-course
discussing his new book the world is flat
which is in its second week i guess is number one on the new york times bestseller list
in just a moment in time is going to address this is gonna take a
little q and eighty and that's
well things of just about five o'clock
but thereafter are starting at five fifteen
there will be a reception high school how many people food is planned for
and they book-signing
downstairs and they washroom ten one o five times welcomed mighty
so thank you very much further
having me it's a it's a tree and an honor to be here enormously stimulating day
already so i look forward to this conversation
thank you also for getting my book titles right you know i've often been introduces the of from beirut lebanon
the lexus the palm tree that's the problem
end on latitudes and attitudes is not a jimmy buffett's song
end and thank you also for noting that i i i my book ascended to
number one this week and the new york times bestsellers i finally made it had
jane fonda
because i was gonna retire my book flat world flat abs if i didn't say so but i i
i'm itself
so i thought i'd talk for the next thirty minutes or so and just the origins of this book and
they accidental weight came about and don't give you a sense that the court pieces
and really look forward to dialog
this book really was
an accident on
but those u remark on know that i'm really i became a foreign affairs columnist
in january nineteen ninety five and
between nineteen ninety five and d of september tenth two thousand one
my column really oscillated between what i would call access issues and olive tree issues
issues about trade technology finance
on many issues about geopolitics and ethnic conflict
and on my was really in the kind-of oscillation mode they say right up until
september eleventh when applied what happened that day
i really dropped the whole x story like a stone
and went off and covered the all three wars common really spent three years after nine eleven
traveling almost exclusively in the air muslim world trying to understand the roots nine eleven and
covering the war in afghanistan and in
and i was really in that mode on right up to the last january january
two thousand four but sixteen months ago
i started doing documentaries recently for the discovery channel we don't want the roots nine eleven
we did one on the on the wall potentials built in in the in the
west bank and in january two thousand four we're sitting around with our discovery of
new york times team
trying to figure out what to do are next documentary on
and at the time the issue of america's standing in the world america's low standing
in the world was a very hot issue
and so i had this idea i said why don't we
when we got a call centers all over the world
an interview young people who spend their days imitating americans on what they think of america
after make fun can have almost double mirror
and we are literally a budget that's show when on certain presidential democratic hopeful named
john carry on came out with his blast against
benedict arnold executives who outsource
as you recall the whole issue outsourcing just exploded
onto the world stage
endowment front pages a business week and fortune and forums and the new york times and the wall street journal
so i said no time timeout wider
why don't we just go to bangalore
he outsourcing capital of india
end on our the silicon valley of india and do a documentary called others side
about outsourcing where we look at this phenomenon from the ground up
and that's what we what we did
and so in
on february fifteen two thousand four set of to bangalore with are discovery crew
we shot about sixty hours of interviews
and in the course over ten eleven days
and over the course of those sixty hours of interviews i got
six hour and search
and it was not the food
it was
the sense i got with each passing it
while i had been sleeping
while i have been of covering
the nine eleven wars
something really big it happened in this globalization story
and i had
completely missed
thought hit me somewhere between
good afternoon everyone
after i have to admit that introducing frank wilczek makes me a little nervous
so so i went to the web
and i looked at one of his
enormous number of prices and and decided to read
the citation or the least the press release from
the lawrence medal
which was awarded to him in the fall of two thousand two
and then i'll add a few remarks as i go along with that and i'm
not reading all of
lawrence medal awarded to american physicist frank wilczek
professor wilczek is one of the most influential theoretical physicist of his generation he was
an instrumental figure in the discovery of the phenomenon known as asymptotic freedom
this is the phenomenon whereby the building blocks which make up the nucleus of an
atom cork's behave free particles when they are close together but become more strongly attracted
to each other as the distance between them increases this theory forms the key to
the interpretation of almost all experimental studies involving modern particle accelerators in the view of
the academy will will checks for is characterized by both its breath and step
professor well wilczek studied at the university of chicago
i should cause there
i got my bachelor's degree at the university of chicago
a couple years before frank and jerry friedman got his bachelor's degree in chicago larry
rosen sent so
we are chary and larry and i in good company
then he went on to princeton
it says where he obtained his doctorate in nineteen seventy four he later became professor
of physics at princeton and the university of california santa barbara since two thousand he
has held firm in freshwater chair at MIT
he is a member of the american the american national academy of sciences and how
has received the dirac medal and the michaelson morley prize
many others are the
press release goes on to point out that many winners of the lawrence medal have
later gone on to win the nobel prize examples include max plank wolfgang pauli
petrus to buy
and then there are a few more recent ones kawai mcnair cornell
here to share and
during character after that that tries to win
about the same time maybe a few months later we learn that frank won the
lillian fell prize
the american physical society in this prize is given
to someone who has done great things in physics but also is an outstanding communicator
in the citation reads for his role in the development of asymptotic freedom in other
aspects of quantum chromodynamics
a cornerstone of the standard model for his remarkable versatility and research in condensed matter
in astrophysics as well as particle physics and for his outstanding ability to lecture and
write with clarity profundity and enthusiasm
and anyone who has read his articles in physics today will certainly agree with the
latter when
bob shafi
and i worked together with operational to bring frank to princeton
i certainly felt was one of the greatest and most successful collaborations of my career
and i'm really proud that we have here as as bob cathy once said frank
is the luminary and i hope he will illuminate as
well thank you that's not an easy introduction to live up to and i i
do expect larger
we're trying to do for
in the first part of this lecture i'm going to explain the origin of mass
you laugh and you may think that's an oversight overselling what i'm going to do
and let me first admit that i am
i'm only going to explain the origin of most mass
astronomers recently have taught us that most of the mass in the universe as a
it is in some
mysterious form that we call dark energy and we really have very little idea what
it is
it's very odd properties it's
most notably it exerts negative pressure
and that produces that seventy percent of the universe
of the mass of the universe averaged over very large distances
roughly twenty seven percent
isn't was something that's also mysterious
so called dark matter
this we also don't know what it is although there are some very good ideas
about it
it doesn't exert any pressure at all
i'm not going to be explaining either of those kinds of mass
the kinds of mass i'm going to explain most of or the mass of you
and me and our immediate neighbourhood the master dominates
on earth in the solar system in in fact part of the galaxy
even though this familiar form of matter
based on protons neutrons and electrons
only constitutes
about three percent of the mass of the universe as a whole
i hope you'll agree that is a particularly significant
a part of the mass
and i will be explaining quantitatively in in detail
the origin of nineteen ninety percent or more of the mass of ordinary matter
just because you can say the words doesn't mean
and they make grammatical sense doesn't mean it makes any sense conceptually
what does it mean to talk about the origin of mass
in newtonian mechanics it really wouldn't mean anything at all
in o one two
i i teach students the the first three laws of the three laws of motion
and newton's three laws but before that we discuss the zeroth law
and the zeroth law of mechanics of classical mechanics is
that mass is conserved
that mass doesn't change
the axis of the examples actually catch that margin are called support vectors that's what
i call the support vector machine it turns out
you can write
this you can rewrite this formula the sign of some
linear vector u in in practice you x you can
rewrite that
a weighted sum of the inner product of the support vector x so another way
of thinking about the support vector is basically some sort of fancy weighted nearest neighbour
OK so you're looking at the distance the inner product between x and y axes
the sort of distance between these two and you're weighting the different examples differently
and finally you're taking the sign of all that
this is another way of thinking about support vector machine
one thing that nice about this formulation
is that these inner products right here
and replaced with more general class of distance functions called kernels
so that gives you some additional flexibility in how the algorithm behave because you can
change the distance function
and in fact support vector machines are one of the
standard techniques for using are for for for handling topical to classification
techniques these are sort of the arm
you know on the brand x method that you always try to be a research
papers these are sort of the the baseline competitive markets here again some kind of
old results but these were from a very influential paper back in nineteen ninety eight
this is the naive bayes and these are on kind of the categories from the
supporters data that i showed you
OK and there's a bunch of different variants of support vector machine based on this
different distance functions
but the simplest distance function is basically just an inner product OK and you know
the micro averaged accuracy here
one which is some way with measuring the average of these ten categories is eighty
four point two
well for naive bayes seventy two point so you can sort of see we're getting
a little bit of extra performance for the extra work for doing this optimisation
in this picture a couple of other albums here which also do pretty well so
there's roadkill here
this k nearest neighbour
o talk about c four point five talk briefly about these other two
right so these other two albums are simpler algorithms
that are
are based on
a particular representation for documents and the representation of very active this this factor that
i showed you
we started out with the vector where each component was the frequency
in other words
so the number like one two three four five right so
the idea in this representation the change these numbers to represent some sort of statistical
weight of the word
some measure of the importance of that word so
a formula which is a rather ad hoc working formula but seems to work quite
is to wait words higher if there infrequent OK so if there words that appear
infrequently in the document so if only appears in you know
you know
and documents and the entire collection image have a high weight weighted towards it appears
many times in the document will have a lower weight
right and this is no extension things that appear frequently enough are stop would you
just throw away
all right the other thing you want to do is you want in
increase the weight of words that are frequent turns out taking those things and has
been through a lot seems to work better than just using the frequency
so this is just the formula for change in the way to these documents so
a kind of common thing to do is to use these weights and scalable vector
so they have like one
so this is called the TFIDF representation
it is a very simple idea and it turned out to be very surprising useful
thing in a lot of different situations
so this is an old trick from information retrieval
and to give you some example
here's another very very simple algorithm so
given an example of vector you want to classify just find the k closest things
the factors that are nearest to where would have the closest
largest inner product and then we're going to predict by basically looking at a weighted
sum of these factors the case we define the class so that if i look
at all the things that the class in some the distances it'll be some very
into products small from the similarities with the highest score
OK so close to a lot of positive things far away from the negative things
will give positive way otherwise twenty nine
so that's k nearest neighbour in TFIDF space right another maybe even a little sum
for his will take the positive examples and more animals will take all the examples
and will subtract one from the couple waiting here alphabet equals one is not a
bad idea
and then we'll just taken as are classifiers so if you like we're looking at
things that are close to the part of the centre of the positive examples and
far from the centre of the negative examples
so these two albums are rocchio
and k nearest neighbour and TFIDF space and using these are actually doing quite well
so therefore there you know microaverage performances up close to a duel but
so these are some other competitive algorithms one of the nice things about the k
nearest neighbor algorithm
ah well actually two nice things about k nearest neighbor algorithm
so getting neighbours close neighbours of the documents sounds like it might be a hard
thing to do is OK but in fact that's exactly what
when i are search engine is designed to do so traditional ranked retrieval engines basically
try and find things that are most similar in this TFIDF space
finding these papers if you have a search engine lying around the to question making
one call
i think that's about this is when you find the nearest neighbors
and that these similarities you end up with scores for every class and it doesn't
matter how many classes you have
you still get scores for every class
so this the very efficient thing to do if you have say a hundred classes
are hundred thousand classes
one last thing which shows the TFIDF is sort of a surprisingly useful thing to
do so a couple of years ago i think in two thousand two or three
jason running at MIT
the paperwork evaluate naive bayes with TFIDF weighting of factors
which are probabilistic point of view doesn't really make any sense whatsoever
right and the other little trick is used on the complement of the data rather
than the original class that's kind of a little detail
so this is the multinomial naive bayes
and this is
his TFIDF weighted complement naive bayes and you can sort of see a fairly large
performance improvement on several different problems here
and in fact what you end up with something is quite competitive with support vector
so what
i'm not talk briefly about some other fast discriminative methods in fact that just with
through this very quickly because i want to spend a the of time on
some of the other things in part two when we got off to a little
bit of late start
machine learning
where you don't want to do all the data back to a central site you
want to locally quantizer or some other kind of compression and send a small bit
rate back to a central site do something sophisticated
so how can we solve the problem in in the theoretically satisfying way kind of
set up this problem where the risk functional is the probability of error or you
label was different than the when you predicted
and the decision now it's got two parts to its both the experiment design quantizer
and discriminant functions and we want to find the discriminant function and quantized to minimize
the probability there
and i talked about kind of literature two main literature that focused on half the
problem and the whole problem either you some q is known try to find a
discriminant that's kind of machine learning
this stick to processing assumes that everything all the probabilities are known so you could
actually get the discriminative by bayes rule
but they focus on getting q
and what you get q then you do actually use bayes rule together the quantizer
OK so so the
the single processing focused on these things known as f divergences mars morris's heuristic you
want to push distributions apart
and these are measures of how close distributions are interview maximizes divergences you're pushing them
apart and that's the way to get principle of how to choose the quantizer or
the experimental design general
OK so there's a list of some of them there are many of them any
convex function of the likelihood ratio
average defines afterwards
and then there was the theorem we need blackwell that sort of said that after
versions used to rank procedures in terms of risk i e probability there
for some unknown prior so that motivated people to looking at literature look after
and then the machine learning perspective was to have a decision theoretic story for you
develop the surrogate loss functions
and they are there for like boost in support vector machine logistic regression so on
their upper bounds on this intractable zero one loss
and then there's a theory
says that if i
you basically have a year surrogate loss is differentiable zero and has a negative strictly
negative derivative the origin then that's necessary and sufficient for bayes consistency so me i
didn't actually to find these consistency yesterday but i mean what you expect to mean
means the number of data points gets large
but you converge to making the probability very close to zero or for the base
rate the best you can do
so in this case is that the functional estimation problem it's not just the parameter
estimation problem
OK so i think we're getting close to rest yesterday
so we're trying to define this notion of universal equivalence among surrogate loss functions
and i had a little notation and
if you know the the main of notation is that for a given circuit loss
function for not zero one loss in general but maybe we have an argument which
is the
but but the sources of reporters risk and just expanding out you get
probability under a y was one and probably otherwise equal to minus one and then
we started the averaging respect diseases we have two
that expectation is location both y and z data has the wine is the component
the classification problem we did one of the average is not the other and that's
what the risk looks like
OK then we profile we do this frequencies sort of well for one thing is
the thing to do and then you try to prove the frequency you it's OK
you the right thing so we take the infimum over the discriminant function
and so we did that for zero one loss and we've turned out that the
zero one risk profile zero one risk was the negative of a after versions in
particular the variational distance and then we did that for a bunch of other examples
and we found was the general stories seem to be emerging
which was that profiled risks of of surrogate loss functions always were equals the negative
of a
i mean after versions
OK so that's a new result that's not been present in the literature for all
these forty years or something
and i want the new results to prove the theorem about it the theorem tells
you there's this many to one link between surrogate loss functions defined in this way
now just loss functions with a special class of surrogate loss functions and after taxes
and so the proof needed to define a notion of the
how social contextuality and here's the first theorem which we went through yesterday which can
go in one direction given a large enough divergence was easy and then backwards given
after versions you get a whole family of loss functions and the family was parameterised
here it is by a three degree of freedom this function f
the house is there has to be to simply increasing continuous and convex sets him
and here are some examples of different choices of g gives you a bunch of
different loss functions all of which lead to the hellinger distance
and then you do this is by doing the conjugate duality calculation here's a bunch
f or g functions that lead to loss functions include the hinge loss
all of which yields variational distance
and then KL divergence
OK so here was our problem and we're going try to solve which is that
we're going to try to get bayes consistency for choosing both the quantizer and the
discriminant function
and now i'm going to draw another picture the
well the losses
so thirteen losses something special kind of losses
and since
and we've got this characterization theorem that says that for every version certain region over
here the born
OK so the
the theorem that the the more down statistical it's kind of this a bit of
convex analysis really
the statistical theorem now says that what you need to do is to start with
zero one loss so here's a particular zero one loss and one regions and go
over to the the corresponding f divergence and now take an expansion of that given
so there's the variational distance and many of you one that is the function that
gives you variational distance
o point here
precipitate on the dust particles of the smoke
and therefore they will grow
and it's not possible to smoke
there will be very small
what are
drop in that
but there are much larger than the small particles
and you will clearly see
the light that reaches q
has been can now
of small in my lungs
distinctly wider
then this
you're ready for that
just remember
first this color
OK here we go
color change
so it was blue
the first time
i mentioned
this guy
the sky is blue
the sky is blue for the same reason
that the smokies broome
in the earth's atmosphere
many very small dust particles
and even if those small dust particles
one of their
in the atmosphere itself
there are small fluctuations of the density of the air
and so if i put q
at the bottom
of the earth's atmosphere which is a big blank areas
we're here
and the sunlight comes from from the direction
so very far away
by the fact that
coming in like so
six straight on the thing to do that is when the sun is
the there
not there
what you see
OK i ever reach
can these find that support
so what is the colour
because blue
we forward scattering
violet either one
kind way more than random or
so when you look
right there
same reason why this focus
is it possible may be that some of the sunlight
that's carriers of dust in the sky
scanners at ninety degrees if that's the case
i mean business
i go with my little polarizes i look at this guy
and i can convince myself that that part of the sky was a hundred percent
of course
there's a whole
is no matter where the sum is
this is about the rise
there's a whole
o ninety degrees away from the sun so there
this is all ninety degrees away from the
the sun is there
all ninety degrees away from
just like this single year
thank you
and so if i look at this guy
not only is this guy blue which i now
perhaps understand the little
but you don't get the direction
which is ninety degrees away from the direction of the sun
no matter where i do
with my little polarizer that you have now in your pocket
you can convince yourself
this guy
is hundred percent
are some
so beautiful
that you should be able to and so now for yourself
the sun
all right
you are here
here is rank of air
anderson is very low in the horizon
the sunlight
comes in this way
because the sun is so low in the sky
so in that
how much atmosphere
this light has to go through
the light
like that wants to scatter
and then there comes a time that all the light being scattered about that there
is no blue light anymore
well there may maybe some of the
i started get
and and maybe some of the light field camera
and then all
these colors have been removed from the white sunlight
what remains is red
so it is the lights
that penetrates very deep into the atmosphere that makes it all the way to here
that has no anymore in
no green
not even yellow
it therefore
is red that happens to be cloutier
specially made
so far away
it was the red light strikes the cloud
so therefore
the same reason why the sky is blue
is the reason why the sun is red when it set
all the sunlight now must go through an enormous
layer of atmosphere
light gone
real light is gone
what you end up with
what is left over maybe some of you
that's what i want to demonstrate
you have my last
i want to catch was my last demonstration
i want to catch kill three birds
with one stone
and the three but i want to kill
i number one
that the sky is blue
i'm going to make a blue sky
number two
but if you look at this guy
ninety degrees away from the sun
in and f in generalisation of boosting to the structured learning problem
browne talks sorry
we do this all round yesterday talked in detail about bursting cells just go very
fast one thing i need to point out is that i have changed annotation love
it here instead of the W's over the features now i'm using actually landers
boosting the basic idea we combine weak learners features
to get our ensemble
and we're only in in other words we're walking around with each repeat feature so
that we minimize empirical error and then we we
find its optimal weight update delta
so this is the approach
o this iterative optimisation approaches gives features questions property and another key idea of boosting
is that we maintain a weight distribution over examples so that it each we focus
more on the misclassified examples
all right so in india original adaboost do optimisation function
optimized the optimisation function considered is the exponential loss
so our our classifier are some world is going to be penalised for every training
instance that is not the correct one
we're going to be penalized exponentially
for the ones
there are ranked higher than the current one so if if the
compatibility score of this leaving this label
sigma is higher than this guy this is going to be a positive so it's
going to be large and if it's negative it's going to be a small in
yes we know that boosting actually optimizes the l one norm of the
margin and that we're gonna use later on
that information we're gonna use later
now how do we do
structured boosting
let's consider the loss function again we're gonna use exponential loss so it's going to
be the same but now instead of the observation
labelled pairs we have is structured instances in which means that the sum over all
labels is going to be a sum over some is something that the exponential
again this is a convex optimisation problem right so we can use a gradient based
optimisation technique in order to compute in order to
four from this optimisation exactly and this will be based on the gradients which is
a actually a function of far
a function of far
expectations of features
and we know that we can we can compute these using a forward backward algorithm
and the scale si in
in sequences they scale linearly so we're good
we can do this optimisation problem exactly by performing a dynamic programming which scales linearly
and what about a adaboost version of this problem so
so the the same the same
the same key ideas will follow as well we're going to maintain a weight or
are training instances in this case the training instances is there is an observation
paired with the possible labellings so we're going to consider all possible labellings and at
each iteration
we're gonna
update our weight so that we focus on the misclassified examples and how was the
obvious here so we're going to say
we see that the this term is going to be no this term is going
to be large for for the ones that we have misclassified because this is going
to be a positive time so we will be focusing more on the misclassified examples
the same is the same as before
same as incentivising right so now we are working on it and we're working with
iterations each it is at each iteration we're going to pick a feature that minimizes
the weighted empirical error and this this actually can that the is given by this
giant beast here
so we're going to find the optimal weight by minimizing the normalisation constant here
the normalisation function here partition function here and if you look at it it's not
the details of this this
formula is not all that important wanting to point out that is really important is
that this is now not only here in terms of the features for all possible
because this time might be very and this is problematic because now we we do
not have the dynamic programming approach to compute the
optimal weights for all possible features
well we will have to do is pointed out by the original CRF paper we
have to perform in dynamic programming for each training instance of sorry for each feature
and obviously this is not going to be possible when we have many many features
right and this is bad
and will be because of this property did this approach has been you know that
it is intractable problem
the simple idea we had was to
use the convexity of the exponential loss
which is actually using in itself in boosting
all problems so cynics financial losses upper bounded by the senior function here and the
inequalities given here
so in fact if i use this inequality
three thousand
nine hundred
and a eight
and the nice thing about this demonstration is that the difference between the motions is
twenty four hours
and you can very easily here that
so here is this tuning fork
four thousand four is
you know we go
a few times now we try to do because
i gave them preferential treatment
he gives
higher pitch when i come to you clearly
this is about twenty four hours
suppose now
that i rotate
a sound source in a circuit
rotated around
like so
angular velocity omega
radius are
this is where you are
and let the circum ferentials pvt zero
goes around with constant speed
so v zero
omega or
and the sound sources frequency f
so it's clear that it moves away from human effort primarily smaller than
have prime will be f
f prime
will be larger than
so as you listen
this sound
you will hear the sound change
in a sinusoidal wave because what matters is not the speed of sound
but the rate the speed of the source but the radial component new directions and
the radial component here is for the zero
he away from you with the radial component is zero
so if you arbitrarily cold this time equals zero here
the velocity radio
the components you are actually is that these zero
times the sign of omega t
so if you recall
not only listen but if you actually record
as a function of time
the frequency that you here
then you hear something like this
and this then
is the mean value af which is
transmitted by the sound source
now you can ask yourself the question what you learn from this
is amazing what you do is you can close your eyes and just record the
sound signal as a function of time
the first thing that you learn from it
is the period t which is by
divided by omega
so you know the period
of rotation you know omega
but you also records
whatever prime maximum is
and you also recorded crime in
so was the doppler shift equation
that we have here
you can easily calculate what these errors
and so you know also v zero
but since he is only are you also know are
so just imagine by recording that sound signal as a function of time you can
determine the periods
of rotation is omega
this breed in a circular orbit and
the rate is even
so i will to demonstrate this to you just qualitatively
so i have here
i don't even know what frequencies produces maybe it's a mixture of many frequencies
that's not so much the point
i want you to hear
if i told you about now it's no longer the metal highlow highlow highlow now
is a gradual change to a height h
no page
and then you see this industry
it is we really don't know
it is really high time slower
but his nose sinusoidal change call signs all changes sign
so keep in mind which is going to be important in what follows today
from this you can determine the periods
the speed
and the radius
no electromagnetic radiation
showstopper shift
that means
if you move towards the source of electromagnetic radiation
you will
we caught a higher frequency than was transmitting
and if the source of radiation comes to you but also
record high frequency
and if you move away from each other your record lower frequency
and the doppler shift equation four
electromagnetic radiation is not so easy to derive you need special relativity for that
but i will give you the result
i want you to appreciate
there is no such thing as a velocity of the receiver and the separate velocity
of the transmitter now because in special relativity
the only thing that matters is the relative velocity between the two
it is an illegal question even to ask
who is moving towards home
and was moving away from home so there's only one velocity
in special relativity
so let this be
the transmitter
of electromagnetic radiation
and there's been a receiver
and this is the relative velocity v
and this angle to say that
i'm not trying to tell you that it is this object that is moving in
this direction it could be this one that is moving in this direction this is
the relative velocity between
the two
in the line of sight
so the
component of the velocity which we call the radial component which plays an important role
that two
so this component
is the
cosine theta
and with this picture in mind
if this one
the wavelength lambda
which frequency f
and this one receives wavelength lambda prime
with frequency as prime
then lambda one lambda prime is
c divided by f crime
and lambda
c divided by f
i will give you the results of the doppler shift equation in terms of land
and then you can always
use that relationship to do it in terms of f
it's given when you really loved this made significant technical innovations in the field had
been transferred to practice in significant ways has significantly influenced the direction of the research
and development team in this also includes a black knowledge
the best innovation award in his friedman like manila due you
nations cup
and pleasure to announce c is mission one is something
the award is given very seven contributions to machine learning and data mining algorithms that
scales to large commercial database systems and for applications in mining massive data sets the
to fundamentally new scientific discoveries and citation links
forty two
so vv
phd from michigan
chief data officer executive vice president for research and strategic solutions
founder and chairman DMX group functions e g is currently fellow ACM and finally to
their and all words
he got to service award in two thousand three from and as born maybe five
minutes exceptional achievement nineteen ninety four
and you can see lead one products maybe three
four security cell is currently
the secretary treasurer and he was awarded that from nineteen ninety two thousand five singh
was the founding editor in chief of security
explorations and also the
and which key ninety five post-conference john ninety six german in nineteen
he just two
kdd and not something like a chance of additional papers and fifty medications and thirty
two twenty
this is the one
like it looks like
thank you
thank you for me
i agree in
everyone this is a
i agree to
let me start with
but actually
thank you some people
i know this is a long list and i don't mean to
and a lot of it
it's very humbling to be awarded the award
it is a big deal to me and i apologize for called by some congested
forgive me
first and foremost thank my family
my wife kristina
my four kids three of which are in the audience
and my parents actually like to dedicate this lecture to memory of my mother passed
away your
know she would be proud of the
a lot of people have influenced my work throughout the years and are listed some
of them are like that you don't want to read everything before that
but the point of
i really don't deserve all the credit three a a lot of people who
i happen to be fortunate enough that they a crossed my line
and we are extremely helpful
in getting to this point
so i mean
introduced me was actually on my
he was my first
summer job
in general more research
and actually introduced me to what eventually became my phd topic
at the time when you're working with
with data on automobile
automobile repairs as GM likes to call it not false
and since then he has been very instrumental in
helping out my career
same degree
shortly thereafter offered me another summer jobs in an effort to put him but i
want to
GPL which also changed my life
there's a lot of people and i'm extremely thankful to them and forced most recently
my colleagues
so i thought i'd do today
and we try to keep it short
i happen to be in a very unusual
w or i guess it's going to be giving a lecture on tuesday morning as
invited talks
and what i wanted to do is leave the two
be very different
i one two
make this one a bit more personal
since it's about
getting an award and
about how i got here so it's really i call a data miner's story
o open is going to have a happy ending
but mostly personal observations about what we are frankly i introduced to
the grand challenges of the talking some more about the technical grand challenges today i'll
talk about the pragmatic once and for all
basically on my experience
through field
on these so hopefully this will be useful and interesting
so i think we'll just give you understanding why data mining is a must
throughout my story at least some of the challenges that i think it's very important
for the pragmatic perspective
and some case studies
well including
so let's start with the
with the again why people being a lot of attention to
data mining
one right
eighteen months we double processing speed
this story to according to many and estimates including jim gray doubles every nine months
so you get
double the amount