affects the tried to was to suppressed by adding the signals to the confounders and
had to report the
the KT and how to get clean EEG but also has an influence on the
from right so we also use it in that respect
now this is 1 of the subjects that are assumed to be applied all the
methods so do you very correlated EEG and the from right and you see here
that the subject correlation is
larger than boards 3 and actually this is not what I should use more statistically
statistical threshold but this this correlation means that the the the false detection rate very
very low and this year the occipital lobe was highly correlated and also the parietal
if we a look at all the other subjects we see that the amount of
correlation varies a lot of here again I used this threshold of important to throw
in some subjects that this this
thresholds in the whole brain is correlated at some other subjects there is not so
much the correlation of forces the correlation is not a measure which all these constantly
compared to what we should do is to use false detection and to have a
lot to do with the same false detection rates for these these images could be
compared with this slide is only to show you that there's a very large variations
of subject if we look at the amount of correlation between alphabet
and from right here and in the light of day this beach and so full
all of of these holes in the lobby of various lived experience that we have
used is the average of all the occiput lead and we have explored also the
reconstructed reconstructed source for using of elites but that doesn't make very much a difference
nowadays season even video it of all people are will show you something that that
that's very robust and even if you do something completely different you still get the
same thing now what you can do because we have estimated the hemodynamic responses from
the data itself instead of using standard family response functions we can also studied and
remembered responses so this part of the brain is the representing the thalamus we see
that the government response look like this so it's positive and negative and goes to
0 these are the non-causal correlation so that you see that there not significant if
you tested more formally then indeed you find that that these points are not significant
and you see for more adept at the periphery of the occipital lobe the
and remember responses or negative starting the
effect at the center responses are negative the implies that the more alpha rhythm is
produced locally the less energy is locally consumed and that the tool for the whole
cortex except for the thalamus that's the other way around so you could think of
that these new
generator of the algorithm is that the thalamus and uh that the regions of the
cortex mm the follows the use of these oscillations
it's not a very good explanation actually but actually I think nobody understands what are
probabilities of what the collision is for the negative or positive
well we also analyze that for all subjects instantly so now we will look at
for predefined points left right warned right parental portal triple point and that's elements there
were there were selected them
the that that ball those points the the the false detection rate was determined if
that will smaller than 1 % then the recent there is and there is an
activity going on there and if that also about that threshold then we put now
here's itself off to 16 subjects you find correlation of the occipital point and that
of the common sense of this stuff the left and right throughout the points also
and if you look at the hemodynamic responses of different subjects that we see despite
the fact that the amount of correlation the total correlation patterns very very much of
a subject we see that that if you look at the acceptable born the all
of the government responses to traders and also the telomeres thereby face extensive involved is
1 subject was a little bit more wild and see also that the left and
right frontal cortex the members forms also look very similar there's only 1 exception that's
the subjects who has a positive their correlations at the cortex and that subject have
recorded another time and again we found this this positive correlation
so I think there still is some antiseptics variability and priorities have government responses is
positive instead of negative that is that the what don't know
not the sort of more interest to give it a bit more detail about what
the the shape of the response if you have if you consider the government response
itself as we have determined it that you can only study at this time resolution
of 3 seconds because that's the acquisition of the of the memorize and to interpolate
the functions we used new parametrization so deposit this parameterization restricted to the to the
hemodynamic responses
not to directly on the
component the model
and then we get to the top of this kind of
examples so this is the thalamus received modification of signal and now we can do
much more precisely the determine the peak times of the year of the hemodynamic responses
now if you compare for all these 4 points of interest all the subjects of
the peak times of the occipital in the and the prior to and 4 and
introducing actually in new approach
that learns an outlier us come filter
and this is work done in collaboration with the bank of doris and stefan schaal
also at USC
so just to start this is the outline of my talk first going to start
by motivating
why were interested in producing an outlier robust come filter
i'll quickly
review what the common filter is briefly
and then i will introduce our method which is essentially
a new way of doing robust coming filtering by learning
beige weights
and i'll finish up by
presenting our results on an experimental data set and conclude
we consider
real time applications where storing data samples may not be a viable option either due
the high frequency of incoming sensory data
insufficient or limited memory resources that you would have
so for example in systems where
the quality of sensory data needs to be high
reliable and robust
detection of outliers and removal of outliers is pretty essential for optimal performance
so for example i can give you an in illustrating applications in robotics which is
what our lab deals with and if you want to do
legged locomotion
and you'll see this in the last few slides the top we're actually show you
results on a robot dog
and undetected outlier in your incoming sensory data
can potentially disturb the balance control that you have on the robotic dog
such that the dog loses stability which is something that you don't want
so in such scenarios where real time tracking is necessary to come filter
is a
very simple method for doing this
it's in fact the
the optimal linear estimator for a gushing system that gives the minimum mean squared error
and it's often used to
projects are estimated what the hidden states are
given noisy measurements
so you can use hidden state estimates to then and also calculate what the measurement
do you should be
now the problem of the color filter though it it's not robust to outliers
and in fact it integrates its performance degrades in the presence of outliers
so let's look at what previous methods have have tried to do too two
addresses this problem
so i just missed really briefly
and the top half of the fly
some of the matter out there that have been developed in the past forty fifty
and the issues that we have with them
so first of all for example you can their methods that consider nongaussian distributions to
model the random variables so the reason why non gas distribution to use it because
they tend to be heavy tailed
so long red sites and
hence less sensitive to
you know the mean squared error
another option is to model your noise your state norms and you observed notice as
nongaussian his tail distributions as well
so an example of such a distribution p the student t distribution
with a little bit flatter has heavier tails
other methods also use sampling techniques for integration techniques and outside the few pieces of
work by kitty to go up
and another approach which is a little bit different uses
a weighted least squares approach
this is something that we you see robustly squares and the idea is quite simple
you basically take each sample that you observe and associate away with it
and you know most techniques would actually model this weighted sum the error function
for example the q function i say that
basically this we associate with
each data sample indicates sort of its contribution to it
it's how much of an outlier this
to the
to the filter so
a lower windsor zero which indicate that it's more of about outlier in higher weight
i mean
so start
do you have an announcement
so here is now
you know
a slightly more interesting model
to come up with this probability estimates OK
to do this smoothing
OK so
what we will do in this model and the probabilistic latent semantic analysis model is
you know we have all these documents we have all these terms
we should use an intermediate layer if you like
of latent concepts
and will then try to estimate for each
document a distribution over the latent concepts
OK so say
however we need to
refer to
as of parameter you know we just call it either OK but it's really just
in saturated probability distribution case for every document every concept there will be approach you
know i'm number nonnegative number which corresponds to probability
and then for the terms are concerned you know we can
private like this doesn't really matter but you know there is a probability
that particular word will express
the concept is the same because this
you know these parameters pi
OK and so the idea is something that
you know in order to deal with variations in the level of the terms
that you know there are these concepts you like trade right so this is one
concept we could figure out that the document is with the concept trades
and then figure out the trade
can be expressed you know that concept by the the term trade but also by
things like imports and economic and knows what all these things actually relates to trade
so if we see
something like imports
it's kind of an indication for this concept
so then you know so that's basically the structure of the model
now these concept expression probabilities right on the right we can estimate based on all
documents that are dealing with a particular concept right so we can use the whole
document collection to do that and
and in a way you can also think of this as kind of an odd
mixing up with them
where each document is kind of composed of multiple topics are concepts
right and sort of we trying to figure out you know what are these pure
concepts like to what we observe
in real life is always something that a mixture of multiple concepts but now we
we assume that
we can somehow you know we have a million of these mixes that somehow we
can perhaps find a couple of hundred per couple of thousands of these pure concepts
and then explain the the documents that we see is a mix of these
pure content
so if we write down algebraically
we can write it like this
the only thing is that actually i switch status and the policy of
it's not a big deal
so this is i think what i would use this in the following so
it's a mixture model
right so the probability of word given document
we write as sum over the concepts and the probability of that concert given the
document the probability of the word given the concepts rights
so that's what graphically we mean by being in the middle right so and then
we some out
that latent variable
it's like in concert very right so we have the document language model to the
left the latent concept is expression probability that the document specific mixture proportions if you
so every document has specific mixture proportions in
these probabilities
we have to estimate some model fitting like
and let me come back to what we saw before the break in terms of
matrix factorizations
right you can actually rewrite
you could you can kind of take that model and also introduces probability for each
document is basically
the document length
in that case here and you can actually write it in the symmetric form can
just by reversing this probability here using bayes rule so you get this
and this actually
you know this farm you can actually think
of this as as a matrix so it's whatever we have and documents a and
q concept it would be an n by q matrix and this you would be
and MIQ matrix m terms and again q concepts and so
you know it corresponds to the composition where you know this this thing matrix here
a kind of the document probabilities and this over here would be termed probabilities
one entry here
right would be
concept hugh what is the probability of a particular term expressing that concept
and then you can see that this mixture model here really just for you know
you can just write it if you if you encode things as matrices just the
matrix multiplication and you have
basically this a diagonal matrix in the middle which is the
the concept probability something different concept might have different probabilities of occurring prior probability
and so there's actually relationship also which i can really show in detail here with
what's called a nonnegative matrix factorisation algorithm by on which
kind of independently developed of our work because of course you know if you look
at the the entries
you know these are all nonnegative entries because these probabilities
right so in particular this is not the solution is not given by something like
a singular value decomposition or anything like that
you know we have we have different constraints here's a probabilistic
so now how do we
the models
and you said no in the observational regime we could have independent dependence between the
treatment and the extra variables and that that is the problem of compact confound basically
so remember that there is that we can introduce the potential response the response to
be supplied treatment f
it is just y to define this way if i think about interventional study
i'm just gonna look at the very i you will have whatever distribution it's got
and this will give me distribution for y as justified so y one f if
one of you know everyone and you will have to work out its distribution
so i got the two distributions no problem what actually go but i haven't done
experimental study done observational study so i observe t and y
what is the distribution of y
in the say given t equals one
so here is that it's one of the distribution of this function when i tell
you that it was one or first of all i can obviously change t into
but secondly and conditioning on was one and that fixed value so i to the
conditional distribution of you guarantee was one
so the observation of this rich y given tickles t would generally have this form
but with a different distribution for you instead of the marginal distribution for you which
is relevant to of interventional regime
i would have to look at the conditional distribution in the observation narration the disk
and they won't necessarily be the same one case there will be the same as
when that conditioning doesn't make any difference
this will be problematic in the case that t and u are actually independent
the conditioning makes no difference
this is a nice thing to hold because then the distribution i get the observation
regime but y
among those patients who happened to be assigned treatment one will be the same as
the desired distribution in the intervention regime
so that's an important condition t independent
that will make i can just that will allow me to jump over the barrier
between the two regimes without making any change to anything we can express the graphically
there's two variables UNC team so you have some distribution
may or may not know what it is team could be linked to you how
the treatment is assigned could depend on your principle
that this arrow like that means the probabilistic dependence on our what i would have
blocked field in it means of functional dependence
so this is wise function write it in in there it is
we have a question is can we measure the conditional independence that we have to
assume that the answer is mostly we have to assume it
because we can't observe u
o point
and that's one of the problems
OK so so what we basically said i mean so this is just a graphical
representation of exactly what i said already we get if we delete an arrow from
that represents the marginal independence of t in the
and the treatment is regarded as being assigned summer independent unit characteristic which is or
at least mimics a randomized experiment were somehow the treatment assignment is done by also
corner whatever which completely unrelated to
the there was used to point to randomisation
randomisation will bring about this rather desirable state of affairs that allow us to make
this link between the two regimes
no it's not if and only if
that doesn't follow from what i've said
but it certainly sufficient not necessary
randomisation but you
males and females in the world
you do
that's get into more complicated experimental designs and so the question is really the randomisation
and so but the definitely so equal numbers in two groups there are all sorts
of complicated randomisation schemes and that so all theories experimental design of i won't get
into that you know
the simple level of independence and identical behavior for every unit they are talking about
this for years
the median age
you know so the question is do i need to toss the coin now i
don't but i need to somehow justify this assumption if i'm going to use it
doesn't require pretty convincing way justifying the assumption that there may be other way
now are room i remember that a special case of the functional model was the
potential response model where this sort of mathematical fiction if you like for variable u
which is by bivariate quantity the two things on the two tablets of stone with
some bivariate distribution
and it's the same story because
again we will make the equality we will be able to use this framework and
say that
it's OK to go from the observation regime to the intervention regime so long as
it is independent of y
and this is so this is a common
important in analyses people who like potential responses they say they scored ignore ignore all
treatment x assignment no confounding and
OK i was there with his wife everybody's got their why doesn't matter how you
you get treated all one regime and the no confounding or ignorable treatment
condition is that the way you get the same treatment is independent of the two
values engraved on tablet to stone
which by the way
and most one can never be observed and at the moment probably
there's no it is
this part is reserved for three years
and this part is reserved for
you can check
that's really what this array means let's finish running the algorithm so that was the
last element so
across enough but we've done that now look at the next to last element that's
four position five my four here position five and decrement the counter
next i look at another three
three is now the position to
so the because here
and then i don't comment that counter i want actually use that can more realistic
comment because that's what it says
look at the previous element that so one ones composition one
but here
and can that counts
and finally i have another four
and for competition for now position for his here
and i recommend that count
OK so that's
counting sort and you notice that all the elements appear and they appear in order
the other
that was the running time counting sort
is an upper bound
it's a little bit better than that
actually quite a bit better
it requires some
going back to the top
how much time does the static
how much time this is static
how much time does this static
each of these operations in the for loop taking constantine time
this is just what is the length of that
how many iterations of that for the father
and finally
this step takes
so the total running time
of counting sort is
OK plus
OK and this is great algorithm if k is relatively small like at most and
k is big like and square or to to the and whatever this is not
such a good outcome
but if k because order and
this is great
and we get our
linear time sorting out
so not only do we need the assumption that numbers are integers but we need
the range of the integers is pretty small for the seven to work of all
the numbers are most and are between one in order and then we get a
linear time algorithm but as soon as they are up to n log n
four toaster back to organ sort
that's great
so you could write a combination of that well if k
is bigger than n log and then i'll just use merge sort
and it's less than n log n o use counting sort
that would work but we can do better
thanks so time
it's worth noting
we've been around but only assuming they were outside the comparison models we we're really
contradicted the original theorem
we're just changing the model
so it's good question what you're allowed to do any
scenario any problem scenario
in say some practical scenarios this would be great
if the numbers are dealing with say by law
then k is only to the eight which is two hundred fifty six seeing exhilarating
size to fifty six and you know this is really fast fifty six plus and
no matter how big n is is linear and so if you know your numbers
are small great
the four numbers are bigger say
you still other integers but they fit in like thirty two bit words then
life is not so easy because
OK is n two to the thirty two which is four point two
a billion or so
right which is pretty big and you need to see julia ray of four point
two billion words which is probably like sixteen giga bytes so you just need to
initialize an array before you can even get started so let's and is like
much much more than four billion
and you really you have sixteen devices storage just throw away which had i don't
even have any machines with sixteen megabytes of RAM
this is not such a great out to just give feels good numbers are really
what we're gonna do next is come up with the fancier out of that uses
this as a subroutine on small numbers
and combines this algorithm to get to handle larger numbers
that algorithm is called radix sort
but we need one important property of counting sort before we can
go there
and the important property instability
so stable sorting algorithms
the order
the core elements
so the relative order
so this is a itself because usually we think of elements just as numbers and
we have a couple freezing we had a couple flaws
it turns out if you look at the order of those three is on the
order of those force we we kept them in order to the last three
and we put it here
and we took the next last three we put it like that we're always documenting
our counter
and moving from
so the end from the end of the rate at the beginning of the era
so no matter
how we do that the orders of the three to preserve the orders the force
space like a relatively simple thing but if you look at the other for sorting
out we've seen not all of them are stable
this is an exercise
exercises figure out which other sorting algorithms that we've seen are stable which are
anchor to to work that out because this the sort of thing we ask and
for now all we need is the counting sort is stable
OK and i will prove this but it should be pretty obvious from the output
we it's talk about radix sort
radius is going to work for a much larger range of numbers in linear time
kind of thing so you can see a model for you probably can't see that
there a line around the jordan for it
which is where the models stocks to the person
the transition is hard enough to see
OK so that's kind of model that
that works
pretty well it's a little bit delicate to do this fitting
so i would say this is
the initialisation of these models is problematic so it's not really and i think that
can be robust in all circumstances and like the previous ones with there's no initialisation
just look in your database and see what looks similar
OK so you can get even more
model based build
and articulate body model either in two d or three d
and instead trying to track these kinds of models when so much about the that's
not really learning once you start doing things like motion models for from these things
in the component
what you start learning appearances well it can be learning
associated with that model but a little bit lose their models which are basically kind
of springs in this
springs and positions so far and i might have a thing that finds i plates
in the image and this kind of model
which is
tells you roughly how much
the i should be apart
OK if you can formulate that is a graphical model of course so
when you're trying to use these models it tends to reduce the graphical model inference
and these things usually continuous state models
we can either happen continuously in discretized positions
so so the inference in a graphical model which is continuous state which is hard
or in a graphical model which has many discrete values which is also hard
so these interesting inference problems the other thing is that often you won't find features
because you're you're basically low-level vision wasn't strong enough
well something was included or something so you can assume have the whole always on
on its these models when you're doing inference
so so the arguments for these things are basically the popular graphical model inference methods
dynamical programming is a good thing to do if you've got a graph that can
be reduced to singly connected graph
which is very often want to be able to do
so these kinds of models
you can search for
the basic parts of the model in the image with primitive detectors and then try
to string together and enter into an articulated model
this is a singly connected
model and that if we node
this the change
from from
coming from united so you can do rapid inference and this can be done in
programming types solutions
this is where SVM
based detector this was just coloured status
similar models from that
you can also do that was
the same kind of thing with things like superpixels that i mentioned before so over
segmentations of the image and then you try to string
pieces of those together
into the memes that you going to make a model
like some kind of inference process
so that's all very well
but if you represent the person as a graphical model
everything is
well nothing is connected so there's no multiple connections you run into problems
which is that
both legs of the model for one link in the image
OK and the reason for this is the graphical model doesn't have anything telling it
to not do that
because the legs independent and inference in graphical models because they are independent
OK so what happens is that both
both legs of model tend to fit the bass lake in the image
and so many but things like that because it's not very good
the way to get around that
which is
in an interesting trick in graphical models is to introduce
latent node
which says something about essentially the state of the lakes without really explicitly saying that
saying something about the state of the makes so the be of the discrete variable
introduced which might have a couple of values in which forces of one for the
other be backwards
and they for stocks the lake having the same position
and then you can do inference in that model because all you have done
in the central node is increase the dimension of the state of which doesn't to
the inference too much model
so so so in some sense it's like kind of dimensionality reduced version of the
full graphical model
you have taken a particular types of behavior the you try to suppress and you
encode them
and nodes
the to the central server so
things can go wrong
further down the chain
you can then these models
this course
images as well
just a little bit on learning
o auto regressive dynamics to this is the piecewise learning method for that images should
video that
it's fairly
it's fairly straightforward machine in twenty two we can and things like tens walks things
so this is something else
a little bit
the more interesting so this is what we did a couple of years ago
we want to we've been doing human tracking with this model based approach
and things always went wrong
you always the model and this track was fitting on piece of the image
so what we wanted to do is look back and say OK what can we
if we try to
just use learning based approach
so we started with so it's wanted to calculate some kind of robust shape descriptor
and use that to predict the three d pose
and so what we use to me and the relevance vector machine regression sparse bayesian
it doesn't matter too much you can also use an SVM greece or even linear
model different models the IVM is good because it's possible faster i
maybe that's the main difference
so how do we cope these things well we took its
who knows if this sentence makes sense all read out loud loosely this can be
thought of as softening the strict definition of co occurrence in a mixture model OK
so here's what i meant by that
and this is very loose
that's the first thing that lives
the second thing that is that so the mixture model we are asserting definitively all
these words in this document are co occurring so
you model better respect that and get give me topics that respect that all of
these words in this document occur
alternatively we could say
as we increase alpha look
some of these words the words about one topic are co occurring within that topic
and the words about another topic are co occurring within that topic
but if i the document that's about baseball and statistics what i'm saying
is that
the words about baseball are all co occurring on the words about statistics are all
co occurring but the words about baseball in the words about statistics are not co
OK so we don't see guassian process and you know
oh my god i don't know anything about baseball pitch
you don't see guassian process and pitch
as a co occurrence whereas you would in the mixture model
can you
can you dig this
when you increase out there and you allow for two topics to be activated in
one document then suddenly guassian process and
better or
what's at home run
very good that's what i want better home runs are guassian process batman are co
occurring guassian process in home and are not caucus
and so
in that sense
we can think of a mixed membership model as softening this strict definition of co
occurrence in a mixture model and what that leads to are sets of terms that
somehow more tightly co occurrence of terms that we're used to seeing together all the
that's that's my instinct for the answer to that question about posterior
during the
the preface to any slaying comment all
one of the four classes were known
to explore the whole
what you want
one of is
and what you
right that's a great question so and we're going to get to something
will get to that a little well we're not going to get the marketing but
we're going
we could have gone to it and what in some of the slides
later but
i don't believe you
is the answer to the question i don't believe
are used as sparsely as
co occurring
topical words
that's just my intuition but
that i think that that's the answer to your question that the reason for this
is the somehow subject to alpha the sparsest
challenging but not only because of technical issues but also because of communication mismatches
also on the human level
medical ontologies have specific characteristics
typically there are large
complex civil park semantics talk to us at least engineers and this requires special treatment
expert knowledge is not always available
in the medical domain because the doctors are almost always
in lack of time
this requires finding alternative solutions to acquire expert knowledge
like we try to address with address with the query and aviation technique
and medical image semantics requires integration
of information
across three dimensions which are
anatomy radiology and diseases
or pathology
and maybe one final issues that i didn't really bring up
so far is that
actually conditions on radiologists are not if they are not aware of the technologies that
available to them
one important step is
probably to inform them about all what they can do MAP because they are working
on their
on the current workstations how they are
on the databases on their
restricted query how they are they have been doing this for all these many years
and they don't really know that they could
change the situation that they could ask for more
so maybe it's a good point to make them aware
of all what is that their disposal
so that they can exploit the candyman more we can do the work for the
there are also dissemination activities already there's a planned to it's going to be enormous
conference and there are publications
the talk about the technical details
also we would like to thank our project partners to DFKI language technology lab and
the houses kaiserslautern
knowledge management group also university of london for their valuable contributions so far
and if you have any questions if you would like to talk discuss more please
contact us
send this email alerts were more than happy to talk to you about it
about medical and the technology
and thank you
thank you very much for this excellent speech and
we are still a couple of minutes for your questions
we have one
well actually as i mentioned in the beginning medical in the first place and are
much intended for health care workers to fulfill their
feel free to address their challenges
but once the start
there is no next system is going to be data
to the public so to say so many should be also
at the disposal of the citizens of
out the of the citizens so
it should be available on our laptops sort
computers so that he
maybe on the web basis so that you can search stand out your
semantic queries on the web and maybe
even standard picture
and then you got from your doctor and you say OK this is my new
this is the
new on x-ray that i have had and you stand in their way
and then you get other similar pictures from other patients and then you can maybe
look into on the related forums and exchange experiences and this type of like very
fast materials so i think these are going to be the future challenges but i
don't really know and they are i mean when it's going to come that far
i believe that
the sounds very interesting for the future
remember so that
well you consumers australia also started
to kind of initiative
semantic systems and life sciences
and the
reply conference last year in graz we tried to create a platform for more
the interests interested parties in this area that means
like siemens medical
if everyone behaves randomly so
now there is no no no plot no conspiracy behind
just simple data mining will detect anything suspicious and not so these is not the questions so
by intuition so
what would you say uh
how many people would be
how many pairs of people
would be fine which they
it is twice in the same could there not knowing each other
we have an intuition
one hour
so not knowing
each other this is also uh uh
so this is an be a monitoring now
billion people just the small groups which meet here and there okay
but so the answer is so this is completely random to people who don't know each other with appear in
who knows what's
in three years
so it's
two hundred fifty thousand pairs
so this is just simple probability that given distance
there's just too many combinations to combinations
to check far let's say
intelligence services just expensive so
what do have
we need to have some additional evidence within the data so that we reduce this
number down to something which is meaningful languages
very hot verifiable at least degree that
what we find is
suspicious people
so this is kind of
interesting examples so that doesn't happen in the past you know when
we had such a small data so
of course this was hard find now with these huge data is very easy to
find very interesting stuff just by
purely yeah
probabilistic simple from the probability would tell you that
in the this waste the
the vast amount of patterns which are generated by out of the data
now you will always find some advances as well
which are completely meaningless
but they exist they are because they start
allowed to detect
so obviously here we would need to know a little bit more about these people than just that they appeared
twice in the same cluster
so this is
i get this example just to give you an intuition that
we need to be careful what you find out of big data
and this is good
area for conspiracy theory people there is always find conspiracies in big data in the small they those hard-to-find
okay so
everyone go to the to deep into the
o operations are the
methods or techniques
but just to give you all
flavour of
type of techniques which are not connected follows a small data
but now we need to be
bare them middle east we need to be able to deal with this
so one is smart sampling of data so this is something which in a small dataset world didn't exist through
so smart sampling means
if you have a huge amounts of data so how to reduce this huge amount
to small smaller size without losing information content from the
for some
problems this is easy
do random sampling can it's already enough just for simple counting car estimating simple
just random sampling would be enough but let's see if we have graphs instance
social networks
the social networks usually have
is power law distribution and so on and we cannot
sampling graphs is
nontrivial you need to be aware of the problem which are solving otherwise you'll basically
if you just take some random links in the graph
basically wouldn't get the structure which you want to mine afterwards
smart sampling can be very hard
for some problems and for some data types
another simple sampling sort of simple
i mean simple nowadays but let's say in early nineties we were not simple far as
how to simple picture so
jetpack is a nice example of
smart sampling cover the picture so
we have this huge image
every pixel inspectorate i mean
that is what the camera produced
but the person doesn't need this to get the message so
think was seeing the discrete cosine transform basically just
the transformed image into frequency space we reduce this
significant frequencies
so this was
compression then we
came back from the most important frequencies
back to the image and the person
watching the image was the message was the same
so this is a nice example what's possible with the image
and the same is ambac formats and so on for the movies is pretty much the same
but not all data are as friendly but still even for that image was not
clear how far in eighties we didn't have this
back so
we have to deal with not too large files but still was
compression was not easy
it was just run length
similar sequence of of of bits and bytes
it was compressed and this was the only one
six seven year minutes but
you can
so this is pretty much the last slide on
analytical operators so
on the top of this previous operators
the same not i didn't go through
so smart sampling is one important intuition which we need to be aware of
crossword puzzle
and the benefit of that is all the images not blurred all the high spatial
frequencies actually is
so from that you can take a photo you may have missed focused and then
the blurb software
all high spatial frequency
so you can deliver sloppy
in taking this for us
and you can even get the link in the
so this is a footnote example from just once in the fourth
so now we certainly
introduced by a little bit of computation in the physical domain
enough capabilities and or software
to recover those frequencies that we
blocking light in time
we can preserve information for motion
blocking light in space
we can
we can preserve information in case of defocus blur
and this seems
contrary due to bad blocking light
in time or space
preserving more information
less light
is more information
and it's not surprising because and i should like driving on the street and is
clear from the sun
retired abruptly
so that's another example where less like
it's more information we can look at history of the sunlight distrubing we don't know
what's going on b
we're trying to block it or time to see if we can see more
so what can we think of it in the more more scientific way
and think about
very simple simplest possible
audience the simplest possible visual systems
like a war
which has a single pixel right
it's just a single pixel
it also seems to have
this very intriguing factor
in its visual field has the shooting big man looks very much similar to our
crossword puzzles here
and the reason apparently is that
if this
i was just open hemispherical a there very very difficult for this war
to maintain its orientation with respect to one strong like maybe this
but this
start behaving very much like a motion detector
i would like to find the mask in front so that if the war changes
the body direction large UCI spike some kind of a sinusoid
so so that allows us this one maintain the body orientation
and if you go to a more complex
they might have four or five for directors
but they still have this shielding so something funny is going on
so in the end the money
my presentation in going to talk war several concepts
where we essentially blocked light
in time and space
in light
in their land and so on
and then i'll talk about this concept of whole computational photography is more than two
different things
so this is of computational photography i feel it's
it's more into three phases and computational photography is a
so what emerging field that combines computer graphics and vision
geometry optics signal processing
electronic hardware
online photo sharing and all that
the first phase i like to call it epsilon photography was similar to epsilon geometry
from computational geometry
where we want to
create an estimate of pixel
with very good samaritan which
we want to just estimate the pixel that's all i can want
and that's been done
typically by
if you want to get a high dynamic range for
i can estimate the pixel value
in case of saturation are under exposure i just bracket my exposure to multiple photos
if we can estimate the value of a pixel because starts in the field of
then you take multiple photos and stitched panorama
and so on
so if you can think of of this
techniques as if you think about the parameter space for camera is six four times
for a few
frame all these parameters
we're just waiting it
in the apse long-range and trying to get a better estimate of forty six
and this is what
computational photography was
for the last several years our so last fifteen years
or so since i work in the late nineties
but that this is not as interesting anymore and moving into
the second phase
which i like to call recorded photography but we don't really care about
a good as up
good modernization of pixel
but i really care about some mid level cues
regions boundaries
decomposition problems and so on
and it's worth taking a lot of photos by bracketing
we want to take one are just a few photos
that reversibly encode information about the scene
and i give you a couple of examples
how much
blocking light in time or space
we can reversibly encode the motion blur or defocused
and lots of other related projects even stupid of cameras
is an example of court photography because they're trying to preserve the treaty information that
would have been lost if you just took
a photo from a single camera
but more sophisticated examples are light field capture which i will talk about the next
detecting the
distinguishing that edges from reflectance edges
foreground background segmentation
engineering the point spread function i give you a couple of examples
and also the focus
also this is an interesting problem
the sum of the information from the measurement and the information from the
associated with the prior
but there's something a bit funny there and
information weighted mean i mean would look something like this
i seem to be trying to add together
in compatible matrices this disguise two by two matrix isn't it with rank one and
this guy
it is it's a six by six matrix and the find space as we have
here so there's a sort of i
you know the impedance
you know why trumpets work much better than penny whistles is because the
the bell of a trumpet does the kind of impedance match between thin tube and
the trumpet and the and sort fat air out there and i guess they're gonna
impedance mismatch and we need an element to like the trumpet we're never going to
get this this bell from two kind of
make the matrices fit together
so what we want to be got in the toolkit we've already seen that we
could use to
this is a know like a method of dimensions sort of argument for the right
answer but i promise you the answer will be right
what's the missing element
we can use for
as our old friend the observation matrix which HMS remember that which miraculously is the
two by six matrix sends sounds promising might to bridge the gap between the
a mismatch so there's the mismatch OK now let's put it right by putting nature
versus in all in all the right places there's only one way i can use
them in each
in each case to make the dimensions work right this is a method of dimensions
argument doesn't quite amount to improve but i promise you the answer is
right and all the
matrix mentions mashup and so now
what we have is a kind of a way of coupling these low dimensional
observations of features into the high dimensional state space
that works
both of the new information and for the that's this getting new covariance the
posterior and for the new me in the past it so that's all
all works nicely now
OK so now i can show you pictures of
a system that actually tracking moving hand using
this idea
so you see to hand is going through
it's fine space repertoire
tilting and rotating and its training in scale and so on and now if i
do something
which is not in the alpine space taken from out then because the contour refuses
to follow because that was never included in this simple model
now another idea which is you know very well known in
conventional tracking you even used in radar kalman filters in real systems is validation gating
this is the idea of testing measurements to see if there are plausible so you
remember from that earlier picture that we had with all of those normals cast out
around the guy's profile and typically along each normal there are many responses so that's
a bit of a problem the ambiguity of you know we're not knowing which is
the valid observation so
in in the sort of fifteen minutes something i'm going to to look at a
more radical approach to dealing with that but a very reasonably tasteful attack
it is the the following idea the validation gate this is really outside the gas
framework now
ruined the exactness of the gaussians filter by introducing this relation gate but still
people do it because it's a natural thing to do it you will bring in
a switch into the
filter hypothesis test so the idea is that if the
measurement you are
about to see
has a an observation distribution of this form it's unbiased so the main observation is
corresponds to the
o point actually on the curve and it has a following covariance and we'll forget
for a moment about the general case where we can write down the covariance so
let's just think about corners for now but this cannot be done for tangent observations
perfectly nicely as well
so now
we can write down what the
distribution is for expected response expected observation zns and it's just a normal distribution
whose mean is just is taken directly from the prediction and whose variance
is made up of two components one is the covariance associated with the observation itself
and the other is the sort of inherited covariance from the prior distribution with the
ages all in the right places so we can meaningfully at those things together so
concepts for transfer transportation so steering a road vehicle
transportation events generally a tipping over
so when you try to acquire too quickly that supply transportation event and and what
incurring damage colliding currents in vehicle accidents
transport across events bring a vehicle
most of the things that you want to talk about we're talking about transfer is
logical vocabulary for talking about the sorts of things that you can do logical or
about know you can do logical inference about everything
it's useful to do it and often the terms already available and again already
i cannot find out as a
as a knowledge base
relating events in their participants so in
it's a very important class of concepts situation parts
so and then types a specialisation situation so for giving a tutorial
is a
the event type therefore the situation time
and therefore we know that our role in such a situation types their subevents
relationships between some of it
situations and relationships between some some situations there are participants
x is this there props things which are involved which are sort of used by
the participants and their predicates reduced to relate these together so far is
it's pretty good
inputsdestroyed so what if i am eating eating is the kind of event inside the
instance of anything event michael witbrock is launched on the twenty seventh of
october two two thousand eight
that's a that's eating event
inputsdestroyed in the evening event were bullshit
so there were some instances of membership for some particular instance of
the whole system
the benefits to the beneficiary of that evening event was either me or the restaurant
depending on how happy i was in new york
the outputscreated and that if you have info
and the sign triphosphate i guess ultimately and in in g
in nothing
in fact
the device used in any event was a piece of
great to transport of chopped tomatoes to my mouth
in the going to a restaurant event was also used in order to have a
computer network computer device used to get take the money
there wasn't a vehicle there wasn't anything damage
it was the providerofmotiveforce already the rule on eating events we say that the
the consumer
of the earth encounter meeting event is the providerofmotiveforce for the meeting events you don't
have to say that there are over
four hundred more of these relationships if you're of patient and you remember
friends and slots
these are the sorts of relations these sorts of relationships which were typically solvents inference
don't stuff
yes idea sort of
the frame system
in fact if not in
these these tend to be very very useful predicates
eleven thousand types of cutting knows singing
the training stage devices
giving something
back OK view of virus when you find the
the USP computer
carving cracking buying
changing the temperature
change site
almost anything you can say i have been type four or more importantly
almost everything of there's an event type in reach of
say i represent i know know finding treasure because of its we interested in
sunken ships
if you start from scratch
classifier that answers your
right so the younger you're supervised classification algorithm will give you
a classifier map access the actions and that's what you're going to use to make
you can analyse
get the statement like this so your policy regret
well the bounded by four key
times the the binary regret
the adagrad of the classifier
on the classification problem
so there's no square root dependence but there is the dependence on the number of
and there's a link on the tutorial web page
to of the paper that
she was how to do that
one that
you can use any supervised
a regression approach
so you so you can use the same graph you can use the same rejection
sampling to get rid of the importance is in the regression approach
so if you remember is greater than the importance weight
the new you through
and this is make sure you you just the distribution so it's
it is if you draw from
this is this paper that we work with younger
and the killing
scrapped that
make sure to draw your learning three distribution which optimize overall
why would they use these as importance weight
so if it was a rare actions
then you boost the reward
because you divide by small numbers so you boost the word the observed word the
freighter actions
and that is
as as this or this gives you this unbiased estimate of the word
but the post the link to this paper the john mentioned
the algorithm is called
cost and
no it's
so it's a different
algorithm is just
it gives you a
of transform in
the multiclass classifier into policy
you partially built problems
so this is an important point so it doesn't tell you how to choose actions
so this is what i talked about the previous slide
right you can either
randomly and then exploit
or you can
do EXP before
so this tells you how to explore how to choose actions to make optimal decisions
and here
i'm giving your way
use exploration the city half exploration the this for
you can apply
any supervised learning algorithm
to learn a policy
that will help you make decisions in the future
there's really of for orthogonal angles
so the first was
to that there is a regression problem so you already have data of the form
it's a feature
features action taken the words the probability of taking that action
and you can treat it as a regression problem
or you can see that there is an importance weighted
classification problems
you can do something better
using the offset the
and that i will describe next
and this is sort of a better way
of using this exploration the
to learn a slightly better
OK so you have
let's just say that i have two actions for simplicity there are two actions were
chosen from
and this is a trick
that will give you
a better
performance that will improve your performance and we'll see why
so that the cos two
so you were is larger than one house so you have this example
coming from so this is your exploration example acts action they can reward probability of
taking that action
you do with this higher than one half
then you say that was a good action to take so you form an
an example classification example acts
common e
so you want your classifier to predict the
on x and this is an important
right so this is the observed reward
minus one half
so this is the distance from one half
divided by p
so instead of importance weighted by our over p
you importance weighted by those offset from one half
by this distance from one half
OK so
now let me talk about least squares with linear constraints
there's a bunch of techniques that
one can use for that
one of these ideas to use the branch multipliers
and you get a system that looks like this is a transposing a looks like
normal equations
and then
this this matrix c is sitting here and here
and you you have to solve in this
formulation not only for the unknowns but for the lagrange multipliers so you've actually increase
the dimensionality of the problem
if you had an variables and p constraints now you have to solve for ten
plus p anyway that's not a good idea ocean because you increase the dimensionality really
constraints reduces the dimensionality and you should reduce the complexity
the problem and often you make it better condition by eliminating the constraints
o is an idea
finish my discussion singular systems i'm sorry i got so carried away here
a i talked about the QR factorizations just a moment ago
here's something what that you can do if the matrix is exactly are not only
can you performed
orthogonal transformations on the left but on the right also
and so we have this complete orthogonal factorizations
and others what's known as the pseudo inverse of a matrix
it can be constructed just from this decomposition is just like an inverse of this
one of the full rank you would get exactly the inverse of the matrix
so here's the definition of the pseudo inverse of a matrix satisfies these four properties
and sometimes called the more penrose pseudoinverse
it in solving the least squares problem if you
construct the pseudoinverse you find out
that's not only do you minimize the residual vector but you minimize the length of
the solution vector so that's the the great use of the pseudo inverse it gives
but the the minimum residual plus the minimum length of the solution
that may or may not be desirable you may want solution the minimum length or
you may have some other constraint that you want to get out of all these
possible solutions
OK here we go to least squares with linear constraints
and here i have this augmented system which is now an plus the by implies
p and this comes up in so many different applications
the people work in math programming they call the KKT karush kuhn tucker that they
were the first ones in in the math programming to to use this so extensively
OK well the idea that i outlined a little procedure where you
south course for the unconstrained system providing you can
and then when she was out for the unconstrained you south of the grunge multipliers
given by these equations here
and then you modify
the least squares solution you would have gone
without the constrained by
adding that this modification and then you get the solution to the least squares problem
so that's sometimes very useful in statistics often you have the situation
you want to know what the solution would be without the constraints and then you
want to know what the solution would look like after you impose constraints and this
is a technique for getting the two solutions providing they both exist
OK let me just say a bit more about this is the some ongoing work
these matrices come up and as i say in so many applications of particular and
solving partial differential equations
one situation is where this matrix a transpose a is singular or almost singular
so what you do is
you have a dispute over here
so a transpose a plus CWC transpose sea trout transpose x by this condition here
is equal to zero
you sort of increase the this
the increase the condition number are well actually decrease the condition number of the system
over here that can be almost always shown
this matrix w is
matrix that you
there are all kinds of possibilities it doesn't have to be a multiple of the
identity matrix talk about that
here i set w of multiple the identity matrix but it can be chosen just
to choose a few of the
the columns of the matrix c and just enough to make a transpose a nonsingular
and of course you want to do this with some choice
it may be that a transfer a has a sparse structure by adding in the
you screwed up the entire structure so you may only want to choose a few
of the columns of c rather than all the columns of c
OK well is just a small amusing detail
if you take the inverse of this matrix
it's the inverse of the matrix without this part minus this quantity here
so this is a this is how the inverse changes when you add in this
matrix c wc transpose and what that leads to is the following
but the condition number of this new system is bounded by the condition number of
the original system plus some additional terms which means actually that the condition number of
larger system may actually increase by adding this part portion here
nevertheless some the one so this is interesting the one block becomes
that condition but the entire matrix becomes may possibly be more field conditions
and in fact we have done some iterations schemes and sometimes there's a remarkable change
by just adding that very
by adding the quality of the larger gamma is the boreal condition the matrix is
the convergence baby fast methodist college in rats and it's a very effective way for
solving nonsense symmetric or indefinite systems of equations
here is a very useful technique
where you can use the technology that you already have
as the following so here we have this constraint problem already and now let's add
in this weighting function square after all and citrus lexical zero
and this goes away
and we and the constraint is satisfied so the idea is
augment the original matrix a by mute times the transpose so that just it says
if you see trams are more observations in the problem and you want to solve
this new
least squares problems
OK and for large and the solution x had new of the unconstrained problem should
be a good approximation to the solution
my colleague charlie
he actually show that this action the for mu going to infinity
this then does go towards the solution of the least constrained least squares problem what
he uses for this was called the generalized singular value decomposition this is a very
body centered cubic
and we go down at all
one one
simple cubic reflects
body centered cubic reflects would face centered cubic doesn't reflect so it's you can't look
in any single line
you have to look at the entire pattern
and so on
and there's a simple way of of kind of flying all of this
simple cubic all
all of the
indices are reflecting
in body centered cubic if you go through this pattern what we're looking at is
the sum of eight squares plus case where it applies elsewhere and that gives you
a nice sequence one two three four five and so on and what you see
with BCC is you have the sequence two
four six eight
the sum of age plus k plus al is even
so that's the way of capturing what's going on in this
the series
and for face centered cubic it turns out that the planes that reflect are either
even numbers
or all odd numbers so for example face centered cubic EC one one one
these are all i had to all zero is termed in this
calculation is being an even-numbered so twos even zero even in zero is even so
three and four reflect
five and six do not
eight does that's two two o and so on eight eleven twelve sixteen so this
is the set of selection criteria
that have been
your convenience
now we can do
now we can do is go into some example
using this technique in order to index the crystal
so i want to show you
two different techniques
that allow us to
determine the crystal structure
the first one is called the fractal geometry
the first one is called the different
and since it's done with x-rays it's also known as x-ray diffraction XRD
and the characteristics of
x-ray diffraction are we use radiation a fixed wavelength
we very the angle
variable angle so
look at this cartoon here
if we have fixed wavelength for varying the angle
i'm going to be moving the crystal this is i'm going to get very angle
what i'm saying is variable angle of incidence
now the words i want to probe all the incident angles and and build the
library of responses for a given incidence angle what's the intensity of the reflected radiation
and the way i do that is to
part being and rotate the specimen and ultimately i end up with a plot that
looks like this
what looks like this intensity versus angle
this is angle
so now we're going to decide
the pattern we observe conforms to
this set of rules up here
and by making that comparison we can deduce
which of these three crystal structures the
crystal belongs to and i'm keeping this is a very narrow set i'm saying this
three nine one so we
confine ourselves to the universe of cubic crystals if you want to get
more general than
it could be any one of the crystals that comes out of the fourteen brevity
lattices plus
a range of bases
so there's a huge database out there that has
values of intensity versus
thousands and thousands
of metals and compounds
huge amount of mineralogy in this database
so when you bring a specimen of unknown
we are able to use this technique
and infer
the constituents are
so first of all let's take a look at what the what the specimen looks
like i can take a few atoms we use a powdered specimens
powdered specimens
so we grind the material into a fine powder
and we put in the silicate
a silicate glass
and silicate glass holder looks something like this
it's very narrow
this is not to scale
definitely not to scale this dimension here
is about a tenth of a millimeter
very narrow to pretend to the millimetre made of
silicate glass
it's an oxide glasses
cousin of window glass
why do we choose it
not because it's transparent to visible light we don't care were shooting x-rays through this
thing for heaven sakes why do we choose this because it amorphous and it doesn't
have a crystal structure of its own
we're trying to radiate the contents of this
and the
the tube itself has the crystal structure how we got to sort out
what's the contents from the container so this is amorphous no long range order and
inside we put little
grains of powder in here
OK so the powder
the powder dimension is on the order of about o
fifty micrometers
and all the wall thickness i mention that that's one one-hundredth of a millimetre
saying it's paper-thin is an exaggeration it's one hundredth of a millimetre
and this distance is about old
two centimetres
so you growing and more personal drop the powder in here and then this goes
into the diffractive element
and is irradiated
and we're going to turn this
in order to present as many different angles as possible we have many grains and
here each grain
the the theory is if we grind is fine enough
each one of these can act as a single crystal
so now
light is coming in reflecting off this but it's cousin is sitting at a slightly
different angle and so i'm going to try to get through the mix of power
and the rotation of the specimen try to get all of the different incident angle
so that i will get as many reflected angles as possible
i i worked with this so my phd thesis
and it was the material was
i was sensitive to moisture in the air had to work in glovebox
these big thick rubber gloves on and and
holding something like this only it's really in real life it's about this big you're
inside the glovebox and its toronto and it's august
perspiration sports just post crying the perspiration is pouring down my face and then i
have to i have to get the power to fall in here
and i'm going to flick this little bit right look at one more time and
then it breaks off
these are you left now it's not funny
or they will be more if the coin has been cast yet and it could
have been already tossed conceal
why would that be
it might be this just some intuitive sense
that i that i can
i don't know i i can
i have some magical forces and here i can change things
so the idea of probability theory
is that no you can't change things these objective laws of probability out there that
guide everything
most languages around the world
i have
a different
word for
and the rest
or luck and fortune
luck seems to mean something about you i'm lucky person
i don't know what that means like the god or god's favor me him so
i'm lucky this is my lucky day
probability theory is really a movement away from that
so we then have a mathematical rigorous
discipline so
now i'm going to go through some of the
some of the terms of probability here
this will be review for many of you
it would be something that we're going to use
in the
so i use
the symbol p
or i can sometimes read out its probability
to represent a problem in probability
it is always the number that lies between
zero and one or between zero percent and a hundred percent
percent means
divided by hundred in that right so hundred percent is one
OK and so
this is the probability if the probability is zero that means the events
can help
if the probability is one
it means it certain to happen
if the probability is everyone see this from over there
and if i can model can probably move can i
just like
you you know you're the most disadvantaged person you can see it
that's the basic idea
now one of the first principles of probability is the idea of independence
the idea is that the probability
is the
likelihood of some
outcome that say the outcome of an experiment okay like tossing a coin
you might say the probability that the particle and it comes up heads is
i have OK because equally likely to heads and tails
independent experiments are experiments that occur without relation to each other
so if you toss a coin twice
and the first experiment doesn't influence the second we say the independent
and so the there's no relation between the two
and one of the first principles of probability theory is called the multiplication
and that says if you have independent probabilities
the probability of two events
is equal to the product of the probabilities so the probability
and the
is equal to the probability
of a
the probability of being
that wouldn't hold if they are not independent
the theory of insurance is that ideally an insurance company wants to
independent events OK
so ideally life insurance is insurance people
or fire insurance is ensuring people against independent events it's not the fire of london
it's the for its the problem that
sometimes people knock over an oil lamp in the home
and they bring their own house down
and so it's not going to burn any other houses down this is just completely
independent of anything else
so the probability that the whole city burns down is infinitesimally small right
this this will generalize to probability of a and b and c
is the probability of a times the probability of the improbable times the probability of
c and so on
so if there a probability is one thousand that house burns down
and there's a thousand houses the probability that they all bring down is probably is
one thousand to thousand power
which is virtually zero
so our insurance companies that
basically if they write a lot of policies they have virtually no risk
and so that is the
the the fundamental idea
which may seem simple and obvious
but it certainly wasn't that when the idea first came up
so one of the
it's that we have a problem set which i wanted to start today and we
not a week this time because we have
martin luther king day
coming up but it will be do
the monday following that
if you follow through from the independent variables
one of the basic relations in probability theory
it's called the binomial distribution
i'm not going to spend
spend a whole lot of time on this
but it gives the probability of
x successes
in n trials or in the case of insurance
if you're unsure against an accident
the probability that you get x accidents
and trials
it binomial distribution gives the probability
as a function of x
and is given by the formula
where p is the probability of the accident
peter the acts
one minus the
today and minus axis
times and factorial
and minus x
and so that's the formula
do this do this again
so now what the cheapest thing to extract
this guy here right
so we'll take him out
OK and now we update all his neighbours
so this guy gets five
this guy
gets twelve
this guy gets nine
this guy we don't update
we don't update and because he's no longer
in the queue
the priority queue
in all these guys now we make a point
the way they supposed to point to
and we're done with that step
now we find the cheapest one was the cheapest one now
the five over here good so we can out
OK we update
the neighbours
yeah that goes to
o to six now
and we have
that pointer
and this guy we don't do because it's not in there
this guy
becomes fourteen
and this guy here becomes
we update
that making b
i do this the right way
because the because pi is a function from the sky
so basically this thing then
this appears
i have another one that i missed
twelve yes good gets removed
OK because pi is just function
and now i'm OK
OK so now what do i do i pick
OK so now my set a consists of these three things
and now i want the cheapest and i know it's in minimum spanning trees on
just greedily pick OK
so what's the cheapest thing now
the uh this guy appear
six we take it
the goal
update these things and it doesn't matter nothing matters here
OK nothing changes to these guys are already in a
OK so now the cheapest one is
eight here
take it out
we update
there's nothing to be done
this nothing oh no this one
there are fourteen we can make this p three
we get rid of that corner
make it point that way
now three is the cheapest thing
so we take it out
in the course there's nothing to be done over there
and now last i take
and it's done in fifteen
it's gone
the goal and why
because it's the outer product of three vectors
and then you just add up a bunch of those ten
now if i give you enough tensors
then you can add up to make any sense you like
any through anything you like if i give you a limited number usually make things
have sort of regular structure this is like PCA but for three three-dimensional things into
so as an equation
we turned the three-way weight into a product of three
factor specific weights
and then we can factorize that top line equation and we see that the energy
contributed by given factor
it's just the product
one of three weighted sums
for each group of units your connecting you take a weighted sum so you apply
linear filter
and then the energy is the product
of all those three manifold
so now for hidden unit h if you wanted to know whether i should try
to turn on
you need to know the difference in the energy of the whole system as a
function of whether ages on or off
so just considering the energy contributed by factor f what is fact and need to
tell hidden unit which in order for a to decide how to adopt to state
give the system the image
h needs to know the difference in the energy the the whole system
as function with its on or off
which is the sum of the energies from all factors the energy contributed by factor
so in fact that one of the difference in energy contributed by factor
when h is on and off
so take the right hand side of the top line
and yes differentiating with respect to sh
to give you the right chance even though something thing to do
what you get is that the whf comes up front
so you see that what
hidden units h needs to see
is the product of the other two weighted sum
multiplied by the weight on the connection between the fact and h
so we can draw the picture
the fact that each of its three vertices computer weighted sum
and what h needs to see
is the product of the weighted sums
the bottom two vertices
and that needs to be sent to each and on its way to change it
needs to be multiplied by w
thirty connectionist way all the hidden units need to see that same message but each
weighted by the weight on the connection
if you look at learning
that message that goes from the fact that che
is what you need for doing that and the learning algorithm balls machine learning outcomes
stays just the same
the learning basically says i want to lower the energy
when i
looking at data
and i want to raise the energy one generation fantasies from the model
and the derivative of the energy respect to work when i'm looking at data
it's just the product
of the state of hidden unit and the message that comes straight from the factory
the curvature of the energy when you from the model
is that same product but when you generate from the model
so the difference of those two parties what you need in order to learn the
one hundred thirty that's great so
you get exactly the same pairwise learning so we took these three way interactions we
factored everything and everything becomes pairwise with these messages products
of weighted sums and that's where the most gets into the act
so now i'm going to show you an example for translating images
we get the preimage
we are propose to image and we get trained up lots of pairs of images
and to begin with the images
will just be random dot sparse random dots and all is just translate to random
dots will have a number of different translations
and that's the training data
and we learn
the weights to the factors
well the whole bunch of active learn latent factor and the weights being vaccinated you
will learn everything we start with small random weights and just like it
and after its learned what i'm going to show you is
the weights the factor has to the preimage and weights factor has to postage
that is these two filters and you have multiplied together center in fact
and of course is going to be a lot of factors assigned show the weights
for the pre and post image full the factors so here's the weights to the
preimage of all the factors
for those who know about translation and fourier analysis and stuff like this this should
not a surprise
and here's the weights to the post image
postage preimage
first image
it's learning basically
the fourier basis and this learning has gratings that are about ninety degrees out of
and we seem like a sensible thing to do and can represent translations very nicely
is that translating images we could rotate images
so we take the same random dot patterns and we take
i just
formulating the iterative methods
and at each iteration you just replace if by a quadratic approximation for just the
second order taylor expansion
and then you solve this quadratic approximation of second order approximation subject to the constraints
and that gives you an update x
is equal to the current value x had this step that you are the fission
is the newton step
so the kinetic approximation would be at x had to be there
mention value
in the product with the gradients
and then the quadratic form it has shown
so it requires first and second derivatives
and then you get a quadratic function subject to equality constraints
you know the optimality conditions are of the quadratic problem from the previous page
so that's how you can compute the optimal value of this quadratic approximation or is
expressed in terms of the difference between the optimal value and the current value
it's your system and delta x and
the college multipliers
so that's the definition of the newton step at x had for convex function f
and this sort of problem with no constraints would be there
the interpretation of it so we have a convex function f locally make quadratic approximation
you minimize the local
the quadratic approximation to get the next value except as the newton step
so this suggests that the method work very well if you are close to the
because close to the minimum the functional actually look almost exactly quadratic
it doesn't really
tell you whether it works for values of x hats far from the minimum
and it turns out that actually in general doesn't work for
x not close to the mean
the four simple
convex functions
because if you do this and it's not close to the mean
if you keep repeating replacing experts expressed this new step x might diverge or
it doesn't converge in general
and it's easy promises to fix the answer is that in general you have to
add in a line search so in
algorithm with line search you would actually first try this from step
of replacing the current it through x
with expressed in units that
if that results in function value that's actually larger than the current value
you want divide and instead by for example two
and then again compared with the current function value
nicky backtracking or dividing the newton step
until you find one
function value that's actually faced less than the current value
and for convex functions you can show that actually is sufficient for physical convergence
so then newton's algorithm would look like this you have each iteration you solve this
new system
if gradient to threats the haitian
we compute the newton step
you have the termination condition
and then you updates the next value of x is x the current value plus
a multiple of the newton step
and should close to the optimum you would like to use to use one
because that's the idea of the methods but in general you need to step size
that might be less might have to take on and
to have a global convergence
or guarantee that it's descendant the function value keeps decreasing
so an example that's what typically looks like if you this is for a convex
function it's quite
complex number of variables and terms in this
but you see it converges and a small number of iterations and that's typical of
newton's method
you also see two two regions so there is the first region where it converges
but not necessarily very quickly
and also
you need to step size less than one to make it converge actually and i
want to get close enough to the solution it accelerates and you get fast asymptotic
so there's actually typical for newton's method the number of iterations is not usually not
very high
but each iteration can be quite expensive because you have to solve this system of
equations to find you have to find the derivative second derivatives and to solve the
system to compute that x
and there is some convergence theory that actually explains this and that we can probably
but it's interesting because the convergence analysis of newton's method actually explains
this qualitatively this two regimes
so in the first
so the typical summary of the standard convergence analysis is that it is the first
but the gradients very far from the optimum
and this is the result established the function value keep create decreases
at least by some constant come up might not be very
large but at least it shows that decreases
and once the gradient becomes smaller close to the optimum it converges quadratically because then
the result is that the gradient this career at each iteration
and that explains the fast local convergence
so there are qualitatively it explains the these two regions
the bound you obtain not very useful because they're very conservative
and they also depend on some constants that you typically don't know in practice but
it explains some of the
the behaviour you see in general
and something so the classical analysis all it goes back to at least the nineteen
and then in around nineteen ninety nesterov and ask actually developed a new convergence theory
newton's method
that is actually for a specific class of functions
he said well it's all questions
and then we can
so in nineteen seventy four
what do they use
they so
so you have two levels of
first was more than one can be saved me one and the second by the
processes the people always for example you could call viruses propagate so of the social
networks so
but before that i would just like to use my thesis committee right cases for
this is my advisor and then there is every blum john lafferty jon kleinberg from
network strength network for these data so we go and collect this data in many
or in various domains so for example we can have friendship networks where nodes represent
people and there is an edge if two people who know each other or if
the people interact then we can have like web citation networks where nodes are web
pages or
papers and there is a directed edge between the two nodes if one links or
cite each other right and then we can have for example sexual networks where there
are links between the people if the people who had some kind of interaction
we can have internet networks meaning which should all this talk to reach or we
can have genetic regulatory networks but here every every
every node is now protein that is the edge between the media interact
more specifically what we are interested in large networks right so we we want to
do is to make statements about how
like networks evolve and for here i have just a few examples of networks that
i've been mentioned during my talk right so for example we have an instant messenger
network where people talk to each other it's pretty much the whole world talking so
we have almost two hundred million people in one point three billion edges
we have like blog networks where we have blogs and blog posts linking to each
other and again we have
an order of millions of nodes and edges become product recommendation networks again
millions of nodes and tens of millions of edges
and the questions we ask in this these are the following
we ask how do how do networks grow following patterns
then once we observe the patterns we ask can generate can build generative models of
networks that we observe this type of
patterns and then for cascades we ask how does this influence spread over the network
right does it spread like three or start or some other kind of pattern and
then once we do these observations we can use this to identify and select nodes
that to detect cascades which
and more generally what the research is about it's about analysing mother and modeling the
evolution and dynamics of large real world networks and this has two separate parts the
first part is about the evolution of the networks and then the second part is
about the cascades so the processes that take place on the networks
both of these two history part three
so first the first question is
what are interesting statistical and structural properties of the network to measure so the question
is what should be go and measure how can we characterize the topology of the
network rail
and once we have done
we can we can go and say what would be the models that that would
model this type of thing our behavior
and once we have the properties and once we can go and use these models
to do some tasks better design new algorithms and so on
so this is how our work can be structure that we have this two setting
network evolution and the processes that take place in networks and then for each one
of them
we first asked what are the characteristics that happen in your real data
then we ask how can you build the model
that would explain this type of phenomenon and then we use and exploit models to
make predictions forecasts and so on
and we have
in all of them and publish them in pretty much all major machine learning and
data mining conferences and journals
so why would you want to do that why why is this important
so i just want to spend one's life
and the first
o thing is for example the structural properties that if you know how
graphs look like
or how normal grassroots group then you can go and say
try to find a lot of graphs of not among nodes in the network and
this can be like spam can be that spanned some other types of things right
then once you have the model you can use this model for example to generate
synthetic graphs which means
in the net let's say in system setting where you have a new routing protocol
or something and you would like to see later over the network
you can generate a synthetic network and then run simulations so it and this way
you will be able to understand how design of the characteristic of the network influence
the performance of you and then you can use these things also for sampling
well the idea is
i think we have a the graph that it's like on the work with so
the idea is let's let's get a smaller graph that we have similar properties than