multiple of
so this is an integer
and so
at any given point
would be an integer
it's a very good
we want to show it is because zero
it would be sufficient to show that it is less than one in absolute value
like in this case can do a bit more
we can select a good ground point
and then it is easy to show
that in this case has this morning
should be an even number
and so in order to show that this is in fact zero
it would be sufficient to show that is an absurd vandalism
how to do it
we start from some
good green point
next point
might be known gold
and we need to make some shift
next points could be but also
but sooner or later will find another group with important
and in fact
there you really
the good ground points
because of and so
we really
this is other small number
and here
is a man
idea of children
he was able to one
the value of x
from up from below
why is
his version of little theorem
last this
additional summons
if you like and they are small
what if you listen to give greater than minus two
the idea was that
originally had to very different techniques
for calculating the number of zeros in the rectangle and on the critical line
in two and found it is in the competition
is a computationally
how to use the same shift age
four bounding in the numbers zeros inside the tender
this was the
content of his
the first part of his statement
and the second part
is a report about the competition
the second part is nowadays
i mean of historical interest
but nevertheless it is of interest it interesting to see
conditions in which
during the
she gives a lot of people about how
computation was done
because that time
it was a new zealand
he wrote
that if you fix momentum if the that
documentation is the in this book
he describes the
this there's a mission
as of two kinds
moments electronic and magnetic storage
the electronic storage consisted of four pages
issues sorted the length of forty binary digits
the average consisted
of a certain number of the
issue of the pages of similar capacity
all of items is that it's available
but is it the funds conditions
you can calculate how many pages you will be able to put
on the left
memory in your book
she gives a detailed description of how the memory was used
one page four categories maturity and
four pages for table flickr reasons
two page authority for calculating such terms
one the pages
important in
two pages four out thirteen
appellate court is interest and
the present result consisted mainly of numbers
in the scale of thirty two
not this amount of time that we see this among but thirty two
do not found it necessary to use a table of correspondence between the words and symbols
but in to the printer
somehow the distance used for themselves
and here right
the right the student himself
with content to see the results of the scale of the two
this species sufficiently formula
that is not as it all was because the punched tape was five
roles and so
it seems that student was not satisfied with other computations
although the details
all the out
and this light
they told
thousand four hundred fourteen thousand dealers
thousands from date
was investigated and ship
but unfortunately at this point the machine broke down
and no further work was done
furthermore this interval was subsequently followed
there have been around
is that on
and the most that can be consequently be asserted with certainty
the zeros lie on the critical line
after equal to
five hundred forty
this was given instigated itself
as far
as thousand four hundred sixty eight
and during cold
there no visible advance
if you look
the table
really not impressive
he after
the kitchen
in the
computation in the rest of you
i consider the value of the input
in front
i am i consider here
what's the ultimate and me OK you can for example
q prime good and here too
few seconds that was what the ultimate and here OK i may have
other labels
in order to keep moving here you have to check with the automaton allows me
to do and i could try
so the game i'm gonna
for requests in a way that
i will be for the moment is not necessarily finite state
but if i assume that that's my game will be fine
so let's take entity penetrate the following
in the way
there will be put together
so there was a sense that
four player zero position
in both trees have been three
so i mean position w
on the left
which is here
and that is called king
so what has a position in the game is OK
in position while you know w in my dream i have the input
and also the current state of mind this is my might not play zero he
has to make a choice
which is the
to choose one possible
the tournament
the automaton
he has so this is q right in my room
so when you have q and you need a you may
also do something else like q two
ten i don't know ways to choose the transition so players you would choose the
she would take
the transition from the automaton which is given here
when you're going to q you read this one you may the left child to
this state and go down to the light chain
the right the basically to the transition
that might be many
two position
the other player
the same spirit as before so what you have here is you choose
what i mean w
so that's the position in europe if him
nine which are the
so you remember where you are the label and transition you choose so it's q
and one of the most successful
OK you rewrite w but i mean we can forget about it in a way
to get i mean it's the it's irrelevant transition it's an entire transition
automaton so that's really
and elements of the transition state of the art and that's one of europe and
so you're like this
and this is one maybe many
as many
i mean positions you may find
from state q one you read labelled t of w
and here it's open to play
and he was OK choose
to go down to the US
so true so it will take you to
if he chooses to go down to the left subtree players zero
you're in
right left on this
cross fingers
so we go down if he chooses this here
we go down here the label that we have
and it's again
the players you want to do something but you're one of those which is this
this sorry i primal
that's why you are
so and i have to say is all from q prime with reading the labels
get by just something together the values of this thing here in this in this
case is going to be a piecewise cubic because these things are cubic in the
in the in the test case
so there's a little that's slight caveat here and that is that the regularizer if
you look at the regularizer that we start with the regularizer here actually has the
radio station coefficient of zero for all linear functions
right so it doesn't it doesn't penalise linear functions at all
so actually it doesn't what we want to do is we want to think of
this as being an energy function and say well what is the prior that corresponds
to the energy function of course that's not normalizable because it doesn't say anything about
the linear functions
so we just add the linear functions that there's a little bit of algebra involved
in that not worry about that
here's an example
so here are some some data points
and then i just plug into the casting process
OK and then i can make my predictions and the mean prediction is piecewise cubic
polynomial but i get something extra here i get to get out of us
i'd like can say something about my my confidence and also like get way of
figuring out what land should be
which is usually something that blind model wouldn't tell you
you know how to trade off the regularizer in the and the data fit but
here this is the best way of doing that by just optimizing the marginal likelihood
there's something slightly odd about this kind of process and that is that the the
individual functions if you draw a function from from this prior because it's the composition
of these little
these little random functions then those functions are actually
nondifferentiable with probability one
so these are quite strange functions it just happens when you average overall and then
you get a polynomial
so the mean function is a very simple function but actually the
the the individual functions from the posterior distribution over functions are quite strange functions and
also it it if you think of then you know what my assumption about the
problem when i start with my prior distribution on my prior distribution is a big
universe of functions that all very very strange
so probably you wouldn't really want to do this
this is only government
also just interpreting as process computed what they the
the covariance function with the covariance function was right and then just plugin
this into my covariance function
right and it only has one parameter
gamma here
and i just optimize with respect to that
gamma and then my predictive error bars
you know follow automatically
searches for me
if you're you're using some of the process of the one norm
the island is only going
absolutely not i just i just plug into the covariance function just like we did
a few days ago here like i do i do functions like this right i
just plug in the function has just this form right it just depends on k
but point here
here there is no noise
well OK in this in this part of the noise that is that so small
that you can see it
in your case there's also no noise so there are two reasons why
your posterior distribution
is a distribution and not just the functions one of them is that there is
noise so it could be that the true function is somewhere else because of noise
another another source of uncertainty is is ignorance
it's because you don't know what the function is doing the function and even if
the function is deterministic
if you've only seen a finite number of data points then you still unsure about
what the function is doing
and the error bars contain both the
both the uncertainty due to ignorance and also that the uncertainty due to the noise
so in this case there is actually a little bit of noise you can see
that because the the the the point deviate from from the mean height but it
would look much the same even if you didn't have noise
OK that's slightly slide as ideas
so how do we actually in practice too
the optimisation well i i just read as black box i just say well i
have a function which is a function of the punisher parameters
and then i just two
so i was tries to achieve the margin which is at least as you
and maybe maybe to achieves a little bit higher margin so but it tries to
achieve margin which has listed so now we have this margin target role
and if you increase the this tries to achieve margin of at least role
may i mean the margin might not be
OK so the maximum margin might be smaller than this role then test fails but
if the margin is actually larger than this rule
this was the confederate past two that the marginal
OK his some theory which relates
essentially role with the performance of the base learner and over the max margin
OK so the idea is OK then let's say you have the
so let's say rosier
this one here
this is the edge of the basin so essentially in an optimal case you would
like to have that the margin the at the margin bound
what the maximum margin is equal to the minimum wage
but this bound shows you that
this is the red line here OK this postponed
and the blue line is a simple approximations and the web on this so this
is essentially
the maximum margin this is the parameter of the algorithm and this is this
parameters of the out of the base learner OK so if OK in the in
the optimal case so let's say gamma is equal to the max margin and max
margin is equal to the role to to discover because when you come out as
the quality i mean if it based on returns hypotheses which have at least cover
OK then the maximum margin this rule
it is equal to go
OK and then let's say we use articles role with choice then gamma could draw
then here
we just have the maximum margin so that
the asymptotically chief margins at least the maximum margin so that's the perfect said situation
OK so usually you don't know and this is optimal
martin so therefore we choose just use some of the rule which is smaller than
the maximum margin
so then we get that
the asymptotically achieved margin is at least the average of these two
OK this is this line here so let's say we set rho two zero then
asymptotically achieve margin is at least half of the possible much use the possible margin
and here's the margin bounds
but if he set rules your three for instance and the margin is really that
large so
if it's smaller than than zero three the maximum margin and we don't even anything
but if it's larger than we
we get a much larger and so
so it's important to set this parameter rho correctly
OK and essentially the idea of adaboost star is that we adaptively tuned this parameter
OK so somehow we have to choose it in the right way that is also
the idea of TV
essentially it sets the this parameter role as the maximum over all margins has it
has achieved so far so it just looks at the combined forces of the last
and caesar which was to maximize the margin
OK then just sets role to this
max margin
so it is easy to show convergence using the setting just using this bound however
there's no convergence rate
OK so
let me try to illustrate this again so i have few the maximum margin on
the x axis k and t is the chief margin of adaboost
after after a really large number of iterations more like an asymptotic setting so this
is the blue line is this bone which shown in the last iteration
and the blue this blue line is the maximum margin which is achievable rate because
i mean it can achieve larger margin than the maximum wage
OK now we let right under article right
and we have two different kinds of base learners one is the corporate of one
so really selects based on which is maximizing the so it's best can do
these are the green points
so we said okay so we
every point is essentially are generated dataset which has a certain maximum margin OK so
this margin here
and then we simply round
i most and see how large the margin is after running ten thousand iterations for
instance OK these are the green points here
we see that these are the the idea of boosting margin is almost as large
as the maximum margin
if the based on its corporate
if on the other hand the based on it's just getting returning process which is
slightly larger than the maximum margin that means i mean it returns hypotheses which is
has edge which is larger than government government suggested this maximum margin is just one
has to achieve so it's not corporate
just performing as good as it should be then we just get the performance of
this bound which we ask
slide so these are the red dots records
OK it really depends on the choice of the base and how good is actually
performing so that means hollywood
got it
using traditional instruments and then you can use these
the goal is to get
so this is for example
and in fact
but of this particular university of come of this
so this was the first person then co-workers was applied is exactly for is a
tremendous energy you want to tell you what for one spectrometer spectrum of the sun
and then it for instance on statistical tests for a comparison
which is the not
fifty to derive its you can of the basis to the something which is useful
knowledge which is that he can be crossed
here is that instead strings
your input space that's more grass
and what makes the between graphs is to say that
given the graph can connect around the long walks on the graph which generates sequence
came together be sequences and when human rights can all of sequences with respect to
the random walk on on the graph you've taken grass
so you to come in with the rest of us otherwise
and the
it was published in
also been applied on when you know people like this whole circus called for convention
is when you have several sequences which was released in the UK
it doesn't matter how they are
and when you want to compare to multiple alignments
you can somehow try to infer what the common ancestor was the only person some
of the model
what was necessary given the current alignment
and if you can between
they consist also you can marginalize over it gets a kernel between sets of sequences
to be in the multiple alignment
OK so there are many examples
and very
related to to the documents
so we now turn to the last there's no question
so is
this is
callers is
i don't know what to do
i think most efficient way so here it is in the position to you can
say OK i don't assume anything we a special kind of that
or i assume
the imagine that you know
i don't
one also places that the most can is that
this probably
it is better than the
the question
so and we can also directly by
generative models
so i'm not sure about the final approach
i wanted to cover the can which is how you derive can from some prior
your mutual
so i would say well that's want say
give me a teenager i constructed it all the way similarities between my sequence visionary
and is used as a feature vector
and i just mentioned the so what works that a
i mean that's interesting because you can prove you see that it was the channels
also in practice this means that
but i would like to tell you what you need to make the numbers that
intended to that but that's about all i wanted to show you some theory
on how to change it can deposit account numbers into the pacific
here is that we can all streams now
other we get interesting feature from images
the express them
o the
sect of features
and finally our present the images
by using the problem
the idea is that
we should move we should find some marketing in some markets in the image
and in computer vision
rather than using just pixels
we want to find
interesting points
structure for reasons when the structure or to the structure or flat regions
in computer vision
we categorise
this is interesting points in three groups
all foreigners
blobs and that's
and essentially
what we are looking for is
i responded this continuity
in one direction
we are looking for
that divides
two different regions for instance because they are are different in statistical pictures
we are looking for
a big so
where delta correlation
indicate that there are two the discontinuity
o we're looking for
it's so where
around the peaks is that is an emerging region
and yes
and most of the bag of visual words all the
was watched by using
blob detector
this pixels this this kind of this gives us a useful to indentify objects at
different scales
in the right way
and after
after looking for this market is this markets
describe discovered some way
and in computer vision usually
we use
histogram of oriented gradients
or SIFT
and after looking for some markets
in the image like an edge
we can
s rocks the orientation of the edge in match
we can be
each of orientation by waiting
with the strength
and we can be so
representation four point
four point detector with an edge effect
in the case of safe SIFT is an histogram
orientation histogram based representation of the local patch around about the detector so in the
case of the sea
we can embed in this picture information on scale
and so on
the main direction of the patch around
an interesting point
and this can be very useful to
make it environments
rotation translation and so on
what we do is we first find some markers in the image
we find
for instance one the structure
to this structure on this
flat region of the right scale
after that
we take in consideration of which around
this markets
we describe
with respect to content the of this page
the building the ball the block
of the image
of course there are many descriptors that have been proposing computer vision literature
and some of the are listed here
just as references
this this picture sometimes
depends of the application
of what people are working on for instance
he said come on flow
i use it in
in the application where
we work with vs
we can
being a kind of histogram over the floor
of of
to understand present position options in a video
or we can information on shape recognise
object and so on
another important cues inspection
and in this shape texture arise
a large number of small objects like some grass or less
the sexual
can be
summarized by a bunch of theatre
by a set of officers
by using a convolution operation
there is this idea to use filters from their visual system where
there are simple cells
that have arisen dressed in the field
of two forms
oriented and lottery and
their response to a small region
so we can use
as set field trip
capture some
or edge
on the average
four out of the patch
and i describe
describe texture
we can use
concatenation of the responses of of
which makes sense
well above the filters we used the officer of the image
and for each pixel so we have
a long vectors
in which each bubble is a response to
the filters as is
filters sculptural structure like
or in the case
average bowl and so on
there are not enough to believe in new some
some changes
some changes in the images
he didn't
the way
that the image look like
so far we have discussed it just
two how to extract
from images
after that we should be the vocabulary
and at this point
but the recognition
i use it
and specifically
we use clustering algorithm two
our representatives
i see at university of southern california and they have system
what summarised in colombia there is
also very active research group
and that means is the system
from the university of michigan
and then
at the dark conferences the document
understanding conference there has been a continual effort in organizing summary
evaluation summary evaluation activities there are many systems presented and and work on the same
tasks and c
what which approach perform better
and these these different systems
all uses extractive methods
i the
dominant approach but sometimes augmented by the use of lexical resources for example in summaries
their work working that resources are used
the problem
finally in the literature is that all these systems including this
very organised and coordinated systematic evaluation efforts are heavily focused on news text
while in the way
understandable the good news text are
a relatively short and and
in a way it's easier to find organize human judgement charges two to charge the
output summaries
and also of course there's also the need to follow up
current you and are reported in news articles were not much work has been
forty eight
summarizing the type of
and for example
for example like very long economic reports
comment report and business reports these things we
so many times every day
and then some background information about me
and this is
extractive summarisation system that you can use it
to do
to summarize multi documents we can also use it
a single document
and it's open source system that you can
download freely
where the system
has included
several summarisation
and you can explore
and the kind of confidence flexibility
and then there are also a group of summary evaluation methods
very close to five
forty five functional components in the system
you need to do pre processing and you need to
calculate the feature scores for each sentences in the documents and then you use quite
classifier to to combine different features
and the reranker to rerank the significance score obtained from classifiers and then post processing
to make the contents more readable today and these
then these are some of the method
sentence extraction methods in MEAD
i think the centroid method is like
in the centre of the mid systems
and it calculates as it does as that is that the average of
all the sentences in the documents to be summarized and this so that these citizens
is regarded as the centroid
four represent the key contents of this document
and then another each sentence is compared with his citizens to see how similar they
of course now they don't use boats any more
they basically fly around the world to different places
so when it came to say to him OK now you are in the business
now you can really do what you want with this business
what are you going to change
you look just for a long time
this array wanted
we said to
due to take people run by boat any more
he said no no cost
for the first
the boat is the past
i've been tracked by the past
then he
he took it out and here ran one more of so
rather sweetly put in a bottle of wine
he said has been in the back of my head for a long time you
said that actually wine spirituality together rather well
so we're going to combine yards spiritual places
and then interestingly he moved into the centre
one of these little japanese trees
it only group is hard
when they reach the full-sized
one is actually
and he said because i want my organization to be upon xi organization
these are the thing about once a tree
once it reaches its full size you still have to look after you have to
prove that you have to shape you have to take great care but it never
grows any big it's slightly changes its shape was never going
my organisation has thirty people i know the more intimately
my challenge
it is not to grow bigger
but to grow better
what i
now convinced
this little exercise has taught me to do
and so suddenly is values
suddenly appeared in the form xi trees
with the book on
so many of us in our organisations and indeed how schools are trapped in the
past we need to remove the mode
from our institutions
we need to see what we're going to put in
in this place
so many of our organisations are consumed with the idea
the only way
to succeed is to grow
but you don't have to grow bigger
you could grow better
you could be on site
it seems to me
that would be
indeed nice
we have done this exercise
with more i think probably
over one hundred people
of all sorts including young couples who are about to get married very good exercise
what is your life to be able to be like but it is our way
of getting into the why question what is important to like why are you doing
what you do we had a very moving moment of the day
last week in madrid
when we had a workshop for people
on the cusp of life
on those curves people who
four we wanted a weekend
went away to to talk about how their lives needed to change
these are people of the age around about forty so far had been very successful
mostly in business small business in fact
but wanted something more out of life
and the major exercise we gave them was to do is alive
which they found absolutely fascinating
one man
came along he was a partner in the sciences
in holland
very strong
dominating character
tall good-looking
in charge of whatever he
because know is the kind of guy you knew it was there is in the
he said
a piece of nature is said to fly which would ask them to do is
that that's some nonsense he said i don't like flowers
but i know breaks the rules library and i suppose that
that's a piece of nature at least achilles is not least you know the seeds
grow in other countries but there is nothing and for all these objects it was
very interesting because you produced one for his father
this apparent cufflinks he said my dad has dominated my life
my dad is a man who says make money
that's the answer to success i want my son to build the family fortune i
wanted to work hard and build a company
and get rich
on the other side
had this sort of the death notice of his grandfather he said my grandfather was
a totally different
he believed in history in education
in philosophy he was a gentleman
he said
i'll put them on either side because i
i am torn between these two people
in their values
and in the middle he push
a rather
ugly little hierarchy
one these only cheap things and i said what's that
he said that's my work
well i said the two from mckinsey business
i'm not very good
he said well
that that's what it is
and then we can that the objects in elizabeth said
but you've got you've got its objects and the apple you're only allowed five
is said i don't care i'm right the rules that's me
so we can't break these rules that elizabeth my
you've got to remove one of these objects
i mean it sounds trivial game what i have to tell you got very emotional
he stood for a long time and they want to the table these six arranged
for his photograph and it picked up the hat
mister away
that tell you that given the certain function you can
construct an algorithm that will
such and such distance
or produce functions that are certain sections social distance from the true function but again
you make assumptions and
you're trying to do something that
is not useful in practice you don't want to find the function in practice you
just want to make good prediction so
again the point of view
but i think more interesting is where you try to minimize the errors that you
and not try to identify something that
you actually don't know that whether it exists or not
i mean is there any truth functional
you never know
so that's why i
better to think about this point of view
which as well competitive which i call competitive approach or
you can call it also the it's sometimes called the regret approach where
what you do is
you don't want to
you find an algorithm that
the error
but the worst case error in the class
you allow all possible problems
but what you restrict
the set of comparisons
i present so you see
you have a set of functions
or a set of algorithms
you look at
the best
such functions
for the problem at hand
and this gives you
this quantity here
now you compare this to the air
but you make with your
and you want
to be an organism
that is such that
and at the worst possible problem
i will minimize
these different or this this is sometimes called the regret because it means
if i had known
what was the problem i would have chosen this reference which is the best one
maximizing minus the loss means minimizing the loss
so i would have chosen this reference but i didn't do it i chose instead
a predictor
i'm a bit sad about it's not having to this one and the sadness is
measured or the regret is measured by the difference in those two losses
in this way i'm not making any assumptions about how the data is generated where
the where the target function lies and so on and just saying well
how can i compare how do i compare
we use
this class of functions
the thing is that often the results look like the same
bounds on this kind of quantity
our model is the same as bound on the minimax
quantity of the previous slides
if you
take the maximum over the problems
such that the target function is in the reference class
if you if you have a set of functions
and you look at
the worst possible error
when the target function is in this class
you're paying more than the same result as if you
and at the worst possible data generation
the loss of another reason with the loss
of this function
one of the functions in this class
OK so it's more or less a matter of taste but i think it's
important too
this kind of quantities in the right way
and i think this way is kind of going in the direction of avoiding as
much as possible assumptions about
what's your problem is
and OK of course what you do once you've defined such quantities is to prove
story once you've defined such quantities to prove upper and lower bounds
and you these is this explains how you would prove such files to put on
an upper bound
taken algorithm
and you want to
prove abound and the difference of the laws of the losses that is independent on
of the data generation maxima mechanism
and that gives you an upper bound
and to prove lower bound
you have to show that for every learning algorithm you can exhibit construct
data generation
mechanism of probability distribution if if you will
that will maximally mislead your algorithm
OK now
i was trying now to
formalise it's what i have said so far
and a few definitions and
of course by doing so i will restrict myself to specific setting in this case
it would be the IID setting
not because i think i is to write assumption but it's just that it's convenient
and you can actually obtain the same one is the same result if you remove
completely decided the assumptions
so because of the classical notation x input space
why is the outputs
usually we take binary classification so it's just zero and one
and the sample size number of training examples
which are of the form
x i y i
and l is the loss function that measures the distance between
the predicted
label and the true labels usually
just the indicator that the labels are not the same
OK so now
with this notation
what they call the expected loss would be denote written like this expectation
with respect to
if there are no
what to expect from the functions within the function before we can sort of see
i function bit boring the green the green line because it only has a single
in contrast the the people functions
allows you to have action at different at different scales
the same action going on at the sort of small area also some global
i'm actually going on along the length scale
maybe you think for some datasets that's more appropriate
that's more appropriate model for your data
and if you don't know
then you can try both of them
and then you can
as the marginal likelihood which one
you can learn something about what you did looks more like this or it looks
more like that
but you just optimise the problem here
let's try another one
now i've been talking about function
you can also get
a function on smooth here the covariance function
it consist
again the stationary covariance functions depend only on x minus five
the power of the semantic prime
the normalizing constant
and then this is the modified bessel function
but if you don't know what those are
i can't remember what they are
but just some functional form you can do that evaluate things
and the and the some interesting properties here is this has also length scale parameter
l here
as an extra parameter new here
it turns out that
this government formed and the cover the that the function that you get
newman one times differentiable
OK so the functions were looking forward infinity french
that means they were very smooth function
maybe sometimes you have
you have you want to model that is that we don't think the thing that
everything you have
there continues to be some of you think that is differentiable
they don't have you know
primitive of of arbitrary order
and this some special cases these are
if you have integer
then there is much to simple expressions the correct don't involve is best option that's
enough to look at
so this is similar plot before
again now parameterized by the new
and again a new
new goes to infinity
get back the the calcium response
and then you get smaller and smaller
then the covariance function
o has a different behavior here particularly zero
function that drawn again the colours
on the other
again we have all the green line
is that function which is infinitely differentiable
and the
the black line here is once differentiable but not vice principal
what you see here
and the
well line here correspond temple function is not differentiable at all
so again we can we can try to learn whether
functions have some of these properties
it's kind of covariance functions
grant went on for four move
periodic function
here's a little construction you can you can you can do to try to model
instead of looking at x itself
you can map
x on the signing call sign of that
and then you can do you look at squared exponential kernel
in the two dimensional space
given by signing because if you do that then you get something which is periodic
because if you change you add subtract two pi from x then you get the
sin x and cos x
but still it will be because it will be measuring the distance is now
on the on the unit circle so it points to be close to each other
and also be close in this two-dimensional space
if you do that then you're
and then you can use them
three the parameter functions can write that the rest of the being
he manage to times square
high times next time
over length scales again in this
in this two dimensional space you can measure
distance is the length scale
so here have
you have chosen his words more
and you got get different periodicities by multiplying
i everybody but the period length
we used to think of one
these three
samples from the periodic function
and you can see that there can be no article should be
the idea the length scale of one
i think that when you change things by on the order of one in this
in the space of
one of the points on the unit circle
that means at its base at the distance can be much more than one
because all the underlying on the unit circle
get the maximum to be true
that gives rise to a very smooth function
here i used a much smaller periodic length scale
it is
know i better not say anything about this because otherwise it would stay talk during
one hour
which is not which is not going to be possible OK so i'll skip this
part and i'll talk about kernels for graphs
so here
are different sets of graphs those disease and directed labeled graph
this is
label tree
disease labelled undirected graph
this is
edge label for
it is a labeled graph
and directed
so you have labelled on the edges you have labels on the nodes
so those are different kinds of graphs and those are graphs that you may encounter
all the more reason is
this is
yeah sure
so the price very
three four
and again
there's something very
i don't there's something very difficult i think on fisher kernels in in addition if
you look
if you
go read the paper on fisher kernel you'll see that
deriving using
these feature vector
and doing inference and dot products with this feature vector feature vector is not exactly
the the proper way to do that there is
he then matrices
matrix here which is the fisher information matrix that you should use
those which makes things even more
but i say that i never practiced fisher kernels if
maybe it is is it's easy
a quick very quick reminder on graphs i think that you already has had something
like that yesterday with
we're sitting
four and directed undirected labeled graphs you have
labeled vertices or nodes and labeled edges and you don't have there's no directions on
the edges so they are not arcs the edges
there's the go if you want to go in both both directions for instance
for chemical compounds you have a set of of of nodes for a set of
labels for the nodes which are
oxygen hydrogen
and here you have different labels for for the bonds
like simple
the ball
i don't remember aromatic
and heuristic molecule the molecule of of
the notation that we used to
to show you some
graph kernels are the following
the graph is going to be defined by
a a set of vertices a set of edges and the set of labels us
with that go with that both the nodes and the edges
those are the labels of the nodes and those are the labels of the edges
he is going to be the adjacency matrix of of
of of the graph meaning that there is a one in these graphs if i
and j are connected in the graph and there is zero otherwise and
and or
i is equal to one if n of only if label the label of the
eyes equal to
the label of of of
of nodes
OK here's an example
it's going to be easier to look at these molecules have five atoms of carbon
so the set of
eight the set of labels for a is is a we consider that DCM all
the set of
o bonds use these as DTN are they are
and this molecule is i don't know how to pronounce it in english but let's
say inference reading
and you have the set of edges
so you see here you have you mention that
here is the first node is if you want here is the second what FT
two and you see that there's a connection between one and two
so you look at the first line and the second column
and you see that is a one
i think that there's something missing here
there should be a one here
because one is connected to six
but never mind
and then if you want to look at the labels of the nodes you have
here you have the the the first line you have
three different types of labels
which correspond to
the three rules
and then you hear from this matrix matrix you see that the first notice of
type one type one is c
the second is of type one
is c
let's go to the forty fourth one the fourth one is of a type
it is the second world single was the
the story is an
and you see that the fourth one is x
this is actually of that
and is the matrix
and what did i say OK i say very simple i simplifying thing is that
all the labels on the edges are the same
so another example
it is these molecules
this is x almost the same as before except that he here you have
only five items
and instead of fun and you have it all
and mike seeks to compose accordingly
so what does that mean
it means that can write this big summation here
as the summation over a whole bunch of factors which are independent neighbouring terms so
i can push this summation inside the product
so i can basically pushed the summation over the whiteys up to
the very end
next summation one further and so on
it's just like with an antenna your
pulling it out
what the values of this
now this summation here is really simple
because i have
well after all if the white as plus minus one got basically
two by two object here
and and we do
two of the terms here
same reducing so to say a matrix into the victor
then summing over the last term then only get something that depends on the white
people minus one
now then i can multiply this
by the next term in the back
which is the two by two object multiplied by two by one object
again mean he can some of the y t one once
and push it further back y t ones twos and so on
but this allows me to do is
reduce potentially
exponential number of terms
because they're only there
two to the t
to the capital t many different sequences here
into an operation
which is
in the length of the sequence thirty times and what they have to do here
well i have to some
all four terms
it's basically for times t
as opposed to
two to the t
was the dramatic improvement
it's just that then programming
so anybody who's
in the forward backward algorithm is essentially
should have seen that before
now with computer do you say to given
in order to actually optimise all parameters
and in order to perform inference
we may have to compute p of y t
given x and theta
or p of y t and y t plus one given x theta
and we might also have to compute well the base possible sequence of the wise
given a particular set of theta and x
so the best sequence i can compute in the same way through dynamic programming just
like you in in a hidden markov model you find the best annotation of the
it's exactly the same structure
now for the p of y t given x and theta
just go back
it said this guy here
it means i have to sum up with this very set of variables
now after some or all the variables from the other side
it turns out now
that for this big product i can push the summation through from the right
to here
i can push the summation through from the left up to here
and they get terms which only depend on this variable y t
and this allows me to get the conditional probabilities very easily
in fact
if i do although summations
because i can push it up to any particular point
installed in the mid intermediate values i can get all those conditional probabilities p of
y t
by just one forward and one backward pass
so as the forward backward algorithm
sum over all
those products here
at a certain point
same from the but on the other side
and this allows you to get the prior probability for a particular entry
but if you store already what you got up to here
new store what you get by going one step further you get the same quantity
for this entity so it doesn't really cost to anything more
except for extra storage to get all the conditional probabilities at one
they you might think well what you actually need them
well you do need them in order to perform inference
it is actually
as it will turn out
these are exactly the qualities that you will need to optimize for in where to
find the parameters theta that will give you good annotation
now here's the diff
so remember this with the objective function here
this piece of them
i know it's convex and let's assume i have some optimisation procedure which can make
do with only the first reverted
the second ones are
sometimes quite nasty but let's assume i have some magic procedure for that
so the first derivative of this expression here
and the question is which one is more likely to join so i have no
that has
that has the connections to the inside the group but none of these three three
nodes into groups connected among themselves and you have a different situation where this all
his friends know each other so the question is is x more likely to join
the y
and there are two competing social theory so the first one is called the information
i need my grand so
this is the next
how to think about this is that for example if
you want to buy
and you get something that he would say OK you can actually to get
independent sources of recommendation so if i hear from training
the friends who don't know each other so from the independent sources that you know
you should go by this thing then maybe i trust i trust that recombination more
than you know if i get recommendations from the same part of the network or
from the same community
some information on say x is more likely to join because he gets get more
independent information or more independent recommendations to go join on the other hand
there is a social capital arguement the same the y is more likely to write
while because then densely connected sets of friends in the network so when he joins
his feel very well i you have a lot of people or a lot of
people to kind of this people already know each other so confusing
right so basically that stress safety is what makes white joined
and actually if you go measure that it turns out that that's the best explanation
what's important here is the proportion of best but the adjacent basically proportion of my
friends were members of the group and adjacent to one another meaning that connected with
the probability of of thinking and you can see there is something that the more
the connections between my friends in the group the more likely i am to join
the social capital arguement is basically the one that seems to be in place for
the larger that
what so just to recap what show
so far i've shown that
so far
the results seem to suggest that this network groups tend to be tightly connected that
said that you're more likely to join you have lots of friends in there and
his friends are connected that that like so
just this was sort of like the motivation for why do you think of network
groups are classed as being then connected right so the idea is that i be
talking about
let's call the communities clusters groups modules
what they're right i'm using these words changing and i don't want to make any
notation about
are the new york clusters story of social groups and and so when i use
distance from it just means sets of nodes with
relatively lots of connections from the inside the two connections to the outside OK so
this is what i mean by now
and the first question you can go and ask okay how can automatically going to
find such
and when i say GO and you know
ultimately find what i would like the idea is that this clusters that they extract
with correspond to somebody looks like so for example in social networks they would correspond
to real social communities in you know biological networks i would hope they would correspond
to you know function functional modules in the cell so that that's the
and let me show you two in two examples of where is so
this is probably the most famous example it's called seconds karate club right in the
one here is that when secretary was during his phd in nineteen seventy
he was observing social ties
in a university karate club
and during the course of his study there were some disagreements in the karate club
speed so basically took the club for
so i could join
the one club and
square sort of the shared nodes joined into the
and then the question is how can we explain this and it turns out that
the the mean of these networks became an almost perfect you know with a single
mistake here explains how people
introduced new uniforms
right so this is not a a nice example where you know network structure actually
tells me use me
o explains
how these two new
good article i got four right so that that's the ideal case what we would
like to to get from find clusters of communities
a different example comes from the web search
it's so in the web search i have the sort keywords and advertising advertisers bidded
saying you know when i was watching i want my at the show
and what we would like to do is we like to partition is this bipartite
graph will find you know this is no adjacency matrix finds thence their some blocks
which corresponds to micro markets being that you know what this advertisers tend to be
done the same
and you know then maybe you could try to exploit the structure
by knowing that you know that is set of people who tend to be on
the on the same type of you
so these are like two examples what we what we hope to to get from
and that is like a lot of methods to the right
not going through all of them but you know my data is nice i can
just use some lower-end
approximation so you know linear methods if i data is not so nice but it's
still a low dimensional manifold in this country as i can use article methods were
in the top down
or i can graph partitioning to find discussed where basically defined some
let's call it edge counting measure like you know conductance modularity but there are and
then optimize
this measure
find cluster
so just to give you a flavour of how these things work here
o away all the items from basic developed by physicists it's very intuitive how it
so they depend on this notion of edge betweenness and between is just the number
of shortest that
but to go from
right so for example this search here on this example has between the forty nine
right because they have seven notes here and
for every of the seminoles if they want to want to get to any of
the seminoles here the shortest path as the growth of his
the highest betweenness edge in our writing by similar to many such between this be
because there are eleven edges here eleven notes here in three here and whenever i
want to get from this the when you see them and i have to crunch
so that if short goes
minors of
of infor
times l
time delta t
what is the difference matters
the difference
is seventeen minus one hundred sixteen
times ten to the minus six
times l
delta t
and if i take
the length of ten centimetres
and i increase the temperature
five hundred degrees centigrade
then this difference
but you can easily calculate is point one six millimetres
o point one
very little
and yet
this one will curve
for those of you
well mathematically oriented
i would advise you to make an attempt to calculate
so you have
you assume that a perfect circle reasonable approximation
so you have an outer circle
which is longer
five point one six millimetres in the in one
try to solve and find with that these
and i went through that exercise
and you want to do that to perhaps and i found that for many for
these dimensions
for many years
that substantial
so this thing is being used for thermostats
you break and make contact heating system
which could for instance be as follows
he would be anywhere by metal
very schematically
plug in the wall hundred temples
you know that's it like that
and when it's cold
this is down
and the works
and then the room temperature goes up
this starts to curl
it breaks
and that's the so much that that is the basic idea behind the so that
and you have the new cars have them at home and central
heating system
you use all over the place
they also being used for safety device
if you have a gas holder either
in the pilot light in the flame of the pilot light
is a bimodal
and when that by metal is hot
the gas valve is opened
when that by metal gets called it shuts off the gas valve
this is a safety device
in fact in europe all guests i've protected
that way
by law
strangely enough not in the united states
it is very surprising if i open my
gas well home my style
the gas will just come out
just like that is no prevention of that happening
you know that's not possible
there's always the pilot light somewhere with by bimodal
it senses that there is flame nearby to ignite the gas
and if that claim is out
the gas valve will be closed
so by metals can also be used very effectively for safety devices
i have you're by bimodal
one side i believe we believe is aluminum
on the other side we believe is i
and when i did that
you will see that it starts to
it will
you get the idea
the thermometer
very crude from the this the idea of someone so of course
mark the set
was the person
who was preparing always these demonstrations in the fabulous way
told me he had at home a
coffee make
and the coffee maker is designed in such a way
that there is a bimodal
the bottom of the water reservoir you the water reservoir
and when the water reaches a certain temperature by mental opens in the water comes
and go to the coffee
i like to show that he was really cute
he was the coffee machine it's not working anymore it's a very old one
but i want to show you with these that by metal
this is that by metal strips
what goes on here you heat it when it's hard enough
by metal lifts up
you can see there's a whole there is that the whole
what comes out environmentalist closed close
the amazing simple idea
criterion for letting the water goes through the coffee is simply
when the water reaches the temperature close to boiling
and you
have your by metal
control it
so by metals
in many ways control matters
the most as in this case they act like
like if l
by metals can be used
in fact the one that you see
right here
it's driven exclusively by
by metal
if you look in the back
this thermometer analysis showed it to you shortly because i broke one open for you
then it looks like this
as the core
this and of the choral is attached to the plastic casing
and here
so i think
state action distribution the next state europe
you're trying to learn
learn mapping so i think perhaps where you're getting to is the fact that there
is obviously a notion of latent learning notion of learning as you're experiencing the world
without being driven by reinforcement learning let me come back to that addressing that i'm
going to try to
o address so that i'm building up
and building up the foundations second get the more
interesting material eventually so little often that
that's too
o i should say some something more slightly more about this so long
this is obviously a dumb way of doing things right i mean you
you can't do use in chess
countries in any real problem so what do people do instead
people obvious thing the parametric models of function approximation based model the transition probabilities and
what functions rather than lookup table
and this is not
a talk on civilised learning or that sort of thing i'm not going to spend
much time in that direction talk about function approximation somewhere down the road but you
all of you know about function approximation method supervised learning methods you can plug in
any method you want right to estimate the model from the data
they just a supervised learning problem and pick your favourite so i learning method do
it so clearly people in general parametric models neural networks
all these sorts of things rather than building lookuptable things my goal is to give
you a conceptual idea OK let's number one whether the more interesting contribution
really now
what about describe now is really the
up until now all of this
what i talked about
more or less comes from outside of forced comes operations research now what about to
describe you the first
exciting contribution that generated much excitement within the field of modern reinforced warning that the
outcome called q learning a bit about the OK
we're going to have direct method
for solving the optimal control problem that is we can learn a good estimate
a good policy
without ever learning disabilities that without ever learning the reward function
is all we do it
you have
the same objective experience
let's look at the unit of experience which is the state
and k actually going to work on k
mister time keepers one
what we're going to do is going to maintain an estimate
of the q value of every state action pair
and every time step
update that q value function
at time k
i will update the state action pair that we see at time k
it's q values
to be a mixture of all q value
and then you guess
this is the or q value
out by the step size let's say it
o point one so it's point nine thousand or q value plus point one times
this new guess
what's the new guess
and you get the immediate reward you see
plus the discounted
best value
of the actual next state you happen to see
so i'm taking k AKR KSK plus one playing it in here right skk skk
escape is one
i'm using the experience and updating the q value for state action pair
this algorithm is called q learning
developed by
chris watkins in nineteen eighty eight
is the
and it provably convergent
under certain conditions of describe to the optimal q value function from which the optimal
policy then the right
it was the first big prior to this came the album called temporal difference TD
not going to describe because you can think of temporal difference in as really the
same algorithm but applied to the policy evaluation problem
rather than the optimal control problem so i'm going to focus on the optimal control
problem just here
we should let me show this algorithm to you
let me point out several features of south talk about converting first observe that this
algorithm only update the state action pairs as they visited
my only update thing that happened
now what i'm about to show you
in one slide
the high level
why this algorithm converges
the same thing that q value iteration
converges to
so let's look at the algorithm again it's on top
here the critical observation
if you look at the thing inside the square brackets
and take expectation
expectation or what what's the random variable inside here that i have ever said his
around the next state
the expectation of the next state
you get the
and the random variable here is the is the reward
because the world depends on the next state happen to draw
so the expectation of this
square brackets quantity is the media expected reward
plus the discounted
the best value of the next day
and this quantity
is exactly the quantity q value iteration users
what it does is iteration
so we talked about is converging by contraction
so if
we could use the expected value
we would be contracted
instead what we're getting
is in noisy quantity that is the expected that that is essentially adding means noise
to this
q value iteration like quantity
so instead of contracting at every step
you can think of we started one
q value iteration would have taken you this too
instead of going to this two we're going to some noisy version of two
about and services push push me
after a while you learn what you can actually do is move the air over
the thing and then click on the button and that somehow corresponds to push the
physical buttons there are actually used
OK finally you can figure that operated device if you have knowledge about how it
works this is often called mental model
one of the best examples i know of this comes from the star trek movies
which may
c where scotty figures out how to operate the cling on starship
even though
he's never been one before apparently
and that he does that because he knows how star ships work so he knows
he's able to figure out the controls humans
normally if we don't do very well with this sort of thing and is the
technologies developed it becomes harder and harder
to know how the thing works you could build a computer from ships yourself
you could have that knowledge but if i give you a digital device there's a
very good chance that unless it follows some simple pattern you've seen before you will
not be able to figure out how to operate based on your knowledge of how
digital systems work depends on the arbitrary programming that somebody else did
OK so this is actually very weak form of knowledge for inferring out of device
psychologists like to distinguish the knowledge that's relevant here to declarative knowledge and procedural knowledge
because the knowledge is knowledge of facts it's the kind of knowledge that we should
have used to learning all the time procedural knowledge is knowledge of what to do
knowledge of procedures there's some specific ideas about how to represent this one these are
relevant to interacting with a device entity concept here is that
the knowledge that is required to interact with the device successfully the harder is going
to be to learn how to use and the harder is going to be to
actually use
OK even if you already know how to use it to the steps involved in
mental steps you have to go through
procedural steps you have to go through correlates with how much of the knowledge there
still are so the classical distinction between system could be easy to be hard to
use actually does not hold systems that are easy to learn almost always are also
easy to use and vice versa
OK this historical accident that we early in the history of
computer systems encountered systems were that was not true
OK but by and large is of learning and ease of use go together
OK important principles of
that has been that can be applied here
it's called the rationality principle when people are acting
one people trying to get something done
a good first approximation is they're trying to rationally
deal with the situation
the trying to meet their goals and what determines how well they can do that
is the characteristics of the task what it is they have to do what's possible
actions can be done what input information they have what knowledge they have their processing
he have limited ability to process information that plays a role in how they figure
out how to get something done key point here is that the goal it the
tasks and the operators don't depend on the characteristics of the individual person or function
of the objective physical situations you can often define the optimum performance in these terms
like what's the fastest way to do certain things with a system that has this
design in this situation what's the best way to delete it word for example
you point out and double click on
for example or drag overall driving over nominating delete more than double clicking on the
and in the middle east he seemed to find optimum ways to get things done
OK rationality principle and say that with practice people try to optimize if possible we
have to have the required knowledge and work within processing limits but
to the extent that they can do this you can actually predict behavior surprisingly well
for example
i can produce
given what i know about it
these factors in the situation
and way most people
but optimize things
approximately twenty five minutes from now
almost all of you are are not going to be in this room
how do i know how to do it very specific prediction behavior and not normally
used to thinking and behavior has been predictable but a lot of situations it one
of the concepts of psychology in HCI is to take advantage of the fact that
under certain conditions you can actually predict what people will do if you can predict
what people will do anything to predict whether a particular design work well
OK so basically is try to modify the subjective especially the situation to allow people
to get their work done better
the small picture
in nineteen eighty three card moran and newell and the famous book of there's which
were having a session on later in the conference to celebrate twenty fifth year that
particular set of ideas from psychology the last hundred years or so of and recast
it maybe that's good
distribution to explain my data
for example the first order markov chain so now what happens is the distribution might
fit the particular data you have more or less well
and basically
if you change the distribution to coat
then the better distribution fits the data
shorter the corresponding code length will be so every distribution gives you a prescription and
how to make a certain code and that code
i will give a short code length to does things
which have a high likelihood
on the distribution
note once again
i keep saying it there's no assumption here the data are sampled from any distribution
this is a purely formal correspondence between two different mathematical notions
namely probability distributions but here a probability distribution is simply a function on the space
which is
always nonnegative which sums to one
and code length functions
the second thing is you can also do this
if you have continuous outcomes spaces by discretizing the appropriate way
i will gloss over all the details there and from now on this talk and
that refer to a distribution are actually mass function i will sometimes also mean density
by that
and then note that in the last slide
i forgot about this
integer requirement so i didn't run up to the nearest integer
and this is something that is usually done that can be justified
because usually if n is not one but a little bit larger than the probability
suicide to sequences that tend to decrease exponentially and so the minus log of the
probability increases linearly
and then if you neglect this round of
then the area make is at most one bit which will typically be negligible compared
to the total length
and if you do that you get a much nicer mathematical theory and also you
get this theory which becomes independent of the alphabet in which encode things so you
would like a theory where
always easy mapping between coding things in binary according things are turning alphabet
and for this reason from now on
we will neglect the integer requirement
and we'll talk about idealised code
so these are coats
we start if we start from arbitrary distribution of call
this still code functions even if it is non integer lengths this is a common
thing in information theory actually if you read information theory papers you sometimes see that
people use the word cold and distribution simply interchangeably
and when they
talk about codes and they speak about
and they refer to distributions the mean the distribution
which is connected to the code by this quality
so this is about the correspondence between probability distributions and code length functions
and now i'm going to use it to define
universal models
and to define universal models we start with universal codes
for the time being forget
forget that this is the talk about machine learning rule only be
talking about data compression for a few slides now
and we'll talk basically about the method underlying most modern lossless data compressors which is
called universal coding
and the idea is as follows
so i suppose
you one encodes some data
and you have a set of different codes available for doing that
and you want to compress the data as much as possible that your goal
you think that some of the code in the set career l the set of
candidate codes will actually do a good job they will compress the data a lot
so now the the goal is to encode the data using the minimum possible number
of bits
based on the set of candidate codes
so i should be doing it will be obvious
is to simply called the data
the code instead of
which minimizes the code length of that particular data
so no that's because i'm not interested in how the actual encoding is done identified
the CO is their length functions so
this is the discrete l is
i call it a set of course but we is it's set of linear functions
corresponding to these codes which each outcome give you the number of bits needed to
encode the outcome
so the of is idea to pick the code which minimizes the length doesn't work
why doesn't it work well to see that
if realize that coding and decoding can always be viewed as a game between the
encoder and the decoder what encoder and the decoder me before seeing any data to
be encoded and they agree on the protocol a drug agree on their called
so after they've agreed on that they split again and the encoder sees the data
he coated any sense the encoded string to the decoder decoder has to decode it
if you think of it that way
then if the encoder will simply pick the code which minimizes the code length of
the given data
it's clear that the decoder wouldn't be able
to decode the data because the decoder gets encoded strings
but the decoder doesn't know what could be in color used
so if he doesn't know what could be in carter used in the decoder also
said curly ali might have agreed on that before seeing the data
but he doesn't know the element of l it's best for the data because
the decoder doesn't know the data that's why you need to decode it
so therefore the decoder
can not
decode the message if the encoder
encoded like this
so now the question is well apparently we can do as well as this but
can be used nearly as well
and the answer is yes
so there exist codes such that no matter what data you get
you always encode sequence
nearly as well as the best particular call for that particular sequence
and could intuitively give a formal definition later what intuitively coach with this property
are called universal codes
so universal it's a bit strange because universal means universal relative to the universe curly
so clearly is your universe you set of codes to which you compare yourself you
want avenue called which is as
no matter what they do you get
as good as
are almost as good as the best coach
in truly l
so here's a simple code suppose a simple example suppose curly l is finite
and then you always have some code
such that no matter what data you get
the number of bits needed to encode the data
it's more equal than the number of bits needed any codes in the sets
plus comes
if n is large
this constant will be negligible compared to this because this is we set typically increases
so then you actually doing a good job
these objects these examples and then the labels are these wise plus minus one and
the end of those examples OK for instance samples are points in rd
and there is some unknown function of x which would like to estimate
and that's that generating the labels given given x
OK there is some unknown distribution holidays examples look like and the objective is essentially
to predict y given x
the problem of course is that the probability distribution is unknown so p of x
and y is not
so this is of course in the ideal case this is really a deterministic function
so it might be just
OK so
so this is the model we have a hypothesis class
so we have a set of functions h
and other this function class we have to pick functions
that somehow would
and we also have the loss function that measures how good our laws our function
h mediation is point
OK so here we have this loss function l that measures how good one that
we we are all public this difference between y and h x are prediction that
could be for instance just zero one loss so if y is not equal h
and you're lost otherwise not so the goal is that we would like to try
to find the function of this country class h that has a small expected loss
if any i mean given data from from the distribution you would like to find
the function that minimizes the expected loss of everything take expectation of x and y
so the problem of course is that we only have a data sample and p
of x and y is unknown therefore what you can do with this we can
try to find empirical minimiser of the loss function here
so we have indeed points of the approximate this
expectation with empirical
version of the
so the question is how can we efficiently construct complex hypotheses with small generalisation error
so over the small
expected loss
OK so
let's go back to our example
we have all training set what might look like this for the first examples of
one class since examples of the other class
of course we need to have some properties of these applets and OK i guess
trivial OK so let's say you have both these these apples you have two properties
of each of these samples so how rare they are and how happy they are
for instance or how like they are actually and then you can just place it
is built in this coordinate system and then you could come up for instance with
a very simple process of classifying the samples to this this axis linear cut
classifies most most
it has benefit is just a very simple hypothesis class so that the function class
would look like all axis parallel cuts which be function i mean every
every axis is cut would be one punch OK so they're not so many here
so yours may be here
OK so it's quite small hypothesis class
OK so this is of course has been formalized so this is the
so called PAC learning theory and that's that's the organisms more notation here so we
are given the sample here we have this set of examples x one y one
two x and y in any given this hypothesis class
initially we have given an accuracy parameter and confidence parameter efficiently we have an article
with that given the training sample generates a function from the hypothesis class OK so
it essentially this algorithm generates given the training sample
it generates a function out of that hypothesis class h so the output is this
function so and we would like to have that
with very high probability this function has a low our OK
so that is
this probably approximately correct
so the probability that the loss of our estimator tension
minus the loss of best function is greater than excellent should be smaller than that
OK so with high probability
with small probability of this difference should be large means that the high prodigy the
difference is small
OK and eight stars just the best function you can be estimated
and there should be some so this should hold but on the other hand you
would like to have this algorithm somehow efficient so
we would like to have a polynomial running time in the number of examples in
one of the one about
OK so
so i started this is the best function of course class
essentially given the process that we just pick one which is best HP that is
the best function which we can pick it also the bayes optimal classifier
OK so where the hypothesis class essentially unrestricted
so there are three levels of generality so i want to see restricted setting where
we assume that the bayes classifier is equal to the best classifier the forces set
so that we would like to have the loss of our estimator function goes in
probability to the loss of the best knowledge
in agnostic setting we don't assume anything about hp but we about the bayes optimal
function but we require that the
our estimate the loss of the estimated goes to the
loss of the best function in the most general setting the initial setting we assume
nothing about HP and we require that the loss
of our estimate function goes to the loss of the basis function k and this
is what we department is going to talk about in the research talk so he
chose i think that posting is universally consistent setting
essentially this property
but i present
OK so we we consider the simplest setting so we just talk about the universe
that i'm going to talk only about the restricted setting so is essentially the space
optimal function is in the past
so i would like to the final two terms that is the so-called strong PAC
learning and compact
OK so strong PAC learnable
they you can specify any delta and x that means we can be arbitrarily small
and the and you get these done excellent without and then generates maybe it's the
computing time maybe needs a lot of examples but can come up with a hypothesis
which is very close to bridge which has the loss which is very close to
the optimum lost
the best action
and that holds for any x on any any day
and in the week the meatpacking and so that we demand only that this equation
only holds for some choices of that
so not for every choice
so for example
in binary classification we could require that the classification error is more than half
it is simply a sum of left moving the right moving
waves which
separate you know in more than two dimensions waves can move in all sorts of
directions in one space and one time dimension waves go either left or right you
don't have much choice and actually the two shorter waves are therefore independent there's something
more which usually with the right if you had you know the electromagnetic field namely
something that grows linearly with tau here
but remember this is not really a wave in just flat ten dimensional spacetime this
is a wave on a string if this thing is closed or small in the
way it can have some overall momentum it may itself move in space time
and he knew the thing that appears in front of the linear theorem which shows
the value of this equation is simply the momentum of the average centre of mass
of these objects
so this is a very simple solution actually
it's convenient to think of the xingu those as some function of l minus sigma
this takes care of all the right moving waves and some other functional plastic that's
all the left moving waves where f and fifteen them you independent functions for closed
if you want to think about the open strings and we'll have to think about
them in a little while then on an open string that are is standing waves
because the wave goes to one and then reflects back to show you only have
standing waves and this translates to the fact that new is if you feel that
new up to assign plus or minus the sign depends on the precise choice of
boundary conditions at the two ends the two simplest boundary conditions are free and point
namely the point of this thing moves freely in space time that's called the only
one or fixed point like the violin string i showed you before and that's called
dirichlet and the different just baseline
OK so this is the solution in a sense of this very simple classical theory
now what do we want to do well we have either closed string or an
open string
and we want to think of them as seen from very very far away as
point particles right
so if you have some string very far away it will look to you like
a point particle and the various properties of point particles which we used to think
of as quantum numbers associated with particles mass
so in charge
a color and so
would have to be understood now as being due to the
the motion of this thing right since there is not the structure here this thing
is structural less all these characteristics have to arise from the way thing moves at
very short scales so for instance the mass can only be vibration energy this thing
when you see from far away it looks like energy of course mass you don't
know what it comes from but if you had huge loop and you could look
at this thing you would see the string vibrating around and that's why it has
a mass this being is simply angular momentum but it's some sort of intrinsic angular
momentum of the loop
the chargers talk next time has to be momentum in some he them directions
and so on and so forth
now let's be slightly more precise suppose we want to compute the mass of this
string what do we have to do
well let me go back to this solution i showed you where x and you
remember was a linear there plus f plus if you feel that actually have persisted
that had absorbed the linear term in there
remember that we had to be in the conformal gauge the conformal gauge was telling
us that the politics and the sigma x y are orthogonal and of equal length
you can rewrite them very easily as the conditions that the derivative of f has
a zero length that remember a lawyer lawrence in lancashire it can be zero it
has to be like like simply the derivative of fifty there has to be of
zero land and these are in a sense the only remnant of non-linear editing this
very simple system you know the system look at first non-linear of square roots and
so on but in the end of the day we so it simply freeway is
pretty simple
but there is still a little the amount of nonlinearity which sees in this
conformal gauge conditions now this conditions such simply constraints from the phase space namely they
tell you what is only allowed initial debate that classically for stream once you have
imposed them at some initial time they are forever
satisfied you don't have to work more
so it's a very benign small nonlinearity but it is still there and
it tells you what kind of strings are allowed
emotions are allowed and this can actually be solved very easily in a very particular
choice of gauge which is so-called light cone gauge now the light cone gauge is
simply a conformal gauge where we utilize one small remnant of freedom to make it
even simpler what is the element of freedom well remembered
x like all other or the coordinates x
there were some
the function of r minus sigma plus a function of tau plastic more
right now you can check and they want to this to you that if you
a parametrized felt blessed by some other out the blessing might feel that a function
only of doppler signal and likewise for the minor this is called the conformal parametrisation
then gauge conditions at realistic satisfied that's pretty obvious because is were only function a
member of domain sigma
therefore i can take one particular according
i decided to write it down as minus sigma delta sigma
linear and you know it some arbitrary functions i can just use this area is
enjoyed freedom and it is convenient to do this not for the coordinate x is
zero as you might be tempted but rather for according to which one course explores
which is x zero plastics one
therefore you define
it out to be simply express plus
in this light cone gauge
now why is this nice because x in the text the minkowski inner product becomes
minus six plastics minus plus x transverse square and therefore one x plus
is linear the derivative is constant
so this becomes a constant that can solve now easily this conformal gauge conditions for
x minus
and there is only something left in the end which are this transverse oscillation modes
so that's how you solve the problem and actually when you write down this equation
the zeromode remember these functions there is a for all four years series but when
you're right down to zero mode of this you discover the so-called mass extra conditions
OK and then you have to sort of replace the sum by an integral
OK let's think for a moment now
it's the sort of move on
you can actually consider joint probabilities between pairs of variables
so what is the probability that that i measure
one meter eighty and today's sun
if things are correlated variables
and not expand when it's hot
OK let's let's just go through the through the notation one one important one very
important prob property is that of
marginalisation so if i have the joint distribution between two events
in a certain way i can i can sort of recover the marginal one
so p of x by basically
plugging in here all the possible values and why could take
and just adding up
all right now we
going example of this
if these were continuous random variables that have to be replaced by an integral OK
so very very important rule that i'm sure you all know and we're gonna we're
going to derive it in a very very intuitive way in a couple of slides
is is bayes rule
now things that using bayes rule makes bayesian
it doesn't right i mean people have been using bayes rule for for very very
long to simple
the rules of probability is and it has nothing to do with being
bayesian OK we talk about being bayesian later on
so what this base would say
this rule says that the joint probability
of x and y
can be computed in two different ways that are very very similar i could first
observe some value of x OK and then i ask myself now that i've observed
x now that the it's sunny what is and what is the probability you know
that i want to it or whatever
and then have to multiply that by the probability that it was in the first place
and i can do this both ways around OK
now once of written this
i can actually
the rival
this OK from this from this equality here
i guess everybody's
perfectly consonant with this thing so far
so bayes rule
and being very important when you're doing probabilistic modeling
because often
in this equation here for example
you may want to know
what effects was your input and why was the output you may want to know
what the probability of the output is given your input right or very often
x is actually going to be parameters of your models and you want to get
you're going to want to build the predictive distribution
so quantities that people
very often compute
and very often you need to actually summarize
a probability distribution by some by some sort of a small set of numbers of
quantities that people can sort of understand and relate to write like if you switch
on the news they always simplify things actually they never go beyond the average really
i mean
maybe sometimes they give
sort of
confidence intervals that's very rare and then when they do
chances are
it's sort of wrong
so if you had if you had some crazy continuous distribution so if this were
and these were
the density
so x could sort of have
you know some
some sort of shape what we know is that the integral of this thing is
is equal to one
but if this was the height distribution of people or whatever
you may want to report something about it so
a fundamental quantity is the expectation
the mean OK
you can sort of see how it works right i take i take
every possible
the height of the person and then multiplied by
by how often it actually happens right and since this is already normalised
i'm actually doing some sort of convex combination of all possible values right
that's what i mean
now the variance gives you an idea
of the spread of the distribution OK is it very concentrated or is it very
all right
so how does how does the variance work
well what i do is i i go to the mean wherever i wherever it
it ended up being the mean of this distribution might actually be here for example
and then i sort of and then a sort of measures
for every possible access of switch to go through the through the space i compute
these little distance here square it
and then i sort of and sort of weighted by
by the corresponding height at this point
OK and this gives me
an idea of how concentrated distribution is
now if i have actually
if i have actually two random variables
one thing i could one thing i could sort of compute is how much do
the covariance list let's draw picture
so let me draw two two possible pictures this would be one
what this is x
and this is why
and then in the sort of axis goes out of the bore you have the
and another picture could go would be
sort of this one
again sort of the contour line of the distribution
now in which of these distributions
this thing
x and y could very
who votes for right
who votes for blue
then as
OK so so
o i i did actually skip over this if if the mean of x is
zero then then it's quite clear that that computing the variances disparities
maybe this afternoon we can actually prove this OK i can someone to prove that
if two
if two random variables are independent the first thing is that you can write there
you can write the joint distribution
as as the product of the two right so for example if i wanted to
know what the probability is that i am one eighty tall and today's sun
i would actually independently compute with the probability of being son is today and with
the probability of me being one it is today
and then we just multiply the two and all right
if there was a relationship between the two i couldn't do that
all right
so one thing i could do now
is i could go to that links manually
and i could be is now a joint probability distribution OK by counting right so
i no longer have two random variables x and y and
and i think them in such a way that i first go and pick an
x and then look at what the immediately following letter was right and they call
that y
and i can i can be build this matrix and i just count again right