the following content is provided under creative commons license
your support will help MIT opencourseware continue to offer high quality educational resources for free
to make a donation or view additional materials from hundreds of MIT courses
this MIT opencourseware
OCW MIT that you
so our first question here about limiting reactant to learn something new
i will encounter in your review reading for the sections that kind of review what
we hope you have picked up from high school will pick up quickly by doing
some review
so how about we have everyone he got ten more seconds on the clicker question
get your final answer in here
right so let's see what we have
right now it looks like are showing percentages here by the looks like hopefully most
of you are able to get the correct answer each two being the limiting reactant
looks like we're still figuring out this room was just motivated we're still working out
exactly how the electronics work so normally wealthier percentage of how many of you got
it but i'm going to say was probably about ninety five percent confidence to write
so good job there if you didn't get the answer right will send these questions
UTA so any time you get the question wrong and you refused to bring it
up in the next recitation section will be able to discuss it there so starting
in we can switch over to the
so there no now
when we left on wednesday
what we have really been doing is trying to give you an overview of all
the different topics that we're going to be going over this semester and also
to make a couple of those connections
between the principles were learning and some of the exciting research that's going on at
MIT in the chemistry department and also to give you the idea
we are going to be trying to make these connections between the chemistry and things
like human health or medicine
now we get to actually take a step back and started the beginning because before
we can talk about some of the more complex issues which involve interactions between molecules
reacting or even when we're talking about individual molecules the bonds form between individual atoms
before any of that we actually need to establish a way that we're going to
describe and think about how
an individual atom behaves and the way that will do this is starting with talking
about the discovery
of the electron and the nucleus here
once we go through that we will be able to talk about describing an atom
using classical physics so once we have an atom in the nucleus what will try
to do is apply
classical mechanics to explain how that behavior
what will find that this fails and once this fails we're going to need another
luckily for us we have quantum mechanics which will be talking about for the next
few lectures and will dive into that we might get a chance introduced stable certainly
in not class will be introducing this new kind of mechanics that's going to allow
us to describe the behavior at all
so i want to point out that it it makes a lot of sense for
us to start with the discovery of the electron and the nucleus because it really
highlights one of the big issues that comes up all chemistry research that you do
and that is how do we actually study
or in this case
how do we discover
adams or some particles that we actually can see it all
and there are lots of solutions that cannot come up with there's always new techniques
that allow us to do this and these are just some of the first and
will go through them in a little bit of detail here
so this all started in terms of putting it in its historical context at the
turn of the century we that we start writing in the twentieth century and were
chemistry was and where we were at the start of the twentieth century in the
late eighty ninety is that we were at the place where there was great confidence
in our understanding of the universe and understanding of how all matter worked so people
in the chemistry community and in the physics community had this general feeling that the
theoretical structure of the entire universe was pretty well understood and they had this feeling
because they had just found this
huge boom of discovery of scientific advances that included newtonian mechanics and included daltons atomic
theory of matter also thermodynamics in classical electromagnetism
so you can understand i really felt quite confident at the time that we can
explain everything that was going on in fact really telling quote from the time
with that by professor at the university of chicago and what he said is our
future discoveries must be looked for in the sixth decimal place
basically what he's saying here is that we pretty much understand what's going on there
is nothing new to really discover all we need to do is measure things more
that's not exactly the case and we're going to start in at the point where
right around this time of great confidence of feeling all has been conquered there are
some observations and discoveries that are made that completely break down these theories for example
in terms of the atomic theory of matter
at the time at the turn of the century
you only allow binary relations and likewise probabilistic relational models are essentially markov logic we
only allow binary relations
and then we you know is in essence we do everything the same as bayes
nets except that the difference is not the first arguement can vary
right so should remember
in bayes nets i always require the first arguement to be the same object
the key thing in probabilistic relational models that
this property of this object could depend on some of the property or some other
object so like and have forms the talk about multiple objects at the same time
and this is self-published question models generalize
there's networks there more restrictive than than islands in the sense that the only allowed
binary relations with markov logic allows any relations
and then compare PRM would so yourself using KBMC
we are somewhat orthogonal restrictions
in terms of your binary relations in these other along articles
OK so each one of them can do things that the other one can at
some level but all of them can be done by markov logic
so what about relational markov networks
well if you think about relational markov networks
somebody has a question
what i mean by numbers in the parameters or the probabilities
right if i understood the question correctly here's the answer
first of all
my answer is in the query space that i have set up
but if i give the right
truth assignments to those predicate signed
now you're right that if i do this naively that's going to be a much
more complex problem then seizing CKY
because now i have to compute all these things that otherwise i wouldn't like to
say to represent them
what makes this efficient is lazy inference
is that most of the places where the prose could be i never going to
worry about
i'm always been assumed that they're not there
i only thought i only explicitly represent nounphrase from one to two
if i have some evidence in the input string that there's a known first from
one to two
otherwise it never happens
so the complexity is actually again ones are being quite nice
we can talk about this
so what about relational markov networks
the query is that you have in mind
in markov networks conjunctive SQL queries which
you can equally well represented as datalog which of course is a special case of
first order logic so it's clear how to do this we can write the queries
that represent the cliques in
first order logic and therefore with weights in markov logic now we need one clause
for each state of a clique
i remember what happens in our lenses that we're going to explicitly represent each state
of the clique
unless we have some additional language for representing the structure that clique which is of
course with markov logic networks provide but if you don't have have such language then
you need the clause for each state of a clique which could become cumbersome if
you have a lot of variables in the clique we we have another nice piece
of work
syntactic sugar not be that facilitates which is you can request clauses with an asterisk
instead of the negation
but this means that you want to commit to create both versions of the class
the version that was a little gain in the vision with a little not negated
so if you have a cause three literals all of which have as risk then
this automatically creates all the it causes k so this makes it very easy to
implement something like like a relational markov network in markov logic
again it's clear what the restriction is is the relational markov networks i'm not specifying
what the structure of the features inside the quickest
and as a result i pay pricing inefficiency
what about bayesian logic
well the logic is pretty language pretty complicated syntax which i will not going to
hear the crucial thing about the nice thing about this logic is that it allows
us to talk about domains well we don't know in advance what your edits
but i see blips on the radar and there are some aircraft there but you
know i don't know which aircraft which in some of the police might be nice
so the question is how can we do something like that in markov logic actually
more than one way but his wife
an object is really a cluster
of related or similar observations
so for example in the resolution which selected canonical application for this an object is
really a cluster of the various mentions that appeared the various corrupted strings and different
ways of writing the referencing and what not
and so what i need to have this in addition to observation constants i need
to have object constants
and once you have added constants this gives me the nice property that blog also
has that more naive approaches like conditional random fields don't which is that i can
talk about properties of the object
in addition to properties of the strings
being three letters long is the property of the string bob
being male is the property of the object body
and we don't reproduce the properties of the object body as many times as the
citation strings about that appear right that would be a better model
but if i have up to constants i can talk about objects in this we
only get to produce as many times as the actual edits that exist
no of course the next thing that we need to do is i need to
have a predicate formulas that relate the two
because this is what i see that this is my evidence this is what i'm
going to query about
i'm gonna cui what objects are there
and one would have know what
relations exist between them
so in order to do that we can just use the no the predicate instance
of which that this observation is an instance of this
and now i can write clauses using this predic
this clause also things like
if this
it happens then this string is another version of this object
like for example if the string is j smith
then this is the instance of the object you know john smith one
and with that know what i do inference with
in the evidence this in the query
if instance of a
is in the query this will
tell me what are the observations are instances of objects if also happen to know
this for some objects which again to block you can actually say for some of
the time that these exist then those grounds of this project will be in the
evidence either way
the inference in in alchemy will tell you how to do it
not only that
in in in in markov logic
small number of variables to particular
looking at the marginal for w we can notice that
the variable v appears only in this factor here so we can pull that out
is the common factor and the summation of these separately from the remaining
some nations
and so this is a numerical algebraically equivalent but numerically but numerically computationally is more
and the elegant thing we can do here is to express this in terms of
local messages on the graph
so this quantity is some function of w will think of this is the message
that is sent from this fact to note to this variable node called f one
to the user function w
and similarly this remaining object will think of this is the message sent from here
to here so each of these are sort of k dimensional vector
and compute the marginal we simply have to
multiply them
point wise together so that's the order k
computing this involves a little k by k
matrix that sort of quadratic in k
and we have to do k
some feature the k values WC there's a little order k squared calculation to compute
that message to can do that very efficiently
and then the multiplication against the k dimensional multiplications again that's also
that's also very efficient to compute this message efficiently we could do the whole thing
in quadratic time sort of exponential time
i i start by talking about directed graphs and maps onto factor graphs in which
each factors of those conditional distributions in the sense that the factor graphs more generally
don't have to be conditional distributions in the from the directed graph they could be
derived from some undirected graph or or or something it's any factors asian any any
situation in which the
joint probability distribution of all the variables factorizes that's all the factor graph is is
expressing so those factors may have interpretations conditional distributions but they may be something else
as well
now the questions
OK so
the remains then the issue to computing this
message efficiently let's look at that message again we can do the same thing we
can reorder the sums and products
again we can interpret
this quantity now see is a message from a variable nodes to factor nodes so
go back a second this is to compute the marginal at this node take the
product of the two incoming messages that about variable node
this is telling us how to compute the
the message from factor to variable node it says take the incoming message from the
but all the other variable nodes into that factor nodes multiplied together anyone here to
take that incoming message multiplied by the local factors and estimation
again this is a k dimensional vector this little k by k matrix and there
are k terms in that some social order k squared again so we have the
order case that operation fauna got another or the case where the operation to do
again we can take this
and we can reorder it
and interpret that as
other messages
so this is the message that i'm going from this variable nodes this fact and
it just the product of the incoming messages on the other
from the factor nodes and the
this a lot more of this
i think in in tom minka store where he talks about various methods for doing
inference on graphs using local message passing
each of these is a little quadratic operation and the number of them is just
going to grow
linearly with the size of the graph
so now
if i make the graph bigger
the computational cost now grows linearly instead of exponentially to big computational savings
if you use something other than that you would
the the
so that's it
they have like
yes i mean applies to all sorts give you insight into the fast fourier transform
all sorts of other
yes this is very very general
exploitation factors asian yes is more general than just machine learning show
the other
so now we are very pleased to welcome
professor anthony from the news to washington who is the founder and director of
the newspapers during center
his triple-a fellow and the founder of several successful start-ups including how much to buy
or not to buy cigarettes and his interest in solving fundamental problems in the study
of intelligence web search mission reading
so thanks are referred to as
thank you it's a pleasure to be here
hamlet is not called for cast
and if that's an improvement but i won't talk about that let me start here
can anybody tell me what this is
thank you to reject test
what i've done is i've devised a rorschach test for computer scientists so if you
look at this
picture you have to ask yourself what's that is that a depiction of moore's law
storage capacity number of web pages
facebook users
it's we live in in an exponential world and the training center
it is meant to investigate a set of questions around search natural language in that
context of just a couple words about the training center and then i get to
the topic of my talk
so we have three research foci
the first one is to scale machine translation to the large number of languages on
the order of seven thousand languages spoken on earth that means forty nine million language
standards statistical machine translation technology doesn't scale
so this number of language pairs the reason is that
they rely on aligned corpora which are manually generated and you can't have
this manual on corporate scale
what we have done is looked at an easier problem lexical translation
mapping words from one language to another with the idea that we could do that
with for a much larger set of languages
and so we build something we call the translation graph right now it has on
the order of
two point five million words nodes and edges indicate translation between one word to another
in particular sense and the question that we ask on the project is the inference
question is if you start in words in vietnamese and you can translate the french
and from french let's say you can go to catalina well
is that true translation path is that truth preserving in other words what's the probability
that if you go from vietnamese all the way to catalan you end up with
the same word that you started with
so interesting problem let me just show you a quick search application built on top
of this lexical translation one of the things we realised is that image search experience
is not nearly as good if you speak a relatively small languages like turkish and
hebrew or vietnamese compared to our experience in english
simply the size of the web's there are smaller so actually makes sense to take
a query let's say in turkish and translated to different language for free during the
search so we built this engine called pan images that use this translation technology
to do exactly that let me just give you a sense of how it works
so do query
in english
is it so you can click translate and what it does is it uses this
graph an inference over the graph
in computer set of translations to different languages and you can see that the notion
of breakfast across different cultures so
japanese breakfast looks quite different
then a typical american one so this is a course parallel to flickr and google
or trying to be fair and you can see the images there so that's the
for project at the training center and you can play with this offline it's at
penn images that or
a second project that has more than a i flavor is we're asking how do
you accumulate massive amounts of knowledge from from the web
o age-old AI problem how do you build
and a i system with a an enormous amount of knowledge and our hypothesis is
well if you can be extracted from the web that would be one way to
build that presumably more efficient than say what's happening inside where you have
the knowledge engineers hand entering that knowledge over
what's been no more than twenty years
what i want to talk about today though is are third effort which is to
attempt to investigate and sketch out a new paradigm for for search
so the outline of my talk i will talk about this new paradigm what i
mean by that talk about our
brand if you will of information extraction which we call open information extraction and and
then i'll talk about the various ways we try to do inference over that extracted
and i'll conclude
so the question that we start with is what is web search going to look
so far into the future further than i think most of us usually think so
pick twenty twenty could be twenty thirty
twenty eighteen but let's think farhad what's going to look like a we still going
to be typing
keywords into the search box
is it going to be a social type of things the running on top of
face because it can be something like my hollow structure that's our yahoo answers that's
human powered
four that social
is it going to be the semantic web tim berners-lee vision are we going to
get there
but twenty twenty what about the technology exponentials in my little rorschach shocked test look
at how they change the equation how do we build search systems that use exponentially
more powerful
discs and machines
so these are good questions and i think the best answers to borrow case lines
the best way to predict the future is to invent it and i think that's
what most of us here if not all of us are trying to do
and again i'm going to focus on our particular way of inventing the future so
and we will
expose an electron
four that radiation
and then we'll see
what you like to do with the incoming traveling wave
plane wave
so here is an electron
has charge q which is non negative it has mass m
and from the left
comes linearly polarized radiation that's what i have chosen
he zero cosine only get
so just comes into play wave infinite in size comes in like that and electoral
begins to shake
and the force that the electron will experience f
a few times is zero
cosine omega right
that's the definition of electric field
as it is connected to force
now when you look all
i do this for bonding electrons through these electrons are bound
and and or
or in the molecule sort of bonding electrons
so when you try to move them away from equilibrium
they don't like that
they experience restoring force because of the
coulomb interaction in the end and they want to go back
so does the restoring force that acts to some degree like a brain
and so it is also then a resonance frequency associated with that restoring force
so the resonance frequency
i will simply call
omega zero square which and k over m and k is then the equivalent of
the spring constant which now acts
in the anime
i will ignore purposely for the reason of simplicity
any form of them
so i'm going to write down on newton's second law
newton's second law becomes now
x double dot
omega zero square
times x
he calls this driving force which is q
is zero
divided by n
times the cosine only getting and the reason why there is an annual because i
have already removed and here and i have removed
so this is an equation that we've seen before
when we were dealing with force oscillations
and it has a very simple solution that a x i mean is eight times
the cosine of omega t
this is only of the drive
and so the object will follow
in steady state solution
and there a is the amplitude
and the amplitude i even remember
if you ask me three months from now i will not remember any more
this is always upstairs remember
and then downstairs
you get all that stuff omega zero squares miners omega squared pillars omega squid government
square the gummi is zero
so you have no damping
so you get downstairs here omega zero
omega square that is the amplitude
of the
oscillating electrons
but now we want to know
how much radiation is going to produce
so now we have to calculate what x double but
actually about
is the acceleration of the electron
and then we want to see how much radiation comes out
and so on
x both becomes miners
only guess credit
sachs was taking the second derivative right you've seen that before
and so that becomes n minus q
he zero
divided by
omega zero grant
mine is only gets credit and they upstairs
and omega square
and that's the next generation of this electoral
but now
i know how much power goes into that field
because the power goes into the field where do i have that i raise my
the raise the
lot work i will do that for that reason so that total politics radiated is
proportional to a square help you remember that i raise the wrong part of the
and so the a squared is what i really want to know
and so the power
that is radiated by the shaking electron
is proportional to forget all the constant
only got two to force
divided by omega zero square
mine is only because it's great
forget all the rest all the rest is gone
and now
if omega
is way below resonance
this is proportional to omega three four
that's a very famous result
which is known in the literature as rayleigh scattering
and the reason why we call it scattering
rayleigh scattering
that you must understand that the radiation that comes in
has this frequency
but the radiation that comes out has exactly the same frequency look that is the
oscillation of the
so there is no change in the frequency
radiation comes in a certain color red light
and then there is a black hole which starts to shake gets very nervous because
of the field and it radiates again red light the color does not change but
it can go off in different directions
that's why we call this
really scattering
and if you take oxygen and nitrogen
in our atmosphere
then the resonance frequency
it is way above
the frequency of visible light
the resonant frequency for optimizing the far UV
and so we need to that condition
that visible light strikes oxygen and nitrogen molecules and for that matter many other molecules
relationship holds
and what that tells you then is
that blue lights
has the way higher probability to be scanner
moving electrons
red light because the wavelength
or the frequency i should say of blue light is substantially larger than the frequency
of red light
so i let me try to stay on the centre bought
and show you what the differences in
so only w
divided by omega red
it is approximately one point five taking side of the spectrum
about sixty five hundred
angstroms random forty five hundred angstroms
and that means that one point five of the pol four is about five
so the blue light
so i am officially go from here on i will be presenting negating the descriptors
into a compact image presentation so this is joint work resettlement they use on polish
from going on but there is something you could
what you want to address is the
image search on large case we want to be able to retrieve is to images
of the same scene or object can the default view viewpoint background so for instance
the first korean bottom is the amount of the database image we also want to
be able to handle copyright attacks such as the cropping editing the second example and
the bottom these images database it has been printing scratch on this can
this because we don't use a short response time from image the to image database
two billions
the images online machine
so most of the related work depends bag of features framework could do get approach
by city councilman as improvement includes is the use of large vocabularies semi pulls descriptor
presentation so decision which has been integrating reasons index and some nice techniques from text
that retrieval as being elected to the image search such as the quick functions
however this approach is the main tractable for human use images only
so efficiency may be improved by using min ash or decision extension or by directly
compressing about of features presentations however
still hundreds of bytes are required to obtain was the quality of the reason is
that exactly as good as the features with large vocabularies
an alternative which consists in using these descriptors combines percussion techniques
the descriptor itself give only very limited invariance to scaling rotation of crops
and is sufficient for our application
so our aim is to optimize trade off between search quality search kind of course
but also memory usage which is critical parameters if you want to be able to
store is indexed memory four
besides the databases approach licence during continuation of three stages
so first assumes that some SIFT descriptors have already been extracted from the images so
this is quite stunned
this gives us and
the vectors that to present image
and now we are going to have make sure he is for us to look
at this to aggregation which from a set of vectors will use a single vector
representing the image vector is subsequently reduced using dimensionality reduction so in these cases is
you know that dimensionality reduction context that it is not exactly stand on then you
could use that is on could produce a code which is the final image presentation
so let's start with the first stage
so we want to be able to present an image by using a fixed size
vector services applications so that they consider
was the most popular idea consists in using the bag of features framework which is
the case of large scale image search for use in specific fields
which are either mentioned and we see in our experiments this idea dimensionality is not
good because it is difficult to reduce their tools without introducing some loss
on this nineteen ninety which is the earliest known which is official canon representation was
very popular
which produce some non sparse vectors these are less sparse on still provide excellent because
it was limited victoria dimensionality so i mean so it can be seen as a
simplification of this presentation
it was aggregation stage it's school vlad which stands for vector of locally aggregated descriptors
the learning stage is quite simple it's exactly the same as far as the features
approach to his we just as the chemicals contained
it's is quite simple now if you want to call six of presentation
we first have to assign each SIFT descriptors to its there are some tree through
centuries of of includes real world
but instead of counting the number of occurrences of each
if you are going to compute the difference between each descriptors on its central to
produce a set of n
victor of differences which are does concentrate so for each simtree we have sort victor
of differences in some cases we have no reason
we just have to send
this also to produce a set of character
you have the same dimensionality as SIFT descriptors
on our final presentation is just a concatenation
of victor companies which is a phenomenon
two you might seems that the final dimensionality is much higher than for biographies them
for but if you just because have this kid times dimensionality of the local descriptors
but in practice it is not case because the typical value
four numbers on sixty four
to be compared two millions words about the features approaches to finally we have a
vector which is only a few thousand companies
so for those who are familiar with the picture i see for presentation
know that you can use the same kind of presentation that is for each simtree
we can depict the four times four grid of the energy of the gradient for
each possible orientations of rotation the main difference in this case is that you do
the difference between discrete on the century we might have some negative values these are
presented here in this case against blue for positive and you cannot is that forces
these two images which are quite similar we obtain comparable of presentation and activities because
lecture in a completely different way
there is no algorithm to decide in advance whether computer program will halt not you
know no general algorithm which will work in all possible cases and he proved this
using that method
from set theory cantor's diagonal method
this is this is
slight somewhat hidden but it's very inter in nineteen thirty six
the wonderful page
what i wanna do is
so you know that there is no general method there's is something fundamentally
example is the difficulty in trying to decide whether individual programmes will hold for now
if they hold there is no problem in deciding in discovering that because in because
in theory does run the program and if you're patient eventually you'll see that holds
the holds but in patient could be a billion years or ten to the ten
to the ten years
but in principle if you want to prove the problem hotel you have to do
is run it
and wait until it the real problems
the tree discovered the fundamental problem that he chose is beyond the power of computational
mathematics and also be on the power of formal axiomatic theory
it is to show that program never holds
to be able to do this in every possible case
that is really a fundamentally
impossible things
so the question is looking at individual programmes and trying to decide whether or not
they hold and the most interesting thing is to is to be able to show
in in in general the program cannot hold
a string points out you know he shows that there is no algorithm to decide
in general whether program holton
but he immediately deduces incompetent of the core area in his nineteen thirty six paper
and the argument he makes is an argument that i give you this earlier in
the first lecture
the basic idea is that has is if you have a formal axiomatic theory you
can in principle mechanically generate all the theorems
so if you had a formal axiomatic theory they're always enable you to prove whether
an individual program
also fails to hold
that's impossible because by running through all possible proves mechanically
you could either we do that until you find the proof of the program also
you find proof never holds so if you had if for
mathematical theory that always enable you to show individual cases whether program alternating that will
in fact give you an algorithm for always mechanically deciding whether problem tonight and he
showed using kind of diagonal argument that that's impossible
so he
in nineteen thirty six to during the views of correlated from his
uncomputability results in computers
and i don't know this in my metamap but by the way
that's a technical non-technical book it's it's a high level
o two will go is as shown on the front say it's it's the highest
it's an attempt to explain these ideas higher level and the journalist would explain it's
actually a serious math book
disguised as a popular science book
and i don't know why the publisher published it
they insisted on publishing this book for a general audience
OK so
so what is the halting probability omega instead of looking at individual programs i want
to look at the ensemble of all possible computer programs
and the idea is that you take back you close your eyes you take about
you throw it all possible computer programs is an infinite set and these have to
be self-limiting computer programs
OK not ordinary computer programs this only works in the nineteen seventies version
of this theory not in the nineteen sixties version so you close your eyes you
shake the
back will then you pick out one you ask what is the probability this program
and that to find the whole thing probability now
this only works because let me let me write it down it's defined like this
so you fix the computer programming language
and has to be self-limiting
basically every car cable program also contributes one over to the kind of the halting
this is
this is the now with the old theory
with the normal notion of the computer program where there are two the NMB programs
this sum diverges to infinity
this is not well defined
to get this to be meaningful
you need to have solved many computer programs and then this will be between zero
and one like
like any good probability
you know one would be all programs all there would be no program salt and
some do and some don't
yes it is
it's version
no programs are my code
this is for those of you who know of shannon information theory and coding theory
these are this is this is a version of kraft's inequality it's a kind of
an infinite version of kraft inequality no i agree
this is prefix free set
instantaneous code the set of all programs has to be instantaneous to prefix three
yeah this that's why
that's why this is between this is between zero and one
now about five thousand nodes are connected directly to the nucleus
and the class
is connected to
i don't know which you could also the fact that features but this is the
part of the network but what is important is not actually very important for
for in the sense that if you remove this notice for example the distance between
any of between the and with depends almost doubles
so this close is very important for the network and you can learn many many
important properties on the network for using this is a statistical physics support which called
conditional decomposition
so in other networks in economic network from become notable for example similar phenomena that
can better understand what is the the close what is the case in the economic
system and this is important so this is another example of networks and show that
there is an example which is related to climate which was just publishing two papers
one in physical review letters and running europhysics letters
so what we do is we do the following will come to get him
and what we know that there is a factor in effect which is actually considered
as the temperature increases in during the
this is the between a a nineteen eighty in two thousand five
and you can see the temperature increases dramatically which is majority in the pacific ocean
in this range and the temperature increases above a certain value
so for sure because it in effect so you can see the new comes you
and you comes in very seriously in another effect and very important for climate i
mean it's a economics also and we want to know but to understand you know
what we do we set
it can be into four separate networks
this is one of which included another notable means the exact positions
and the network in the US and another the cells and what we did is
network which is the similarity of the cost the combination of this one is that
we need some elements of between places in the network
and in the same for each one of the networks and we measured
the number of links that exist
in the network during the time
in the ordered which includes also in time
and what you find that the it links actually many links disappear go down to
see exactly the appears is this is number one and jimmy and you see when
you get to the number of links that exist in the network
and suddenly the neocons then there is a big dramatic change in the number of
links again you know the number of links that goes down the number of links
this is one but what is surprising is that that not only the network can
this can identify individuals we know that the reason you actually this is the measurement
average temperature in the ontology and once it's already in use it much better
when we measure only locally but this is measuring but not on this energy we
see that in fact which is not believed to be also affect other places this
see it also in this achievement in this in is and you can see this
picture this number two number two a think is this one
and number two you seem the in number three and number four and not the
i don't see the temperature to reduce it is average temperature but generally you but
when you look at the talk
you can see the temperature affects the you consider
measuring the temperatures
and making the temperature you see the links disappeared in
in different places around the world which are not in the original film new and
this is an house in how to five kilometres if you want to go and
you get the results the patrol fluctuations in the density of most effective and you
but effectively and you can see in the network what does it mean
which is in
the not all the interaction between the nodes may be more important than the notes
themselves which makes it makes sense so i wanted to look at interaction and to
see whether we can learn about a new so and they actually would be
well since it is much more sensitive than the temperature we believe maybe it will
be useful in the future we don't have yet to sort out to to endorsing
the phenomenon that even before the effect and only a few days before this would
be a prediction and it will be very important not only these we see also
the link breaks and what we see in the blink surely this is the a
typical links and you can see
this is the actual this type of links
this is one of the things that the this is the cross correlation between the
and you can see that the link is a coarse correlated in the center some
links are not in the centre of the time delay
this is the time lag to cross correlation time so they have an effect after
on the twenty days
the maximum easier as the true course correlation which may
represent meaning that using the word and look at the links which a very different
you can see that the doing that such patterns but the link appears and disappears
appear disappear and measure this you can see again exactly this so the patterns we
look for patterns of plus minus plus appear disappeared
and measure the particles you can see also that these patterns the exactly the appearance
so we need to understand the disappear but we can see that they not completely
disappeared but they appear and disappear during the mean it's
so i think i'm you i was already almost time let me only summarize the
aggression and gives some some challenges
so my talk is wasn't feeling and applications so some utility companies and i didn't
give it full network and
four distances for example
this is my time is longer and this is the famous from result look into
small this executive separation but
what wasn't known is that misty and this was using percolation using celia for physics
one can find that if you take the most vulnerable
any another kind of graph it becomes much longer it becomes all the into the
ones so this is relatively new is that only three with four years of networks
was studied classical metal was studied fifty years almost and another
the result is that logan is the distance when your scale free
and this little again becomes low again for scale free when you can look at
the minimum spanning which means you look and optimize on the
the minimum of the optimal but surely replications of network studies in understanding but also
similar systems
for for the network and metabolic networks and other biological network gene
interaction networks social we've confined uses social behaviors which could not be found those you
need a lot of statistical analysis showing recent searches so that you can find uses
in their social networks social systems predicting
epidemic spreading using elements maybe will be a future to to prevent epidemics maybe
eventually can improve transport in weighted networks of size and
but let's
say well let me draw just a little bit so here is the horizontal let's
introduce a coordinate system in was there's a horizontal and here is the best to
indicate where I am with respect to the picture
so here boat
here the
and the path of the boat is going to make a 45 degree angle with
so this is the path
that we're talking about
and now let's label what I know
well this angle is
45 degrees
this angle I don't know but of course I can calculated easily enough because it
it has to do with
if I know the coordinates of this point x y
and of course that horizontal angle I know the slope of this line and that's
the ad that I will be related to the cell so it's called itself
and now
what I want to know is
but the slope of the whole
have so why prime so let's call y equals y of x the unknown function
whose path whose paragraph is going to be the of boats
unknown graphs
what's it's so well it's slope is the tangent of the sum of these 2
angles alpha plus 45 degrees
now what why not well I know that the tangent of alpha is how much
that's why over x in other words if this is the point x over y
this is the angle it makes with the horizontal if you think of it over
here this
also this angle is the same as that 1 and Y over its slope is
of the line is white X so the tangent to the angle is Y over
X about the tangent of 45 degrees that's 1
and then there's a formula others the hard part or all of the knows of
formula exists and then you look it up if you've forgotten it by relating the
tangent giving you the tensions somewhat 2 angles and the you can if you like
clever derived from the formula for the sign of and cosine of some 2 angles
but 1 peak is worth a thousand finesses so it is
the tangent of alpha
what's the tangent of 45 degrees so we write out also tails divided by 1
so you'll released when the formula 1 minus tangent alpha times 45 degrees this would
work for the tangent to the sum of any 2 angles that's a formula so
how does that I get that why prime is equal to
the tangent of alpha which is why over x always like that combination task 1
divided by
1 minus Y over X times 1
now there's no reason for doing anything to it but let's make a little little
prettier and thereby make it less obvious is a homogeneous equation by it's by multiply
top and bottom by x it looks pretty
X plus Y over X minus Y equals y prime that's a differential equations
but notice that last step to make it look pretty has on the on the
good work is fine if you immediately recognise this as being a homogeneous equation because
you can divide top and bottom by xxx but here it's a lot clearer that
that's a homogeneous equation because it's already been written in the right form
OK let's now since we know what to do without the use of the new
variables equals Y over X and as I wrote up there z
for why prime will substitute z prime X was
and without let's
but solving the equation becomes z primed X plus z is equal to
z + 1 over 1 minus Z.
what is the only other we want separated variables so you have to put all
disease on 1 side and so this is going to be x d z dx
he calls this thing minus z
locality in the following sense
that if x i and x j look close to each other in the high
dimensional space
the image is why i and y j should be close to each other in
the low dimensional space
in other words we're looking for this map
because that will actually get to that locality preservation
preservation but
this particular
notion of it
small maps are going to be given by the actions of the classes
what do you want to do is you want to minimize
particular quadratic forms
so notice that
w i g
is large
if x i and x j are close to each other
when w ij is large XII next year's clo are close to each other and
this forces why i and y j to be close to each other in that
if w i j is smaller
that means i next year were not necessarily closely that each other
then we don't care what why and YGR
we only want to ensure that if points were close to each other
in the high dimensional space
they continued to remain close to each other in the low dimensional space
so this is
hi argument
here here's the fundamental identity
this is a few lines of linear algebra which
so you are encouraged to skip
we are trying to prove yourself but basically that quadratic form which i just wrote
down why i minus white squares WHA ends up being just the same quadratic form
is why transpose and why so minimizing that
it is equivalent to taking the i can vectors
and that's how the eigenvectors of the laplacian
show up
give you a picture first
before i will tell you a little bit about what this might correspond to on
the underlying manifold
OK the picture is this
remember the picture of vertical bars and horizontal bars
OK so we have the set of all
pictures of vertical bars on the the set of all pictures of horizontal bars and
every picture of the vertical bars of point in high dimensional space and every picture
of of horizontal bars of point in high dimensional space and so suppose i give
you all these points
OK i give you a whole
a bunch of points
some of those correspond to pictures of vertical bars and some of them correspond to
pictures of horizontal bars in
you don't know which is which is have a collection of points in high dimensional space
and the only thing you know how to do is PCA
and you apply PCA
the picture on the right
is the picture that he was c
the reason you see the picture is as we just discussed
the pick the set of all
images of vertical bars
i'm not a linear space the set of all images of horizontal bars are not
a linear space in fact they are
two-dimensional manifolds
in the high high dimensional space
and so trying to linearly fit something through it leads to disaster
on the other hand if you applied plants and i can map stewart
the picture in the middle is the picture that he was c
you see two connected components in your data
that you pick out
and one connected component consists of all the blue curves
and the other connected component blue dots in the other connected component consists of all
the red dots red is not working on this particular version
sort of finally get right so we
we are considering these against six different features you know now we basically just go
through it and we collect all the features of these con features that happen to
be binary here because we don't have multiple
events in the same sequence so basically you know
x come field x come alive will have you know
feature two three four and six active so we'll basically get this binary vector to
represent that these are our first six features
why prime has nothing active so it just be the zero vector
why double prime you know has these three features act and the other three is
not and the triple primarily has this first
OK and and then basically
just to give you a second example so you don't have only one example
this one is useful
all of these things cheaply or
the goal of is all of which is land use during
i mean
so you should probably
yeah definitely they they are talk right that's why why said right imagine that if
you think is over over lunch break right coming up with these features so i
think we need usually we need to distinguish i would say the features that just
deal with the output part
right and correlations there
usually you might have
we might have a domain knowledge that really tells you write what type of dependencies
you want to capture what types of things to look for
if we look at the input side right and how that correlates with with the
outputs right so for instance which words are likely to occur within a particular segment
right you could just take all possible worlds right that's why i said it could
be like templates and then indeed you might need to use them
feature induction of feature selection methods try it depending on how you actually training tried
to basically prune back and limited to
a smaller number of features but basically that
so so here you know this is not the way
as i said right you're not actually going through feature one by one so for
instance you know exactly hand picking system and systems and so on and so forth
right that's why i said this thing of the template right template that does that
template would be a word occurring in the name of the three ties
right this could be a template and maybe this for all words or maybe only
four words that in your training data are frequent enough to actually show up there
right so this would be a lot of pruning and
a word occurring at the end of of of of the company name the tried
the template might be that indeed
you might want to have features that not just tell you in the name by
the density and are at the beginning right because this can be important so so
in that sense the template i think is designed manually and then use
automatic techniques to prune it printed
or in the example here
so this is a
this is for the passing case
right where
you can basically just take
the problem the context free grammar
with the rules that are given to you
right and just
directly translate that into a feature representation and then we want to do here is
just you basically look at
right so we need to
we are given an x and we
some y and we want to know what is the corresponding feature representation
so what we could do is basically look at the number of times we've applied
to certain productions so we've done as two NP VP
so this would get a kind of one industry
we would have a production rule let's say that says we would just over-priced that
didn't apply so that the world is our production process that we're nounphrase
goes becomes on
OK so we see this here and here so we have twice
and we have a verb phrase moving to the verb and the verb phrase so
we see this one here and so on and so forth right so this is
all the part that have to do with the production part against these are things
that are independent of the important right they model
like which types of trees are likely which types of productions like and then when
you come to the level of where you actually
go to the terminals
here right the actual words that been with the representation becomes lexicalized phrase and probably
much more dimensional because now you actually need to know
right something like
you know the probability to go from an on and replace it by some actual
words like boeing right or have of seattle and so on and so forth right
so you also can include here but again you can imagine that this is a
a very high dimensional representation that you're getting their right
the main idea
so we know what this
that is because these in my graph
right so we will see later
how that how the
it comes in
so here
the the feature representation in principle you could just doing anything right it doesn't matter
i mean but it makes sense or not right i guess here
just the branching it just needs to work out such that you have a certain
number of non terminals in the end that is really the length of the sentence
that you're looking at right
and and above is just you just need to apply the rules right but you
could you could you know located you might think is an on and it was
generated from an phrase or something like
so maybe not grammatically all of this of course is nonsensical but that's what you
want to look right what is
grammatical and what is not so so basically and if you allow right that
basically every
every word can really be you know if you if you have rules
we actually on the right-hand side here for the for the actual words right you
don't constrain it
then basically
you know if you have prior knowledge of course that you know that located is
you see that comes out is assigned sensitive
minus and pluses mind so i can do negative work
if the two don't have the same polarity
i want you to convince yourself
if i didn't come along the straight line from all the way from infinity
but i came in a very crooked way
finally ended up at point p
that point
that the amount of work that i have to do is exactly the same
you've seen the parallel with a one where we dealt with gravity
gravity is a conservative force
and when you do with conservative forces the work that has to be done in
going from one point to the other is independent of the path
that is the definition of conservative forces
electric force forces also conservative
so it doesn't make any difference
when i come
along the straight line
to this point whether i do that in an extremely crooked way
and and finally
and up here
that's the same amount of work
now if we do have a collection
of charges
so we have pluses and minuses charges
pluses and minuses classes minus classes pluses
you now
can calculate the amount of work
but i will tell you would have to do
in assembling that you bring one from infinity to you not to one another one
you add up all that work some work maybe positive some work may be negative
you arrive at the total amount of work
but you have to do
to assemble
these charges and that is the meaning
of capital
now i turn to
electric potential
and for that
i start off here
with a charge which i now call us
capital q
located here
at position p
edit distance
are way
i place
best charts
plus q
make it positive for now you can change it later
coming negative and so the
electrostatic potential energy we we know already we just calculated that would be q
times q
divided by four pi
actually non-zero
that's exactly the same way that we have
so we
electric potential electrostatic potential energy
is the work that i have to do
bring this charge here
now i'm going to introduce
electric potential
o council
and that is
the work per unit charge
but i have to do
to go from infinity
so that
so q doesn't enter into it anymore
it is the work
you know charge
to go from infinity
to let location
and so it is the work unit charge
is little q
this appears
so now we write down the at that location p
potential electric potential that location
is known need q
divided by four
epsilon zero i
the q has disappeared
it is also is scalar
as you know jewels
the unit here
is joules per coulomb i've divided out among charge
it worked for unit charge
no one would ever called these jewels
recall one call these vaults called after the grateful that with a lot of research
on this
we call this fault
but it's the same
as jules
if we have a very simple situation like we have here is that we only
have one charge
and this
is the potential
any distance you want from this charts
if i
goes up you further away
the potential
will become lower
this q is positive
the potential is everywhere in space
four singles chart
if this q is negative
everywhere in space the potential is negative
electoral elected static potential can be negative
the work that i do
the unit charge coming from infinity
the negative if that's the negative charge and
the potential
when i'm infinitely far away
but his arm becomes infinitely large
that's the way
we define our zero
so you can have positive potentials positive charge negative potentials and the negative charge
and if you very very far away
potential is zero
that's not true into our vendor graph
it's almost sphere
israelis are
about thirty centimetres
and i'm going to put on here
plus ten microkernel
it will distribute itself uniformly we will discuss the next time in detail
because it's a conductor
we already discussed last lecture that the electric field inside the sphere is zero
and that the electric field outside is not zero but we can think of all
the charges being at this point here
last stand
michael was all year as long as we want to know what electric field outside
so you can forget the fact that it is a sphere
so now i want to know
what the
electric potential is
at any point in space want know of this here
and i want to know what it is here
o point p
which is now distance are
when when you like
thousand different what the first
then you would need to compute for every test data point d compute housing can
and the newspapers
and i'm mainly talking about other people this competition
the main idea is that exploit the ten y of x five
OK and if he have a linear combination of higher taxes which are very high
dimensional and hide the linear combination is also going to be
OK so it's a linear combination of part back this again going to be sparse
if you not combining make
and that we approach is one things that i'm going to explain this
and also i think we try to every
OK so
maybe some general
so we
i assume that this
five x is very long
but the only thing which we need is
some operations which
x certain elements in the
we need some lookup operations
the base
may be very well so despite x is indexed by a certain substring so for
instance we have one element in this fire x for every subset what became
we can use it became a kind of address into the feature space
OK so now we have to do operations in the feature space
point you would like to change one element of the vector in feature space
so if you know there are only a few i mean very few non zero
element and we would like to modify these fuel elements and the idea is that
the only store elements which are nonzero
so we use
three ar what only the number of elements
and what we need to look at single element or to add something to an
twenty two operations between
it's very very efficient
OK two operations so
we have substring you would like to support
like the value
and you can use either stored or we can retrieve so and we've only
one great suffering we just need to store like where every substring
the way i mean it's almost
so the important point is that we can using these operations we can precompute lighting
linear combination of these i o x i so given a set of training examples
can put it the community
it just needed a perspective drawing the vector
and if we you have that can be computed in your community
this operation is to look at all substrings
the six x
and sum up all the elements in b
it would have been
and we take
we've looked into the back of the year
in that moment c
but this is something
if is a non-zero value
so this
so now the question is how can we do these two operations
look up and the adding operations
i don't have any suggestions
explicit maps you can just take like all the pain that you just have map
which is as big as the number of him
so it
sigma small k k is small
then this is feasible to have this much memory allocated
you're fairly neutral about them
ten u love them dearly
and when you plot these two against each other you get this negative relationship which
is extremely robust every single dataset we have we pick the same relationship of those
who love me still you see most of them
but if you're gonna look eyeball those data there's a sense that which
perhaps there are layers
and indeed when we
did some
serious cranking on these data
that's what we were able to show so these this is a really using the massive fractals
to look for a recurring patterns in the data
on the left is are
ethnographic social
groupings database census data based on the right down here is all
christmas card database
and the key
the issue is is that the peak here
that's the the fractal parameter the rest the harmonics and they're kind of interesting in some sense
but really just harmonics about
the position and those
the fact chromosome both these datasets in exactly the same place is almost exactly three
well that's telling you this is a recurring pattern
in the scaling ratio three
in these datasets and this is picked up the latest study by somebody else
question that it looked at and hunter-gatherer database
looking at the structural groupings and then they used an alternative
much simpler we had some astrophysicist to the masses so that
i think the most complicated way
actually do it
they was jumping anthropologists actually markets hamilton i think that the santa fe institute now
they is taught in order analysis which is very simple because it just simple graphical
techniques as the slope on the line
there is they
scaling ratio they came up with the scale ratio is about three point eight
but in fact they only get three point eight because they included individual
as a group so one
on the left hand side is the first warden order
if you exclude at
and just start the true group if you like which for them as a family
what having will be individual on the left-hand side sister paula slowed down
if you ignore the slight tilt slightly negative slope almost exactly three point two after this as well
there we've yet to tell
they're sold on the idea that the scaling which is actually four
but it's not and we pick up the same scalar ratio in species battles that
have multilevel social systems as well so it's quite universal
but what it means for use that's what your social world looks like they the
centre again you're surrounded by a series a sort of layers so ripples on the
pond if you like
all relationships are different quality as you go out through these layers
the number people included
increases but the quality
emotional intensity relationship declines issue these lattices inclusive right the fifteen increases
o five fifty include fifteen so
we know they go right out fifteen hundred it goes beyond a hundred and fifty we can pick the signature
as far out as a hundred and fifty
fifteen hundred very but there's a big difference between
the people inside a hundred and fifty people outside people inside and fifty people have
real relationships with have relationships which have a history
relationships have obligation and trust and reciprocity
outside a hundred and fifty there essentially quite acquaintances
so you're most acquaintances probably in this out a five hundred let the fifteen hundred layers for people you know
but they don't know who u so i guess
the most diverse president obama said about here
i mean if you lost him
drop round arabia
on saturday night
first all he would look surprised second level
very large gentleman with bold gender here
but come and talk to you
so are people out there that we know by site that appears to be
the limit on the number people's faces that we can recognise that we can faces
closest to this
line to this model
i ask as well what about these not say OK it's red thing
threats OK
and then
we rebuild the model and we get the lines dividing line
a little bit higher
because it's on one side of the red one the other side was it is
the ones which are not we know about
again the machine selects
the question which is
close to the small planets
can read
and then
questions here
and would say so that there was one one so still and we have aligned
their on one side of the red one stands on the site only once and
so if they continue
so this continuous after twenty questions
hundreds so
one is one hundred questions and roughly the line but it was impossible somehow tool
tool of
distinguish of to me to build the straight line which would divide rule from red
ones but still blind more less converge here and now we have a model
say well everything what's on this site is most probably rats
of red color and everything was on this site is probably look all around
this is the
finally the final result
this is roughly the idea of what this active learning cycle thus
and so this is kind of that you can imagine instead of this maybe thousands
o point because a hundred thousand points and
maybe not just two dimensions hundred thousand dimensions and this is the process which can
save you a lot of money are is a lot of resources
when you're trying to take for label are
the query documents in whatever way
i have one more demo forgot to show it before which i think it's
also quite a good demonstration of
what learning does
before i mentioned is support vector machines and also for support vector machines
probably the most popular machine learning methods today because it has
and so it's so it's quite effective when it's
it is very hard to beat it
so this is the them all of
and how this method works
scenario the following again here we operate in two dimensions normally operate in
thousand or ten thousand or even more
but again algorithm is the same the whole situation is the same so this scenario
is the following so here we have
and so we have minds
and now we would like to
with the model
in this case the model is just a straight line
we see lights
this red ones from the ones
i think so in this case this was pretty easy because
we separate the them
now its inputs
a few more minor like this now and say well
right now it still this was pretty but let's see if we are evil
now we got confused already
what happened now
OK computer was really a lot i mean i know it's already confused because the
language is simply too
two simple i mean the language to express the model is to see how we
can increase the
power of the language expressivity of the language that will use the polynomial
languages instead of just a straight lines we will use the
well only polynomial curves
and while
this helped to bit
still i mean some
classes are some blue blue ones are on the
on the site where the red should be about small as it was able to
isolate reference from one pretty efficient
they can still be a little bit more
well mean
good job we can support some here
now it's
it's confused
but now we can increase the
the strength of the language in use this gulf kernels kernels are
just the way
how we represent internally the
space of the
possible concepts i wanna go too much into the details just the the
a different kind as we can
we can bring different optics
different optics into this high dimensional space
well this one was pretty good so this is basically a red ones are on
light sites and the
red ones are
and the blue ones are more less the dark side
let's make a a show a little bit more
this is
one typical even example which
obviously linear kernel cannot do much
also not much i think it's just something here
in your mission model based
if you have a partially constructed tree like this
so you have much
this data points into some cluster which those data points into some and also for
as well
what the what the model is saying is that
the data points within each connected component here
his model with a single gossip
so this
and of course the single girls is into is a very simple model probabilistic model
is simply a spherical shape
helen ghahramani zoubin is going to give a talk more but i'm not sure there
this thing but i really like model
what they say is that instead of assuming that each of the constructed subtrees here
is modeled by a single garcia
each other subtrees is in fact the corresponding itself to make sure model
for example this subtree right so has lead a b c and d
it's going to be model with
make sure
in one component all the data points belong to one calcium
and in another component is to data points belong to one goes in and those
two data points belong to one thousand
and then in another component this data point belongs to his own gaussians
the losses on goes
c and d
how much together
so this is what's called tree consistent partitions
and what this is basically
if you take this tree
and you come back
cut the line to this thing
then you get a one of this partitions of the data
we have or want to go into details because it's quite mathematical
but it turns out that the algorithm is
this is very similar
the probability of the data under a subtree
can still be computed recursively is not going to be the same as as before
in fact the probability of a subtree here
it's going to be
the sum of two terms one is the probability of the individual subtrees
multiply together with multiplied by some factor
and the other one the problem is the probability of
all the data points and both
and also this approach can be used to obtain a lower bound on the probability
of the dirichlet process mixture
so this just that
a throwaway statement
what are the pros and cons of probabilistic
hierarchical clustering
it is still in fact very easy and efficient
to implement as small so the algorithms
given to you
so the question is how do you define this problem probability of the much cluster
this is the probability of the individual cost
and you can compute the probability is efficiently
because you can
compute the inner because the fashion as well
it really
is basically the same framework as normal linkage algorithms that they use
to tell you about
in this sense is still
easy to describe this
the output of this algorithms to people because
it has to understand english english
so the probabilistic models are more into interpretable because it's basically gives generative process
and a tree
with high probability is simply
so basically the trees which
the algorithm returns to you
try to maximize the probably the probability of the data
but unfortunately
because this thing has to be probabilistic models
the in fact less flexible than
then distance metrics you can define any distance perfectly u one and u
but in terms of probabilistic models is important that you actually write down the probability
distribution has to sum to one
over all possible
so that gives you constraints
it also deals nicely with partially observed data because
the probability of the of the data
this problem this can be computed even if we don't observe
every entry in the data vector
and there is a coherent measure of goodness of fit for resulting
for the resulting tree
but there still no notion of uncertainty because it's still again
if you if you give it a data set it only returns to one single
tree it doesn't really tell you how much they actually the truth
is the is the true true
the true
just to reiterate what i said in the beginning there this in fact to these
ways in which you could believe
the at the
the there is in fact two distinct ways in which you could believe
the data is
generated because there's two possible generative processes for data
the first one is that we believe that the the data comes from
groups of sources so this is the mixture modeling approach
where you are in fact believe that the data points is heterogeneous has comes from
multiple groups within each group it's very simply doesn't have any internal structure analysis
one colour symbolism
and in this up in this approach we simply use hierarchical clustering as an efficient
so chris search procedure
to find a good way of
partitioning of the a into different groups
different sources
the other belief is that we might believe that the data in fact has an
underlying tree structure
so this is the case for example in in front of genetics
and i linguistics as well
so in this case
we want to use hierarchical clustering to in fact find the tree
the following algorithms out a about
so the previous algorithm which after about all
as the underlying model a mixture model so it in fact
corresponds to that particular to that belief
well the two algorithms which i tell you about
not too against the
one framework which i tell you what next
in fact
it follows the second
a set of beliefs that we believe that there is an underlying tree
and we want to find an underlying tree
we do believe that
OK so these
after the
no i meant specific point from the mouth time and that's the say that now
it's actually all on that problem he is given that each of those methods
supplement what does it mean that fact that it's going to some extent also practical
this is it possible
one the problem still had
low additional cost
perhaps so you could say that it is something which is one of the officials
but there is
the important point that
and you
what what the accuracy is that it is influenced by many many more
but there's sense of your
it's not feasible sets c
you may
one of the objective or
first part of the brain
in polynomial time and that's all those twenty is at
the company but there
that was the you
for much of the USL me my
functional level one or both of the policy
four methods
a lot but none of them so the
a most of the laws of the state of the art
that the actual accuracy while whatever located in percent of the optimal way
they are five percent of the optimal some of these
when you look like property will be made available on the same side of
it was a lot of course
the normalisation
is a normalisation of the show absolute purity right
the addition of europe for the
and was about you know absolute accuracy
it is look for is like the parliament classical optimal itself with the one you
the minus one but when you
normalized by the world looking for the normalized by the size of the department of
the size of the additional that continued world
for each u i mean when
doesn't actually want
the what the problem is going to be able to
and we'll see
OK so i put some
the first of those
so the goal
but there is a course for
methods in the first is that the
the question of what they sold by that point out the
problem when decision variables it was the
the idea was the first thing that came up with the u
the design dimension
unless you're being the past
one of
now the last thing you get
code problems with this is why
and that appointment book holding up
as of thousands of variables some you know
you know
variables and constraints
but but in typical only upon the province's precedence
the you first use
usually they also the
so that's a problem of the most of the people that lot of
one thousand your system
o uses and in addition is like the form
the this to all the most of the work that comes with all
the practical and a few hundred thousand of them
one the problem of
actually can
forget about
methods of a
but that his
really large scale problems
one of the last is
a cheap method
most of that
is it proper
there's an emotion
and what is the name of our lord the this it is the sum of
all of what one of the oldest
that is not good enough
and there could be
that what
and this he
but in one
but the
that at all
and if you are interested in more small organisation
OK not allow the
but i don't think this is you were a kid let's let's see what happens
the what's the matter so much of this state
but if you
i think in objective as a whole
or you thousand
but i will hold
subsequent formal constant musicians
the present level of well let's see what you end up with the model is
the only of some of the idea
what can you say about those workers from a convenience about you that you are
interested to minimize
convex function f of x all over on this one but still in that i
but this one
i love this one as it is the one as the maximum the was sponsored
of by
but the political
OK so and the builders assumed that this function is convex access
able to introduce
background dataset
in the first setting
for example we can use the random graph generators to generate a set of random
graphs and then use them as background dataset
so in the first that is the problem becomes
can we find some significant graph patterns
in this datasets such that it is seldom appear
in the random graph datasets
so this is just show you multiple graph setting scenario in graph data mining
i'm showing real applications so we have a single graph mining problems but today i
will focus on the multiple graph mining scenario because the much easier to to
to present
so when we talk about graph patterns the first question is what kind of
patterns might be interesting to our users
certainly the definition of interestingness is related to specific application scenarios
however there do exist general
definitions which is meaningful to many applications
here is an example frequent graph patterns
frequent graph patterns are those common sub-structures existing in a set of
of graphs
suppose we have a collection of active chemical compounds that are active to HIV
then frequent graph pattern mining can help us to find those
common sub-structures existing in these chemical compounds
certainly the discovery of such substructures will be very useful to drug design
we if we replace
the chemical compound dataset
with a program
sytem call graphs
the same concept can be applied
but for the discovery of full
routine system call behaviors
this routine system call behavior is actually can be used
to detector system anomalies or intrusions
frequent graph pattern mining can be applied to gene coexpression networks
for example to find those frequent dense graphs existing these genes
coexpression networks
these dense graphs can be taken as
function function modules
and actually we can use this problem
we can use the function modules to predict the functionality of unknown genes
by the functionality of known genes in the same modules
so you can see that for very simple
concept - frequent graph mining it actually can find a lot of interesting problems
besides the frequency as this criteria
actually we can come up with other
interesting criteria which is actually popularly used in the data mining and machine learning society
for example information gain suppose we are given two sets of graphs we would
like to find sub-graphs which
has the highest information gain for example fisher score
for example a significance test like a g-test score
so let me first introduced the very basic now for mining path frequent pattern mining
and later i will show you a direct connection between frequent graph pattern
and other graph patterns with respect to
user specified specified objective functions
so here is the definition of frequent graph patterns
the definition very simple suppose we are given a graph dataset D
and a user specify the threshold as theta that we would like to find
all of the subgraphs in our graph dataset with frequency greater than this
user specified threshold theta so here the frequency is defined as
the percentage of graphs in this dataset that contain
this subgraph g
so the concept like this very simple
so here is an example about frequent subgraph patterns
suppose we have three chemical compounds like these
and if we set to the minimum
frequency threshold for example fifty percent
so in this graph actually is frequent subgraph
because this graph appears at least
in this two chemical compounds
here is another example
we have three program call graphs extracted from program traces
each node represents function
if function a calls function b
then we will
build a directed edge between function and the function b so we can collect a lot
of system call graphs for
each programme run
and if we set the minimum threshold again for example at fifty percent
it by careful examination we find that both
these two
of program call symbol graphs actually frequent graph patterns
most of them appear in at least three two of these
programme call graphs
so you can see that frequent pattern actually is very relative concept it is related
to the
frequencies threshold setting later i will show you actually it is a bigger problem
so far i would like to present
some basic graph pattern mining algorithms which had been proposed in the past several years
so researchers have proposed many patterns
mining and especially frequent the while pattern mining algorithms
for example we can use inductive logic programming to represent graphs as datalog facts
and the using the logic logical programme method to generate those frequent graph patterns however
the process would be very slow
and the most of the existing graph pattern mining algorithms actually can be put into
the second category graph theory based approach
basically they use different
heuristics and come upon our method to generate to frequent graph patterns
so again in this category we can
divide this method into
one is apriori based approach the second is the pattern based pattern growth approach
i'm not going to show you the details of these algorithms one by one but
later i would just to show you is a high-level design principles
behind these algorithms
all of this algorithms actually show
a very basic rule being frequent pattern mining it is called apriori
property i think most of you probably already know this
so if a graph is frequent as in
all of its subgraphs will be frequent
this is a nice properties that means
basically you can enumerate this graph patterns from small size to large size
during the enumeration you can check their frequency
whenever you find out graph pattern that is not frequent
any more
then need not to extend
this graph part anymore because it's unlikely it's super graph will be frequent if it itself is
not frequent so here is the basic enumeration pipeline to generate these graph patterns
so start with a small graph pattern for example k edge graph pattern
we can generate k plus edge graph pattern candidates
diffusion losses you should also be assured of divergences because you can learn a lot
about loss functions by looking after
and vice versa
so one direction and this is it it is very easy in the other direction
is the core of our paper several pages of proofs of a little little challenge
that is the last theorem in this section of the talk and so i will
tell you how you prove it and so on but let's just assume it's true
alright analysis read as some easy consequences of that OK
so i suppose we start with zero one loss here we mapped over we expanded
we map back and now we get a whole bundle of loss functions there they're
all universal equivalent biosphere to zero one loss
i what me well that's good other loss functions andrew any probability distribution which all
the quantizer is the same as zero one loss ranks all zero one loss is
our goal here that's the overall loss function we're trying to optimize ranking the same
zero one loss consistent doing the right thing
but this is an if and only if there
which is which also says that you're not consistent zero one loss sorry if you're
not equivalent to zero one loss outside here another loss sitting out there
right that means you're not universally equivalent to zero one loss that means there exist
some problems which you get a different answer than zero one loss
which has been shown not consistent
there might be some problems which is that which give the right same answer
but that's not good enough for us we're trying to do general theorem which is
that you the same in general
OK so this reduces to a very simple problem now
loss functions are universal equivalent to to zero one loss
right that's easy because we know how do we go out after version space zero
one loss leads to variational distance
expand variational distance and you come back and you get a whole class of loss
in particular you get the hinge loss is one of them
plus you have to consider one so hinge loss i the support vector machine
leads to consistency you can join you can use the support vector machine formalism and
jointly optimize with respect to the to the discriminant which is what's usually done the
support vector machine and a quantizer
and he then had all the same kind of correctly then that will be that
will give the right answer
boosting is not
right boosting leads to another f divergence which is not the family
so if use the exponential loss behind boosting
then you're not equivalent you're not consistent
OK you can use that function or both of them in general
you there might be special cases which will work but not injured
OK so that's an interesting character a you know boosting SVM all these different losses
in this flat classification are all consistent
they lead to that's where the earlier we talked about it but when we don't
want is harder problem doing experiments line and the in the quanta and the classification
of some of the more and some more
yeah absolutely this function is also universal equivalent to zero one loss
and the square loss if you take the one that comes down and is
a flat after that is also
and i don't i don't have a kind of a list of all the others
it sort of effective beginning when i was never really done that kind of looking
at the others
at this point
i don't think it is actually
i have set down and work that out
we just got it's easy to work out you just
calculate the f you see if you can get it right here is that i
find related to the
i think is
OK so that's that story
so next sort of
application this that's one application is to consistency results and you can use this for
the kind of problems now that was for quantization from line we can also use
it for feature selection as another kind of experiment design problem how to find feature
selection stage together with a quanta with classifier discriminant but they jointly estimated together give
you consistency so you can use this for has been done but that's not something
that would be fun to do
here's another class of applications of this which has a with the estimation of divergences
you know think the kullback leibler divergence we managed to estimate the kullback leibler leiber
divergence from data
why would you want to do that well what's the reason sometimes we want to
optimize KL divergence is so you might be trying to build estimate if you expect
to you optimise it
special case killer is the entropy
well i interested in estimating interview from data
so there is for example the KL divergence somehow however how might we estimate that
from data well killer is based on two measures
p and q
so can get you have to assume you can get data from both p and
and then you know how in some sense will plug it into this formula get
some kind of an estimator
the problem here is that if you look at the key part you've got both
and log appearing together in the formula
and so if you think about things like kernel density estimation you have to develop
into a good bandwidth for estimating p part but also the log p and those
are incommensurate things to do
meaning that so this is supposed to be the arrow the cost
of respect to the parameter space on on the plane
meaning that you have directions where the
second derivatives of the cost are very large and directions where
the second derivative the costs of small and you know
this says slowing down training and so on
but in recurrent nets actually you might see things like this this
is actually the case with a single neuron with feedback
and you have these ridges so instead of things being these valleys
being symmetric you have very high derivatives on one side but
not this is the high derivatives on the other side
and here we have a nice slope going down in this direction you
actually would like to go down in this direction the problem as
you do that you approach this region which is close to probably
a boundary of basic attraction thought
this is in parameter space so it makes it makes it possible to
approach those boundaries that have very large gradients and near
those boundaries gradient become huge and kikuyu often you
throw off the learning so by simply scaling gradient or sometimes
just ignoring it and doing random move
you you just you know goal not too far away then continue and that
really the sole lot of these problems doesn't solve the
the long term dependencies problem
solve the problem coming from the large gradients so this is called
the gradient clipping is very very efficient
and you should all have in your encode right
so now i'm going tell you about approaches to try to deal with
this problem of long-term dependencies so in
in than ninety three paper that we wrote
about the long-term dependencies
so this was an early version of the joint paper ninety four
we a we proposed something that has the flavor of lstm is
is not the same thing but the idea was that
again we have this memory cell that at each state gets updated by
just copying itself and and we have some kind of decision that
gates that this that you know whether we copy
or all we don't and and we use some kind of heuristic to decide
how to provide a gradients but this idea that you should have this
kind of self-loop to keep information for a long time
was there was also a in ninety one in push writers thesis
yeah i actually tell you about lstm right now so
there are different variants of the lstm basically all of them the
central idea is there is this state variable
has a self-loop with itself another words
i call this the call the cell in the lstm
that the news state will be equal to the old state plus some
kind of update and we can control with a gate whether we actually
copy the old state to new state and whether we actually
know have an update coming so so the
the important one is the for the gate here which
which multiplies the self-loop path so it could kill off a self-loop
path and the reason to do that is that some if you didn't have that
any would just keep adding adding in the state would keep growing
and growing and yeah this might prevent you from forgetting things
sometimes you actually want to forget things because you have limited
memory and in the case of lstm there are also extra gates which
control whether we actually add something into the state so there's
the input but there's also gate which multiplies so it can kill off
the thing that will be added and they also have an output gate
which i think is useless but controls whether something is going
to be sent to the outside world and the gr you get a recurrent unit
has a slightly simpler architecture so it's but
it has the same self-loop and it works basically the same as the
cheaper to compute so several papers are using it
this kind of the same principle
so that was ninety seven lstm in ninety five
ninety five we the there's another paper that's missing
should have yeah we proposed in nips ninety five proposed to use
temple hierarchy so this is answering going as a suggestion
that maybe we could use multiple levels of time scales in
order to bypass this problem of having you know the multiplication
by many accordions so f what i mean here is here the bottom have
regualar regular recurrent net but at the next layer have recurrent
net that's updated less often somehow and then another one even
less often so here i double the period and so what happens is that
even though the path through the the the the the fine time scale
recurrent net may just make it impossible to learn long term dependencies
you could learn a long term dependencies
by having gradients propagate through the shorter path that goes
through the slow time scale so this is the general idea
and devil in the detail how do we know define when those upper one
should be updated and so on there you don't even have to have
a discrete updates you could have slowly changing units
higher up rather than you know i update every
ten timesteps i just update by copying miles value a little bit
and adding a little bit of the new value
another idea which came about the same time from
the giles in the top right what you see is you can have recurrent
net we skip connections over time
so again what you're doing is now you create those paths in the
graph which allowed to go sort of faster from the past the future
with less nonlinearities in between
and and that also works
so example of these these are hierarchies in recent work we did