and if you want to have that you have to have a prearranged agreement on
one and two and this is something which is completely missing in XML so there
you have label tree and that's about
this is feasible
if you have a closed collaboration so for example if you have agent with let's
say agents in small and stable community so for example the best example is one
of the ontology editors there was the ontology is also in in an XML based
format and we defined some domain specific vocabulary namely an XML schema for our own
purpose but then this is hard coded into our tool and other tool without having
more knowledge can make use out of that so there's those small and stable community
namely our institute that knows what these domain vocabulary is about so the next step
if you want to go to the web then this of course is not scalable
so there's a small conclusion XML is not machine accessible meaning it's basically to put
some brackets around what you have here
but the
this could be also written in greek letters so it's not understandable for computer what
really standing there
next step what we have now as the basic infrastructure is XML and name spaces
but on top what we had with RDF and RDF schema is not the first
set of ontological primitives where you have a prearranged agreement on so this is the
next step in our hierarchy
so what
do you get out of RDF let's start with RDF well RDF provides so-called metadata
about went sources so what are metadata
a common definition is data about detail so you want to say something about something
else and the RDF community basically has an idea that they want to say anything
about anything other than everything else so there should be no restriction
to achieve that they introduced the so-called attribute value tripled
but basically it has an XML syntax so is serialised in XML
and if you look from from my graphically oriented perspective of the chain triples form
the graph so so let's make an example
for example you have your work that object the attribute telephone or telephone number and
you have the value which is which would be my telephone number so this would
across the graph structure simple graph structure if you have the RDF description
compared to html or XML it would look like this so you have the pre-arranged
ontological ontological vocabulary you say that you have within the name space RDF you have
the description
and you say something
about your work
and what do you say well that the telephone number is about that looks very
similar actually take some and that is due to the fact that it is serialised
in XML
so you can add more triples you can say well
this guy has a home page on this home page has the side which would
and for example i would explain RDF and RDF home page has at the site
on the w three c something which is also quite common in the RDF community
namely that you refer to certain resources by new artists that's why you need the
URI so for example if you want to refer to RDF as the topic you
could use the RDF website from the w three c that as you might know
the difference between your eyes is that the URI as the union unique your resource
identifiers so to be unique and you should address uniquely resources but it's not necessarily
reachable in the in the web and the URL typically is a uniform resource locator
so it's also accessible on the web at the different but you could also use
some websites for example to uniquely identify certain topics like RDF this case
but as you get by RDF schema
well defined the vocabulary for RDF schema basically
and this vocabulary is organised the so-called typed hierarchy so what you have here is
a class you the top class of relationship you can say the type which would
be an instance relationship so it's a little bit confusing because the RDF people have
a slightly different notion of what they call the property we call the relationship of
what they call the class we call the concept but in principle it's the same
so you're property the property of so also within relations you could have some kind
of hierarchy and for a property in relationship that the so-called domain in range with
which would be the start and the ending point of such a relationship so if
you look you are you have
as the relationship of the property has supervised so the domain would be
this class this concept york and the range would be here rudy
so you have your car supervisor be as the chain triples these are the concepts
of classes and this is the property of the relationship
what do you get by RDF schema
so now you can say that you actually
the the type of phd student
then type is similar to the instance of so you would be an instance have
a phd student really on the other hand would be in type for instance of
professor at UC
the property has to provide the has the main phd student and has arranged professor
now in fancy rate the schema by york has supervisor rule
so this is the basic idea plus you have a typed hierarchy so for example
phd students class of person and professors also classes of person
what does it look like an idea but i don't want to bother you too
much with that syntactical stuff but just to give you an impression so for example
you could say that a motor vehicle is the class which would be the first
OK so that's the that's the machinery that let's get
let's get this relationship between the rademacher averages
and the VC dimension
OK the the rest of the expectation microbridge is no more than something like the
square to VC dimension over n
so we could throw that into the results that we saw
last time
in terms of
the the uniform convergence results that i quoted just a moment ago
if we're going to class that has this dimension d then whatever the probability distribution
with high probability
the maximal deviation between
risk and the empirical risk between expectation of the loss incurred by s
and the sample average about thing
OK maximizing overall in the class capital
it's no more than something like scritti over and
load factor
and some small to
right this is like
ah logbn one of adultery
right and then using the same ideas as we saw
at the end of the last lecture
that means that if we minimize the sample average to minimize the empirical risk
then the risk is is
not much bigger than the is is no more than this class
the minimal
OK this is the best in a class
and this is some sort of a complexity penalty
you know additional an additional term that depends on the VC dimension d
three something like square the over
OK and going from uniform convergence to this thing is is very much the same
as we saw last
and i guess i've been a bit more cavalier with constant here
right because
because i get to give away a lot with constant when we go to the
generality of the VC dimension
OK so so we could say something about the behaviour of the empirical risk minimizer
of some class of functions that has a finite VC dimension right its performance it's
risk is no more than the best we could hope for from that class
plus something of order of square the average
OK so already mentioned you can remove this log in factor here
you don't need that but you need more refined argument to
to remove that
and i'm looking
so that the the more refined argument involves
looking at covering numbers
and some results due to two d double e
OK so the the
actual method that can concerned with the learning algorithm here is particularly simple right given
class capital f which is minimizing empirical risk
OK this is not
not very complicated so very general result
and there are lots of approximations made along the way but it turns out that
the rate that we get here is minimax optimal right this this square root
whatever and is the
it is
it is the right the right right in the minimax sense
we'll have a look at that
so he is the of
first of all i guess you can get rid of the log factor and get
a result that's the the
rademacher averages and no more than some constant times the square root
of the VC dimension of and you can refine that even
and say that the
this notation expectations of sigma
means the conditional expectation
right we just integrating out sick sick conditioning on x one through x n
you could get on the rademacher averages
the conditional expectation of these things in terms of the VC dimension of the restrictions
of functions in f
two x one to xn
OK so we're saying something that's somehow incorporate information about the the distribution
in this sort of results o
you could also do that although it's
not so easy to
to get meaningful estimates of
of these things
so now let's look at when i said a moment ago
that you know this is the minimax optimal right what i mean by that how
do we set this up as as you know what's what's appropriate minimax sitting here
we talking about so
let's define the following notion of estimation error we've got
within this subset is very low
we're going to applied
two their boating dataset
and in this case the result is just one
is one of the boats
which is actually the number four
this is the number of
of the attributes
and this is their there
the rank which is number one
it's what is the freezing or or not of these physicians
now that's going to take on another one
you all know how to do this just
click and choose
correlation by entropy or gain in entropy information gain
and now we're going to use the ranking method we just ranks
attributes by
decrease in entropy
increasing information gain
this is not what i in general because it violates every variable alone
in this it does not take interactions
in two
account anyway
if you apply it
this is the wrong
then we just
it is
nice to see that the top
in this list is the same variable as before
but this
completely random i mean it it it shouldn't be the case in general because they
are quite different methods
data visualization
this is a different data set
it's to identify kind of glass by
the elements that are present so the magnitude aluminium
that's it
here we have a lot of classes
as you can see
by that diff by the number of different colors in the picture
it's quite difficult task this is well known in the
in the UCI
this is the full
collection of byproducts by pulitzer plot is a scatterplot of one variable against another viable
so you have a quadratic number of my blocks
you can
have a look of each of them to have the first impression
scrolling down to the right everything
this is the full set of my blood
this anyone know
how to use this
it's a lot of information but if you train your eye
which is what human beings
are good that the train the eyes
well trained and their eyes stood
the train the brain if you prefer but
what can we say about this data set
the different colors and different classes
so you are seeing now for example
i think this one
here you have barrier against
i don't know what this
what you see here
the yellow classes
but if pretty quickly able identifiable by this combi nation
there are no yellow visible here
so you can just
the this
with the linear
classifier quadratic
if it fits better
there are some errors but
if you pick just one
you can so
on it and see the
of the two barrels
and the different classes
in this case is same as
you can't separate anything from these two variables alone
as you can see
not a single class
you can zoom in more to see this mess
this is what we see
same as i mean
it's nothing to do here
so on further explore a quick look at the experiment
i'll just show you
the main we know
neil experiment
we select different datasets from our collection of fires i smoking
and class
the three that we have been using
and we select
three classification methods
decision tree
multilayer perceptron
and the naive bayes
we specify
the number of false in cross validation specify the classification task
ten repetitions
many things here
and run
well this is of course this is separate compiler presentation it takes time
in this case it took
about three hours
we case not to fast software
but this is nice this and the classification error is
we can what damien everything went well that's what you what it says here
you can analyse we're going to split this quickly
for example you can analyse
in kind of
cross table performance mean performance of different datasets the different methods
and you can perform to take these tests
kilometres per second yes that's what it is
conservation of angular momentum
that the product of QP
must be the same as q
times the a that's immediate consequence of the conservation
and you momentum
and when i had this up
let's QP
i better find
two a which in our case
is about
on the thousand kilometres
because able to fifty thousand kilometres
so when you have these two up
you must find very close to a hundred thousand and you need to do
so now we know everything there is to be known about this ellipse
that came from
the initial conditions from the four numbers
but i gave we don't periods
we know winograd which is you know what marriage is
we know the orbital period
anything we want
to know
now i want to
getting into is subject which is
quite difficult
and it has to do
riding a rocket
when you are in orbit
and your
or it will change
and i will do it only four
some simplified situations i start off with a
circular orbit
and i will fire the rockets
in such a way
i will only
if i read in such a way that my velocity
well either
increase exactly
video of it
but increase in this direction or that it will decrease in this direction
so if i'm going in orbit like this
you know if i am i rocket like this
or if i am i rocket like this
that is difficult enough what we do now
so this is our circular orbits
radius or
and at location x
twelve o'clock that's where i fire
my rocket
the first thing i do i increase the kinetic energy
so i my rocket i bless my rocket we go in this direction
i lost my rock
there's reaction
so to speak which was originally
this orbit
the speed will now increase
i had kinetic energy
and now
i have no speed which is higher
if my speed is higher
then my total energy has increased increase the kinetic energy
the burden of the rocket is so short
that i can consider after the birth the object is still intact
a very brief
so to kinetic energy has increased the potential energy is the same for the total
energy is up
and therefore
the total energy
now is larger
and the total energy
that i had
in my circular orbit
but if that's the case
then clearly to a
must be larger
in two are
i'm not going to elliptical orbit
because the new velocity is no longer the right velocity for circular
so what's going to happen i'm going to get
elliptical orbit
like so
by two a must be larger
then two are
because my total energy is larger
you see that immediately when you go to equation number five
if you increase the total energy then you're a will
OK so too is larger than two are
it also means that the period t
must be larger
then the period
in your circular orbit
find so far so good
my other option is
i'm going to fire the rocket
when i you are getting this direction
so i take an adding energy out
so after the birth
my speed
is lower
my speech is now lower
i taken kinetic energy out
when i take an attic energy out the total energy is going to be less
than the circular energy
two a will be less than two are
and the orbital period will be less than the circular orbital period and therefore my
new ellipse
looks like this
so these are the three situations i want you to
carefully look at because i'm going to need them
in the next very dramatic story which has to do
with the romance between peter
and mary
i two astronauts
and they are
both in orbit
in one and the same orbit around the earth
this is peter is at this moment
at that location x
and this is where mary is
they are exactly the same way
but different satellites
you go around like this
and they are
edit distance from each other
which i will express in terms of
the fraction f
of the total circumference
this arc
he calls off
times two pi are
that's how far apart
and that means
four mary
to make it all the way back
two point x would be one minus f
times two pi r
so far
so good
mary forgot to lunch
radio speed and says peter i have no food
very sorry for her
there's no sweat
i will throw you and
so peter prepares and sends which and wants to throw it to mary
in such a way that mary can make catch
and feeder
do this
the best way the most obvious way to do do it
to make an orbit for the
hansen bridge
whose orbital period is exactly the same as this time for mary
to make it back to x
and i'll be more specific by giving you some numbers then you can digest the
they are in orbit
all the action
so that
well i will tell you that
tag like
the nature and
the time they can show that the kind of
that i can't
actually i
the bad
i can
what is going on
i can tell
how you
i'm going to
five five
now i
how do i get back
i just
we have
eight years
and you
i average i i i
and i found that
thank you
i mean that
i happen to
thank you
you can find
it's it's intentionally offensive they're basically did in many ways trying to create these taste
boundaries to keep out the people
who can't deal with it
OK we move on to study the ephemerality
let me give you a sense of how health morality is actually implemented on four
i'm going create a thread
look something like this
when i started that thread is going to go up to the top of four
chan's first page
as other people start posting new threads might read gets pushed farther and farther down
just like any other form
the difference is that there are only fifteen pages on four chan two hundred twenty
five threads
once the two hundred twenty six six thread shows up my three four o fours
not found that means everything attached to it is completely deleted forever
the only way to keep the content from getting deleted is for someone to come
and reply
if someone replies my friend gets pushed all the way back to the top
therefore can
this is a process known
as bumping
keeping this algorithm in a sense in mind
we can turn to the data we collect it
a complete data set of two weeks of slash b
that's five and a half million posts
almost a half-million france
and if we replace the history to watch what is ephemerality really look like unfortunate
here's what we found
the median thread last less than four minutes
i mean by the time you redefine hilarious try to tweet about it friends read
it was probably already deleted
shortest reign lasted just under half minute and the longest lived thread
last no more than six hours a response to this was why
the median thread here has one post and one reply
the other forty three percent reply rate is actually consistent with other kinds of sites
if you want to see what kinds of things get responses longest lived thread was
something that really generated lot of reactions or was really entertaining this was a pagan
who was actually offering to to answer questions about being a pagan whereas the short
lived thread was someone who is simply just trying to get attention and no one
was having
now let's turn to the first page
to understand what first page matter you need to you need to know that people
unfortunate often sit on just the first page of results and refresh all the time
so while for threads on the first page is the only chance has to get
so now let's do the same analysis focusing just on the first page what we
the median thread disappears from the first page across its whole life
in five seconds
that's it comes up
goes down gets bombed
goes away again
five seconds
when high activity periods less than one second maximum no more than thirty seven minutes
there are ways to play with ephemerality
one of them is called bumping i told you about being is but there is
that there some people actually replied with the text bumper band something like that in
order to push intentionally keep the threat from dying we see that about two percent
post to this
at the same time there's something on this stage
where you reply but
don't bob
so this is this something built into four chan and we found that less than
one percent of posts actually did this
so we draw from this is that fourteen members
to play around with the ephemerality of the site when it benefits them
now turning the volume for a moment this means that there are about thirty five
thousand threads four hundred thousand posts on on slash p per day
contrast that with about seven thousand posts on today
twenty five thousand usenet posts which their rolling was continuing to grow or sixty five
thousand youtube videos per day so say more about it is the number of videos
posted to youtube but imagine if the only way you can view youtube is to
go to youtube come and see the last fifteen videos and just hit refresh a
single feed that's what i'd like that's what it feels like to be on four
people don't sit by idly they refer to having slashed the folders on the hard
drive where they were they archive important content or things that they found hilarious that
they want to post again later
and for particularly memorable threads there's something honest for carbon fourteen are kind of or
which is effectively museum highly entertaining i recommend it
we can argue also that ephemerality
plays a role
in four chan meme creation
fourteen lots of names for example here to aerial that you see in the upper
i know
i mean we all
it is
so i think the point of
the this
well you can also be used to
and i
it's very simple way
one way
great is
and as you know
it is assumed
and also
just a
well the
OK all the
that we
or in
of course
and i should
two years later
you know what i
this approach
so what i i call
and the y
o a
these rules
like piece of as where
well why
it's a lot
the problem
and the nation
so when we use all
call it
well i mean
o or one
the following content is provided under creative commons license
your support will help MIT opencourseware continue to offer high quality educational resources for free
to make a donation or to view additional materials from hundreds of MIT courses visit
MIT opencourseware OCW that MIT that EDU
OK so i'd like to begin
the second lecture
by reminding you what we did last time
so last time
last time
define the derivative
as the slow
the tangent line
so that was our geometric point of view
and we also did a couple of computations
we worked out that the derivative
of one over that
i one x square
and we also computed
the derivative
of activity and power
for n equals one two
and that turned out to be
sorry next to to the
and minus one
so that's what we did last time
i want to finish off
other points of view
on what the derivative is so
this is an extremely important it's almost the most important thing of the same class
but you have to think about it again
when you start over and start using calculus
in the real world
so again we're talking about what is the derivative
and this is just a continuation of last time
so as i said last time we talked about geometric interpretations
and today
we're going to talk about is the rate of change
as an interpretation
of the derivative
so remember we we graphs of functions
why of back
and we kept track
the change in x
here the change
and while let's say
from this new point of view a rate of change
keeping track of the rate of change of x in the rate of change of
it's the relative rate of change were interested in
and that's delta y over delta act
now has
another interpretation
this is the average
usually we would think of that if if x were measuring time
and so the average
and that's when this becomes rate
and the average is over the time interval delta x
and then
limiting value
denoted d wide and that is
so this one is the average
the rate of change and this one is the instantaneous
OK so that's
the point of view that i'd like to discuss now give you just a couple
of examples
so let's see
first of all
so maybe some examples from physics here so q
is usually the name for for a charge
and then
dq dt
what is known as current so that
one physical example
the second example which is probably the most tangible one
it is
we could note the letter as by
and then
the rate of change
this is what we call
so those are the
two typical examples and i just want to illustrate
the second example a little bit more detail
because i think it's important to have some visceral sense of
of this notion of
instantaneous speed
i get to use the example of
this very building to do that
probably you know
or maybe you don't
that on how to win
there's an event that takes place
in this
building really from the top of the building which is called the pumpkin drop
so let's illustrate
this idea of rate of change with the pumpkin drop
so what happens is
this building
well let's see here's the building
and here's the
here's the dot that's the
beautiful grass
OK so
i can go to the
very quickly
OK so here is the definition of a finite mixture models
we see the point x i
for each data point x i we
but i which corresponds to
which mixture component it x i came from
the cluster indicator variable that are drawn from this distribution
upon given by pi
so this is
by the mixing proportions
being bayesian search and then given that i
all the axis is drawn from the distribution parametrized by by of that i
that being bayesian which takes place prior over all the making of options as well
of the parameters
by a
so good model
so the model selection
o averaging problem here is
we want to figure out what
the hyperparameters in each one of the dirichlet parameter
and most importantly what number of components in a finite mixture model
if we take the bayesian approach
we are not worry about overfitting
we can imagine taking a number of clusters in a mixture model to be really
notice that we can integrate out all parameters by and
mixing proportions pi
that we integrate out those who
and those are the only latent variables that in our model
the number of latent variables is if and where and is the number of data
so if we take him to be really large
the number of latent variables
that we have this not actually grow in terms of k ones with integrated accross
the components
the mixture components
so what this means is that they will not be over fitting in this model
notice that
there can be at most and components which
active in the sense that the associated with data and of course
the reason for that is and data points each being associated with one of the
but it turns out that usually the number of such active component is much less
than n
even the put even though the the total number of mixture components
he is
to be infinite
so this actually gives us an infinite mixture model
now you can do
we show that this thing actually what
the book
so this is is our
the point of the the point and we have sampling from the posterior of
during the infinite mixture model
the ellipsis here corresponds to the
mixture components which are actually active or associated with a
and in fact that the number of mixture components
within a model
but most of the time we only the small number of mixture components which are
actually associated with a
OK so
there's two issues which will have to address the issue is
and we take this
infinite limit
there's a limit when it goes to infinity
and the second issue is what is the corresponding limiting model
so what we would like to do is just that starting with finite model and
taking the limit
we actually want to define our infinite model directly
and then from that can see the relationship to the final
many of so
i guess everybody is familiar with some part of the by now
it defines a distribution over functions
trial of test it does this process
if for any finite set of input points x one x and
he invented the x one until you x x and this thing is the multivariate
gaussians this defines the goals process
so the concept of the has
i mean
and the covariance
an important part of the property of the marginal distributions
is that they are consistent
what is meant by consistent here
what matters is that
if you take
multivariate analysis
and you integrate out x at thing
that would just left with respect distribution over f of x one f of x
and minus one
and what's
it is important here is that the distribution is again given by gauss in
it with exactly the same form that
it's only been just from x one to x minus one
i think you see the sequence of inputs are
this that
visualizing because
so you can visualize the gods process i think that refers draw out of that
and we can draw perfect two given x one and x being given x one
x two and so forth
in if there are more because
or do any of that
we can actually do this because each of the conditional distribution is
the gulf
f of x y f x and
moving on to a dirichlet process
just as the
process has now
distributed marginal distribution
a dirichlet process had reached distributed marginal distribution
so people familiar with
there is a distribution
the rate of
can be again
dirichlet distribution is a distribution over
the k dimensional probability simplex
the k dimensional probability simplex is simply
a set of factors
i want to i
it and its heart
and it's fun to one
they can also think of this as the distribution
so this is because i want i e as the distribution as the discrete distribution
over here
being the probability of choosing
of the case
we see that the distribution is the distribution over the k dimensional probability simplex
we say that i want it reached the distributed
if it is the random vector where
the then the look like has this form
so that that's the of of interest the distribution
show you that
a lot of nice properties of distribution but just show you
you wouldn't be breaking by pushing on your break
you wouldn't be heating up your brakes
but you would somehow convert
this energy
into the rotating disk and that would slow you down
so to slow down the braking quote unquote
it is now
done because of the conversion from
the linear speed
which comes from gravitational potential energy
to the rotation of the disc
and when you need to the image
you tap it so you should also be able to get the rotational kinetic energy
out and converted again into
forward motion
and if you could really do this then you could go back uphill and you
wouldn't have to use any fuel
all you're
five million rules
can be consumed them in an ideal case
and you wouldn't have to use any
now you can ask yourself the question is this is the only useful in the
mountains could you also uses in the city well of course you can use it
in the city
you wouldn't be breaking like this then which again you would slow down
by taking out
kinetic energy
of linear forward motion
don't that into kinetic energy of rotation of flywheel
and that would slow down
and when the light is to traffic light turns green
you convert it back
rotational kinetic energy
in two linear kinetic energy and you keep going again
now of course it is always easier said than done
but it is not complete fantasy
people have actually made some interesting studies
and i would like to show you
atleast one case that i'm aware of that i found on the web
that shows you that the united states
department is
taking this quite seriously
this is the view graph is also
on the a two one home page
so you see here the idea of mounting such a
flywheel under the car here
this says the location of the flywheel energy management plan wonderful world isn't it
and you see close
of this
i didn't get any numbers on it i don't know which fraction
of the energy can be stored
in your flywheel but it's it's an attempt to people are seriously thinking about it
and it may happen
in the next decade the cars may come on the market
well by some of you
energy these can be
can be salvaged instead of heating up the universe
use it
yourself which would be could be very economical
i have here
also is on TV first
in this toy car
as the flywheel
is here
the fly with itself
is the wheel of the car
but the idea is there
in this case
i cannot converge
linear motion into the flywheel i could do that but i'm going to do it
in the reverse way
i'm going to
this flywheel
a lot of kinetic energy of rotation
we will see shortly how i do that
and then i will show you that that can be converted back into forward motion
in this case very easy because the flywheel itself
it is the real
let me
try to
power this car
i do that with this plastic
so i'm going to put some energy into this we'll into this flywheel
and then will see whether the car can use that
to start moving
great is my lecture notes with their
you see it works
and of course if you could
reverse that idea
that when the car before it stops
getting back into the flywheel then you have the idea that
i was trying to get across
very economical and definitely
that will happen sometime
in the future
fly reels are used
more often than you may think
at the
magnet lab
has two
fly reels
which are
they have a radius
i think of two point four meters that is correct
and each one of those flywheel
has this morning mass of eighty five tons eighty five thousand kilogram
and they rotate
at about six hundred
you can calculate
the moment of inertia
rotate about their center
axis perpendicular
to the plane
you know
now what one half i omega square is
and so you can
calculate the kinetic energy of rotation
the kinetic energy of rotation
is there no warping
two hundred million
each of those rotating
fly reels
now the uses rotational kinetic energy
to create very strong magnetic field
on the time scale a short five seconds
so they
mechanical energy of rotation
two magnetic energy which is not part of a to one so i will not
go into
how they do that this is part of a two and i'm sure all of
you are looking forward to a two two
that's when you will see
how you can convert chemical energy into mechanical energy we have already seen the demonstration
in class
by we converted
mechanical energy when someone was rotating into electric energy if it wasn't it and we've
got these light bulbs although about
you can also converted into
magnetic energy
and then when they have created a strong magnetic field that they do the research
and when they want to get rid of them
they going around and they don't that energy that magnetic energy back into the flywheel
well then start spinning again
at six hertz
needless to say that you which amount
rotational kinetic energy
must be stored
in planets
and in
and i would like to spend quite some time and that it's a very interesting
i will first
discuss with
and the earth
and see how much rotational kinetic energy
it is stored in the
and in the summer
this is also on the to one home page
so don't
copied this
let's first look at the sun we have the mass of the sun
we have the radius of the sun
this is the u i
and that's take one photon that comes in
which happens to be linearly polarized is directly
we pick one photon but is unpolarized light because we're going to have so many
on average there is no preferred direction but i think want to start with
and now i ask myself the question
if that photo
it's kind of a new direction
in this direction
how is the vector oscillating here
so this is now the position vector r
and this is the direction h
which the electrons are going to shake
because the photon comes in
which in the field taking lies this story going to shake like this
you will immediately conclude that you like to go back to linear must be oscillating
like this one
because it has to be perpendicular to
are which it is
and it has to be in the plane of a an r is only one
solution and this is the correct solution
now the next photon coming in
and the next photos
i'll give the color just
distinguish the two
happen to be oscillating in this area
and i asked myself the question if that photo is carried in your direction
in one direction is the field oscillating you come to exactly the same conclusion in
this direction
it has to be perpendicular to are which it is
and it has to be
in the plane of an are that's the only solution
a little later there's another photon that comes in
how is that
electric field
we can observe here of course in this direction and so
no matter how they come in
unpolarized light you always see
that is the photon
is scattered over ninety degrees you will always see polarized in this direction and therefore
you have created linearly polarized light
so if you want to hear
ninety degrees angle or if you want to hear at ninety degrees angles but of
course it's the whole plane
then you end up with hundred percent linearly polarized light
if you go through the same exercise c and angle your forty five degrees and
you look here
it is only partially
indeed if you rotate in front of i for another
you will see
clearly light intensity changes but not from the percent polarize you couldn't turn it into
and if you look from above
you may want to go through the exercise for yourself
you will see that the light
remains completely unpolarized
so it is only the ninety degree angle that is very special
and that's what i'm going to
demonstrate to you
but before i demonstrate this there's something
that i have to tell you that i cannot hide from you i wish i
could but i can't
it's not something that is my goal during this lecture it has nothing to do
with this
but that's the fact that the probability
when you scatter light of very small particles
tens of micrometers of dust particles
that the probability
of scattering is way higher for blue light than it is for red light
so like co training so
ng and cardie
of human language technology two thousand three
they have tried see supervised learning here somewhere
you start with some examples to annotated examples trade
cool which means nutrients several in this case i think it was too late to
so you
two classifiers on your current example set
the for the examples
of which
the bulls classifiers for which both classifiers
i was very certain about the classification
they are added to the training set and intuitively
you reach system
until you can not improve the accuracy
upon some validation
recently we've in this
calling paper of two thousand
we see also kernel methods that are being used
forced of sentences compared to show
but this is a difficult task itself
the resolution of
of note use
finding out that bill clinton is former president
for these kinds of situations finding this equivalence relations in the text
they are quite difficult
you need to first of all you need
also knowledge
that the president is the person
so that all animals also that the clinton is the person which
the first one you can
we too are named entity recognition can find easy easily with some small weight
the second one to know
the semantic class of others
just common nouns
not proper nouns
it's much more difficult
course you can rely on all
lexical databases
like worst that
but still then you have the problem of word sense disambiguation because so many meanings
of the term in enrichment
well usually
we have about the same results if you take
the first meeting of it
because it's it's quite noisy so you
when you do word sense disambiguation
this relies the meaning of it
on the other words in the context of other words in the discourse and several
he excelled learning this
but to we like actually resources that somewhere have stories to this context so you
can easily compare with his context find out the exact meaning of
so this if you using these methods of using these
these databases
it's also introduces quite some noise
another task which we are doing here is when performed
process use
well i showed examples of mergers between companies for instance instances
an entity relation recognition task
we have here we use a lot of supervised learning
i showed two examples
kernel methods that you could use
f measure that if one measures
if you look at these measures i did not
posting here
this looked to away to a lot
you can go to these articles c
it depends only on the class that you are looking for
certain types of relationships
they are very easy to detect
they are very straightforward patterns
other ones are more difficult
to detect text causes ambiguity for instance
the features
and also the number of training examples
this is actually
well these are the two problems section
first of all you have to see
most of the patterns
in your training set otherwise
the system
that it's very difficult to them or to interfere with the other patterns
and secondly we have a problem so this is the problem of recall
and secondly we have a problem of lower precision when c
because features that we use so we cannot
which feature sets that language by which we describe our examples
might not be
good enough
to make the discrimination
between the different classes
another task
so entity relation recognition
the first two
so this should be pretty natural just from
statements even more natural if you'd rather picture so we we have some vertex u
we're using weekly lines to denote potentially long pants as opposed to edges
we have some intermediate point x
and we have
some target v
and we're considering these three shortest path is a shortest path from u to v
this is its weights this is a shortest path from u to
here's its way
it shows that xt this way and the point is
well this should be the shortest path for a shortest path from u to v
and in particular one such path is you go from u to x and then
you go from x to be
so i mean this sum is just measuring the length of this particular path take
shortest path here take shortest path here and this is supposed be the main over
all past so certainly this is that most of this particular part the sum of
these two guys
OK another person
OK this
this stuff is
so again two
so more exciting algorithms
well we're going to algorithms to which is always more exciting
today we're
look at a particular version of shortest paths
the shortest path problem called the single source shortest path problem
it's a little bit more general from go from a to b
the problem is you are given the
a source vertex and you want to know how to get from that source vertex
to everywhere else
so we have all closed source vertex s
and from that
the sources we want to find
let's say the shortest path weights
from s to everyone
in particular we also like to know the shortest paths but that isn't too much
so that's delta eskom of for all vertices v
OK so this is actually a little bit harder than the problem we started with
the getting from all around cambridge now we want to get from all around to
the entire universe
OK it turns out this sort of one of the weird things about shortest paths
according to the state of the art we know today
which seems to be
it seems like the from the following statement will remain true for all time but
we don't know
the best algorithm for solving the ADB problem given as given to you from s
to t is
no easier than this problem
the best ways we know how to solve going from a to b is to
solve how to go from a to everywhere else
so we we serve can help ourselves but to solve this problem turns out
today we're going to look further restriction this problem because this is a bit tricky
well so the next class
but today
we're going to get rid of the
a negative weight cycle issue
by providing negative weights
three and assume that all of the edge weights are nonnegative
for all vertices u and v
so in particular
shortest paths exists provided patterns exist
and we don't have to worry about these minus infinity is dealt
is always bigger than mine something we still might be plus infinity if there's no
but this will make life a lot easier and the algorithm will cover today really
requires this property can
get away with that
next class will
get away without it
with the fancier and slower
as i can see that the main idea we're going to be used for the
stay is
which should be faster than dynamic programming generally
and the tricky part would be
proving that the greedy algorithm actually works
i think this pretty much only one
natural way to go back
there's one with that works car about creating say maybe not the obvious one
so let me give you a little bit set up
the invariant we're going to maintain
is that at all times we have
estimates on the distances from the source to every
vertex might distance i mean shortest path weights i'm going to use weight and distance
interchangeably here for more intuition
and in particular i want to maintain the set of vertices where those
those estimates are actually the right answer
this is less as big as big as will be the set of all vertices
where i know
the answer what is the shortest path distance from less to that vertex in yes
so for starters which distance do i know
yeah i know the shortest path distance from s to s
all if i assume that all of my weights are nonnegative i really can get
from as any faster than not doing anything can have a negative weight cycle maybe
distance from s s is minus infinity
OK but
i can have negative weights so there's no way i can get from s to
s in any faster than zero time there might be longer path still has zero
but it can't be any better than zero
so in particular
i know that
so initially as same as
OK and the idea is and accumulate more and more vertices that we know that
some point we know some of the distances from some of the vertices
so we have this
we have some clout here this is as and this is everything else this is
the graph g
some of the vertices
and you know some edges go out from there
and so we have estimates of how to get to these vertices some of them
may not have been seen yet they may not be connected to the scope of
this portion of s
i mean not directly they might be connected by some longer path that might they
might be completely different connected component we don't know yet some of them we have
this optimal alignmentI've plotted the sequence number of X J and the sequence number
ofY K okayand the the the lines represent thematches and the crosses re represent
the unmatched points in each configuration and thisyou knowquite stunning to saythere's nothere's
nocrosses none of this matches crossover each other
and that was notconstraint in the in the model anyway so this is
optimal bayesian alignment happens to have found a matching optimal matching that's consistent with the
sequence order now of courseyou couwe now know now we've seen that that we
could've use that sequence order in our model andin our inference that wewould've got
the answer very quickly because it would drastically reduced the such scale of the optimization
we wanted to do butit's it's interesting toknow we didn't need to
dothat and indeed in in this field there is some interest in structure
comparisonthat's independent ofsequence orderbecause it's possible in the evolution ofproteins that
this sequence order is broken commonly it's conserved but not always so that that thing
isof someinterest and this is another way of visualizing that sequence order so I've
taken thetwo configurations andcoloured them in this rainbow sortof wayso thatyou can
see you as youprogress through the sequence orderalong each point cloud
you get this kind ofcorrespondenceit simplymeans howfar isin
one end one endat the the sequence so I've used the rainbow going from a rather
uninterestingrainbow going from red tohow blue is itdark bluecouple of extensions
other additional information sometimes thesepoints arelabeled in various ways for example we know
they know about things like hydrophobicand hydrophilic residuesso you can imagine
the points carry marksor colors some sort ofcovariate information and we can we
can use that this is a particular form of that discrete version but you can
ifyou're willing toextend the model so that the generative model not only
chooses whether or not this hidden point is observedas Xor Yor both or neither it also
chooses what color what what what whatmark eachpoint isgoing to have and if
you take this this this kind of form that joint distribution then really nothing much
changesand you canstillmake inference in the model in exactly the same kind
of way and then thing we've done is to look at multiple configurations so what
if there's more thantwo point clouds lots of pointcloudsand you can you
can extended it in a natural way you havea still have a single hidden
point configuration now you have a matchso dramatical configurationfor each of the observed configurations and
the morecomplicating matching structure so a particular hidden pointcan be observed in any subset
of the configuration of the data configurationsthat'san optimal matching
inone particular caseI haven't gottime to tell you about it the notationsis cumbersometo expected
the the joint modelsstill has the same general character and you have
because of this the generative model having to have probabilities of all patterns of the observation
there's there's some interesting extrapremises to think about them soI mean one
simple idea is simply to say well each point is independently observed inthe first
configurationsecond the thirdfourththe fifth but you mayalso build insome dependentsyou know for example if
ifyou're thinking about these these different proteins is being evolved from some common
one it may well be that the processof loss of structure takes place over
the evolutionary timeand that will introducesome dependentsin principle you could do that kind of thing
so we'vewe've compared tosome extend we'vecompared freeway matchingversus all thepossible two
way matching and it's intuitively clear and indeed wewe we can say
that even if you only care about a two-dimensional matching it's worth looking at figure
relations as well because there's always this borrowing strength from data okay so if you
just think about how that works as a result of observing extra configuration you have
a you've you've tied down more definitely where youI isand that's valuable information in
deciding if X J and YK arematchedsoyou know this is all basedon
doing its jobokay that's seminar one any quick questions aboutthatand I'll do something completely different now
the second one is to do with tomographytomography is about mapping the
body without cutting it upthis is emission tomography which means what you've done
has filledthe patient with some sort of radioactive drug orgas orsomething injected
patient with something thatthen emits photons andyou canrecordthese photons
tryandreconstruct somethingand I've worked on problemslike thison and off over the years I
paperinthe transactions a long time ago doing Bayesian reconstructions initiallyjust
themap reconstruction based on thealgorithm and later astudent of mine
did a fully bayesian versionbutrecentlyI've beenworking with NataliaBochkina in
Edinburgh to examine someof thetheoretical properties of thebayesianreconstructionsso
pretty settle this is a medical technique medical imaging technique
called spectimages function notform it's not looking for the shape of things it's
looking for what's goingon because you choose a radioactive label that is attracted to
intointobody tissue in a way that you can interpretit
the devicefor detecting the photonsthatcome out is calleda gamma cameraand our objective is to collect these photons
outside the body and tryand reconstruct the pattern of concentrationwhic are calledX of where
that radioactivelysub label substance lies in the bodyI think we've said all about that so that's
the model was a very nice almost completely believable likelihood model in this casevery
verybasically based on high school physicscause we cansuppose we
have thispoisson linear modeland whatdoes thisrepresent what we have is X transformed bysome matrix A
and then as as our vector of course Iwill what this means is
and start
OK so i'm going to talk about clustering
and i figured out that many people have you already know
the clustering so many people already know what he means as many you already implemented
and so on
but some of you don't so i really had to struggle the last week to
figure out where should start
i start with the boring stuff like you need something linkage
and half of those of or whether should start to something more interesting so i
decided for the interesting bit which means that the boring that comes later when it
comes to the total from the interesting bit
and was also means that the order of my slides not exactly one i designed
and so maybe
we see that there is no doubt
so i mean this but is not really up to them but essentially what i
want to do is now i want to start with the advanced algorithms section
because i think so and the i want to present in detail and spectral clustering
because this thing on the one hand it's a very interesting with and it also
shows that many things one has to take care of when one tries to design
a testing algorithms and many steps involved in the local school of them
in detail
OK we also have some other things which are partly
in the first section which i will present maybe later today or tomorrow
and then this is the
third and fourth lecture for tomorrow mainly will concentrate on issues which are more from
a theoretical science so
we want to ask the question what can be defined what clustering is or can
be defined
does it have anything to try to define what clustering is
does it had to look at i summer theoretical point of view one of the
questions we would like to look at and so on
and that's what i want to talk about tomorrow
so before we start
OK clustering most of you know what it is but intuition is
we are given some objects that can be whatever we want to be dated second
images can be added gene expression microarray data whatever so we have those objects and
what we also have some relations between those objects so what you want to do
in the end we want to say which are similar to each other and which
are sort of belong to the same web of objects which objects belong to different
groups some home
in order to do that we always need some information about relations between objects
and this information can either be we have something like a similarity function or distance
or it could also be something more abstract like a neighborhood relationship certain points are
neighbours of the science but we don't have to like a way of quantifying
something like that
and then OK the goal is to find groups in the state of points which
have something to do with each other
and intuitively summer it's clear what you want to achieve with that but practically it's
often very difficult to really get a grip on what exactly want to do
and one of the reasons is that actually there are
there might be very many different reasons why you would like to do clustering so
the first reason which is i think maybe the
the only reason is
you want just explore data so somebody just datasets like is setting
if the customer and he comes up with this data set in this city u
there no clue about the data is not such ever before and before you know
started of this
designing the most complicated model two
some data might
just try to play in the data and try to find their structure in the
which you should need
to know before you go off and do something more complicated
OK and what you can do this is clustering so just apply clustering procedure trying
to figure out the groups in the data which might have something in common and
maybe in later analysis you would like to treat those groups differently
that might be
so but here is really more it's it's really playing around it's not
you don't have to
like an objective go like minimizing the squared error loss whatever it's just
it's more fuzzy set
the second goal which is very
very important
and it becomes even more important as
the data element grows
but often so many data points
that is simply can't run out on your five million data points so you need
to do something about that
what people often do is the first of all cluster the data points
to some groups
and then they try to run the algorithm on the clusters instead so instead of
and because
this guy
was a calcium
with the mean which was w transpose x
um and the
spherical variance we could solve but now we're saying this is gonna be
the general linear function
we can't do the integral in general that's the point i was making
i want to map to nonlinearity calcium you can't solve the partition function which is is what you need here
okay so
that's nice
what we can do is um
we can sample
this is approximately equal to one
these samples from x
sample-based approximation
and we can even compute the posterior by a process known as importance sampling now
this is easy to compute because this is just a nonlinear mapping of some points
through the nonlinearity so you can compute this likelihood you can't compute compute this approximate
likelihood is an approximation to the likelihood you can't compute
real likelihood that you can park on compute this sample based approximations so this is like super mickey-mouse sampling
it's nothing like
what you've been seeing from mark
it's very very easy to do
and this is the type of idea that
we just take
some points here
in the one dimensional space we match them with the nonlinearity
to the two dimensional space and they disappear now as points in the two dimensional space
and then when you do the sampling basically what the model shows is you just
need the likelihood of these points these things corrupted by noise
so actually the density you're looking at is the sum of each of these points
with a little circle around it
a little gaussians circle
that's one way of looking at this density you've got these points which is sampled from your guassian
he's your sample points and map them to hear and they've got little gaussians density
is now the trick in on
density network is
he also share
you should really i mean in some sense you could sample separately for every
i am
piiv accent
but he share the samples for accents just have one set samples all the accent
i and then so this model where you've got i mean you can think about
pro in fact
as did etienne shows you can actually think of this just as the density in
itself some points mapped to the two dimensional space with little galson bumps around them
and then the likelihood optimization is kinda straightforward
i say straightforward there's a lot of little mafia but it's simple enough this is
the sample based approximation so i've used and hear instead invest as i did when
i draw it
but basically incentive
log-likelihood you've got the sum of the log this summer across the samples for the data yeah
and that's for sure
each data point is still using the same some so this is the idea of
sharing those samples and you can compute the gradients
the gradient of the log likelihood looks like this
this term appears because the
the differentiating on the log you get the gradient
one over the summer and various stuff popping out
and actually
can typically be written you can think of this pi hat this term here is the posterior probability
over data points coming from one of those samples
that's interesting because actually this is arising from importance sampling
but it's actually looks very similar to e expectation maximization and that turns out to
be a duality between these models that you can interview this
has importance sampling which is what guided or in the duty and this type of model is viewed as
an expectation expectation-maximization mixture of gaussians and i'll explain that when i explained duty and
because i was sort of a different interpretation
but the same basic idea
go back to
so also into really works the same way broadly speaking you start with these points
aim at them in a nonlinear way they lived on a two dimensional space
but they constrain the point still with the constraint alive on this manifold
okay so
this is the oil data and i'm not use many samples has already a hundred
points in the sample and has an effect
look at these they also
but it is going along here that's again the technical term for it because it
and also
these little things here
what's going on there
is i actually shown this i should probably have shown the samples in this space
is only a hundred samples space most which are over here what's going on over
here is about three samples from the gauss
being mapped to this space so when you try to understand where these data data points are
they they might they have to be a convex hull of the three data points
here and actually what they're saying is this one is halfway between one and one
and so they just leave on this line all these points living along this line
as a couple living on line there so you see that if you want a
in these cases and hundred samples
is actually quite a lot in two dimensions that is still undersampling you see these
sort effect so the blue is separating from the green and the
and be a red
but i'm
it's kind
corrupted visualization due to the sampling step now if we go
four hundred points in the sample localized visualization is yeah
the this doesn't work as you increase the number of data points this is i
would say the best visualization we've seen so far the oil data it separated the
were said
well i want ask i came up with it
that's to see that it's true how new ideas over-claiming
reclaiming that delta two
two delta two t and i would like to know
what does that mean
it's clear that both sides are zero away from the origin
are totally clear
it's clearly labeled blow up at the origin somehow whatever delta thing but what is
how could this me why don't know the factor two in the air and what's
what's going on
i could take elements
the same area that's true that's that's maybe that's o
the key insight that if i integrate
everybody knows the role of the delta function is
now suppose i agree to
delta two t
do i really get one
one of the rule
changed variables right i knew very well that you be two t
so use to t
and the you new in two c other two
so the areas of the same so that's sort of why factor two is in
and more generally some
direct question here
so the areas match
the two sides
but the the full match would be checked that only when you really know what
delta function is because really
function is that you know what it does to us move
what does it do to a smooth function you
if you take has a function in you multiply by this
and you have great
this is really the definition of the director
and you get what
that's really the definition
so much but that's okay
so that this is all the same and we should share
the same definition as you can see e
and multiply by this strange thing
and now do do i really get the same effort because it's a sure they
are the same
why do i get well we're not going to do here
the same change change of variables right to should be you
to date she is the u
question is you are to so
it's a little different
i'm taking this function defined by the time i would like to
i can get
the value of this
you equals
which is
good deal
so the two sides give the right thing
well so there is
successfully solved one more
refinement equation
one more very very special case
so we tackle another one
i mean for me to call one more that i know the answer to
o race this for delta
right up new special case
i i coefficients are going to be here
one four six four one
all over
add up to one
i don't have dealt more fifty
so i
OK if i raise this
this example and make space for the new ones
right this is the next example so the coefficients one four six four one
which is really
it's the convolution of one one with itself
well one two one over four x was
the convolution one two one with one two one with b one four six four
one how do i know that
multiplying polynomials
with coefficient one-to-one squaring is this one is the same one to one
i remember binomial numbers in pascal's triangle or something i see those numbers
it turns out that if i look at the equations it would be convolution of
i know this solution for
the solution for the
if i can involve the coefficients you could just check that kind of play
so what is
this can involved with the first of all tell me
how far it stretches
how far it is the head of the hat stretch
remember that we've already got a period stretches from zero to two
where will have like that with itself
go o to four
go to for zero one two
and the idea what it will look like now
is that's
doing convolution in your head is not a lot of
especially when the function different parts and you world have the convolution integral
after a keep track of which perjury and actually it's going to produce
four different parts here
well let me say what think you
it's the cubic flying but why
we think but it's the spiral
changes to some other cubic
changes to some other QB
changes some of the human
so why is zero
this fact has finite length is need
that's a very important function
and of course
this model is the product of r one r two
and it's argument it's angle
polar angle is the sum of the old two angles
and you add the angles
and you put down your books angles but
and being photographs under a argument
in other words it makes the geometric content the multiplication clear
in a sense in which
this is extremely unclear from this
you know blah blah blah blah blah whatever turns out to be
you have not the slightest intuition that this is true about complex numbers is
the first that first thing is just the formula
whereas this thing is an insightful representation of complex multiplication
now i'd like to use it for something but before we do that well let
me just indicate how
the the exponential notation enables you to do
things in calculus formulas that are possible to remember from calculus it makes them very
easy to derive
a typical example of that is all
suppose you want to for example integrated
negative x cosine x
number one you spend
a few minutes running to calculus textbook and try to find out the answer because
you know you're not going to remember how to do it
or you run a computer and type in matlab and something or or you to
your pocket calculator which will give you formula and so on
so you know you have AIDS but doing that but the way to do it
if you're on a desert island
and the way i always do it
because i never have any of these little is around
i trust and i cannot trust my memory
probably a certain number of you remember how you did in high school or how
you did in eighteen o one
if you took it here
you have to use integration by parts is one of the tricky things
it's not required on an exam because you have to use integration by parts twice
in the same direction
and then suddenly by comparing the end product with the additional products and writing in
equation somehow that falls
the value falls out
well that's tricky
and it's not the sort of thing you can
waste time
stepping into your head unless you're going to
the the integration be on
during IAP or something like that
instead use complex numbers is the way to do this
so i think of this cosine x what i do is i think that either
cosine x
is the real part
the real part of y
well cosine x is the real part of e to the INEX
so this thing
this is real
this is real too
but i'm thinking of it as the real part of
e to the i
now if i multiply these two
together this is going to turn out to be there for the real part of
the e two r
minus x rated very pompously and then i'll fix it i would never write this
you are you
it's either minus six times
and they once were
the idea of what we need to maximisation the case we need to
exponential families so it's
it's been a bit of an industry
but a simple case will be where phi
if x and y
it's just
five six
after product time you y
so in other words what i get is point of x and y
it's just
on objects
zero here
four of x two
will be
here here and here
and will fall exceed three
on fixed
you know
i guess i don't have to continue beyond that
will be a very simple way of encoding this
now delta wildlife crime
this is what i take to be the error
estimating what prime instead of y
this could be something like zero one loss
so for instance if i need to the optical character recognition
then for digit between o one and ten
once you know
well of course there is no specific preference if i get one thing wrong with
the other
in general if i have some annotations of documents
the in there will be annotations which are much worse than others and i definitely
need to be able to take care of that
and now what have seen as well
i want to ensure that my correct
label namely y
the inner product between topics and y and w
has to be great recording
the and i'm going to make
by predicting y prime
rather than y
now this will be the score that i'm getting for my incorrect label
for fixed and y fronts
minus sign the size of this lecture
without outside of the hard margin solution
or in other words
what i'm getting is
the difference between four x and y and w
when treated as a function of y
is an upper bound
on the error that making
if mean right inequality
so what does happen with this means
five x and y
off x and one prime
it has to be greater recall in delta
of y and y prime
one this site
so this really means that
the difference in this course
a of x and y w
and for the incorrect
this has a major i've the mistakes going to me
so what is happening now is that the marginal
it becomes adaptive
with regard to
while the labels to them predicting
it's just like well you know if you're driving along the road in the salt
you're not going to be that careful about not maybe
try a little bit of the boundary of the road
on the other hand if you drive somewhere in the mountains and there's a really
steep precipice he would
try as much to stay away from the boundary
because if you cross it you will just fall off
so i it
it's a similar thing happening here
we try to stay very far away from those labels which will give you a
catastrophic error
those which don't really hurt is so much well you don't care much about
and now what's happening is i just use exactly the same optimisation problem is what
was there before
namely just one half the square percy times politics II's
except that out constraints now are much more complicated
before that the constraints are just one constraint for observation
now i've got a thousand classes
i have a thousand constraints
so and i imagine have something like
million observations
maybe i've have got half a million classes
things like that can happen for instance level ontologies
writing up that constrained optimisation problem is utterly in fees
the only way i you can deal with this is by essentially going for subgradients
before we do that
let me show you
what the margin is
so here we can see
that would be the margin corresponding to multiclass
that's the real problem you can write about
you might want to do that exactly once in your life in the ranking
the interesting differences that before that we just set up front between the five fixes
but now it's inappropriate between differences of of x and y
i and y
thank you could for instance used
svm struct but also europeans there's also on methods all
and we should will be showing you how to use that one later on
which relies on a very very simple idea
but you can just to insist on the list instruct if you want to use
well they basically does
it just
finds the verse violated constraint it every time
and just as that the constraints of the now solves the optimisation problem
so rather than dealing with the brilliance of constraints all at once justifies the constraint
as it in
the results of problem at another constraint and we solve the problem
the key difference between what this is all the does
and what about the method does
obama takes the entire set of observations is one
at in one big fat constraint and keeps on doing this
and this can be paralyzed fill in as many machines
so that's why
you can actually get fast convergence that way
but we should
discussing that in a lot of detail
so don't worry about this is this is just going out of print public
so one way of
implementing it will be you take an existing also
you define a loss function
define a suitable feature map phi x and y
i'll show you
which ones are really useful
and then you need to find an algorithm which maximizes this expression
why does that matter
it matters
well how to get the first constraint the worst constraint i think it
w two
sum-of-squares weights
over the input weights only
andy w three
some of squared
summing over
these output weights
only now be a more dimensional valid thing to do
and then you can say my regularizer is
some over three go from one to three
alpha psi you w see and then you're doing something dimension invalid
rather than just pretending that they all have the same
regularization constant
so when you do that's like someplace
instead he data are going to have a smaller as you manage to perfectly fit the data
and the weights blowing up which is what just happened with no regularizer
you can add on you can set we alphas say to one just the start
off with so alpha one alpha two and alpha three rules that one
and i go downhill and the first iteration looks just like last time you keep on going downhill
just sit still
and you go for ten thousand iterations hand hasn't blown up and gone terribly weekly
to fit every detail of the nice
right you might say well maybe that's better
but you might still be a bit dissatisfied because
you know is that's really the answer to the question what was the question
anyway be objective function that we are now minimizing called em
and is equal to
multiple he did
some of our history
he w
that's what we're now minimizing that's objective function has gone down and settle down and
we found an optimum of it and the weights have blown up
okay what's next
i suspect what's next is an interpretation of what we're just doing so let's see yeah okay
let's go back to
the single neuron
so the single neuron
looked like grass
and i want to
encourage you to feel dissatisfied with this
hand feel dissatisfied with
this thing as well
that we just had a moment ago
and then we'll fix your dissatisfaction
so why should you feel dissatisfied with this outcome of having trained single neuron
as a replacement for the pigeon that discriminates
pebbles from reasons
have think
about what one source the dissatisfaction might just be
and on it all depends on the value alpha and d
has you set alpha to different value you get different answers here upset after point
one and you get a different solution
and he said after one get a different solution again so
the one issue is how do you have the damn regularization constant
but another issue even if you were happy with with some magic which is the center for this value
you might say
i'm willing to believe that the predictions here about so quite well calibrated to this
data i think it you know it looked reasonable saying it's a twenty percent share
an eighty percent share you that's okay but i don't believe this extrapolation overhead
if you look at points
called ayant be
are you happy with the idea
they would just as confident that eh is sort
ninety percent certain degree in the other class
hand be is also nineteen sensitivity in the other class
is reasonable
if you are dissatisfied you might be interested in
these view of learning has an inference
so we discussed
learning has communication
now going discuss learning with regularisation weight decay
so if someone minimizes something
i ten today
i will exponentially the thing you're minimizing and organ interpret as the probability whether you like it or not
so if someone takes and w
the history w
plus alpha w
minimize it
i will say
all right
i'm going interpret interpret that's in the following way
the posterior probability the weights given implicit assumptions you're making
in the minus and w
on z
and that's equal to the product of
the probability of the data
given w
and the prior probability
i've w
given all
this is your posterior distribution given the data and your other assumptions
and that's normalizing with something
implicitly if you minimize this thing u of finding the most probable w given these assumptions
the probability of the data given w is it to be gene
hand the probability w the prior probability is it minus alpha
on something
so this is an interpretation of what people are already doing it doesn't change anything
but it may add some useful perspectives
so if someone minimizes this objective function
they are implicitly assuming that
it really is the case