to me
we want do
do it
there is a
but really the most
so let's see
this to
she gives you a
the school using the
the relationship between space so you
i think
so we that
here is we strive
we that
she was
this a
so there is
is it one
this one
it is
there are many
set so easy
which is
well is
this key to
so for instance that
one is set
it two
and in the formulation
so that's
i meant
donor flickr busiest banker
man in the centre long island when she was very elderly
and she told me that when this happens
had its opening party sort of a housewarming party
she was ten years old and she began to slide down the ramp
ah with another little girl
screaming having great sensor pleasure going down the ramp
and all the other results tried to stop them
except for corbusier
who said that his house was meant
for people to live in
for children to have fun
la roche
in his
journal entries describes the number of times he had to rebuild the house
the mechanical problems the flora that had to be replaced the heating that didn't work
the plumbing that need to all the systems that failed and the budget went four
times what it was supposed to be
but he was still very proud of this beautiful building
after the failure of these big house in switzerland then designed house that i referred
to earlier that he made song forty his mother and father on the shores of
lake geneva
he allowed his mother however antiques fair
it was a small house and de perfect space
a wonderful place
just to look at the sunshine
he did of course in paris in the twenties these
pavilion be
has played in which many of you know
he was
furious at these seven civil authorities
for the circumstances of his building
is given
the worst location in the fair
and which is why he built the house around a tree
which he had really intended to do
but this
pavilion gave him a chance on
so his design for a city for three million
again i assume that most you know more about the corbusier's urbanism and the
project the city for three million
then i do
but what i discovered in his letters is something that you might not know about
which i think is terribly important he wrote to several friends
he intended only as an idea
it was hypothetical he really did not favor
the destruction about repairers paris
he did not want to see them play
to this day
i encountered people who tell me
on corbusier the man wanted to destroy paris
that's what he's known fore he's the man who could entertain an idea
but it doesn't mean that he didn't have great understanding and sympathy
for the year regularity about the city
here is in front of the famous planned
in fact the way that he lived in paris
was not the way most people picture this is it
photographed by the side of the
charlotte marshall i
on the twenty shock up he lived in the seventeenth century house
on the seventh forward one disfavor painters of
was gaussian whose work is behind him here
wasn't strict modernist he was above all else humanitarian he
loved this primitive uneducated artist who he felt was wrong about the art establishment court
was always helping gaussian financially and legally trying to organize and he was a man
but key rate don't keynote
by the way early in my research
i told my wife that the corbusier's copy donkey hodie rather astonished me
because it was founded in these high degree of historic has
anne catherine thought that i was
losing my mind until she went with me to be found out sooner corbusier in the library
we pulled out his copy a documentary
and indeed it is bound with the skin and fir of one is
beloved characters
there were different dogs name and so on there is some confusion
on this issue
i also learned from these taxidermist
that he had some of
pen so those are
john bones including the job
made into a sort of a paper holder that whispering gallery
and he kept on his desk and the clampdown on papers and he would open
and closed and open and close it when he was designing somebody entrances for shopping
now in their twenties is when he began that would be gone
but he kept a secret from modern-day you weren't supposed to living with a woman from monaco
um in paris
and have your swiss calvinist parents know about it so there are plenty in letters to we've gone
telling are
the way in which she had to address mail to him when he was fifteen and a lot of secrecy
then his father died
when you reach his account of his father's death
u come to realize how deeply sensitive courtroom was as a human being
i had the experience researching this one mile
mother father was dying
and that's something i could feel
so much what court who had experienced
the things against which he reacted as a young man the wanting to go further
wanting to be different and then coming to realize as was his good fortune and
my fortune
that his father had been a man
who is an example are kindness
an example are straightforward this
the court lucia couldn't stand corruption
he couldn't stand the policy
many people would say he aired on the side being part two
opening in the things that he said
but his father represented integrity and good to
i also discovered in my region
that year
his father died he wrote a letter to his mother
the situation of his father's death
and referring to
the needle
how to
gives insight
why this issue shows that
a within the
well said
interested in finding
p of
x i
the rest
all everything that i i
the question is to show the four
mark field for vision that the set
is set of children
of those parents was what they
no everything
everything is not
so the probability of x i given the rest
is equal to the probability of x i given something else
what's the smallest something elsewhere which is correct
and this is the answer
well why is this well
the first thing you should realize all these thing is just before the separation
if you want
to the separate
is no
from the remember this separation is
it represents conditionally independent
it is independent of the
you can see in a directed graph in the sense that he separated from
you want to find which is the minimal set separate
x i
the rest
and it's obvious that band
why because all the
all the that's the goal
they were the parents of the more exciting what
those that be
the field had the
the children is also because any
possible that
that connect children
with the
with exercise
which is
how can you have two had or has failed if that fails it's OK
if it were head to head
and if you don't have to call council so
that was
well the block
his whole
those that people are so notable that we block to ensure
CORP and also
the minimal set due to conditional so that make sure that your conditional distributions to
to the
the conditional distribution
the that's for the
will be a simple way to explain the complicated explain just the algebra
you know that p
x y
is equal to p
x i
x not i
divided by p of x
these nominator is the sum
x y
of the of x y
next modernization
but this thing has two factors
one factor
that he bowls
to get
as close as possible as a random sequence
the answer for full seven
if you do
normal this chef was used as you show normal
but if you can show in many other ways
you can show for for for example just changing talk of
so you have that here
of cards
it just allowed to
shuffle talk right time
so you would have
to model this
you have the probability
i j
different from zero
all the rest
anything that's not transposition of those two cards
because you're
so you only have all of the
anything that's allowed fish to shuffle two cards
and then you go operating with this
this function
you do many many in iterated
operations of that
and then you ask how close you are to the uniform distribution
in the end
so we have these norm there
in this case norm is called the covariance distance
you can prove
this sort of
the sort of statement like
how many how many cases you have to apply this
to get close to normal distribution to add up to a random distribution uniform distribution
so this is in general what you can do with
if that
we are transform groups
yes transitions so
it flips it shuffle
you're willing to bet that the convolution is this
but the bottom line want to estimate convergence
in this case here some more general statement you can use always use symmetry two
reduce the number of variables
like for example in the case of the cuba showed before you don't need to
to work with all the space of the kids can use with
much much smaller
o job this part here this is
fastest mixing markov chain you not only can
as for
the the
you know you use how
how you can count
how how many operations you need
in the mean
the mean number of persons in need to
the back of cards
is it can model is a markov chain
and you can ask as well what is the
fastest mixing instead of establishing
what what is your
your procedure you're shuffling
you can ask which shuffling will give me
the fastest mixing
how do i get there uniform transition as fast as they can
you can use you can reduce the number
of variables in the search space
so you have
an efficient way to calculate
so here's the formula for the inverse
of the transform this is the case now
no it's OK it's written there as us
as for continuous groups
and i mean in in
in my mind and the next steps will specialize was formal
for the rotation
which is by
will use it
representations of the rotation group
you probably
you can learn this with this naming
sort of wording
but they are
representation i guess everybody knows what are the representations of the
rotation group
you guys probably know the spherical harmonics
well the spherical harmonics
no much this is right
this for
can you read that first probably be the
so it actually when you look at the expansion of the function
in terms of spherical harmonics
which is these y
this is actually a four-year spansion
of the
of the function
and you get
description efficient here
f l and
these are
four here transform
for set index unbiased representation
it's you can read these
no standard interest for you
as the wave number you remember when you do a one-dimensional thing
the composer signal into the
and mornings
which is the frequencies contained
in that signal
you have a sound
you the composed these in all monarchs first harmonic second one
and so on
this index is in this case is indexed by just the number which is the
but for the
in the case of the text fea you have two indexes
but still
you know those
the case of one dimensional thing
you have the wave number it's associated with this and signed course of
and here those indexes
those indexes are related to these functions here
which replaced the sine and cosine
forty six c
so you can always represent the function
using this fourier components here
this is the open
if you opened this expression you have this thing here
this is the
fourier transform
this is just what i world war
but the
this is the forward fourier transforms
and this is things works right
this here just explain what is the
or am
of the right
so we see that
can you imagine of x
every node i just have to look at what the maximum here was the maximum
here with the what's the high point of the interval
which everyone one is those is largest
that's the largest
that's subtree
modifying operations
OK so let's first to insert
how can i do insert
OK so the two parts
the first part is to do the tree insert
just the normal insert into a binary search tree
but i do
concerning you have all
through new are linear
how can i fix up the ems
that's right you just go down the tree
go down the tree
and look at my current interval
and it's got bigger max this is something is going into that subtree
xavier's high endpoint
is bigger than the current max update the current max
just do that as i'm going through the insertion wherever it happens to land in
every subtree that is this
we know that it's on the way down i just updated
the the
you know with the maximum wherever it happens to
whatever happens to fall
OK good
so i suggest you just fix them on the way down
but we also have to do the other second can also
you we need to handle
let's just see how we might do rotations
so let's say this is an eleven fifteen
that's a right rotation
the school offers more
this is still be the
child has thirty that one has fourteen one has nineteen
so now
this is
we wrote it this way so this is the last fifteen
and this is the
six one
this one i look at
this is my formula here
is look here and say which is the biggest fourteen fifteen nineteen
i look here which is the biggest thirty nineteen or twenty
where once again it turns out
not too hard to show
it's always whatever
was there because we're talking about the biggest thing in the subtree
in the membership the subtree hasn't changed into the rotation
so that just took or one time to fix up
they are all generated at random
independently with probability fate is being one of my claim is this is the formula
the probability of the sequence b
when theta is the parameter that generated the data well that's
very simple
what we have
so first the most important thing is first of all these big product the product
comes from the independent so one of the building
blocks is always if you think that something is generated independently at random so you
have to form a product of the individual probabilities so this should then be the
probability that
we have
generated x i
well what is this if x i is equal to one
then this should be the probability of being one should be
actually fate well to the power of one estate o one minus a ten to
the power of zero is one any from the other hand we had
x equals zero
and this would be a one
and we would have a one minus zero is zero so the probability for zero
would be one minus status so it's just another way of writing that the probability
for x
being one
it would be for a time in the probability for x
i will zero would be one minus data suggest a simple way of writing that
so this is the probability for the data
the parameter theta
so we can view this whole thing as a function of two objects we can
view it as a function of the axes
but let's say we have a fixed dataset so these axes are fixed numbers did
not variables anymore fixed numbers but
we can view this object as a function of status so it's a function of
theta for fixed data and this function is called the likelihood function
and we can use
this likelihood function
in order to try to estimate the parameter theta under which these data were generated
because we don't know we just see that the data our model is that this
is the generating mechanism for the data so the question is
it has a free parameter theta what should be the right parameter so one assumption
is a good estimator might be the maximum likelihood estimator and the maximum likelihood estimator
is the one that is defined as making this likelihood of the entire sequence
most probable
sorry for making this data
the probability for the data making these the observed data most probable so we tune
this we
take different values for fate and take the one that makes this probability largest so
this would be considered as the most likely parameter having seen the data
so of course it sounds very much like a principle and we should ask later
in what sense might this be a good idea
the first all sounds nice right
what you see should be most probable
otherwise it's not most probably would actually think what you see is very untypical right
i mean so you believe you have to come up with the data that makes
not an untypical event that very typical one i probability then so technically what you
have to do is you have to maximize such an object usually would take the
derivative with respect to data and set it equal to zero
just to get a maximum or a local extremum and well typically well if you
have a product it's usually with you differentiate it's much nicer to deal with some
rather than products of people take the logarithm
it's also nice for another reason because if you have a product you multiply things
so things can be sort of becoming exponentially small in n or exponentially large well
this is probability is probably becoming exponentially small so if you take the logo bit
it's usually a manageable number so if i take a look at this object i
would end up
precisely with that
line and if you think a little bit
that these axes or zero and one
if you have just if you count how many ones you have because the zeros
are not counted at all if you just have zeros for axes in the summer
the zeros are not counted up to zero but here it counts the ones
so if you take the sum
and then you get ten times logs data in one because in one is the
number of ones in the sequence
in this other
objective one minus XI discounts to zeros because effect size zero then this counts one
and so you get in minus and one which is the
zero so this is your likelihood you log likelihood
and he would like to
sort of take the derivative of this object set it equal to zero
and let's see that i do that probably in the next
now let's do it
there's an exercise so we just take
in one
ah logbn eight plus
minus in one look one minus eight i take the derivative
so i take the derivative with respect to theta
the data so
look for data gives me an innovative data
and here i get in
minus in one i get the minus sign from this
and i get a one minus and this should be equal to zero so the
only thing we have to do is we should
solve this with respect to one minus with respect to data so
well i could multiply this by data site would get
ten times
one time state is equal
it is here that i multiply the whole thing by one minus eight
so i should get this is equal to zero so let's collect all the theatres
so what i haven't actually
practice that but it should always come out
so you get an and i get a
measuring the magnetic field which is induced by that
about by electrical currents in the in the brain
yes it is
pictures are taken from
some article and i a bicycle what
what what what what they're trying to represent that i'm sure is very deep
but of course then the point is that when you have a single sentence at
some point
on the head then
you can it is reasonable to assume that it receives signals from many different places
in the brain and perhaps these
this is activity in the brain is small less can always be divided into you
know a limited number of discrete sources
so you have a limited number of seats source signals mixed in the
each of these measurements
here's kind of illustration of what what this is an easy machine looks like it's
like an extremely big tank and then use it on the on the input you
hate there
but it's the nice thing is that you don't like needed complicated preparations you just
stick your head in there and then you start measuring and do the thing measures
different kinds of stuff at at the each of the four it's of points actually
i think it gives a three-dimensional signal in each of those
in each of those two hundred twenty two
sensors on the head actually there are now also measurement devices that have more than
two hundred percent
so this is the thing that i showed in the very beginning
here is the number of measurements
given by by immediately so here we have only a few of those not of
the one hundred and so on but so what we can see is that clearly
we have some kind of mixing happening here
we have like these phenomena that like spikes like this and spikes like this they
can be seen in many different senses
and so it is reasonable to assume that you might have something like a linear
mixing well actually there are physical reasons for thinking that the meeting is linear because
in these electrical signals will be more-or-less some together
and then when you do i see
what you get is something like this
well actually what happens is this
a bit not not exactly what you expect it you will get some so signals
that that's really do correspond to the seeds of certain has specific physicality
signal sources but they are not usually they're actually in the brain they are something
that's outside outside of the brain on the in the head or maybe somewhere for
this is this signal here
quite well separated by ICA
and it is about eye movements
the muscles in the eye when more they really do certain kinds of electrical signals
that sensors to capture
and then
this thing down here it's also pretty well separated but it's actually signals coming from
a digital watch that in the in the rest of the of the person
of the subject
and in the same way here
it's actually the heart beat of the subject
and there are a couple of signals which correspond to the activity of the jaw
muscles because actually at this point of time
the the subject was told to bytes
and so these muscles suddenly started strong strongest of activity
so what you see in the in the beginning of people wanted know like separate
brain activity into different components but what happens is that you actually doing something some
kind of perhaps something like noise reduction here so you get these signals like heartbeat
but you are certainly not interested in analyzing with human brain and so but if
you are able to make so separate them like this then it means that you
can remove them from the data
and then you have like with a measurements of brain act
actually there are like this i artifacts for example they are very annoying because they're
the amplitude is much larger than the amplitude of the brain activity so there are
actually a number of methods developed for getting rid of them
so i see it seems to do something rather it
but what you can do is
it's really you can actually get into the brain activity itself when you talk about
when you measure evoked magnetic fields that means that there's some kind of stimulus that
comes into the brain and then you measure the activity that is evoked by the
stimulus just after the arrival so as demons means for example in order to be
that you here
it can be also you know some something happening on the video screen which received
by your eyes
so i'm going to be there's also because i know them so this is all
work by by the kind of the big idea and co-workers
but what you do get you we have some simple results were so for comparison
they have computed the the principal components of this potentials and then the independent components
of the potentials
well one thing to notice that these principal components don't have any any physiological localization
because after computed some components from the signal you can actually measure where
that kind of signal should come from if it comes from a single if comes
from a single single so single place in the brain and it happens that all
principal components that doesn't really work
they don't seem to come from any single
a place in the brain is the independent components are localized in the sense that
you can actually really show that the that that kind of fields
that measured fields can be produced by activity in the scene
small point in the brain
and he said that well and is the working hypothesis of most of the brain
in this area
that's the that you actually have like small very small
o point light source in the brain that are active now and
the drivers
this action potential is the energy has been stored up
in these concentration gradients concentration gradient is a form of energy
why is that
if there was no membrane there
what would be
the concentration on the inside and the outside
the same there would be inside and outside the not so expensive those edges drilled
holes in the memory
you know one july holes it'll all equally bright
you know because just by diffusion there will will go to the instructor with no
entropy will sit in it will be equal concentrations if i want to establish concentration
gradient and i have to work against entropy that takes energy here
and that is a form of energy that i had to put work into moving
ions around in order to establish concentration gradient
who's in charge of carrying out that work
who is it that sets up
these concentration gradients
in the south
membrane proteins
certain membrane
in particular
membrane transporters
involved so we're going to talk about transporters
and then we'll talk about some channels
the first one
there is
and a c
any ideas what an ATP driven sodium potassium pumps does
set of how does it set up a constellation gradient
so what is the problem
it pumps a sodium
a proper sodium in or out
pumps sodium out
it comes
potassium in
and it does it as an even exchange
what i would like to do it is an even exchange one sodium for potassium
charge conservation exactly so there is no electrical work to be done if it's what
someone for one
and is there were no to be done yes there is because obama pumps sodium
out of the cell
i'm doing it against the concentration gradient from once i get going i'm doing it
against the concentration gradient so
energy is needed to move the sodium out of the cell against its concentration gradient
energy is also needed to move a potassium into the cell against its concentration gradient
and where do we get the energy
so when ATP is burned
in order to do that this guy gets called and pipe order sometimes
because it's an entire transport something like OK
the pump that is an ATP is to use the energy
from an ATP to exchange this guy that
there is an eighty
calcium pump
for transport
and as you might imagine
what does it do
it transports
a calcium
i am
out of the cell
and it happens not to do that in exchange for any other i
and it's too
it is driven by ATP
we'll pom-pom pom pom pom pom pom pom pop keep
will this thing to be able to keep going forever set up arbitrarily large concentration
when i
well with nothing to back it can we could keep going
it gets harder to put stuff actually working up against the bigger and and bigger
concentration gradient
and the ATP is only going to give you so much energy
so to certain point
the burning of that ATP or however many ATP's uses for a specific mechanism won't
so there's gonna be some natural upper bound to how far it could go in
setting up the gradient because there's an actual amount of energy can spent
OK do useful to think about these gradients as you work that you've got to
do in the whole gets steeper sleep
all right so that could in principle
electrical gradient the concentration change across the cell but there's one other important component we
have to think about
and that
is something called a resting
potassium channel
so what is the resting potassium channel
the resting potassium channel
is protein
it's it's the membrane
and it's got a whole
a poor
and that poor here
it is designed so that was sodium can't escape through that port
and you can imagine that some little bit of clever molecular architecture to make their
sodium atom not be able to get sodium ion up here we get out the
potassium might be able to get out of potassium ion
i can get out
this is a completely open door
that allows potassium ions to escape
isn't this stupid
we just spent all this ATP
getting potassium and sodium out
and here i go opening the door for potassium saying you're free to leave despite
all the all the work we put into bring you into the cells
it makes no sense
all passengers going to rush out
can alter as in russia
the concentration leading because which way
it's more inside more potassium inside less outside so the test was going to rush
o one electrical gradient
if there is an electrical grid so maybe the beginning there is no electrical gradients
so potassium rushes out what does it do
makes more positive on the outside
now the next passing wants to rush out
and it's going
down its concentration gradient
so there's no
local minima as in there's no maximum cell points and there's no local minima for
convex functions
which means that as soon as the gradient is zero
then you have a global minimum
i don't know what's next
right so what's next is there is
not in minimizing problem that that the problem of immunization that you might
find in classification
so it's a little bit complicated
when you see that first so we could try to go through the steps ones
one by one
and what i wanted to show you
that's too many
encounter problems
minimisation problems that are
but was going to constraints
and you're going to be able to use lagrange multipliers to introduce the contraints constraints
in your problems
and they in turn for these kinds of problems the minimisation the minimisation of the
functions in the
in the original variable will be equivalent to maximizing
another function
the dual valuable so
people will talk about about prime prime all in dual problems
and i learned from the two players
that's just an example and i won't go into the security of all that i
just show you this example
here is my favourite classification task
i have some inputs
which are a couple of examples labels y i x y y i was why
is one
my goal is to find an
linear superior
that is going to be predicting
the values of the labels
so what i'm gonna
training to find the best w
so that the function
and w of x
as w and b of x
so i'm afraid i'm trying to optimize for four wnb so that this function as
WB best predicts the
the right so what i really want
be my empirical research is going to be the son
of y i
so why is different from
so to predict the label i'm actually going to take it assigns so maybe it
would be better if y
if y is clearly minus one
to predict the label of the new why i'm going to say that my prediction
is the sign
of as w ax
then when i want to make sure that the and the empirical risk on my
data is small
empirical risk here
is the sum
of the indicator of whether my prediction as the good sign or not
i six i have now
and we're going to be trying to find the values that are as small as
so basically instead of any meaning minimizing this as we're gonna require a rigour it
so real problem is going to be to minimize on w and b
the empirical loss
leicester regularisation which says that w shouldn't be too big
you need that because if you replace w by
lambda times w and if the words equal to zero then you always have the
same answer
here in in terms of the size
you know if you want to avoid that w goes to zero
chris infinity and you have you have to regularize that
and now
well the thing that you have a there is a little bit different
because what happens is that
this function here
as a function of w is not convex
and since it's not convex it's not so easy to
to minimize
so we're going to be replacing this function here
the the lost which is there
so what you want to think about is that
what you want to think is that
if i plot here
the product y i
times the sign
so i want to move to
pay nothing if it was was things are of the same size so if this
product is positive
and i want to be one if this product is is used to have a
different site
so this function
this this is not
question to answer
in fact it is undecidable
now before i
the next thing is to assign credit for
so again from last year has
only two possible truthful
and let's assume we
you know how to do so we we have more already
we want to know where the former is true more under particles
assign a
so given to assignments a and b
so far eight
i said that
b is an experiment of a
agree on all variables except possibly x
so they assigned the same terrible the same value
every variable except possibly
they can assign the same value to it
it's just to
simple to say that this is an operation under
this interpretation by
so you can equally used
so you can see this simple
by for example
it's just a function that takes three arguments
return t
interpretation i
it's kind of
i function because i so much
a seven
to higher order function that takes three arguments
again we assign truth table for
we do it by
inductive the
examining on the basis for
in the base case when you have the atomic formula which is formulation symbol
and terms
and we know already how to calculate the value of change
we just have to show that
the japan the top
t one tn is a
interpretation of
the relationship people
gets computing to central
and this is point six
it does seem a bit pointless because because white wine
well like guess said logic
a big part of logic is really starting form the state
particle and this
to see what you like
ninety four
so the variance
is fair and the
it's an experts they agree on every
the interpretation of form
base case
interpreting atomic
one is just simply checking whether
topples terms
i is in into the vision mission
and the other connectives to propositional connectives standard so
of a and b is true for all n
oppose to the following is the truth assignment
now four
universal and existential quantifier
we basically
i have to check so for example
the interpretation of full of xt
have to check
whether g is true for all possible values of x
this is the notion
so we can for this time the data and experiment
which means that degree on other values except possibly
change the range of
if you can use
i just think that this is the standard for
state all the students in the class
existential quantifiers of course to find these things the sixties
experiment feel
he is
it's a model
a formula is true in the model
it's true of
so it's true for all possible values for x
and it is valid
is true in all possible model
it is found in
this it is true no matter
one interpretation two functions
predicate symbols and because
a formula is satisfiable
well there's an assignment
that's the true
four very fine authenticity and things like that
just he is an example where you have to fingerprints and to match them up
and you check whether they
are really sufficiently similar
because fires belong to the same individual
so i think that is small
this is a feature of the input
specific locations of this image on the left hand side
the effect features in the right hand side and then my task is to match
the features here with the features that
OK if this match
is a union sufficiently small
the match
according to some property definition of smoothness
it's likely that
these two fingerprints belong to the same but otherwise it's not
so how do it so this is not problem
so it seems to to be able to problem is that these are coming from
because you have
many points here that can match many points five
which he in that region
and in fact you can
use graphical models to represent to model this problem actually
o thing
the proper solution for
same example just with all time
same house with the
images from different perspectives new to match features one image to another image
to recognise the object
here is yet another example in image processing
so in the top left to have an original image
and then in the top right you have that image with text
proposed to
basically have described the content of the image
they b in the pixels
that have been proposed about that
the question is how do you
only at the image in europe
right side
how do recall the original image to have good approximation
how do we actually
that image in the top right
could be something close to the machine
top left
in the bottom
you had two examples of constructions using graphical model
so you don't
you don't get to observe the pixels
the white
pixels in
the text
you just rely on those pixels that
and you need to fill in the text with proper image
and that's what you're saying which is quite
no not at all
not in fact scale there's absolutely
that is just
for arbitrary images i don't absolutely know that there is a wonderful
i have the training process the rest of the world
so another example
we have an image on the left
and here we have a corrupted version of that image with very severe noise
and here you have
one example solution of the denoising of
this image
in fact denied this image to them with approximation of the region in which which
we never see
so this is one of the first approximation kind of thing that one of the
the few with what is it that one
then you can obtain the the last approximation so remember the only thing you get
to observe the noisy image
that in which is the reconstruction
that's the only thing you get to see you never get to the original
and so that's pretty graph
if you use any naive type forward new learning
basic image processing cores
you'll never be able to something like this
you really need to go for more sophisticated
why graph models
the answer here
because in graphical model since we analyse
image as a graph we can consider the connection between that pixel and all its
for all
locations in the image we do these analysis and then
every for every part of the image we have given preference of which value
xo would like to
all these
nonparametric bayesian models seem to have the work
process occurring somewhere because
stochastic process is basically an infinite dimensional probability distribution
so originally this this terminology was the process of course due you to due to
the idea that you have some kind of sequential process observations which just continues to
but then you look at the joint probability distribution of all these observations that you
get all these these individual events that you have all the time
and so you define to somehow have to to study infinite dimensional probability
but more generally these these these could be infinite dimensional distributions which which have no
notion of time what they don't need to be annexed by time is an expert
something that could be annexed by points in space or whatever you like
OK and one
i mean probably the most important stochastic process of all the stochastic process
is the typical definition that i that i
at it some time
copied from i think some machine learning takes i don't know which one what it
says is
gaussianprocess is the probability distribution on an infinite collection of random variables and their indexed
by t suggestively four times
and such that the marginal distribution for each finite subset
of indices discussing so
that's what is this this definition that that karl discussed in this talk that you
something like that you can think of the function is something like an infinite infinite
you say that this function is distributed according to process if any subset of elements
of the vector you pick any finite subset
has a cost distribution
what's this definition does not tell us is whether such a thing exists right now
all it says if it exists we call it goes processes
but not whether it exists or not what we have done it does not tell
us you know what we have to
what kind of conditions we have to impose to make it unique
what about
it has to go in there in order to make it uniquely defined mathematical objects
now the next slides i guess are kind of technical
what is a
by exist
suppose you have the set of all
infinite dimension measures on on on
the space
on in which these functions like OK
to say OK there might be probability measures and look at the set of all
of them
and i want to impose imposing here
is is a condition that
all the margin that there is one of these probability measures were all the marginals
are gaussians
but they might not be right nothing guarantees in this really
it's the case
we might just end up if we if we look at if we look at
this as a set of constraints then we might have end was was it was
an empty feasible set
the new
one of the one
it would also be cast it should be
better be
it's exactly so
so we we make we can make this assumption
on certainly that that all these finite or this finite subsets of variables have some
girls in this tradition
but whether that whether or not there is an infinite dimension probability
that has these as its marginal
this is not a priority
but of course it works
good so far
so the the
the theorem that that
it tells us that that this actually works is called the congo extensions here
some people just call it the congo theorem but there a million and one can
go here and so there is a kind of extension here
and what it tells us is the following if you have
if you if you imagine you have an infinite dimensional probability distribution your stochastic process
and now we look at
at the finite dimensional subspaces of your space and take the marginals on those
then these marginals on arbitrary so if you take for example the five dimensional subspace
and you take the margin on that
and you take a different for a five dimensional subspace takes marginal and
you choose the subspace such that they share some dimensions if you marginalized both of
you five dimension that down to the shared subspace
we must end up with the same margin right because they're all marginals of one
it's the same stochastic process
so that's something that these marginals certainly will have to satisfy
and what's the commonwealth serum tell us is that is basically all also works the
other way around
if we have marginals this set of marginals all finite dimensional subspaces which are consistent
in this fashion
then they defined
stochastic processes and its unique exists and is unique
so it is kind of ones that we have to invest some work into the
like the technical setup
but once that is done
it's really appealing in its simplicity
good so
and the slide here is the technique itself that's what looks ugly so you
what we what we want to define is this is this measure
this is our stochastic processes so it is a stochastic process it sounds complicated but
it's really just the probability measure
and only its own pretty large
this is probability measure corresponds to random variable
which is again defined in abstract probability space and maps to some
o space
OK and and so what we have to do now is we have to set
this space here
and then we have to figure out what we mean by marginals
can the way the way we're doing that is the following so we start
formed by the two variables d
d c
c a and the b and that's what
i was here and similarly for the denominator now i see that distance
does not depend on b similarly for the standard default we can cancel them
and we obtain a function which is not dependent on c
so we demonstrate demonstrated that a b and c are indeed independent
given a and b so it's pretty easy way
four marker matter to understand
this is just what i i have shown before by graphically work
i cutting the leak
every time there is
and also
in the past
between the divided ball the time conditions
so in this case
so there is a viable here and i'm not conditioning unit
so the line will be maintained so in order to have independence we have to
again block or the part between our
my voice
is that clear
so on
these might actually give us another way of this or of inferring dependencies in
belief networks i one described here you can it later but the main idea is
to transform your belief two into the
an undirected graph
seven steps
and then use the independence matter that i just described and therefore more coming to
and method might be a bit easier than
the matter that's playing yes earlier really
they exactly the same site yes
but you might sometimes referred to use this
it's this
it's less
mister OK so
let's now i think i have described two type of
graphical models and how do they relate can we always this process
a metal with a markov network the answer is no like let's look at this
example you i have either
which means that
the the joint distribution with factorized this way
right because have
two routes and they
and the cause c which has two parts
now obviously i we want to form
march connector will ever put pen show
on all three valuable that means that they will have a link between all of
and the which means that now
a and b
not be independent anymore
in our region
a and b were independent
now we can also the obvious question
can we express any
mark on that tour we don't believe that and the answer is to gain or
lose we look at the
example in europe
to to have kind
to to transform it into believing that will have to one thing
kind of the same structure so we
we cannot have the link here between b and c and d a d
and also to ensure that the that the model is the graphical model is acyclic
we have two
related to collider
these are just point here a few point in the other direction we get a
cyclic graph
so that means that we will end up with a different set of
dependence independence relations for example
in the original graph b and and c were independent given indeed because i conditional
bought so i can't think here the catholic here while in this
OK is
then divided will be in c would be independent given a the
because if you look at the part
we have collider right in the park with the condition
is it could
c and we we do conditions sorry on this
on the collider the therefore we
we have dependency
please stop it
there is something that is not clear
nest now let's talk about the type of
graphical models
i want to see in this talk mainly the factor graph in a factor graph
in addition to
note we represent random variable with a square known
which represent nonnegative functions
its neighbour viable so for example if i want you to present the nonnegative functions
of a and b
and then we will have
here f two is a non negative function of b
c and d and so on and the john function is obtained by simply the
product of all these factors
so here
factor graph are mainly or use a lot of fun the sun
inference we will see later and you notice the talk about functions not through redistribution
because they're being used also for good
performing efficient computational just probability
so inference problem and i so far as they knew
out to understand i being different graphical models and how to understand the dependencies
as i told you graphical model also
use full because they enable us to develop efficient events i one so now i'm
going to explain a little bit about that
so if this correspond as we
you know by now operations such as computing marginal compute conditional distributions from the joint
distribution in general
inference is very difficult problems and also because we we a machine learning many many
valuable in you know our graphical model normally
the first single connected type of graph
there exist efficient i agree
based on the concept of missing that's what they do i mean by singly connected
graph is significant that the graph is a graph in which there is only apart
from one node to another
can you tell me if this party singly connected yes because i wrote it so
that OK so if i have a link from
the two
i will obtain more to the story from it to be a more typical
the graph is that because there is for example apart
from e to d
discipline going this direction or i can go also from me to the passing two
g so there are two parts
let's discuss about this out to perform inference
in in factor graphs and the concept of message passing let's suppose that we have
for binary body one a b c and d
and our distribution
is factorized this way the means that
i will have a factor graph representation
here where f one
connecting b in the four i factor for this and so on and here i
have only
so if you want to apply this to
during decision error
good to be
how can you really the number of mistakes make and the training set we did
the number of mistakes make on the
however addition problem here
the people that classifier
you have an algorithm that generates classifier
so you have to decide which is your classifier that we're going to
you have options
well one natural option is the last one
you cycle over the training set
and then you take the last one generated the last classified by the perceptron
and then you measure the of that one
but this is not good in statistical
because it's going to be robust enough because it would be very
a question on
not the error but it
i'm going to quickly to show how to get it deleted these in all i
get about the whole point wise
and i wanted to all the probability
so what do you
if it's wide
then it fine
the game
but there are few technicolor things that we'd like to check and see and then
it will be
but now
it's the
on line
the batch
so now
is drawn i i d
from a known
fixed the distribution
on the
b by the cartesian product of
this is based on the label
a little bit but but but
now whenever we have a classifier
we can measure the risk
i know that we are now ready
as a function of directly
this is just the probability began writing in different ways the probability that on a
random x y
drawn by the
prisoners can say that the margin
and no party
well this is the reason for this
the misclassification probability
all the classifiers
so now i would like to really
what what other things i would like to relate
i would like to relate to the
what we have what is that my all and me
well all the learning is me an example of the opposite the symbol of classifiers
so if i run for the prime suspect
my online classifier
perceptron he
twenty like
on any
dream you can will not taking into account cycling seriously new in a moment
wired for i'm think in extreme profanity
i'm running my online classifier
and i'm getting
at this time so that the classifier will have you found something about my very
well as he was funded by the many of these will be
the same is not distinct effect of classifiers
maybe w zero is good for forty one
will be the
OK but i want to do not
multiplicity here
so now i want to relate
i want to relate to the average risk of the classifier here
with the fraction of mistakes made by the online growing
as these five where
so i'll will show you that there
this one is
the average risk of these guys
and never miss beat fraction of mistakes to in be close to each other with
this was giving away
of relating a
useful quantities
at risk
with this statistics
an empirical quantity which is the mistakes if they can serve as around my i
usual way of computing the about
i want to get the takes good proxy for some property that we want to
this proxy is my
this exhibited by fraction of mister
i want to bound this quantity here
so i'm just going to get in this one and this one
and then i introduced this
random variable
he are
WP minus one minus
OK now i go back to my old the notation for
indicator function of b
then the deputy minister one may be on the here
example of the brain
look at these random variable
what's the expectation of a random variable
the expectation of the
we do that is look at the amortized cost of the i th operation
OK what's what's mts
emma tries cost
OK and then we'll make the argument which is the one you always make your
mark price cost down upper bound the true cross
the amortized cost is going to be easier to
OK so amortized cost is just see had to let me
tried lots around here on the right
this is by hand
which is equal to the true cost plus the change in potential
that's just definition of emma ties cost when given potential functions
what is
the cost of operation i
in this context here
we access x
what's the cost of operation i
two times the rank of x which is
two are
so two are
that part of the
well we have an upper bound on the change in potential
it says
so that's two
now it might cardinality
plus he supply
they are very with me
OK so let's not as good
OK that's equal to
two are
two of the size of a
minus OK
i want to plug in for b
it turns out very nicely
i have a
equation involving a b and are
get rid of the variable
size b
by just
plugging that
so what do i plug in here
would be equal to
or minus
the size of a minus one i wrote the other way
and then plus t i
in this sense
or as a plus
plus one
everybody with mister still
an algebra
make sure to the algebraic
OK so that's equal to its mode file this out now
two are
two a here minus
minus a so that for a
in two times my stars minus two are
two times minus one minus two
was minus minus two
plus two
and then i have to be i
that's just algebra
that's not bad we just got rid of another variable
but variables to europe
no matter what the rank was once i know what the number of
versions was here
so that's now
equal to
four a
class two
those two t
that's less than or equal to
four times
four star
STI i
using the fact that our star
is equal to the size of a
plus the size of c
plus one
and that's greater than or equal to
the size of a plus one
so by looking at this time basically
looking at
are a
the fact that
that a
when they do here
so we have our star is greater equal to
eight plus one
right so therefore
eight plus one good
yeah so this is basically less or equal to four a plus four
which is four times a plus one
i should put another out step here
OK because i can if i can verify it like this then then i get
nervous OK
this is basically most for
a plus four that's four times a plus one n plus one is less or
equal to our star
and then to t is at most forty i
so i got this
a so survey see where that came from
but what is our star plus t i
what is our star plus dr
that's just see i start
so the inner ties cost of the i th operation
is it most four times
ops costs
that's pretty remarkable
OK so it cost of the i th operation is just four times
because now course we have to now go through
and analyse the
analyse the
the total cost
but this is now
we basically the mean of each component are quite well separated
on the of similar weight on similar violence
so i want to is basically
part of the brain to sample from it so in this framework the way you
would do it for example
it you would consider sequence artificial target distribution
so that essentially
the target distribution is equal to the likelihood of race to the pole of phi
we're fine between zone one time supply or distribution OK so for
any called one then the target distribution is simply the player
OK on then you consider an increasing sequence of phi and so that will basically
five p define all official target distribution when you have actually phi p one one
o five p of the ties the like you to point out that is the
what you do when you do similar to talk to about it and bring it
to the two things you know the camel
but basically
so paul
for each
usual target distribution pi and on then you use those web move that's all you're
doing actually work on
but i don't musically is that for each of these like you basically MCMC kernel
two footballs like perturbation in the rule and i just used to store the image
processing arrays which is very nice i just use like
some kind of metropolis i think a for all this
these parameters OK
well i don't use these little in kelly's actually already done he doesn't use whatsoever
the geometry of the target distribution which i know is a mixture of twenty four
nodes OK
in proc
basically if i look at the MCMC
OK i told basically that targeted the distribution in the final
target distribution is the posterior distribution of interest then this MCMC kernel or if i
were to use it by itself basically gets taught in one of the local model
of the distribution OK so
if i were to use simple MCMC
these basically
move the MCMC can only not working at all which is like really get stuck
in one mode the distribution because the model very well separated one from each other
and the first
OK so what does it tell like basically using all this kind of artificial
basically target distribution using the sweat move
wait so is simple to devise a simple idea i think on quite powerful so
this is for example here
the marginal posterior distribution of the two of two means OK given up salvation all
i see that a recovery in this case the twelfth mode because i just project
the target distribution in two dimensions so basically
this kind of prior to bring type ideas can be quite willful to express very
naive with quite powerful to exploit actually to explore for sale distribution so that was
the basically
using so we are using over one million so important on you could tell me
i've been using thirty two thousand after distribution is called crazy actually works much less
than that i can use actually fine with more than enough so assume that this
is actually quite a nightmare code OK
well it turns out that this type of categories
can be very
well actually very suited
two GPU actually so
whereas for example what if were to implement this algorithm generate one million so important
of this by using the pilot ongoing algorithm using eight told an indemnity
the temperature of the CPU started you take like sixty minutes
on all the human plane that's on the GPU
it takes you basically two seconds
so it is an example where
basically type of ategories well basically do
use like the
you the GPU is actually quite short on make those secularism which were not necessarily
very interesting before actually really i competitive to state-of-the-art MCMC OK so even using that
by wal-mart thirty an intermediate target distribution it only took me twenty eight seconds to
one my algorithm on the GPU is very nice very power is a board because
now this box over here this acoustic event detector has nothing to do with the
site scientific hypotheses is just a black box we want to be able to feed
and features about the the mean rate of the of the impulses on the auditory
nerve we want to be able to feed and some estimate the perceptual salience of
what's happening and we want to get out some kind of estimate of whether the
order acoustic event was detected or not so we so so we put in whatever
pattern recognition algorithms we can we can and here we take a set of universal
approximators in this case adaboost fed into into a hidden markov model
we train the we train the adaboost hmm hybrid in order to detect events as
well as possible and then we see whether it whether it matches the performance of
human listeners and if so then we determined that in fact this this bar is
important for as an input for the algorithm
i think that's that's the the general structure of
in the center
that's that's in one slide overview that subscription of what i'm going to be talking
about today how do you how do you take a pattern recognition algorithm and applied
in order to answer questions about the real world and here if you the criteria
that you might use in order to choose those algorithms first of all is your
shallow or deep
in a sense a discriminative discriminative algorithm can pattern recognition algorithm is extremely useful if
your hypothesis can be written in closed form
because if it can be written in closed form then the then the error can
be minimized in closed form if not then you may need to invoke some kind
of into intermediate variables and if you need intermediate variables then you need some kind
of bayesian architecture second how much training data do you have in order to learn
the former hypothesis if you have a if you have a hundred thousand training examples
then number one structural risk minimisation is going to be too computationally expensive most of
the time and number two it doesn't make a big difference in fact we don't
see much difference beyond about ten thousand training examples between empirical risk minimization and structural
risk minimisation if on the other hand you have used fewer than a thousand training
tokens than with any good universal approximator you're going to overlap in the database
by by using straight empirical risk minimization
third does your hypothesis depend on time and that is does the past state of
the system contribute to the way it behaves in the future and second there is
is the output of the hypothesis real number or a or an integer and these
last two things dynamic state function range service of binary categorization of all the algorithms
in machine learning into four words that i'm going to use again and again for
the rest of the talk those are classification where the output is an integer and
it has no hidden state regression where the output is a real vector and there
is no hidden state recognition where the output is a series of integers and state
matters and tracking where the output is a series of real valued vectors and the
state of the system matters
and then we have to train them
taking the turn the previous
page and dividing the world into discriminative versus bayesian methods first of all we might
look discriminative methods because they're easy empirical risk minimization using discriminative methods has been was
was solved by the perceptron in the nineteen sixties we essentially to some kind of
universal approximator we
create an error metric and then we
minimize the error metric there at least three or four classes of universal approximator is
available to us so universal approximator is essentially a remand into greater
by the ryman integral theorem any function over any finite domain can be approximated by
an infinite number of tall thin boxes
the sigmoidal neural network actually doesn't model those that it is a series of tall
thin boxes models of this series of tall of tall thin step functions the
the gas mixture of gaussians models in this series of smooth tall thin boxes and
a piecewise constant or piecewise linear systems like classification trees and k nearest neighbors do
actually model functions a series of tall thin boxes
all right i'm going to be talking primarily about sigmoidal networks a mixture gaussians as
we go get the piece need for discriminative training is some kind of a
differentiable error metric and
most of the organs or talk about can be can be trained using either minkowski
norm or using some kind of likelihood function which is
in fact logarithmic minkowski norm so i think asking or so the the best norm
usually the one that we really want is the zero norm we really want to
find we really want to say that the the hypothesis it's the data is correct
if it's exactly equal to the labels that we're trying to get
the problem is that that's not very trainable parametric if in fact the hypothesis is
not exactly equal to the target label what do we do next
and so
and so we have a series of trainable error metrics for example the manhattan distance
in the euclidean distance
we're essentially if we train the neural network to minimize the to minimize manhattan distance
we wind up with a neural network that computes the that computes the ob posterior
or a median of the of the label distribution if we minimize the euclidean distance
we can recreate in neural network to compute the posterior mean of the label distribution
and then finally we apply the chain rule in order to minimize
that is for each of the training tokens until the area starts change stop changing
we take our parameter setting we adjusted in the negative direction of the gradient
we just eight as necessary in order to minimize the minimize the error along the
direction of the line was chosen with the direction of the line is computed can
be broken down because of the structure of the universal approximator so here's where ryman
actually comes in to help us to the universal approximator says that the the functional
approximation or creating is the sum of one of the very very large number of
tall thin boxes and each of those tall thin boxes adjusted only in order to
all in order to approximate the training samples the fall close to the tall thin
box so we compute the derivative of the error with respect to the hypothesis at
that particular
at that particular IP training sample
and then find the gradient of the that that particular hypothesis with respect to the
parameters set
all right see the applications of this in audio processing are so ubiquitous that haven't
so coming near the end of the course
this lecture
well be a mixture of
linear algebra
that comes with a change of basis
and the change of basis from one place to another basis is something
you really do
and applications
and i would like to talk about those applications i got a little bit involved
with compression
compressing the signal compressing an image
and that's exactly
change of basis
and then
the main theme in this chapter
is that the connection between a linear transformation
which doesn't have to have coordinates
and the matrix
that tells us that transformation with respect to
so the matrix is the based
of the of the linear transformation
let me start out with the nice part which is
so just to tell you something about image compression
i was of you well everybody's going to meet compression because
you know that the amount of data
that we're getting
well the these lectures are compressed
ah so that actually probably you see
my motion as chair jerking so i use that word have you have you looked
on the web
i would like to find a better word
compressed let's say so my
that the that
complete signal is of course in those
video cameras and in the video tape
but that goes to the bottom of building nine
and out of that comes
jumping motion
because it uses the standard system for compressing images
and you'll notice that the stuff that sits on the board
becomes very clearly
but it's my motion that that
that needs a lot of bits right
so and if i were to run up and back up there and back that
would be too many bits and they would be
even more
so what is compression mean
ten i mean just think of a still image
and four satellites all and computations of the climate computations of combustion that
computers and sensors of all kinds are just giving us overwhelming amounts of data
the web is to now
some compression can be done with no loss
lossless compression is possible just using
sort of the fact that
there is there are redundancies but i'm talking here about lossy compression so i'm talking
here is an image
and what is an image consist it consists of a lot of little pixels right
maybe five hundred twelve by five hundred twelve
due to the night by two to the ninth pixels
and each
so that this is
pixel number one one
so that's the pixel
if we're in black and white
the typical pixel would tell us
a scale
from zero to two fifty five
so the pixel is usually a value of
a one of the
x y
so this is the i th pixel
it's usually a real number on a scale from zero to two fifty five in
other words to totally eight possibilities
so usually
be again a set of values it may be
whatever the problem requires then
mutation is is
selecting random you certainly returned changing
from zero to one or vice versa
now draws over is believed to be the key operator genetic algorithms
again it mothers a certain processes known from biological
for our algorithm it is important
as it performs
exchange of information between individuals
now how this is done we have and
a simple example here this is the very end of the crossover record simple or
single point crossover
relation consists of
binary strings two of them are shown here as parents
the one on the red one
they are selected randomly in the population
the next
o thing that happens randomly is we select a certain point
crossing site
and what happens finally is that
these two substring
substrings are exchanged so from two parents you get
two offspring
as shown here
and these
two strings
present new points in the search space or new solutions
at this point
that is performing this operation
we didn't check
the quality of the solutions so this is performed syntactically
but just in the next step which would be the selection
bad solutions will be discarded and
good solutions will
to contribute to the next generation
the idea is to combine two
processes one is sort of
random exchange of information and mutating that
which is actually the exploration generating new points in the search space then we get
all the applied the second
step which is selection these models the principle of the survival of the fittest which
means solutions survive and multiply even just like in nature but
best solutions
left out today they
this card
regarding the selection
again many
versions of doing this procedure but the traditional approaches fitness proportionate
which actually means
probabilistic multiplication of solutions
according to their fitness values so fitness is actually a measure of goodness of solutions
again this is the i the objective functions used directly as given by our problem
or some modified form of the first of the dysfunction tailored to the needs of
our specific problems
and with him and so on
so one idea is to implement
these fitness proportionate solutions to the so-called roulette wheel models
what does it mean
first the
theoretical background
if had a population of n individuals
and solutions and strings with this every to
each solution is evaluated according to the fitness function let it be
the function f
if the sum of their fitness values is sigma s
and the average function average fitness is have average
according to this model
the expected number of copies of the
i individual would fitness f i because two this expression now what does it mean
and is the number of individuals in the population
this individual i
with the fitness of i is now
in the selection process we are trying to find how many copies of it will
result from this procedure
so this is divided by sigma after so if we take this two
terms and
or sigma have divided by and this is
just the average fitness so
comparing the
fitness of the particular individuals with the average
determines the probability of multiplication what does it mean
up to size five
unigrams would missing words
bi grams are not the words
three words fourgrams in five
and i think one example presence these fires
look like this
so we see karen makes community
px on the them
two hundred thousand times
or ceramics companies fifty three times and and so on
actually this is grammar school community
and in common because of the three d one
or serve as the inspiration for these are forward disappeared this
particular set of strings appear on the web or in the corpus index
seven hundred ninety
well as we have sixty gigawatts of such
frequency distributions in this is
quite valuable resource for any anybody working in
this is something which you can check
you can download these because simply
o thing is to be with you can order it and you get it for
another level of representation of text representation is part of speech
part of speech text
so here
we go one step ahead from the phrases
so basically
the task here is the following together texts and we would like to assign to
each word in the text that which
denotes type of the work
so maybe i can show the example so these are
types of the words which we usually do it so
we're now adjective adverb pronoun preposition conjunction
inter injection so these are
no no no no adjectives are
the features of the work
a four and so on so basically these are the main the main categories
and now the task of part of speech degrees
tool signed the right categories to each of the words and so this is an
let's see if we have
if you have a sentence
like she ran to the station quickly so that each
it gets its stuck pronouns were preposition adjective noun
usually we deal with the
well because we can have many many coded hand coded rules for
tagging such attacks but usually we do this by
with statistical techniques and
we learned attacker and this would be usually used
it's hidden markov models that link
this so this is something which
well at least next level of a
text representation why we would need this especially for tasks like
named entity extraction truancy and a little bit later
feature selection because the couple of dust which which would use these texts
OK another next level of
text presentation is
one using these taxonomies started designers
what is our desire probably you know from the
book this is
a sort of database which connects the different
the words or phrases
with the same meaning into the same sense and the senses are then interlink some
kind of a higher level structure which see written later on
and on the that the most commonly used general thesaurus is
wordnet which exists originally
it was made in english and now it exists in many other languages eurowordnet has
which covers a lot of
european languages i think check check
language has one things you have pretty strong with asian linguistic here
and so
many other languages have this is
and many many are still ongoing efforts to be so what is what
basically what it consist from four main databases so the database of nouns database of
verbs adjectives and adverbs
and each database consists from
many entries and each entry is
one sense
one senses one meaning of the word
it's a
in a sense because all the synonyms all different words which mean the same
it's a musician instrumentalist player so this would be the sense for
musicians of all these three words which would mean the same or person individual someone