flavor that
research thing as well
we talked about directed graphs and it's very intuitive to try to think of directed
graphs in terms of causal relationships
and you know
inferring causal relationships
this is the fundamental component of both cognition you know human beings and animals are
constantly trying to figure out
causal explanations for what's around them and also the science scientific discovery
is all about discovering causes for facts
so it's important to think about causality and phil david will be talking about that
in the second week
but just to give you kind of a little flavor
although independence relationships might be identical there because of the difference between the graph that
went from smoking
the yellow teeth
and got the win from yellow teeth smoking
so in particular the way to think about these things think of these as binary
that variables
the key idea is to think about
what would happen if rather than just observing these variables we were able to intervene
to actually do something to the setting of the variable
OK so the probability of smoking
given then
that the TV
of the particular person are yellow
it is not the same as the probability of smoking
given that you painted somebody's teeth yellow
OK these are different things so the intervention
of course you know painting somebody's teeth yellow doesn't cause them to smoke i think
my cousin to get upset you wouldn't cause smoke
on the other hand if we think that smoking causes people's teeth to get yellow
then the also
unethical intervention of forcing somebody to smoke
i would presume we
their probability of teeth to be yellow and that
that probability
it would be
the same as if they were
smoking of their own free will
this is a gross simplification but hopefully gives you a flavor for the difference between
just observing
variables and being able to intervene to infer causal relationships
and the key difficulty in learning causal relationships is you might have a causing b
or you may have to be causing a
the problem is you might also have one or any number of hidden common causes
causing both a and b
so observing relationships between a and b
it's very hard to figure out what the causal
link is
all right
i'm just i think i'm just going to skip over well i'll just say a
couple things about this
we just talked about directed graphs what about undirected graphs
so can we do parameter and structure learning in undirected graphs
and the problem with undirected graphs and you know general factor graphs if you just
write it out as the fact that it didn't come from a directed graph originally
the problem is that there's this pesky little normalisation constant k and usually we just
said well that's the normalisation constant maybe we you know we don't have to worry
about it but in very already describes ways of trying to estimate normalisation constants which
you know
it's difficult computational problem to compute the normalisation constant
the problem with parameter and structure learning
is that if you're graph looks like this and each of your factors has some
associated with the then you're normalisation constant
is not constant
with respect to the parameters right
for every setting of
these parameters this whole vector parameters this whole thing has to sum to one
so the normalisation constant z
it is actually potentially very complicated intractable function of your parameters
computing the normalisation constant is computationally intractable usually
for non tree structured graphs et cetera
maximum likelihood methods and bayesian scoring of structures all that becomes formally computationally intractable
and in fact
it's you know there's sort of levels of computational intractability and this is
something that is
even more intractable than than some other problems but it doesn't mean that we can
try to solve it so there are algorithms out there approximate algorithms are based on
MCMC and other methods that are trying to solve these
OK this is an active area of research that
ian marie myself have been involved in
i've done a very good job sort of using at the time without getting into
one bit that i want to talk about that i'm going to
use my last five minutes to go into that just to give you a flavor
so that's the summary of what i talked about today
and we have five minutes
and here's what we're gonna do we have the benefit of videolectures
you can go home
play this
slow down
so i'm going to go through this really fast and to try to do this
in five minutes
and then you can have a coffee break to recover from it and for me
to recover as well
let me just tell you about something really fun it's work in progress we don't
even have a paper on it but the reason i'm talking about it and first
of all what i should say is that this is with co-authors ryan adams and
hanna wallach who deserve all the credit OK
and the reason i'm going to talk about this is that it's something that brings
together a whole bunch of topics that are covered in the lectures
in these two weeks
so the topic is learning the structure of deep sparse directed graphical models
so what is that
well the reason i'm talking about is because
it has to do with graphical models
it's related to deep belief networks which have hinton is going to talk about next
we use markov chain monte carlo methods and some nonparametric bayesian model
so all these things come together very naturally to solve this problem
it could be one
the possible i can values are
and minus one
i n minus
and no others right
now other slice that this this is
see why that is
while suppose we have an organ value and i can vector suppose so really this
is the reason that
so why
if if i have the will and x
all apply here and again i would have square attacks
what i what i learned from f squared x
it would it would be lambda square right because it would be lambda fx but
the fact is another landslide so i lambda square next me jumped after the four
facts i would learn that that was planned for facts
but now if f
if i had this incredibly
special situation
where the fourth power has come around to the identity
and this would be x so i learned that lambda therefore so
lambda therefore it has to be one
and if lambda fourth is one of those are the only
four possible landing
first of all we have a by a matrix are actually we have n by
n matrix for every n
the this is through these are the four organised
so what
what puzzle could remains here
but i'm going to ask you about
this is true for any n any and it's true for any n
and that is
i agree so that
i did you might try to prove that
i guess
maybe have square is minus
five right
i remember i
if f squared is minus side and then we're certainly got after fourth nailed
i think maybe half squared is minus site
and forces
that would be that should be fun to
to prove
but it gets let's take that as something we can check
and then that tells us what the possible organ values are so one of the
questions could i
i could ask about the multiplicity is exactly
and that's there's an answer for that
you know
let's see if any a by a since forgoes evenly the weight i suspect that
the the reach multiplicity two but my memory doesn't know this isn't the problem i
really know about
i think an otherwise there's you know then them
if it's an by and
and and and four doesn't go
even in the way and then we've got some
you know we've got to make the count right but it's no
what is known
in a satisfactory way at least as far as i can tell and i
had just had occasion to look through various
it is one of the eigen vectors
we've got the i mean it seems amazing to me
we've got the organ values
we know the multiplicity and that is checked out
but what watson nice description of but straightforward description of the eigen vectors
we've chosen one
in that basis
we write
we write the signal in that basis and that's what my lecture that's the math
part of my lectures
now here's the application part
the next part is going to be the compression step
and that's the last thing
we're going to lose information
and what what will actually happen at that
well one
o thing we could do is just throw away the small coefficients
so that would be
that's called threshold thresholding we set some threshold
every coefficient
basis vector that's not in their more than the a threshold value
and we set some threshold so that are i can see the difference whether we
throw away that
our can hardly see the difference whether we throw away that little
a bit of that basis vector keep it
so this compression step
compressed set of coefficients just keep going here
so he was going this compression step produces some coefficients c that
and with lots of with many zeros
so that's where the compression can
probably there is enough of this vector of all ones we we very seldom throw
that away
usually it's coefficient will be large
but the coefficient of something like this
that quickly alternating vector
there's probably very little of that in any smooth signal i mean that's high frequency
this is this is low frequency zero frequency
this stuff is the highest frequency we could have an
there's all the noise the
gender is producing
that sort of
output but a small lecture like this one is very little of the highest frequency
very little noise and this like OK
we throw away whatever there's and we were left with just a few
coefficients and then we
a signal
using those coefficients we take those coefficients times
there basis vectors
this some doesn't have sixty four terms anymore
probably it has about two or three terms
so that if we say it has three terms
from sixty four down to three that's compression of twenty one to one
that's the kind of compression you're looking for
everybody is looking for that sort of compression
let's see i guess i met the problem with the FBI
and fingerprints
so there's a whole lot of still images you know you with here some you
make these
inky mark
go somewhere
used to go to washington gets stored in a big five
so washington header file of thirty million
murder is
cheetahs on with there's other stuff
and actually
there was no way to retrieve them in time like so so exposure at the
police station
it's OK this
a person may have done this
check with washington have they got are suffering his or fingerprints on file
washington will know the answer
within a week
with if it's got filing cabinets full of fingerprints so of course the natural step
is digitized
so all fingerprints are now digitized
so now it's is fully least electronic
but still
there's too much information in each
each one i mean you can search through that many
if you if
the digital images five traf were
by five elsewhere if it's that many pixels
you get compressed so the FBI had to decide
what basis to choose
four compression of fingerprints and then they built a big new facility
in west virginia
and that's where
fingerprint now suppose that so if you
i think if you get your finger princeton now at the police station
if it's an up-to-date police station it happens digitally and the signal is sent digitally
and then west virginia to compress and index
and then
if they want to find you they
i can do it within minutes
that within a week
OK so this compression is
comes up or signal for images
for video
which is
like these lectures
there's another aspect
you could treat the video ones still
image after another
and compress each one
and then
run them and make of it
but that missus
well you can see why that's not optimal
in video
so for instance in the video
o thing you you you you have
a sequence of images
the video is really a sequence of images
what about
one image to the next image
there are extremely correlated i mean that getting an image every split second
and also i'm moving slightly that's what's producing the
jumping motion on the video
i'm not like
you know each each image in the sequence is pretty close to the one before
so you have to use like prediction
and correction i mean you might
the image of me
one instance one time step later you would assume would be the same and then
plus small corrections
and you would only
code and digitize the correction
and compress the correction
the sequence of images
it's highly correlated and
that problem and compression is always to use this correlation is fact that
in time or in space
things don't change instantly
are very often smooth changes
and you can predict
one value from the previous round
OK so that's the those are applications
which are pure linear algebra
i could maybe i maybe allow me to tell you the
and the book describes
new basis
the competition for four
so the competition for four e a is called wavelet
and i can describe what the basis is like saying the eight by eight days
so that a by a wavelet basis
is the eight is the vector of all ones eight ones
and the vector of four one and four minus one
then the vector of
two ones include minus one thousand four zeros
and also all the vector of four zero
good morning everybody
you know what it's like when the conference organizer ask you to give the keynote
and you say ok big honor like to do it and that i shall ask
me all this is the tenth anniversary can you use that as part of the
theme of your presentation and all by the way can you also give me a
so by the time you only have the vaguest idea what you want to talk
about you know you have to keep you happy so
you give some title and then a few weeks later you get what the french
call this as this clear which is the idea is you get on the stairs
walking back home you know all the things you should have said
and then i realized what the title should be
so the title is not what it says your program something about universal patterns the
title actually is
ten years of semantic web
does it work in theory
so what i want to do in this talk
is back
at ten years of our work
and i'm not going to celebrate our successes because they are so obvious they don't
need to be stressed it's obvious
because we have done a good job as engineers we have built
really successful very large artifact but the question for this talk will be done any
every besides building anything
if we
learned anything
that is of
permanent value
this is going to be no by definition this is a pretentious talk right so
it's always science conference
it's always pretentious to talk about science instead of just talking science and
with some trepidation i i started this talk and i'm not the only one so
jeff norton who is a leading researcher in the database field
last year i think it was that i see the two thousand ten he also
gave a talk
about science in this case it was about the scientific process
and how we organize it and he started
with an introductory slides that i thought was very appropriate so i for freely borrowed
this slide from him so what he said was well when he announced that he
was going to give this talk to a colleague so the first response he got
from a colleague was called i i look forward to it
he's said this to another colleague but then also explained what he was going to
talk about
and the response was oh how are you ever going to make this interesting
and then you
tried it on the third colleague
and the response was well jeff
you've now reached the age where you're old enough to scratch about in public so
go ahead
and maybe the most disheartening response was for it he announces plans to a senior
colleague and emeritus and response was this don't do it
now given the keynote anyway means you are a washed up has-been so
but but notice the floor piece of logic in this right so
even without giving the keynote you could still be washed up has-been
so in that case you might as well give the keynote as well
so that's the plan
talking about
generic los junior close science lots of computer science before i
i can talk about generic laws of computer science i i need to make it
philosophical confession right i need to explain to you where i stand on this idea
of of of what science is
so here's my view of science
what's called the philosophy of scientific realists
and i'm even naive scientific realist maybe i'm even happy naive scientific realists so what
scientific realism
so here's a quote from the stanford handbook of philosophy
it says
philosophical realism
it is the belief that our reality is ontologically independent from what we think
just to quickly summarize
so we thought what concepts the empirical risk EX
o point six functions
the actual risk
also to do this
one of the principal one principle
to estimate function which we have low actually
they only knowing the training examples
the principle of the minimum here
just saying we would like to have a small risk
because his
we can compute the dangerous with it simply minimize our here over the last
get a function which we hope will small actually
i already told we minimize
here it is
what resulted was it depend on the size of
first of all because the are lots of the function class the the more likely
it is that we have to have more here
from that point you would appear to be with
and then you get with this small here
but it turns out in the theory there's a lot of the more likely to
cause but there's a lot of that
the more likely it is that you have to choose one for which the difference
between a terrorist activities is large
you would like look at the same time would have liked
it allows you to get a small
at the same time
he class which is small enough such that the rest of the challenge
and now analyse how it works well because
based on the law of large numbers
recall that one function the members flows from process
basically we to generalize this to many functions or even if many functions
OK so the analysis works as follows
first of all
find this shorthand i
for the zero one loss
so i is the zero one loss of the training examples x i y i
so whenever it is correctly classified
this training example
loss is zero whenever incorrect losses one
now if of is fixed
if all x i y i independently sampled from online distribution
then the squid is phi and also independent of each other
and they have another property of course also called the files because the values of
plus minus one
these are independent bernoulli trials
so this is
on the statistical point of view the same thing
as a consequence
potentially a biased coin something like that
so it's a random experiment which is the result zero one
the empirical means if you
he was
so why always plus one one
you can also define last one of them
in which case you would have a hard here
so my question is that the plus one minus one
must i would have so that this thing is zero
so this is like a contrast
so your fuzzy kind
then you can do things like to compute the mean
how do you get heads or tails
over n coin tosses
we consider the empirical mean of this
quantity of this random variable
then by definition we get a terrorist
of the function f so
live in
this definition of course i here
it exactly what you see in greece before
likewise if we compute the expected value of this thing
it was a
many examples of the mean
averaged over the unknown underlying distributions
you get the
for are
all question of studying how the risk and the risk relate to each other
is not transformed into the question of how
empirical mean
all this only variables
converges to their expectation
big the difference can be things like that
others a classical bond in probability theory
was proved by
how much what still alive is a few years ago it was
this is an example of what people call it a bond
roughly speaking to because of the distribution of the
if you for your kind
many many times the distribution will be more and more people the point is if
you have a fair coin toss your clients
in the two thousand ten times it will get
seven times and every time they
if you toss it one thousand times
you will not get seven hundred ten thousand three hundred maybe
five hundred three and four hundred ninety seven or whatever so you will if it's
the distribution will be more and more sharply concentrated around the expected value
and the way to describe how concentrated distribution is around its expected value is is
simply by giving up bound how likely tails are tails of the distribution of everything
that's far away from the expected value
we would like to
limit the probability that
you empirical mean here
the expected the expected value
by more than epsilon
and telephone tells us that this probability is found
by this exponential term here
this is nice because you see
the number of files goes to infinity then this is your very fast
exponentially fast
for each fixed epsilon because we can't put it down zero because otherwise the material
we can put aside any small number that we like this thing to
so this is one is quantification of all past
large numbers works
the first is this in your hand notes this slide
mistakes like to tell me
OK so
OK maybe a little bit about the this notation so here i have put p
which is also probability
strictly speaking this is not the same
probability that about four
member of the board probability measures
government the random experiment whole the x y here were generated
because here is the probability measure over n
here's of x y is a product measure
it's interesting to note that the extreme this is an extreme terms way and according
to entire according to pi star
is an exchangeable at the current time according to
so i'm going to have this
this some
this will be
one of the elements the first element
the first
term of the sound and this will be the last element in the last term
of the sound
and in between i have all these things that i've inserted which is of the
possibly money-spinner posse manor c
OK and then
what's going to happen is
and note that
and active according to high
the first team minus one time steps
in each of these
two expectations
that means that
the difference
in these two the expected sum it's going to be entirely due to how it
behaves after the first human s one time step because
expectations just equivalent to the first team at one time step straight so that means
that can limit
the range of the sound from t primality
and then that's the definition of these it
OK so you think about this
one way to think about this is that kind of an unconstructive reduction of reinforcement
it says that there exists some constant classification problems since the cell them well
piece of reinforcement learning
really tell you how to do it
if you
happen to have an optimal policy around at training time
like maybe
maybe alex smola is
who started the machine learning summer schools knows how to get to the next
so you can tell you how to get the next given your individual actions
based upon your
upon by his guidance you can derive a good policy
the this this kind of approach
before reaching the next
OK and
we need to think about what we can do in in kind of a constructive
so this is
this is
it is maybe of inspirational says that there exists some constant the classification problems is
the solved the of reinforcement learning but it we need to think about how to
actually draw samples from these distributions nor two
to construct this policy which will behave optimally
i'm gonna go through
a huge tricks people have
people have thought about for trying to do this
in general all this analysis
it is going to apply to the fall
reinforcement learning problem
which is is it's good compared to what i talked about earlier right
the earlier is talking about markov decision processes which is a very limited form
however we can rely upon having a generative model for that trace my so the
trace model
what you do is you you just you're behaving you're acting directing and acting is
a stream of experience
the generative model
you have got a more powerful mechanism for interacting with the world
you can now
you can now say suppose that i have some history of observations
it takes an action then what happens next
and you can say
suppose i have the same history of interactions take some other action
for the
the general case you going get through square
OK so
so that that's that's the basic budget and hopefully it's simple enough that
it's very clear now
the bank several people have mentioned that there are sort of the limitations of one
sort or another
so the question is what's wrong with this
what you mention out
so you can reuse the previous state seems kind of weird
we have the samples from this set the recursion and we just ignore them for
the next recursion
it seems to baltimore
potentially suboptimal
what else is wrong
the computation is certainly as pretty substantial issues
because we're sort of enumerating
passes checking the upper and lower bound and
this is a
one issue
what else is wrong
it's actually amazing how many things are on the the side of the several more
this is something that i had from you entirely
which is the label complexity
you have infinite labelled data
to measure the disagreement
regions size to infinite precision
we can do is unlabelled data is just checking to see if there exist two
parties disagree
but what we can rely on
an arbitrary precision
computational issues
several different able complexity issues we're throwing away examples is i pointed out
what we didn't do very well when we want to
have the
so on
with the best which is smaller than the
it's kind of weird
and then of course if you care about solving real-world problems often you care about
things other than zero one loss
the sort of the whole space of things
which were not even addressing
OK so to the that the
almost all of these have been addressed
so is the this paper is about generating generalization of power
not notable case
and there they deal with the label complexity problem it partly due to the computational
this paper is a seat belt also deal the computational problems in a different way
the the first label complexity problem turned out to be unreliable
you can get rid of it
under current assumptions
so the lower bound saying you just can't get along the and so on are
small compared to here
human married
the derivation of cal uses all the labelled examples
which is nice
one one issue which comes up mention is these
upper bounds and lower bounds are often quite loose
and people try to make algorithms based upon these bounds of it's it's not
i mean you worked on the slide of course some work and
you know something we succeed but to some extent they are still on the loose
and we would like to do
we mean what it means that we very pessimistic as for more labels into really
i don't know about the model
maybe something like that could work but
OK so
one way to
deal with this what the signal in some sense the the that you can use
importance weights
and you can you can play games of importance weights you say the samples much
more important than that one because i had a very low probability of a single
and that will help address the smoothness and these bounds
and then you can also you can also deal with
other loss functions
OK so
you've already seen a calcined rhythm there's a generalization of it involves more analysis for
nonseparable case
so what i'm going to do is show you
we discussed this this newspaper which uses
the importance weights
o but i guess first necessary about the lower bound
OK so
money had a lower bound which which we generalize a little bit so that had
the VC dimension
because the basic claim is
for every hypothesis space with some VC dimension
amount of regret and what you said about these
for every minimum error
among the regret is less than
the minimum area divided by two
you can construct a distribution d
so is that all active learning algorithms require
the times
new squared over epsilon square
labelled samples
six you probably on with
with reasonable probability
OK so
so this is to get an occasion
there was the these calloused rhythms
and one the claims
for the non several were nonseparable version of the cap
two thousand seven
what is
done most often is defined sliding windows
last three hours
and you can define landmark windows from september for first
up to to now
the window specification
can be done
i with physical type
with the data
we have logical type
number of items
so usually when
you want to queries three new defined window on the
and the second thing you have to do when you queries three
it is to define when you want to have the reserve
do you want to have the results
every time one element and has one three or you want to have the reason
that some regular intervals so this is the
we fresh and refreshing
so the rate of producing research
every ten items or every minute every hour
so here is an example of a sliding window
so we suppose that
this is the current time
we have defined window to be the last three hours so we provide research
and if there refreshment refreshment time is this
then at
plus the refreshment time we will provide the new uris but
for this period which has been like
now we know everything about
structure data streams
and we we can now talk about
data stream management systems
for data stream management systems
and the outline will be the following so there will be two parts of the
user point of view how do we use this system
and the
computer scientist point of view how is it
and then i will finish by
giving names of
several existing system
so the the definition of a DSMS
it can be done in contrast with database management system
in database management systems you have the data model or you can put what you
want to know the relations in the database you have the structure
data is stored in the on this and you can access data with language and
usually the extra language
and if ten shows you that you have good performance
good response time even with large volume of data
data stream management system
we should be we provided data model
it's going to to provide the same doing data model as a standard database management
the between structure
it's going to be able to store
then the relation
which are permanent
these systems will be able to process streams on the fly
i mean without storing all data arriving in the
in the history
they will provide
and this fear language SQL like language which has been extended
applied to streams and especially by
windowing features
the added to the standard SQL language
we will see that
queries some streams
i will not be the same as querying
prominent data
a new concept has been introduced this is the concept of continuous queries
in the data stream management systems you will find some tools for capturing input streams
so usually input streams
arrive in
in internet ports in machine
so the a data stream management systems provides connectors
o ports and ways to decode the structural
of data arriving in football
into the structure which has been defined for the stream in the system
it matters
data stream management system as given
good performance
that's a demise in computer resources
in the case of one three
several streams several queries on several streams
and last thing process you can
is the ability to face variations in arrival rates without any crash so this would
be important point because as you
i said
in the first slide we can not
and control
arrival rate of breakers in the system
now we
i'm going to talk about
data stream management system data model or
so in fact stand
you will find
i could you know i could run myself but then they would look horrible basically
you know
it's an icon
thank you for your so
right so to but in particular what we're trying to do here we're trying to
represent a mapping from state and action to a probability distribution over states but were
uncertain about the probability distribution so we need a distribution over the distribution and that's
what they're actually does for us
keeping track of this sort of stuff is actually keeping the posterior is actually very
nice it just counts so that's good work by keeping this count we can recover
how much uncertainty is still at any point in the learning
which is good unlike example the distributions over an infinite set
which you know turned out to be sort of nice you can still keep these
probabilities but imagine doing that planning things that you should before we're now instead of
having that little vector over
the two numbers well i guess you can still keep it you can use either
side represent as well so you can still plan out in the posterior using the
dear so representation
OK so
that doesn't change things all that much and there's a bunch of bayesian reinforcement learning
papers that that hard use this representation of the posterior
there it it really hard to plan and the resulting space
the best
that i've seen out there is a relatively new to a couple years ago
pascal poupart et all
i have an when called beetle
which tells all talk about a lot of people have tried to approximate the result
of the value function for the resulting
infinite dimensional MDP in various ways but this is this one seems to be the
most successful so far so they basically use some of the latest ideas from solving
continuous partially observable markov decision processes
so if the if in the discrete model that i should in the beginning with
the tree and so forth really what we're trying to do is planning to pompey
we we had uncertain information about our true state what's the probability with which model
we really and and we don't know so we have a distribution over that planning
the probability space is what
it what upon the model is about but since now we're working in a continuous
the parameters of probability and we probably over the probability are actually talking about it
you know to high dimensional continuous
partially observable MDP soap on regular police family basically impossible to solve but then you
can make and continuous
what is a continuous over right so so
in the standard palm BP have the discrete distribution over the like the world in
the case that we've got its that's not in the real power and punjabi we
do these estates of the world in this example we're actually talking about models which
MDP or we can we don't know which MDP were and so we have a
distribution over which MDP we might here
one that's just the distribution over models but
but that's only if you have a discrete set of models there's model a b
c and d if if the general space of mdps are parameterized by continuous quantities
which to say well what's the probability if i'm in the state i go to
that state said writing down to model
an MDP model requires writing down a bunch of real numbers
and so now
our uncertainty and that is the distribution over the real numbers
so that's the sense in which it ends have been continuous
there are i guess we're representing things dear size it's not we just you basically
have like an m squared times
a kind k kind of thing
and i think we're keeping count anyway they're not actually continuous values that just
there's numbers but the numbers without bound infinity
it's still an infinite MDP just i guess the discrete infinite MDP
countably infinite
the head of the back
it seems like you could use entropy is
entropy is i tell which world tells how confused we are about world around them
the entropy of one
one of the actions decrease the entropy dramatically that we're saying
so so right so a good heuristic is often
if you've got time for it take some actions to reduce the entropy
it's a heuristic it actually solve this problem but it but it is useful anyway
and symmetry is very nice
for calculations because when you have this symmetry can simplify your problem and divided by
two you get only had and then you can use the other one
by symmetry so if you break everything
you have to calculate everything and it's quite difficult
so these are one dimensional here
but i presented but you can constraint as many called you can put as many
constraints as you want
this is for example of potential energy landscape for uranium two hundred thirty eight
you have here is very city here in
treat this elongation
and here we previous this asymmetry
you see here is the ground state for years isomeric well this symmetry here leading
to two symmetric fragments
but you see here that you have another value here
that is developing and it's even lower in energy than it will end with a
small from big one
so you see here that we these degrees potential energy landscape
you can explain
while the nucleus is going to have
asymmetric fission was a small fragmented way it's because of that results so it's lowering
energy so these
but here is much more favor than this one
so we it
constrained the calculation you can explain many features that are sears
in the UK
of course when you have deformation you had this thing about is that the way
so this is the story cities so this is an instance died schematic
but this is very simply so you have generate c and then when you increase
the formation of the
then the liberals to go down so they completely make
so it's magic numbers here
explain that recently so the difference in energy between two level
so they become negligible
and sometimes you have new gaps that do appear so here not so
but you have some time to get
these are some real calculations from microscopic calculations populations four
seven million one hundred fifty four
and you see that here you have no doubt that do appear for
so this is elongation some deformations
so that's why tomorrow i will talk about exotic nuclei as search the search sorry
for new
quite magic nuclei so very stable nuclei
due to these properties
the spherical cap disappeared when you have some fun here you can find new gaps
of new
big stability for new nuclei
of course
with this deal with this mean field can go beyond introduce some exhibitions
there are two types of approaches
if you want to consider only these
individual excitations so you promotes some nuclear
it is or what is done
is what we call a p
you can introduce these
large amplitude correlations so
especially when you have constraint
care it's very easy to introduce these vibrations
so then you have access to to individual excitations and collective states
and this is the results obtained with these the all mean field calculations
where what is calculated is the first collective state rotational vibrational
positive states and you see you have different states here
which have been calculated
no question why in the nuclear shape pertinent
how can it help for
comparison between theory and experiment
it's because you have some more than others
which explained that for a spherical nuclei you
so second i cannot rotate because you don't have
because of quantum mechanics you you need to have differently i too have excited states
with rotations
so it's very good media it's vibrational spectrum which is
proportional to all these
two these
i'm government to sorry exhibition energy proportional to the angular momentum so you have equally
for the former nuclei
you have rotational spectra perpendicular to z
to the axis of the main axis of the nucleus
evolution axis and you have the spectra which is proportional to that so you have
this because he's not equally spaced at all
so if i take back to two examples of last time less course
these were some i one hundred forty eight and gadolinium
one hundred sixty you see that here
pos and you you have equally spaced
so these we'll be associated to spherical nuclei
four gadolinium you have very nice professional so
jim jeffries one
this is these are
the most famous example is very passionate about rational
in many many nuclei you have something mixed between repression rotation and vibration
but can help for example this is a summary of isotopic chain
from one hundred forty eight so the one that presented before
to one hundred fifty four
and you see that you have to change between the
vibrational spectra to repression picked from here
in this case here
and you see that
with very
you can reproduce here that it's very cool and then you have for this one
hundred fifty
the name which is a little bit different
and deformations in creating really really crazy
all these states are located in this way so there really are different of the
correspond to fashion brand
so all these effects are very
this structure is very very important because imagine here
you only ten six k and so you have
around one hundred fifteen pounds chance sixty and you have something
completely different
to keep multiple parts trees for partial plans and they use the same knowledge in
this bottom-up fashion
what that is it what you believe in good ways of using the site but
i said in in one kind of conjures up the idea of hierarchy that actually
just kind of the knowledge the idea of grammar and if you're learning that you
might want to learn hierarchical task networks
when you look at lands and you see this regularity all the plan that people
seem to be doing it and travel plans they don't seem to keep on making
cycles there's just one more or less go straight and so you would generate hierarchical
task networks which will ensure that such plans be
you are you could try to learn the grammar of the correct solution solutions and
that's not possible
then i said is and the idea called shop which is some sort of how
to cope plan but it's quite different from the sort of constant reduction schemas what
they want to be doing is not only do this say
not only do the same
how do you
he and commit action and between primitive actions they also value
if you have this cool first applied this
if it works then try this
if it doesn't work then try this one so they giving and bad policy there's
no search left anymore the search is now
but in the program that the shop land right so here is actually a shop
land about travelling and you know it is that is that it did not travel
by bus only if going by that doesn't work
so it's been set up front so you almost giving much more a
much more of a controlled the the search for your neurons search for
so think of this as you know if you don't like c like shop you
write your plans planner in shock
surprisingly shop planets do better than normal HTML elements
because i'm giving even more probable planning to my so sampling the planet one
if you don't like extended knowledge to
that in some of which also can be learned it in remember the reason i'm
telling you all this stuff is all the things that you can learn
and you can start thinking in the back of your hand how do i learn
this sort of knowledge you know plan examples
OK so you could learn how to hierarchical schema you can learn invariance you could
say well in this domain are you know if took a truck is the locations
one and i cannot be that simply cannot be location this may not be present
in the domain physics but you look at the the main i mean you look
at the deductive closure of the domain and figured out that no such state at
what seems to be reachable from any legal state
OK you might want to learn and that's a useful thing because then in in
if you are doing planning especially in the backward direction
you might find that you have a state which actually is not it will never
get the initial state because it assuming that well i want because of this section
i want to be location one at the same time on the the location and
the search happily expanded by the end of that and take their child and you
know it's better to cut your losses and get revenge
and if you have this knowledge
can you can learn rules about optimality saying do not have package two
at the same location
you could learn i mean fact saying learn what people write in the knowledge base
planning black people actually write these things for each you can then apply these kinds
of simplifying assumptions saying one step back is lauded it should immediately move
nothing really makes that happen in the domain physics you know you can load the
park and
keep bi together that's what you know it it seems like a good idea to
move it
you know i remember that when you do this you are cracking down some solutions
we just solutions in the most recent syntactic sense if you do this you get
to the goal said but you don't like it similarly similar to my saying about
it and i really don't like walking presented even though that's a syntactically correct
so once again these kinds of you know actually knowledge communities
this is the other one that i mentioned earlier you could write rules about
state sequences that are not good
this sequence of that
in particular you really want to write articles about state sequences that are not
OK so that if you have progression plan and if you find that a particular
class particular brand seems to have a set of six states which winds up violating
a rule already
then you can
OK to do that in a sense you end up writing these rules about state
sequences in this case in a linear temporal logic habits for example here is and
that it is an example of this knowledge if you e on
then please wait until on citizenship
just increasing the size by looking at the bigger balls or is it because there
is some interesting property within those borders
and you not of justify prior
just get guidance
i mean this was a bit of repetition of
what i said before so maybe a
and you will see the slides if you want to
read them
i went into the kind of important messages and then we try to save
some time for questions and also to give you but the thing that they have
taken in the first lecture
OK so it's here i cannot help justify our prior what can we do
this is the problem right
the whole
the game of machine learning is
you have you are given the problem that you have to solve this is to
find a good classifier are good predictor
good model for that problem
and the whole idea is to find
i mean OK if you are bayesian you have to encode your knowledge input prior
and if you're not the bayesian it's a matter of you know
trying to figure out how best to use the knowledge that you
because of course if you don't know anything about the problem the problem can be
anything and
i don't know algorithm which allows you can try your
the favourite algorithm can fail SVM with gaussian kernel
and that might work but it does work it the reason why would work is
your problem magically has the right property of
you know
the target function most with respect to the euclidean distance because in the past colony
of being in this so if it happens that
the have this example again
if you happen to have a target function which is
very close
then of course if you use the gaussian kernel which is trying to and you
maximize the margin which means minimising the norm in the RKHS and of course
if you have the time
on that
target function
and you try to fit these data with this was function
you might get to the right
but what if your target function
is not small with respect to this euclidean distance but smooth with respect to just
another that you don't know
right let's say
that same year function is most with respect to the hamming distance
in the binary expansion
of the exit
right so you take x
you might be these binary representation
let's so you're between zero and one in particular the decimal expansion in binary
if you xis and then
you're looking at the hamming distance between two axes and that's your notion of similarity
and you have a target function which happens to be small
with respect to
this is the which means like if you change just one between this expansion is
a change in a bit
the times the value of the function does not change much
this is the case then you would have a target function which
you know
it looks like this
and practical
and i think
so of course if we use some data
from that
and you try to that was function you don't get the right thing
you just from that no matter
even the tomorrow almost they you get what i mean eventually you might want to
because you know the gaussians can approach arbitrary functions one the
i think of
whereas if you knew the right
the notion of was that if you knew this
that you should be looking at the binary expansion
and you can call that into your prior or in your kernel
then you might immediately with very few points find the right thing
how can you choose between those two how can you like if you come
one comes with the problem how can you tell where this is the i mean
which kernel is the best
well you can't apart from real trying things and playing around or
asking the expert about what he knows about the problem in this kind of thing
so that's why i think it's more an art than a science you can't really
prove anything or justified
i mean is some
bayesian with the if your rationale
you can do it in the sense that
rationale meaning
there is some kind of
maybe even a single way
to go from what you know
the writing the right prior
that's fine but
depends on what you know
maybe another way to say that is when you want to design an algorithm
two steps
the first one is to choose this preference for this
the notion of your prior similarity measure whatever
you know there is no guidance i mean is there's is no
true but you can get some guidance maybe you're looking at about that
but you know some people get very intrusion from
there're some people
i get the impression from practice and just that's fine
here is not only way
and then you have to exploit
reference for different and that's where you can maybe formalise a little bit more
and you know
improve results of the four OK within that's
common within that
choice that i made because i choose the margin as my criterion or because i
was the kernel of something that is
i can prove that what i'm doing is not too far off from what i
would do in if i am
seeing the whole distribution that's the only thing that can say and you can also
see how these things are different like what you're doing on the empirical data and
what you would do if you want full knowledge of the distribution and get from
their sum from
one thing which is important is also the computational cost i will not enter into
for this but
you know that that is really an important part of algorithm design you may
OK so where we want to go
OK when left
wait wait don't go up again you just said well
right right
right right it's gone but did you have thought before it was gone
there was only structure to this crazy crazy world
circle seem to be plant friends are really was that try again
right well that's what
that's a lot
you have to get
down left
left left left left OK we hit the wall once in that trial and in
fact i suspect will never hit the wall more than once again
people thinking up
left left left i get what do you think what's happening on that we don't
have any
but it was probably the diamonds yeah
you don't know just
i had left and right columns because they put
it's safe
right right
OK so that was diamonds
well anyway we do a bunch of a bunch of these
and it turns out you can't even kill them they come back anyway
there's ultimately this ten of them and the last in the last one and i
think classes is the is the wall and the reason i tell you that is
because i done this in the following setting is the same series of mazes for
all the different people i tested on but i very
the wall rules in the three worlds so in the first world and we did
world two by the experiment experiment one every screen it was always plus that was
the wall
OK so you can imagine that you would have picked up on that right in
experiment two
it was always one shape was either plug this state being plus shaping circle the
shaping diamond and once you get the hang of that you only make one mistake
right once you realize what's going on you hit that shape and then you say
there are lot of the project and you see world laws are in the new
pottery at least that's what people in my study didn't look like that's what you're
doing is well experiment three was different
there was always some feature so it's either fish that would one of the particular
shapes one of the particular background colors are one of the particular foreground colours
OK so there's really twenty seven different combinations of cell types but what people and
that one realizes that is always
is the background color a specific value back cover color for color the shape and
so they will make maybe two mistakes over bump into something and they was know
was that because the color or the shape or the background color the thing that
i just here and the hit something else and noticed that there was something in
common between the two of them and then they see all the walls and they
thank you
the new ball is
to get i'm not as far as i know
i did hear someone say oh yeah i know the problem it can the wall
can be a circle on this because circle you on the goals would be unreachable
all the all the color of the patterns that are used it was the same
ten may sixteen ten pictures for all the people so they ended up usually having
with this one solution to one side the other that's why this two goals by
way so just one more
sure we can i think i think if we do we could turn this into
a group brainstorming session to make a sellable video game but the point of this
was something a little bit different which was that the last maze for all three
groups of subjects now i say subject that's really unfair because it was like my
kids into my students it was i got moderate amount experimental psychologist so i don't
know how to actually do this but what i do is i run you know
my friends on it and then i make generalizations the talks which is kind of
like the a really bad psychologist but what would be interesting thing was the last
maze for all the subjects it was always plus that was the wall right through
because the experiment when people had to be plus experiment two was always the shape
and close shape experiment rate was always some feature that feature
and what would happen is they make depending on what they maze that they saw
leading up to the last one they make no mistakes one mistake or two mistakes
say maze same population of people probably but different prior experience coming into k so
they can ever changing either
exploration behaviour depending on the kinds of worlds that they were expecting
and and i think that's the real thing in the real world that we
learn from past experience and applied to new tasks right and this is partly why
i think yesterday the taxi worldwide so well with the with the group because we've
seen things like that and we know what kind of things to expect we didn't
want to bump into the walls yes sure it's possible and in fact i could
give new game where the walls were the goal and eventually we got around to
checking that but that was when you check first you're going to check the things
that made sense and fit with your experience so really what i'm talking about here
is a kind of transfer learning is this idea that you can learn from some
examples to do to do better or faster on some new test problem
we're test problem here is an entire reinforcement learning environment
all right now what's interesting is that the reason that i bring this up as
a way of transitioning out of the quick work is because we can quickly learn
any of these classes any these three classes we can make a quick learner that
takes advantage of the structure in that class and learns effectively and would do the
same thing is the people here that if the class was you always are going
to see a plus then it would make no mistakes the last means if that
the class was euro should pay attention to shape it would make one mistake on
the last me and if it was feature one that would maybe maybe two mistakes
in the last maze but the thing is
i didn't tell you which class which experiment you're running even though there was such
thing as experiment you're kind of putting this together as you went flexibly and beyond
based on your past experience with other experiments other silly video game thanks to a
quick can't do that take the quick stuff really requires that you specify the hypothesis
class and then learned efficiently with respect to the hardest thing to learn that class
so if we tell well it's possible that the features can matter
then it was it's going to learn like it's in the last class is not
going to take advantage of the fact that there's a shortcut to commit
so what is that sort of lead us to
the following content is provided under creative commons license
your support will help MIT opencourseware continue to offer high quality educational resources for free
to make a donation or to view additional materials from hundreds of MIT courses
this MIT opencourseware OCW that MIT that EDU
we're going to do
the first of three
lectures on the last topic
talk about phase diagram starting today one day
and wrap it up on wednesday
phase diagrams is related to the question of stability
and sustaining the solid state
we've talked about
the behavior of solids
and we have used
solid in order to
teach the rudiments of chemistry but today i want to talk about the conditions under
which solids are stable
but on what conditions do
solids remain stable when they become unstable this important industry for example
running a castrato making auto parts
you want to know what this little vacation temperature is for particular alloy
it's important in failure analysis something like
the fall of the world trade center looking at the metal specimens to determine what
was the mode of failure
the temperature excursions leave signature thermal signature indicative of the history of what happened to
by determining whether something went above a certain phase transformation temperature we can
retrace reconstruct the
the incident
you might say well
what's the big deal i mean if you look on
look up in the tables everybody knows water boils at one hundred degrees centigrade
it's not so simple
let's say decide to realize your
life's ambitions go
climb mount everest so you plot down ten thousand dollars to get a permit from
the nepalese government
the next thing you know you're base camp twenty thousand feet
you have a hankering for soft-boiled egg
jupiter campfire
but in the action
five minutes ten minutes fifteen minutes apart you want hard-boiled eggs
hard world eggs
after fifteen minutes to opening eggs
still running
you really steam twenty minutes twenty five minutes
every time the yoke
it's still running the white convertibility OK still running what's going on while we talk
about the nature in
the white teenagers is sixty five degrees centigrade
twenty thousand feet the atmospheric pressure is reduced to the point that water boils at
the nature in temperature of the egg yolk and so you can boil until the
end of time you always have soft-boiled eggs if you like so well that you
can screw up
you can screw up
so what do we know from this little
and don't
this little anecdote is that the boiling point
the boiling point is a function of
it's not that simple let's go to another place let's go let's go under the
hood of the car and my favorite places OK so here's what's going on under
the hood of the car
here you've got the engine
and inside the engine we combustion the combustion gives off a huge amount of he
we have to dissipate that heat so
we have water channels running through the engine and out
the radiator
and the radiator cools the water before recirculated thanks to the action of either fan
or wind or some kind of movement of air
and so what's the principle here the principle here is that inside
the radiator we've got a solid this is the the rat
it's probably made of
in the old days and the amount of copper but nowadays making more and more
the amount of aluminum and we have liquid which is the cool
this is the coolant this water
and we have a big delta t here
right this is
hi this is cool
so we have a heat flux going in this direction
and this is working great because
the density water is high
and so therefore it's able to transfer heat
very efficiently so this is good
this is really good what can happen if things go out of control things go
out of control and we start to boil
you know the boiling point of water is more or less one hundred degrees centigrade
were down here we're not at the base camp on mount everest here's what happens
when things start to go to control now we start to get gas bubbles
these are the gas bubbles associated with the boiling of water and now the heat
transfer between a gas
and solid
between gas and solid is very poor
think about it what's transferring the heat is the atoms in the atom density in
gasses spas so
gases are very poor heat transfer medium so we must avoid boiling if we get
boiling then we get on with thermal runaway situation because now we got boiling in
the first place because the water was too high but now we're doing less efficient
job of cooling
and it's going to get worse and worse and worse until finally bowl
so what i want to do is i want to get my liquid range
i want to tailor the properties of the cool i want to call it that
will be
boiled over proof
so if i could raise the boiling point that would make the car safer to
drive under extreme conditions typically what happens is your zooming down the highway on a
hot summer's day and there's some reason to come to an abrupt stop and then
there's all that heat to be dissipated
no more you get the benefit of the motion of the cart marriages relying on
the fan so what can we do if we go to the top of everest
and the pressure goes down
and the boiling point falls
could i raise the boiling point by applying more pressure
yeah let's put pressure cap on the radiator let's keep the contents the radiator high
and if you read the talk to say
it is in an environment that provides students with interactive simulations for understanding mathematical function
this is the sample activity in this interactive simulations where for instance here this is
designed to help students understand the relationship between the function graph
and the functional equation and is activity this tuning can move the function around on
the screen
and on the other hand let's see what the changes the corresponding changes in the
creation of the modern or can change parameters in equation and see how that changes
the graph of the function
and what we've been doing in the context of
this interaction we have been trying to experiment with different sources of information on the
students' behaviour during the interaction to see
sources of information can generate can allow user model
to generate better predictions of how much the student has learned
from the given
the interaction section
and we we have experimented with a in just using basic actions so for instance
in the case of example that i showed you are often the student what kind
of parameters justin was changing how the student was moving around was moving the graph
on the panel
and this this gave to the system so using just information on the number of
and coverage of
actions that this is the student perform with the simulation
and we also try to see
if we can infer self explanation behavior by using as information only for how
what is the time that the students spend in between two options so time is
a measure of
i think the students taking more time from students reasoning about the outcome of the
action issues presenting and so is getting more information out of the simulation
and we also try to see
if adding information on
the students gaze patterns and she is working with interactive simulation could
increase mobility model accuracy and in particular for instance we have tracked
we have given the model information on whether the student is shifting attention from one
town to the other when she's making changes in one issue should look at
and the corresponding effects in the second
and what we have seen we have
compared to three versions of the models
they just use action
as a measure of activity but doesn't even try to capture whether students of explaining
or not one that uses tries to capture what the distance of explaining or not
and so by using information just last time
between two actions and one model that uses information on both
i tracking and time to assess whether some explanation is happening
we can see that if you use information in both time and i tracking we
have a significance in this case significantly higher precision in capturing self explanation the system
is better at predicting whether the student self explaining during the interaction
and there's also generates better model accuracy in predicting students' learning at the end of
the interaction
following these results we
i want to continue using eye tracking information because we believe that provides a very
good window on student could mission during the interaction with this particular
learning activities
so what we discussed so far as the possibility of having tutors that can help
students improve their method mitochondria behaviors what about
the other
research direction that i mentioned that is the ability
having tutors that can also take into account student emotional reaction during the learning process
and react to that
so that's what i'm going to the second project that i'm going to describe and
the project involves
aspects in educational games so it also relates to the research direction of having more
open-ended activities that might involve interaction in this case with an indication
we focus on educational games because the occasional games
our educational games are systems that are designed to trigger learning by again like activities
and this is becoming a very popular trend in education because we all know that
electronic games are very engaging and the idea is to try to see if anyone
in this case
five to ten times better than a bad recommendation and user can stay away longer on the website it generates
in the case of this website which has roughly ten ten million clicks per day
lots of reading
so this is kind of big data with real time element
so response time needs to be like
twenty to fifty milliseconds everything what's above hundred millisecond s
not useful
others keep what we track about a user here i mean the profile of each clique is
morning star heavily in along many dimensions center so that's why this
this is gonna be great
yeah for some
people which are charities that we have also
this will be
the rest we have history we have a couple of other things i mean this
is what everybody's doing so what's available we don't
we don't get any external
sources everything just things which are available through the
cookie tracking ant what's available from the log files sense
now that's it
similar setting was let's say
what we did far analysis on
the new york times
again each from each user is being threatened then we would like to come up
with in real time with the segments of users which
which appear so have a time so advertising campaigns can be more efficient so
the scale for instance here would be
roughly fifty giga bytes of uncompressed log files per day is limited to two hundred million clicks per day
let's say around
forty six depends on the day unique users send seven thousand pages are visited one
hundred times for so this is the distribution of
another example from british telecom
so here we observe
british telecom telecommunication internet telecommunication network like
twenty five thousand devices and technologies this
problem we are solving is
if a problem happens in this network so
device starts complaining can then all devices which are connected to this device
starts complaining and this is network effect now the problem is to find the root
cause the root cause the device which is really
the source
of problem so
the root cause analysis this is kind of probabilistic reasoning setting so this needs to
happen like you know second after
the failure happens
it was
this is more like the generic question about the clout on the well depends how you organize the
problem uh sorry for solving problem on
amazon yasuhiro if you do this in the wrong way then this can be
of course bottleneck
really depends on the problem some problems are more friendly
four hour
clouds some are less friendly
okay but let's continue here so
for instance in this case we are solving this root cause analysis and prediction what
might and anomaly detection what values smell the smoke but there's no fire so
and did this happens all the three
and they have like ten two hundred alarms percent
another example which
so this is just the pictures so for instance know the big data which is
stored in the context of planet daytime this couple other projects
so we are monitoring all mainstream news stand
blocks as well
from the whole world
like seventy five thousand in news
if you open this page with and clean them or you will see how these articles are
just rolling so this is kind good source of
of big data fore
and now each article which we crawled from these are assessed feeds gets also semantically enriched
the next
then complete semantic enrichment natural language processing linking to melody
and then this is the input so we have stream of
semantically annotated
which was published just in the last minutes pretty much
okay let's keep this
visualization parts
maybe just give you an example mining so huge social networks so this is work from
utilities send the equal rights
from microsoft's
there analyzing one month of microsoft messenger
social network
so for each person basically there was the log file for each person who logged into amazon messenger
they knew
gender language
end now the questions which appear to be aware what the structure this
communication effort so
is a little bit longer presentation these but just give you a couple of
slides on this
this was hundred fifty giga bytes per day
uncompressed was
like four five times bigger
because we have sorted array not simply sorted array
but so that arabi the radius much closer together as possible
so it's always divided by inter while it's beautiful compression
because we have very very different distribution here
they're only one which featured four horror insertion
and the problem was distortion in that
if you look into this picture we can see that there
it's full have information and we don't have placed inside information
and when they are going to use the information what
what we are doing this
we divide not into
two plaques
and it means that after the division
this is not you have empty cells
and the more in your smallest of value from this not to be true
to date
so the tree is different from ordinary tree that you can see in in in
the party
is that
it grows from
leaves to root
not from root to leaves but rather in opposite directions so always late
leave and this new nor does provide gating on level
and it means that also that
the tree
in stable situation when you have to have a lot of things
it's on average
has half all cells not use and this is bad
four using in memory you can use it especially compressed around but it's not so
good but on these and expression in database applications not so well
we have
this place is much cheaper and it down but i don't bother about this lies
the second
we already have when we had into this not we already have
and think cell don't do we don't need to divide it again and you and
you would fall
and therefore
what they don't we don't need a lot of usually usually this leads to provide
additional are extremely restoration in real
so if have
computer is small
what we have a collection
huge number of documents be in a lot of different
i don't know maybe
and in this example with our text documents there are a lot of names
and geographical and other names
for unknown reasons trying to do it
from nineteen use only one megabyte of memory
actually the beginning of nineteen
you don't have any any other choice than to put parts of dictionary to model
and in this case is the trees structure
so what we're going to do if you are in such limited situation
using a smaller dictionary
when venetian documents for example the hash hash
when to be done with a group of documents
really combined from there
and add them to this country and these
and that's all we have dictionary very good so we don't dictionary
we even consider a situation when you should edit conflicts and to men
then i think what was going on usually when creating search engine actually a haven't
done got
we already have
dictionary and the
the are doing indexing and maybe were can do some experiments with charge
is that
you are developing this is what you want before development
it's complicated you'll have
got additional information and now you know the
it's not available on this hardware
for example knowledge actually so the that it can feed into your even even on
the on your knees
so what you can do
it scaling
and basically you have to approach the scaling
the first approach is to simply move to a new computer as so you can
actually it was and saying something like this
and now we try to do this but we need more memory
what we need
let's look into a catalogue and know by this user from there
four times memory and the other
so this is vertical scanning and
the problem is article scaling is that
figure out where the climate is grey on
and in order to do that you have to find the path through this semantic
and you can use any of these sort of cross-town links
so you gotta to figure out when it's possible to sort of in first knowledge
over one of the sort solid links and when you're supposed to sort and negated
conclusion using one of these cross-town links
there's a lot of work in the literature trying to use things like how specific
links so if you've got a shorter path between the object in your conclusion
we should take part in preference to another part
so this part from clyde elephant to gray
overrides the path from clyde to federal control of to not great
just looking at that you know you're in trouble so a lot of the research
and definitions of you know this is what when you can draw conclusions and when
you can draw conclusions and so on and really it just became more and more
difficult to
trying justify why this particular why quite should be grains cases to
what should be done
OK a little bit later we had this idea of frames now frames approved probably
end up being quite
for me it is the computer scientists because it ends up being sort of precursor
so object oriented approach which is common in london
programming languages
and the basic idea is that the price of the frames gives you a typical
instance and you can fill in all the slots
so this is the frame for a trip
and there are some things in this trip true so number steps
and this step might have different attributes attributes be things like the beginning data
the end of the step how you managed to carry out step and so on
what you would said like this one
the only method of trying to represent knowledge and same usually have some pretty typical
frames which can be used to populate the frames and draw some you know read
initial knowledge and then of course you can come back and you can buy some
of the knowledge
and in fact you can have these procedures stored
in some of these attributes to work out the value of attributes from other attributes
and so on
so is one which is the procedure to work at the cost of the trip
so by looking at the individual
OK that's
another method might be trying to represent uncertainty so one of the more
so i think she gets to this point which was
well a lot of the work is done in the standard with standard sort of
probability axioms but in in case you see a lot of work also using the
possibilistic axioms which
differ sense when you come when it comes to combining knowledge
so for instance if you know to preserve sort of probabilities two propositions and you
you will look at the conjunction of the two
well the possibilistic act and the possibilistic actions usually take the maximum of the degrees
of belief in the
of the two
propositions but you can
OK then this an attempt to do things like in bayesian networks here we're essentially
what you're
trying to do
it is instead trying to give some sort of heuristic to evaluate the conditional probability
which doesn't require you to go through based formula and trying calculate all of the
conditional release by using the by using this network you can
determine the conditional probability without us having to
prior to this huge form
there are other methods like this to shape theory fuzzy logic which again you sort
of numeric
instead of using triple space using some sort of numeric assessment of the
the level of degree of belief in the proposition and then how you go about
combining those
great ability
it's essentially what differs between all these methods the way that you end up combining
the degrees of belief when you have more complex formulas
OK now one of the sort of hallmarks of logic in artificial intelligence is this
idea of what will nonmonotonic reasoning
now as i a nonmonotonic reasoning tries to capture this notion of common sense reasoning
so the argument would be that if we look at say classical logic be in
propositional form or in its first order form
that type of logic is good for
reasoning about
like mathematics for instance
reasoning about the true mathematical statements
where it's less
so in other words for everybody in population
this variable is instantiated two
person has hypertension
well that was the case
finasteride discounts hair loss just like i said before for
if we find that an individual uses finasteride
it makes it explains away the hypertension
making it less likely
so the people who use finasteride would have less hair loss
so selection bias is present in our sample can can screw up the
because the
causal markov assumption of bad
that is not yet
can to happen and that's not merely obviously problematic as they had in common cause
thing but is something you have to be careful
this is just last right there are not independent in our observed distribution although there
amongst all people did not independent the probability distribution that we observe
fourth one is kind of funny one
and this
in this domain there's always the population my examples of all the population has been
the population happens to be units of time
in nineteen ninety and we just take each day
if we looked at at the bottom of first the dow jones and should be
my here one
because all the nineties about average one up my harlan's going up the same time
but nobody would ever think about jones and which had a causal effect on my
carolina and vice versa so
so the causal
the relationship between these two variables is is
there is none yet they were correlated
in the last few weeks has not gone back down so that kind of
in the case because the relationship is not there
actually that was up again
those down again
school like this not
perhaps the condition that is most violated is that it can be no hidden common
i'll come back to this like i said i don't that assumption is isn't all
the reasonable
but it's easier to develop a theory if we take
so that from the start of making it
we need to go back
well if there is a causal feedback there would be correlated
but you couldn't
applied the theory because the theory requires that the adaptive causation only goes in one
so one is causation one is correlation and these two different concepts
OK to keep track of the time i realize
two thirty eight already is going to quickly so far
there's something different is the conditional dependency among these variables that is not entailed by
the markov condition
this occurs because comprehensive example involving
these variables that's the right as i told you before lowers DHT levels
that's actually how it
during baldness because DHT is male hormone that
makes hair fall out the lawyer DHT levels
actually the a lot of studies and if you do that around the age of
twenty you what was your hair
not sure but it's very likely will map
now it is a study in logan and i'll show DHT levels though
low you know cause low DHT levels cause erectile dysfunction
so given
this causal chain you would think the use of finasteride cause erectile dysfunction
so in march started
offering this medication
they fear decided
the form
it's going to be used because it out of the room that the termites and
and to the truth
what's going on here
because we want to take the medication right it's just that this happened well
actually in enough
in a very large controlled study
it was essentially found that even after independent there's some very small evidence that there
prior model
which is the same with logistic regression we also get
one model
so let's say one rule or whatever but here the idea is that you would
a model which can be let's say also transformed into the individual rules and that
you would kind of be able to understand the individual decisions based on the
pass which leads you
two there
the final decision
so also the approach
here is based on the most informative attributes which is put in the particular note
of the decision tree and the
way the most informative activities is determined is by the heuristic which is called the
so called information gain and that tries to mimic the
property known from information theory which is called entropy
which is used to characterize the impurity of the set
of instances which are in the particular note
so what when is the entropy in the of the decision tree the largest
the largest entropy will be when there are examples of different classes which are in
the set
so then the entropy is the largest then entropy is the smallest or equal zero
when all the examples
in a subset
are labeled with the same class label
so the idea is that in every note we will select such an attribute
we took all the
after splitting the note the entropy will in the sub notes will be the smallest
so that the intuition behind the decision tree learning algorithm
and if we formalize this
measure of entropy
of a set of examples s
so we have a training set set of training examples
suppose without labelled with different class labels in our example it was three classes
like it was two classes like play tennis yes and no
the entropy of
a set of examples s is the measure of the impurity of the of the
set as
and it is computed with the following formula so let's look at the simplified version
the case when we have just the binary class plus and minus entropy with computed
like minus probability of class plus times the logarithm of the probability of class plus
minus probability of class minus times the logarithm of the probability of class minus so
this looks pretty horrible but if we look at in the intuition behind this will
come become very clear
let's look at this formula
we want would like to have
such that
the entropy is the highest when
the in the in the set of examples we have representatives of both classes and
the entropy will be the highest when we have fifty percent of examples of one
class and fifty percent of examples of the other class so that's
totally that has the highest entropy and exactly here is the maximum of this function
which is the probability so if we plot the probability of
class plus here
at the scale of zero probability
one probability one so in this point
all the examples would be of a certain class plus
point all the examples will be of class miners and at this point there is
fifty percent of examples of class plus info fifty percent of class minus so in
this case the entropy is the highest
in this case the entropy equals zero and in this case all the examples belong
to class minus the entropy zero
if there is not fifty fifty distribution for instance if we have eighty percent of
class and twenty percent of class minus the entropy still relatively high