to allow users to find them but also
you come up with alternate techniques to going to figure out that all these things
refer to the same entity
and then finally we have multiple meanings thank you so if you
go and search for swimming and facebook and you say that you want to like
swimming for instance
we probably don't want
link you to this
the other guys
film from the sun that film festival
probably when you said the lights make you remember you
so if we can to do all these things well with the bias
and that is the
you know by having this nice
picture you know how all these things are related how people related to them
it just makes everything sort of more complete it means that
not only are you link to the right thing when you go and find activities
now it is the quality of experience side because
and also on the other side because
you know
so what's going on
one of the things that you find all these things it is the
if you have the that from different sites right so in the database for instance
in the information is going to give you a somewhat different plants the same thing
and now by together you end up with the union of all the information from
all the different
but it's important to maintain high precision that over merge and
i mean the same thing mean
so i but what we want to do this was
based on one
we don't number studies where we look at the importance of social context and you
know what happens when you put these spaces next things for instance and we found
is pretty significant increases in terms of these are the overall performance of all these
things that are
so if you can
when people to these things and then you're going to play with
it's appropriate pages
and you get this two-and-a-half times increase in social activities so people are much more
likely to look like but if the faces of their friends and st
and then also the more is because the business so if you can put faces
necks things like and provide some context for advertisment i actually make people much more
likely to but interact the ad and also the
brand recognition remember what they seen because it's associated with this and there is no
one like
so if you take away from the first there and so there a huge amount
of video it's it's not just offensive but this huge that lots of different types
of things have pages in places and people so and so forth and and we'd
like to have more and more structured data just because it's easier to work with
in the context and things like that
but according the very high quality really want to make sure that there are lots
and lots of different entities the same thing
and we want to build the tools that enable users to merge things together in
the same thing
it so that from the fact that
so something we can do that was once they accomplished the first part and gather
all the structured data in sort of a high precision and high quality
so the first thing is actually
and unstructured view of test
and to this what we did was this is
relatively simple automated techniques looking at updates from all of the hundreds of millions of
of users
the findings it is interesting to note that there as an interesting
and we want to be extracted was
and if you go back to two thousand eight two thousand nine
there this big for swine flu scare right
so you can see
the the red line here is just occurrences of the word well the living lab
and h one n one swine flu
going back to NACD sort of follows the seasonal trend that state and you get
this huge spike which is one the swine flu scare off
and then to die down some people so i forgot about until the fall and
it is actually an old people started to get this one
so this
we know it's all the same attractor here but this is very rapid oscillations
first all the people of swine flu and so we will not interesting
let's zoom in on the
so averaged over many weeks
and we don't want to release of the the y axis here is the fraction
think that contained the word balloons
so in the same way
people tend to get the on wednesdays
they tend to think they have answer is
in that last weekend
another big thing
came out of this text analysis
and was this mean for now
and the families
let's say people will go and post about the bad things happen to them
and you can see where this website that was
around ten thousand i
but first no became
it wasn't just find website really was what
and again you see these solutions
when you go into everything that kind of money that and then the other you
know it it's about a third from the celebrity
there's a few things that know how structure this is all just like me unigrams
and now if you think about it was somebody started
most users
are in some way associated with some countries
so it's not just the faceted of
we know approximately
because of course they have to be an expert in a we know where they
come from
so we only get in his way
so how are people talking about something in different countries
and this is an example from the recent japanese earthquake where you can see you
can see what happens is this big spike mentions of the earthquake and the green
outputs you might imagine that at test time i might just accidentally by sampling sample
the same case as the training data
so am i allowed to include that in the test set or not when i
evaluate generalization
that's the subtle distinction is generalisation strictly training data or is it just from future
data drawn i i d from the same distribution
OK i really think the right way to think about generalisation is data that is
not your training data explicitly not your training data because then anything you can do
better than chance on generalisation really means that you've learned something otherwise you might just
if you see for example
one of the possible instances in your training data then you could get good tested
even without knowing anything
these are just some some last comments here to formalise these these ideas so capacity
the the term capacity refers to the complexity of the hypothesis space OK so
if you're hypothesis space contains many many functions
then in your machine or the hypothesis space is said to have a large capacity
and learning is really going to be nothing more than a search in hypothesis space
within the second hypothesis space for
members of the function classes that do well on the training data
and this will will see the second have some other properties like they look not
too complicated
any inductive learning hypothesis here
is a generalisation is possible
that sounds like a pithy statement but it's a very deep statement
the inductive learning hypothesis says it is actually possible to learn something about future data
that you haven't seen before
this is the solution to this paradox and the solution is pick very restricted function
class that is to say a hypothesis class with low capacity and apply it to
the training data
notice that you do well on the training data and then you you have some
reason to believe you're going to do well on the test
you can actually prove in very strong
mathematical sense
that there are limits on how badly you can do on the test error if
the capacity of the hypothesis space is small and you have low training so
again this is the sort of the whole field of learning theory and you're very
fortunate to be
one of the hotbeds of learning theory in the world so i won't even pretend
that i know anything about this area except to say that it's always been a
little bit beyond me and kind of mysterious but it has these very powerful results
which are the
there's a sort of backdrop of the probabilistic approach machine learning and one
i want to say i want to defend learning theory a little bit here people
often disingenuously criticized learning theory by saying well but the band that people come up
with in learning theory on the test error those bands is so loose that kind
of useless so what contribution has learning theory really really made
OK to criticisms people make of learning and the answer is that learning theory showed
one particular properties of the data
of the function class and of the search algorithm that you use on all three
of those learning theory has something to say about how those affect the future test
so even if numerically the bounds that you get out of learning theory might not
be very powerful to the general properties that it elucidated about the structure of the
learning problem have been invaluable and it's really made a big difference in
in the practice of machine learning so even though you might make a strong argument
that the bound themselves in a very tight i think that the contribution of learning
theory has been very very important in particular answers this question how could we ever
do machine learning it s is that in very formal
just a small
defensive learning theory OK
so the converse of the inductive learning hypothesis is that if you don't make assumptions
you can never learn anything
OK so remember this example
of course you guys are all assuming because you have a million visual cortex that's
very good at keeping you alive that these functions are smooth because you like to
connect things with smooth surfaces but
if you make any assumptions there's no one could predict this function
there's no way you could predict the value of this point in particular what if
you just
so given in training cases
and you for a polynomial
of order n minus one
to the training data
what would your training error be if we measure air by how far your prediction
is from the correct the training would be zero because the polynomial and degree and
minus one can always go exactly through any endpoints by your polynomials gonna look crazy
OK but i didn't do they have the same time as a
black communities of doing this is my questions back
good morning
they all try to describe
two u er
some of the
the main advances in this subject over the last ten years which have a lot
to do with black holes show this will take us first a little bit
a far away from particle physics
but then it will come back in a very interesting way to QCD and particle
physics as using end
let's start slowly with black holes black holes are fascinating astrophysical objects there is for
instance most likely one in the centre of our own galaxy that people are actively
trying to look at
a it has a mass which is equal to a few million times
the short mass
if you convert these two
frank units like mass units usually it's a huge number ten to the forty four
implant which is the scale of quantum gravity
and they have also ABI which are correspondingly large ten billion kilometres roughly for this
these are called supermassive black holes they are the largest such objects in the sky
and there
essentially as classical an object as it can get actually
it's hard to get something that's more classical such black holes
when one thinks about such black holes there is one shot of defining feature in
classical general relativity for what the black hole is
this is the fact that it has an event horizon
an event horizon is
a very simple
it is simply
the horizon so surface surrounding this
very massive black hole that resulted from some gravitational collapse of some
super heavy body
and this surface first because the property that even light cannot escape show the gravitational
attraction is so huge
that even lie
turns around as it tries to escape the black hole
falls back in
therefore behind this horizon you just don't see anything there is no signal that can
come out out
we from behind the horizon
the region behind the horizon is see them to the outside observers
this is a very nice
a literary analogy which has been
most distressed by lenny susskind that find it intuitively very appealing because it really
it gives you the correct mindset when you think about the horrors of the black
and this is basically the analogy with very very actually such things that even constructed
in the lab they are called acoustic black holes
basically the analogies the following think of somebody here it's there are in except they
have taken in time reversed order because i'm going from our
chef houses here before usually are
it is out of the false really going downstream another upstream but suppose for a
moment that it was the other way around you are moving in from some asymptotic
region where the river doesn't flow much
so the velocity field uses very very slow and you can narrow upstream or downstream
without any difficulty
and then as you approach the singularity which is waterfall
the river gets faster and faster and at some point it so fast
that's actually the velocity field the flow
of very very is fast
then the olympic champion of borrowing say what's in our case of black horses of
the speed of light
now in this case there is absolutely no way you can upstream
necessarily going downstream you're therefore don't download you can get off the shore here but
in the black hole there is no shortage so you definitely don't and you willfully
and yet you don't really feel very much while you are approaching this wisely because
after all you are nicely along and who who knows what will happen next and
as a lens suskind was staying in the california league a new passing before i
seems very ancient while it is happening
it's like being in a rowboat above the niagara falls if you accidentally pass the
point where the current moves faster than you can row row you don't
but there is no sign
danger point of knowledge
maybe on very very rare signs but not on the horizon of a black hole
so this those you know things
this horrifies rose are in a sense
a place where nothing very dramatic happens as long as you are going along and
falling into the black hole you don't feel much on the other hand from far
seen from the asymptotic regions there are definitely very dramatic surfaces because beyond the horizon
there is not a problem that will ever come back and tell you what happens
which cannot be modelled by any theta
then the posterior
given the data will converge to a delta function
around some value data had
where data is the value of the data that minimizes the
kl divergence to the true probability distribution p
so you converge to the closest possible points in data space
two that he stuck
and the data had that minimizes
the KL divergence the star is also equivalently
the data had that has maximum likelihood
under the generative model
you're basically cannot converge to the maximum likelihood estimate
data that this is the log likelihood averages over the
the district the true distribution p of x
how different can beliefs be between different bases so one thing that seems a little
worrying about the basic framework is that subjective you have different bayesians coming with different
what effect does that have well there's another result
called asymptotic and then the results of everything i mean states for finite dimensional data
so consider two two bayesians with different priors p one theta and p two theta
who observe the same data d
so for example
data could be a number between zero and one representing the probability of a coin
coming out heads or tails
and imagine you have two very different based in one of them
his math on
the extremes near zero and one and the other one
almost all of that on
values around point four
here's the key assumption assume both bayesians agree on the set of possible and impossible
values of data
which means that even though this one put are almost all that in this one
but almost all the math here and here
the value for which
he wanted data is strictly greater than zero and p two of data is strictly
greater than zero are equal to each other for both of the
the domain is the interval between zero and one
then in the limit
the number of points going to infinity
the posterior distribution for the first made the and the second basically will converge
in this matter of
uniform distance between distibutions thank you start out with
different beliefs as long as you think the set of possibilities
is the same
you will eventually converge to the same beliefs
having observed there
so another thing that
people worry about a lot of where you choose your prior prob
and this is something that there are lots of different schools of thought
all kind of paraphrase different principles our ideas you can use which is your right
objective bayesians try to come up with objective priors
so in general that corresponds to non informative priors
that attempt to capture ignorance of some kind
and then they try to have good frequentist properties
and there's a lot of work on trying to develop objective priors in the very
o thing to do
some people might argue is impossible to do
so maybe if you can afford
you know
some problems that objective higher so
one of the issues is that you try to come up with this not informative
but sometimes
that leads to improper priors so for example non informative prior on
the mean
the gaussians we might end up being a uniform distribution from minus infinity to infinity
which is not a proper distribution it is not something you can
sample from or
you know normalized or anything like that that's called an improper prior to its use
improper priors then you get inconsistencies you get incoherent
and incoherencies with these to be exposed to
the dutch book and stuff like that so it's dangerous business
then there is
priors of convenience school they've seen me do this a bit in the last electrode
the some priors
like for example conjugate priors
lend themselves to analytical solutions and computationally efficient inference
you know we're all practical people will will use these practical considerations often choose prior
with the hope that we've managed to capture the range of possible parameter values that
we believe the actual parameters belong to an remember by the previous arguments of asymptotic
and consensus we don't have to worry
about having exactly the right prior to come to that in a minute there is
sort of exactly the right prior we just want to try capture our beliefs and
then be somewhat practical and how we deal with things as well
so that's the friday prior to to being in
hierarchical priors
are the concept of well i have the prior on this parameter data let me
defined that by having hyperparameters
and OK those defined the distribution over data but then what distribution which i put
on the hyperparameters and you go one layer of the user can be defined some
hyper hyperparameters and so on and so forth and so
hierarchical way of defining models actually often quite sensible
at some point you want to stop the hierarchy because it doesn't make any more
and they also don't get very good local optima and had deep that's
this will see later you can get much better optima
so the idea is we want to keep what's good about back propagation which is
stochastic gradient descent
we want to get rid of what's bad which is everything depending on the labels
so instead of learning the probability of a label given image
we just can the probability of an image we can learn density model images
and now we don't need labels and what's more each image has much more information
in it
the typical label
can be big
and lots of pixels and so each image was a lot of constraint on a
density function
was if i give you an image in the label
i might try and get the right answer i don't get much constraint on the
mapping from images to labels
the bits constraint on the mapping imposed by training example just number bits it takes
to say what the answer is which is very many
so now the question is what kind of generative model should we learn
as you all know i think has been a big revolution in statistics and a
and there's a kind of model which is directed basically graph
and there's been lots of work on how you
learn these
and how to do inference in these
is there
sparsely connected each node only has a few parents
this clever exact inference algorithms division has many parents imprint gets much trickier
so in these
i'll be using
directed nets in which
the observations of the leaves
one of the
and in that kind of net
then the inference problem is if i you know the the parameters that you know
the states of these nodes determine the distribution for this note
the inference problem is figuring out what states of the there's probably were when you
see the data
the main problem is figuring out
weights on these connections to give you some ground right function for
the probability distribution here given states of these guys
typical values binary units we can generalize and later
so the initial user just stochastic binary units where
you get some total input
from other units
so when you're doing
generation this will be top down input
the probability of turning into unit on is just the logistic function this template
so now if all only units like that
so rapid neil introduced nets like this in about nineteen ninety two
william is like that
it turns out is easy
to learn the parameters if you can compute the posterior distribution over the hidden causes
a data vector notation
if you can compute the full posterior here or even if you can just get
an unbiased sample from the posterior learning is easy
so i show you data vector
if you can give me back
an unbiased sample some binary vector
this is sort of plausible way in which this stuff might have cause that stuff
then learning is very easy
the difficult thing is getting this
sample from the posterior
so here's the learning rule suppose we have an unbiased sample from the posterior
so i gave me some data down here
my unbiased sample from seriously binary states for these units
and the learning rule is just
for the weight on this connection what i need to do is compute the difference
the actual state of this guy kind by sampling from posterior
this is just like this one or zero
and the probability with which this guy will be turned on by the generative model
given the actual states of these guys in the posterior
that's all these
s j is here
so the probability to on i
it's just the logistics of the input it gets from all these actual structure
and it turns out the maximum likelihood learning will is two
to follow the
direction in which shows increasing the problem the
observed data thank you
is to change the weight in proportion to the learning rate times
the state of this guy times the difference between the stated that guy what you
and who would like to have some more time
let's get on
okay so is there
is anyone who
it's relatively confidence
that he or she has found a solution
the other
right right
so u
these are you apply the definition
you substitute this from the kernel
and then u
his linearity
so linearity means you can take these
coefficients inside the sum
it also means you take and you can take the sums necessary inside the dot
product it also means you can take the sums into the dot product
this to both at the same time
okay and then
and that's because
so this vector here
it's called this me
this is the same that are doesn't matter that we use different index so this
is the product of some vector with itself
and that's not negative
so is that clear to everybody
so you're saying that we only put this
and this inside but we did the sums outside it
something like this
well it turns out that
not all these terms will be positive
because this is not the same as this not necessarily right that
terms if i equals say they were positively other ones not
and so
when they when you sum them all up there will be positive but some of them might well be negative
okay thank you very much so let's
then we skip the second one because it would be too complicated now but later
on it would be very easy
yes so the question is he says
phi is a function of x and d
of five expires function of ex-prime so that both
functions well all the elements of human space right
question how to define a dot product in the hilbert space
it depends what kind of objects they also have a space by definition is a
vector space with the dot product
which is complete in a certain sense
but uh
so you can you can define dot products for functions have been defined dot product for vectors
four functions a typical product for instance is
the integral over the product of two functions
but in the reproducing kernel hilbert space which is what we're dealing with today it
will be a little bit different
so maybe just for now just think about it abstractly dot product is just this is symmetric by linear form
with certain properties and so
yeah i don't know
i times better
so it's just the dot product is just a certain mathematical object in
certain type of vector space actually in between him a space of three hundred space is not complete
and there is a mapping phi i could go into a space of functions but
it could also be a mapping into a vector space if you prefer to think
of it as a vector space and then use it on on the product
any more questions about this
so yes so i assume the spaces are
this is something that maybe the physicists among you will be familiar with and for
the computer scientists maybe will initially be be a bit scary to have this
the spaces that could be potentially infinite dimensional
but the hyperspace are mathematically very nice objects very
well behaved and usually
most the things that work in normal
the euclidean vector space is also working hilbert spaces
okay so let's
well to a few more properties so basically the
my goal now is
we've seen
this is true in the first
of these two statements
and basically want to prove the converse
which which i mean the following
if we have some positive definite kernel so kernel
that satisfies
this property here down here
my laser pointer
the that satisfies this thing
there exists some mapping phi
and some
space age with the dot product
that phi maps into
such that the kernel can be written in this form
so this means
everything that has this form is a positive definite kernel
and every positive definite kernel actually has the form of can be given that fall
not necessarily with a unique five but there is some five such that the kernel
can be written this form and it's very
nice because then we can basically think of the kernel as the dot product
just somewhere else and a lot of things become very clean and nice and simple
point this thing becomes very simple proof
and since we're not going to use this one
in constructing the converse of this
maybe we just skip it for now so that was
get the converse and then
let's see how it goes
okay so let's think of a few more properties
maybe we don't have to prove all of them but again i would like to play around a bit
and the
it's a
so this one may be worse
the first one and d
let's see
describing this important experiment
don't worry about it not just run a intuitively
this thing
talked about the probability
if you
the toss coin n times this is the probability of getting a sequence of results
with the property
for this sequence
the empirical mean
and the expectation differ by these epsilon
and this little variant of telephone which we will use later on
which is a very
the situation where rather than comparing here mean to expectation
comparing two different empirical means
so we
we do the experiment two in times
we compare
the average over the first n
coin classes
with the average over the second and the independent
you can imagine that if
we know that this thing here is true
whenever we toss in times is expectation
and of course because again and again it's also close to the station so that
both within epsilon with expectations with
put things together
five inequality
we get a bound on half of these two things can be from each other
and it's a similar bond
the that now
instead of epsilon the right hand side one side two
we have seen some of two here
was where it gets at point here
OK so this is bound tells us how far empirical means be from each other
and this is something that goes into this part is that
these are
you have two n independent trials
can use the product
oh you mean can you have a different probability measures here and here
but with the same expectations
i don't see why it should work
OK but the last eight years
humans that the same but
i think it also work
from each of the same
and this will be quite useful this thing here down here
remember only before the test
we cannot compute expectation of risk
we can compute the expectation of test error
in other words can compute the rest
this thing here not the talk about
something and uncomputable more one less just talks about to run ferns
later we will try to reduce our
problem something like this and they we want we want to use this bound
also also
very slowly with respect to machine and the terminology
and this last
so the the first part here
here means that the probability of obtaining
m sample for example i mean
so pairs x y
where the training error and test differ by more than epsilon
it founded by this quantity here the probability that there
different file then founded on
so far i talked about one fixed function f defined these losses
police said that
these are independent bernoulli trials values one fixed function f x y i
now the question is what happens if we have
we have several functions
maybe even
this is the
maybe these functions
you can chose
from the training points
by this i mean
so this function could be the function minimizing the training error
this is a function that has seen
as much hydrogen ions at the mountain after that you put in water so it's
ionizing completely and weak acid means that you're not ionizing that much and not forming
that much i truly am i and when you put the acid in water
and you can also consider whether some things are strong acid
in terms of its pk
as well not just k
and remember the relationship here so pk
equals minus log of k
so we saw you know with the PKW before
so these are the the same expressions
so if you have a small value less than one
here this is small
going to have a higher value for p
and so
the higher the value
the weaker the acid so you can think about whether some things we gathered in
terms of its k
or in terms of its pk
depending on what information is given to you
and that's the relationship between those terms
so here are some examples
of acids and there's a bunch of these that'll be in your book
here we have the strong acid
and you can see these k numbers are enormous
there are very big so you go pretty much all to product got all the
hydro any amine concentration
so they ionize completely up here
and once you feel most probably hydrochloric acid
hydro makassar those would be the one thing you probably c
in problems that in the book
and then
we go from the strong acid down here week these are cases of less than
so here you don't have nearly as much ionisation and of course when these numbers
get small pk also get bigger
and we can keep going
there are a lot of methods
keep going down here to where you have really
truly small k numbers and quite large PK's these would be very weak
very little
ionisation when you put that on that as it into water
let's do the same thing for bases
so let's look at the base in water
so let's take
NH three
in water
the base will accept the high iron forming NH four plus
so when you have a base in water
you're going to form hydroxide
when you have an acid in water are going to be performing hydro neon ions
so in this base in water
you're going to be talking about the these
ionisation constant
which is you talking about
and so KB
is going to be equal to
concentration of products
and equilibria
over the concentration of a reactant
again water is not included solvent in this case
in the KB here
is equal to one point eight
ten to the minus five
so it's a fairly small number again
thank you for coming to my talk
in many respects because i'm not doing post google art
before that just
very short biography i
linguistic of the university and it is and then i went to south germany got
a message to the station was extended phd also germany the
research institute which is called the media and after that i
that is cost that goal
and today i'm going to talk about and the measurement process and
some topics which i know more about his age
so if i'm talking to quickly or if you have questions feel free to drop
me a note
well i'm going to introduce new people or to my friends and they asked me
what i do have access to computational linguistics and natural language processing go they me
what is that to with little world war natural image processing what race relations the
so the first two bytes of just explaining
where the information comes
so natural language processing is the processing of major languages and the images are
languages like russian english german
all of the approximately five thousand languages exist in the world and
now part of google's mission is to
organize the world's information and make it universally
universally accessible so
it means in the first place to organize the information available on the web that
the information available on the sites and most of the information there is
concord nature which text serious people talk to each other
so it's all about language
and it means two
organized was information is to understand those documents to understand the text to understand natural
language to present to the users
the sample is
the use and the information retrieval
so we have users
this was search for things but it also gives rise to different topics machine translation
speech recognition of civilization and
there are two sides the image processing so that people also
why do we need linguistic you can build statistical models two
so many things without knowing
much of the language and one that's true so right
now might techniques need for scalable ontology language processing and those
bag of words model or
which are used for example
vector space models
things like TFIDF which are not that much is to try to find get some
comments so there's not much is going on there
but deep understanding
implies analysis
linguistic analysis of on different levels of participation information syntactic information semantic analysis discourse analysis
so to say
and today
i'm going to talk about the following things such as this one and see more
about just a brief introduction what kind of in the tests
dean so that will spend about twenty minutes talking about things like machine translation speech
information extraction i won't go into much detail here
because the
several reasons that complex topics that one second it's not really what i'm working more
competent to talk about things like civilization and this is what the second part of
my talk is going to be about
so the second part of my talk i will present
and that two summaries using different languages and i will present experiments that will use
if you know the site
and then we also showed
youtube and how users comments to be used
also to get an idea what the media is that
so that's one
i guess most of you know that google
his interest in machine translation so
there's one which translates
i thought the dotcom they come and any of
one sentence in language you don't understand or something that you understand want to translate
and this translation works
four about what it the moment the quality difference
quality of german english or english german translations definitely
so this presentation is about to turn nature i usually like to help people in
trouble with questions so please don't hesitate if there is something you would like to
so this is the way i defined feature selection
imagine that you have the data table
the lines are
patterns and the columns are features
and you may have thousands to millions of low level features in a lot of
recent applications
they represent themselves in this way
and you would like to select the most relevant features
in order to build better faster and easier to understand learning machines which in essence
was down to
selecting the number of columns of your data matrix
so in the first couple of examples of applications of this problem
i've been working a lot in the medical
data analysis and the first example is taken from the kenya diagnosis problem
in which looking at patients have been had had their blood drawn and
from there sarah
what has assessed the
all of their genes and this is done with the so-called DNA microarrays
so in in this slide each mailbox here represents
the level of expression of a given gene if the gene is underexpressed compared to
normal it's blue and otherwise it's right it's overexpressed
and as i said before each line represents the patient which con represents a future
in that case the gene
there are some special causes the tower to the right and the left and those
were present target
there are two subpopulations in the data the patients and DAML patients are two different
kinds of leukemia
and those are represented by here you're ready
bar and here the blue bar
so one very simple way of selecting future is to looking for those columns in
the data set which are most correlated with the target or which are most often
correlated with the target so here we have the opposite of the target
we usually use target values plus or minus one so would have all plus ones
for the ll and or minus ones for the AML so we call in that
case the positive class class
so this is what people in this early paper in nineteen ninety nine had done
they look for those
genes that were either correlated are correlated with all correlated with the target
you don't need to limit yourself to two classification problems you can do multiclass you
can do regression in the a variety of other cases but the problem always boils
down to finding a subset of the original variables the most predictive
in this example you see another representation of the data instead of showing the data
matrix like in the previous slide we show three features and we have a scatter
plots of the examples in this three dimensional space
so imagine that you run a feature selection algorithm and you find those three
informative features
and imagine that you had three classes in that case it's prostate cancer problem and
there are three populations tissues
tissues that correspond to benign prostate hyperplasia BPH and two different ways of cancer grade
three and grade four
here are represented by these edits as we show the three clusters forming by the
three populations in this three-dimensional space
so feature selection can be both used for improving predictions
or for facilitating like here visualization of data
number to show you a couple of examples of feature selection to illustrate that are
feature selection does not always yield performance improvement
in this paper
the oscars
try to perform cancer diagnosis
also from DNA microarray data and they vary the number of genes in here they
show accuracy of classification
for the problem of classifying fourteen tumours and then they tried a number of different
classifiers without entering into details in these new have different curves here corresponding to different
strategies to be adopted and you see that in some cases
there is an optimum
accuracy increases as ring
increase the number of features and then decreases again in other cases even monotonically basically
monotonically increases so the more features the better
so as it turns out that nowadays there are some very of some parameters that
are very robust against overfitting
in the old days people used to say that there is this curse of dimensionality
and that it is extremely important to do space dimensionality reduction in order to get
good performance when you have very few training examples
nowadays this is no longer true you can work in very very high dimensional spaces
and if you have a highly regularized classifiers you can get a very good performance
without performing first space dimensionality reduction in this is illustrated by his here the more
features the better performance gets in the way a few
throw away some features you throw away some information because you're not sure that you're
going to be eliminating the bad ones
however for some problems you do see a very clear optimal
so for some problems in which you have a large number of features that are
then filtering them out
does improve performance and as you can see here in this problem of drug screening
and in which there were around two thousand five hundred compounds that were tested for
their ability to bind to a target sites
the the purpose was to determine whether a molecule was going to be active or
inactive and there were
over a hundred thousand binary features describing the properties of the
three-dimensional molecule
most of these features being completely useless and in fact as you can see as
a function of success rate the optimal number feature is between
at twenty and forty
here's how to solve the optimisation problem
and i have shown you want application i would now like to
i would like to retain is but i'm not i don't have the flow
thank you
OK thank you
so i would like to show you a period which is
very important for kernel methods
it's important not just for support vector machines but also for other types of kernel
and it doesn't
it's not complicated to prove so i would like to to show it
so think about ten minutes and then i will
i have time to tell you a little bit about about logarithms of and support
vector machines
so this is called the representer theorem and in the original the first person which
is less general than this one it was proved by bobbi bind kimeldorf
in the theorem goes as follows so suppose we have a positive definite kernel
we have a training set
training set this is for the case of regression estimation but
you will see later also applies to classification
so we have here inputs and we've output values y
moreover we have a strictly monotonic increasing function
on the positive half axis
so this function is
on the other
and plays the role of rescaling are
martin to or regularisation term
and in addition we have a cost function
it's a bit complicated by the cost function that measures
the the empirical error also you want is to compare the empirical error could be
for instance squared error that we use so we we measure the square deviation between
the target values why i end of prediction f of x i
but then some all these i that would be one possible such cost function but
this one is more general in that it allows dependence
jointly on all
points at the same time
so it doesn't have to decompose into some
in the statement of the representer theorem is that
any solution
of this problem solution of minimizing this problem
so the problem is to minimize the empirical out plus
this regularisation term to think of this as the margin to before we had a
norm of w squares to think of this is the norm of w square by
the modern world
so any
solution to this problem can be written
as an expansion in terms of kernels now the crucial thing is kernels centered on
the training points so these exciting of the training points
OK so
so surprising maybe because we are solving the problem in the in this reproducing kernel
hilbert space
which can be very high dimensional hilbert space in the case of the gaussian kernel
it's an infinite dimensional hilbert space
which contains all possible functions
sitting on different points all linear combinations of all these functions and even the limits
and i'm saying that the solution to this problem always has an expansion
o is the linear combination of kernels
sitting on the training points in the training set could be just a tiny subset
of the whole
set of possible points on which you could have come city
so that's nice because somehow it reduces the problem of finding
the function minimizing this risk functional minimizing this objective function it reduces the problem of
finding a function in high dimensions are in infinite dimensional hilbert spaces to the problem
of finding
a finite number of coefficients of five
and this is actually
you've already seen an example of this which was the support vector machine
and see where it is
the support vector machine i was telling you that
there's an expansion of the solution w
in terms of the training points
so that was nice because that it that meant we only have to find the
coefficients alpha i
so the same thing is true in the more
general setting
and i'll show you why
OK so this is the year so it means that
many learning algorithms all the ones that satisfy the conditions of this theorem have solutions
that can be expressed as expansions in terms of the training examples
the or in their original form
cost function
took the form of a sum over quadratic errors
but it works for arbitrary cost functions even depending jointly and all the points and
it also works for more general regularizers but that's not important for us
it's a to see why this theorem is true
so the way we're going to do is we decompose
that's the solution is assume f is the solution of all problems this optimisation problem
and will decompose into apart
that is a linear combination of the training examples of the kernel sitting in training
plus some power that's orthogonal to it
we can do this because we're working in hilbert space
so it's this notion of the orthogonality we have the product
and so we can we can decompose this function in this way and it probably
would think that this is a very low dimensional subspace here
subspace where they spent by the kernel sitting on the training points and this could
be something in a huge space and what we're going to show is that this
actually begins at this part zero the
without making the solution works
remember in the formulation from before
i was saying
you seem to prove so
so we have this decomposition is a linear combination in terms of the training points
this is still from the part of from the path is orthogonal to all these
basis vectors
spanning this linear subspace to all the girls single training points
so now we
all functions
to some training point xj
if we do this we remember by the reproducing kernel property from yesterday
application of function to a training point is the same as taking the dot product
with the kernel sitting on that point
so the kernel is
he's actually this point evaluation functional that if told you about
yesterday the kernel is the represent of point evaluation
we can write this as product
in this function space between us and the concert in the next day
and not just substitute my expression for f in here and here i case the
next day and this is some so i can take the two dot product separately
now i know that the product between f perpendicular and k zero
so this thing here banishes so what we're left with is the dot product between
and this
and now we can take some of what we want but the crucial point is
that the results of application of f to a training point is independent of this
point of this part here so if we only worried about flying elephant training points
this thing isn't going to make a difference
so in this
the first part of the tutorial i talked about
adaboost and a couple of ways of understanding the algorithm
one way is to think is in terms of the original technical meaning of what
boosting means
which is to take a weak learning algorithm converted into a strong learning algorithm
is this microphone OK by the way
so better
the good
all right
raise your hand or something if you can hear me OK
so we looked at boosting in the technical sense very briefly and then we talked
a lot about understanding boosting as an algorithm for maximizing the margins as the margin
maximisation algorithm similar but different to support vector machines
so what's kind of interesting about adaboost
is that there are many many different ways of understanding this one
and so what i wanted to do
is tried it describes some of those other ways of understanding adaboost which are really
very different ways of understanding
i plan to talk about the game theoretic view
of adaboost and then go on and talk about boosting as a method for minimizing
the loss minimisation methods
but running a little bit short of time so i'm going to have to
kind of skip over the game theoretic you which is that a high level
a game you know we're talking about very simple matrix games like this one for
rock paper scissors
and one of the
i'm just going to zip right through this so one of the core
theorems in game theory is what's called the minmax theorem which says that basically if
one player goes before the other player you get the same result as that the
other player goes before
the first player this is kind of the fundamental theorem of
zero sum games
and it turns out that you can associate a game very natural game with adaboost
adaboost is kind of an interaction or boosting in general is an interaction is an
interaction between the boosting algorithm on the one hand and the weak learning algorithm on
the other hand
so we can associate a very natural
game matrix game between those two players
in which
the boosting algorithm has as its choices of play
the training examples and the weak learning algorithm has as its choices of play the
weak classifiers so on each round of boosting
boosting algorithm is choosing a distribution over the training examples that kind of its play
and the weak learning algorithm is responding by choosing one of these weak classifiers
the point is that obviously going to pass to get any of the details but
the point is that you can associate
this game with boosting
so what they feel can build the matrix what's the big deal
well it turns out that the minimax theorem the fundamental theorem of game theory
it turns out
for this game to say something really interesting
it says that if we start with the weak learning assumption which says that for
any distribution over examples
you can find the weak classifiers accuracy
is a little bit more than random guessing or hoosier is little bit less than
random guessing
then you plug that into the minimax theorem
what it tells you
is that there has to exist a weighted majority vote of the classifiers such as
the weighted majority vote which is found by adaboost
which correctly classifies all of the training examples and in fact it does it
with positive margin
so the minimax theorem tells us that there exists a weighted majority vote
which classifies all the training examples correctly
in fact adaboost turns out to be
algorithm for playing this game
so it turns out that adaboost
it's actually just a special case of a much more general algorithm for playing games
repeatedly in such a way that eventually you solve the games meaning that you find
strategies is optimal plays
so for instance we can show that the distribution of examples that computed by adaboost
is actually
in approximate minmax strategy for the boosting game so this kind of tells us
something very specific about
what those distributions are converting to for adaboost
and it also turns out that this
game playing algorithm
if you set things up a little bit differently then you end up with an
online learning algorithm similar to the ones that you're on talked about yesterday
it gives us a different algorithm called the weighted majority algorithm which is also an
online learning algorithm
in fact we that adaboost actually came about was we started with the weighted majority
and we kind of
i ended up applying to
the game that i was talking about that here
OK so that's a very quick
look at the connection between an interesting game theory
there's a more popular view of adaboost which
grew largely out of
the statistical view of boosting
which is to view boosting as an algorithm for minimizing a loss function
so we've heard a lot about loss functions over the last several days and probably
last week two
there are many or most learning algorithms minimize some kind of loss function
minimize some kind of loss functions
so it is natural to ask is there a loss function that associated with adaboost
and it turns out that there's turns out that you can view adaboost as an
for minimizing loss function
so if you go back to the training year proved that we went through before
you can see that what adaboost is actually doing this it's not minimizing the number
of mistakes on the training set
but it's really minimizing is the product of these normalisation constant right we had step
two of that group way back when
was that the training year is upper bounded
this product of the normalization factors
and if you work out what that product of normalization factors as
well it works out to be
this expression here which is just one over the number of examples
of this funny
exponential loss function which is e to the minus y times at the back side
where have backs again is this weighted sum of the weak classifiers
OK so the claim is that this
exponential loss
the natural loss function associated with adaboost
so what is that really mean well
it turns out that on every round of boosting with adaboost is doing is it's
greedily choosing
alpha t
and the weak classifier ht
so as to minimize the loss function
it turns out that adaboost is really kind of the greedy procedure
for minimizing this loss function
so then you might ask
i will not go through your body x-rays may go through your body gonna rays
funny but infrared radiation and visible light gets absorbed by your body and so the
question now is real that time you
and then the answer is no you would hardly notice fifteen watts per square meter
your body itself
radiates about hundred joules per second because of the body heats that you have
and so the thirteen what's
the square meter that
you have your that's a uris cross sectional area is about one square meter just
to round it off
so that means that in joules per second would be observed by your body
and that will not
factor you in any way
but let's now take a situation
we have
he is zero
equal ten times higher
which is the thousand volts per meter
now the poynting vector
goes up by the square of the
so now you're going to get
that the poynting
i mean we factor is one point three
kilowatts per square metre
and that will fry
if you walk
make it
in the field infrared optical
well by the
one point three kilowatts per square metre
that is very dangerous
it gets
skin cancer and worse
now why do i mention that and why do i focus on that one point
kilowatts per square metre
because that's exactly what the sun does
there's the song
anderson is a rather powerful light bulb
about three point nine
times ten to the twenty six watts
and this is where you are on earth
and the distance to earth
is hundred fifty
million kilometres
so i can calculate now
how many joules per second
go through one square meter here and this one square metres held perpendicular
two the direction to the sun
so that
value for us
it is of course
the radiation that leaves attended my three point nine
times ten to the twenty six
and now i have to divided by the entire surface area
of the sphere
it goes in all directions
that has this rate is
and that surface area
is four pi
times the radius square
so is hundred fifty
times ten to the ninth because i have to go to MKS units
it's great
and that is now the number of watts per square meter
we receive at earth from the sun
and that number
it's a very famous number that is one point four
per square metre
and and that's why i picked the one point three show you
that if you walk around on the beach
you don't take care of yourself
if you do that too long
that is very dangerous because your body absorbs that
this number is called the solar
it has major implications of course for people who want to harvest solar energy
the maximum that you can ever harvest
for every square meter to dedicate to solar energy
you only get
fourteen hundred joules per second you can ever get more
the electric power capacity of the united states is seven
a hundred thousand megawatts
for which you need seven hundred powerplants
a full-size power plant
it's about a thousand megawatt power plant
we need seven hundred of these power plants
to have the capacity
forty united states
we are energy
we consume more than one quarter of all the energy in the world
so if you want to replace by solar energy
that's a major problem
because you can only get
one point four kilometres per second for every square meter you can calculate
how many hundreds of square miles in the desert you would have to
with solar cells which are extremely expensive
in order to get electricity
and the efficiency of course is never
one hundred percent and also when the sun is low on the horizon then you
don't have this one square metre
perpendicular to the direction of the sun so all of that has to be taken
into account
so energy
it is not very important in our lives unfortunately
and this is the number
that is the ultimate limit
now comes the question
is there such a thing
as a electric field of a thousand volts per meter
in the solar radiation
could we actually measure
the electric field
just from the radiation of the sun and the answer is no
and the reason is that the radiation is not really in the four
of our idealised
plane wave but more important than anything else is that there is no such thing
as as just one away from the sun
has the amplitude of thousand volts per meter in fact the radiation reaches us in
small packages
broken up into pieces so to speak
however since the energy flow
it is
one point four
kilowatts per square metre
it is perfectly OK with me that you refer to this number as the poynting
vector i have no problem with that
but it is a little bit naive
to associate with that
at different intensities
that would be interesting to which can you see why the band gap in 1
. 1 EV versus visible light is really important
how well this 1
what if instead of having light coming in 1 I connected this to a power
and I
part the electrons out of the valence band in the conduction band from which they
would fall
and then emit photons
so I could make a light-emitting device by pumping things up and having fall this
is why this class of materials is dominating the modern world materials with the band
around the value of the
energy in visible light are called semiconductor per cent for a reason you'll see shortly
in terms of their connectivity their electrical conductivity is the least appealing of the properties
it's their ability to interact with
radiation makes them so
so exciting
national we could actually do a task we could we have actually measure measure with
these band gaps are by tuning the value of the incident radiation so for example
if we did this with
long-wave radiation
keep moving moving moving until we get to a value of photon energy that causes
expectations we could have a sensor that detects when the incident radiation is being absorbed
and we can plot that energy supply so we can have sustainable of the incident
energy when the incident energy and this is the 1st absorption the percent absorption
by the crystal and this would from 0 to 100 so energy moves from right
to left it goes inversely with Llandysul so high wavelength is low energy so at
low energy we expect materials to be transparent at high energy label at some critical
of energy absorption begins and this value here is called the absorption and the absorption
so I'm here very very high
wavelengths are low energies the material that appears transparent transparent because the incident is less
than the band gap and a high energies the material appears OK it's absorbing
because here the incident is greater than the sum of the
and surrounded series due to defects that it's not perfect shop so perfectly shopping search
and so what I did OK let's do the calculation Cycle and Carriage silicon and
diamond silicon diamond so the band band gaps and electron volts for silicon at 1
. 1 4 . 5 . 4 and ordered is just said well band gap
energy is now converted to photon energy so just do HC overland so of the
absorption edge land of the absorption edge this is equal to the
band gap is equal to h c over lambda of the absorption edge for silicon
it's way infrared it's 1125 use these ugly units mm and diamond is down at
and words visible light
visible light is around numbers 400 to 700 manages to you can see that this
is out I and this is down in the UV
so we could make a plot here that this is 400 nanometers this is 700
nanometers so this is visible light
then this would be silicon out here at 1125 mm
and the diamond diamond over here that 229 manometers invisible library between
and I thought well there's just probably another chemistry lesson here self
1st what to summarize here what we see we've seen here that the metal has
no band gap so there's there's no gap between the top of the bonding in
the bottom of the anti bonding orbitals in an insulated there's a huge band gap
in the semiconductor there is a moderate band gap were moderate is defined literally in
reference to visible light
now this was an interesting thing I've here's here's your group 42 us the periodic
table and these are the values of band gap energy of Amari showed you that
Diamond is 5 . 4
and silicon is 1 . 1 and again would now germanium is going out to
n equals 4 so so that it's still S P 3 hybridized you this is
forced to 4 p 2 forms for
SP three hybrid orbitals
0 . 7 to 10 it may surprise you to has 2 different crystallographic forms
called allah tropes 1 of them was metallic and the other 1 is s p
3 hybridised so to actually has a semiconducting form it's a tiny tiny band gap
the stochastic process namely the random variable t
as a function of x and y
it is not a random variable of data
and i can ask well what's the distribution of the stochastic process
two fixed indexed by x and y
well obviously since this is calcium that also has to be garcia
furthermore the mean vanishes
can just pull the expectation in
the covariance
well the current duration y you explain what prime
well this is the expectation of o theta
o for x and y with theta
theta was far explaining why prime
this debate here doesn't depend on theta
notice that it
so i can pull the expectations on
so the expectation of state is the transpose
just to correct
now this is just six months with setting
so this all collapse and just getting up from twenty five x y
for fixed right
so what i've done is i've rewrite yet another way
of how to get
the second
just go back
this was the kind
well now sits well we could just as well
with those terms
not trying to normal
with this as the covariance matrix
and all the estimation straight in that
in some cases this is going to be computationally more efficient
for instance whenever the inverse covariance matrix
it's something that you have easy access to the information matrix itself isn't
and that's the smart thing to do
can be cases where for instance you take as a graph the graph passing as
inverse covariance matrix or some modification of that
operating dusty parameters
can speed up things by orders of magnitude
but that's a numerical thing
in terms of statistics is that it's exactly the same thing happening so that in
one case
you might the office
in that case you optimize over t it was k times of
so if you're casting process paper
we talk about this
you know what it means
it is all confused you now you can just forget about it because i'm not
going to use it afterwards
but next time you read about process paper in this country you pull out that
slide number nine
and just use it to translate things
right now let's look at a couple of
simple cases
so don't be scared fifty five slides on that many with lots of pictures in
and here
well if i have a linear also kx
the next prime is just
it's time that's fine
so this what has nothing to do with the previous slide in world is just
the linear covariance function
pretty boring but this will give me a linear models
but the people in economics use that
the classes so that would be just e to the minus explore exploit
the jean-philippe show you that last week
everybody investing before
the kernel of order three
looks a bit weird but it's also kind of
so done is space fixed one argument and but that's the value of the other
ones throughout the entire range
what you would probably notice that these polynomial kernels can be hard to control at
it's the values can become very large
if you don't risk scared about in the right way
this is a risky thing to do
to you get new
it's probably a good idea not to use the polynomial kernel in the first instance
just use a simple RBF kernel trying to see how well how are you doing
and then maybe look at polynomial kernels
i'm not saying that they might not really work well
so for instance for optical character recognition that great
four strings they can be really great
in comparison
so could not
might be able to tell you a lot more about that
plates a first use an RBF kernel
you will be
it say
if you want to get support you can use something like lines
not just here
and that's just multiple convolutions of the unit interval
if somebody goes to you tells you well my ten kernel is really what you
an engineer
they can be seen as a sort mathematical formalisation very simple evolving systems and we
talk a little bit more about that tomorrow
i'm going to present is very highly prestigious you of what's important to make sure
work OK so this is what i believe
are important to making hinges were other people would have would tell you very different
but it's my lectures i can tell you what i want because here is a
can only called g a
initialize population
the sun
period of time you evaluate the fitness you selected
a new population based on the thickness you need to members of population you to
cross over and he returned the best member of the population of the sometimes there's
lots of variants on this ritual talk about some of those later
so let me give you a very quick example of this is this is the
graph coloring problem to a given a graph
chris evert citizens images what you want to do is you want to call it
the graph you want to sign a colour to each of the vertices
to minimize the number of edges with the same colour differences
so these are called colour conflicts this is a perfectly coloured graph because on the
complex and how did that produces produces by first occurrence the
i do culling that season and putting in the edges of i didn't get any
colour conflicts so
i cheated but wish to see algorithms to to do this but then g
let's take the g g eight in slow motion so you firstly just generate a
big population and and often people use randomized
colourings you could think of having a more intelligent way of
forming a new population there's some advantages of just using around population is it gives
you a very diverse population to start off with so these are just randomly coloured
and then you have to
evaluate the fitness
see you take a graph and you can
the number of
edges where
you have third
for all the same colour in this case the cost is a
when you select a
new population
but using preferentially fit members one way of doing that is you signed some kind
of weight
so far this is actually to do a technically in biological speak fitness is a
measure of the number of offspring you compute potentially
potentially produce
and this is kind of use slightly ambiguously in an evolution in GA's because people
actually just talk about
fitness is can any measure of how fit you are of one to be strictly
proportional to the number of children you produced
so when you have some probability to do with
your fitness
and then you select
from this probability
distribution so there's many ways of doing this election there's many ways of going from
belief in how
your members of the population are
to producing this mission measure in some of these are better than others and the
talk very
briefly about how they define what they are
mutation you basically change account of one or more of the vertices of we have
a problem like this we choose
the third season random
so which is this one and we just change
its colour
OK that may or may not increase
the cost in this case it increases the cost of decreased the cost were trying
to reduce the cost
i could
two mutations involve more than one
mentioned more than once
so it changes colors
one of them was one of those
what happens
one the increases it increases a sort of like you can present wrong but
that's so in that case
i just actually end up swapping
when my colour complexes so as to solve blind imitation
and in crossover ideas i take two members of my population ages like those random
are pair of members of the population random
and then i take one half of one and the other half of the
in this case
i've taken this half of this one and this half that one third of like
i can also produced to complement of that we take this half of this one
and this offer of one so often you can do the complement and
to some advantages to doing both at the same time so you don't lose any
genetic material
so is it usually costs associated with crossover
so here are two graphs are quite low cost graphs
this one actually
evolved to find these these are quite low cost graphs
if i came across some over
so before crossing a sort of dividing them into how does not really any particular
instead you could say OK i'm going to divide basically my my my initial
state vector into some vectors of lower dimensionality on that they these guys want to
time using say
initial processing so the same idea this selected jury protocol MCMC idea you bright your
initial something problem in the sequence of support so for example i could consider exactly
the same thing OK well basically what i'm doing is that now instead of basically
proposing sampling adding appalled distribution applied to they all the company
at the same time at each iteration of my reason i picked world only one
of the coordinates of the state vector OK so uniformly between and
in the set one two two nx number the dimension of the problem then i
propose only
candidate new value for all of the state components white k on they use the
same the marginal
as marginally independent pop although the distribution and the marginal probability distribution on the joint
choice so this is simply an malden shifted
on the i accept
these basically
local modification of the state vector because i've only modified xk
using the metropolis hastings acceptance rates OK so the thing i suppose which in this
case is simply basically
what i have written before instead of having to raise your proposal all over the
essentially state space i just put basically the dissolution of the world component of modified
i'm going to discuss that next like so that's where i grew
so let's consider this time the case where work on that we discover it doesn't
agree with so
you do that
so this is basically you can compute easily
acceptance probability
of your metropolis hastings sampler OK all what you see appearing is that you see
appearing essentially the conditional distribution of the company in xk given the remaining value the
components OK
but i do know x minus k OK this is all the company but the
company xk time basically the marginal distribution of these get consoles OK
time to public so what you see is that these things this algorithm is nothing
but essentially kind of generalisation
of the gibbs sampler
because if i were to use the proposal distribution
for all y k the the conditional distribution company and j
given the remaining
the other component i would have an exit polls probability of one
so these things actually when you why did you think of what you've been doing
is nothing but actually a generalisation of what upsampling does except that instead of dating
component xk k according to the full conditional distribution you have more freedom and can
use any proposal distribution
OK so if you do it it seems that we don't actually quite well because
essentially using the same proposal
the distribution of the the case when i was trying to update essentially everybody at
the same time so i got the same structure full proposals
but i have data i do the update one at the time the acceptance right
now is becoming obvious fifty percent on in the sense that basically you can check
some are approximated europe you you actually good approximation of the target distributions like earth
could tell you if you had sample exactly from the y target you would have
equal to zero
someone please quite close to zero when the two bodies look so that seems that
in a sense we have one small decided if you the initial state vector intercept
component update them one at a time you might well OK because you actually have
much you kind of
acceptance rates so doesn't suffer from the curse of dimensionality and they don't infinity sorry
well well well that's not quite true as pointed out by one of your colleagues
because while he was working so well what i've been doing before
is because under the target distribution i was considering before
basically the components where independent from each other the target was factorizing so that's social
really simple problem actually not considered that basically
you have basically that
and the target distribution you have correlation
the company correlated clients basically which is sigma
then if you tried to
use basically
the same type of strategy so use the try to they all the guys are
well you find all that
essentially you can have an exit polls which is as bad as initial case not
surprising OK on this quantity which should be call approximated to the all well sampling
quality from this community via target distribution with zero mean he's like twenty eight so
you're really really OK
now if you try basically to the one at the time and date
you've acceptance rate which indeed
marginally you seem that basically algorithm is quite well because the acceptance rate of forty
percent because you when your data components one at the time but it's actually a
really bad on one one small why is it so bad it so bad because
actually what you're trying to do is that you have essentially i'm unsure vector which
can i where you can have extremely i'd like a large correlation between companies which
dated individually
so basically the algorithm gets stuck in local maxima even in this case word community
wide ocean distribution itself that that's actually
so more not quite good OK so
some all
you know once more just to point out that
you have to be very careful when using this type of MCMC tiebreaker is OK
is very flexible you can do this idea of like breaking up the initial vector
and inflexible some components of they then likes indeed early on i acceptance rate still
doesn't mean that the algorithm generates generated by mixing markov chain algorithm that makes very
quickly towards the target distribution because they are potentially really i don't want to be
a very strong dependency between components which are updated independently from each other termites
just one small warning about the use of this idea is OK
that's say a this kind of rejection like independent sampling egories
so for also form essentially the multicolored valediction says
you would like to dates
a lot of simultaneously a lot of value which are highly correlated together simultaneously
forty very difficult because you cannot exit polls which was very small
are you can try to obey them independently
you might have radii exit polls right doesn't mean that is a mix with k
so that's a bit something about the world and application and basically special case of
the metropolis algorithm which is actually quite useful particularly
it's to say well OK
we talk try to use
actually the fact that metropolis hastings gave us a bit more flexibility than an independent
samples so for the time being we considered the case where once you add to
the current state of the markov chain is x you move accordingly we're just proposing
and here in the denominator for the probability of the data
i've i've symbolically written that now is as an integral rather than something that simply
the thing the normalizes this posterior probability if you integrate over all possible
sum over all possible hypotheses
one of the things that you
will see in this formula that may appear bit odd our
not entirely
expected is that we are required to write down what our prior probability of the
hypothesis is before
you see the data
that seems a little strange before you've done the experiment how do you know whether
or not to higgs boson exists
well there's a bayesian statistics provides no unique recipe for writing down those prior probabilities
but there's no escaping them you can not somehow try to sweep them under the
rubble there are many attempts to do so so these these priors always exists
and bayes theorem really has a sort of if then character what it says is
that if your prior probabilities were specified by some pile of age
then bayes theorem indicates how those probabilities should change
in the light of the data
right it says how you're probabilities should be updated
when you see the outcome of your
of your measurement
the bayesian statistics itself gives no
unique prescription
for these priors
there are there are
that's a long story and i suppose i know nothing about the hypothesis to begin
with how can i write down priors and there are certain guidelines you can try
to follow but it's also very difficult aspect of bayesian analysis
you have ten minutes is
by that was that was my general comments on those two competing schools of statistics
now i would like to go on introduce a little more formalism about random variables
and i think that will bring us up to the top of the hour
a random variable is simply a numerical characteristic assigned to each element of the sample
and we can talk about discrete random variables such as the number of events or
or continuous random variables such as in an energy or momentum
let's suppose that the outcome of the experiment is some continuous quantity some variable x
i can ask then what is the probability to find x in some infinitesimal interval
near the value x o between x and x pos dx
you can you can argue i think very generally that probability should be proportional
to the size of the dx so you can imagine that probability has to be
proportional to dx and whatever
other function of x i need to multiply
to make that any quality
that is defined as the probability density function or PDF
the PDF f x basically
telling you what is the probability to find x not exactly
as specified value but within an infinitesimal intervals
if x represents the outcome of my observation and i make that observation it has
to be somewhere
so if i integrate this probability over all possible values of the variables
that integral has to be one
because the probability of the sample space is equal to one
in other cases if x is discrete and discrete OK suppose that is not continuous
but it simply has a certain fixed values x of i
then the corresponding statement would be that the probability of x by
it's just some numbers and we would call that is not a pdf simply a
probability sometimes the probability mass function in that case the sum of the probabilities has
to be equal to one that is to say
this variable has to take on one of its possible values make the observation
OK so here is another important related
the cumulative distribution function very often we want to ask for the probability that the
observed value will be less than or equal to some value x
so i would find that simply by integrating the pdf from negative infinity up to
and if i'm going to use a letter use different letters for the pdf maybe
f whatever
if i use a small f for the probability density function then i would typically
use a large as
for the cumulative distribution function
o space which
OK so
the cumulative distribution
so here just illustrate that if that was my
the interval between any two fixed limits
of the pdf that gives me the probability to make the observation between those limits
and if i do that from negative infinity up to some value of x and
plot the result as a function of x that i get a curve that always
starts out zero
and eventually comes up to one that's the cumulative distribution
in fact mathematicians would typically start by defining the cumulative distribution
and then saying the pdf is simply its derivative
that's a little more general in fact as you can imagine there could be cases
ex-prime equals y
why primary eagles that
negative x
we can write down the solution that directly but if you want to do i
give values and i vectors the matrix will look like this
equation will be lambda square
one zero lambda
plus one equals zero so the eigen vectors will be plus or minus argue values
usually plus and minus i
but in fact and then from then on you can work out of the usual
way the
i can vectors but
complex i vectors separate with the rear look you can avoid all that is by
writing down the solution
the solutions are sines and cosines one basic solution will be x equals
cosine t in which case what is why well why is the derivative that so
that will be a minus sign
another basic solution will start with x equals sign e in which case why will
the cosine t
it's trivial
if you do that
one of these things look like well
either these two basic solutions looks like a circle
not traced in the usual way but in the opposite way for example this starts
when t is equal to zero
it starts at the point one zero
now if this the minus sign were there this would be x equals cosine t
y equals signs which is the usual counter-clockwise circle
but if i change y from sin t two negative sign t it's going around
the other way so the circle is traced that way
and all the other circles this is a family of circles all of which according
to the values of c one c two concentric
all of which go around
so those are close trajectories those solutions the trajectory of the vector field closed
the come camera about right and they repeat in finite time
OK now
these are no good
is the kind of not interested
these are commonplace where we're interested in the good stuff today
and the good stuff we're interested in is limit cycle
a limit cycle
it is a closed trajectory with a couple of extra hypothesis
the closed trajectory just like those guys but has something they don't have mainly it's
king of the rules
they have to be isolated
no other guys nearby
and they also have to be stable
so the problem is here
none of these stands out that these stands out from any of the others
in other words there must be isolated means no others nearby
that's just what goes wrong here
arbitrarily close to each of these circles is yet another circle doing exactly the same
that means that it did this some there only a mild interest
what is much more interesting is to find out cycle
where there is nothing your body
something therefore the looks like this
here's our pink i let's make this window
there's a limit cycle seems to be
one of the year by guys do
well they should approach
so somebody here
like that
does this
spirals it gets ever ever closer to that thing
now it can never join
it can never joined it
because if you joined at the joining point
i would have to
solutions going through this point that's illegal
so all i can do is get arbitrarily close
other computer screen it will look as if joint it but of course you can
it can
it's just the resolution pixels not
the resolution is good
and the ones that start further away
it will take longer to
a find their way to limit cycle and i'll always stay outside the earlier guys
but they will get arbitrarily close to
how about inside
inside well start somewhere
and it does the same thing
and in and the first half of the talk here but i want to leave
you with the idea that this is just statistics
and by the way we come back to the example in the second half and
explain why i think this has not happened
i for example in detail this is just statistics and if i can help guide
our beliefs but can quite magical p value added
the p value greater than point zero five some people believe that for sure but
that's just the
an arbitrary complex is very similar to that there's nothing
stuff in it
after the break relax this assumption of no hidden common causes like this
so i guess is over
three thirty five thousand
they five minutes later
because this is kind of
called so but that's it doesn't seem like it it's often one
can we do anything if we relax the this assumption that assumption we can relax
and that's the learning quite a bit and that's what i'm going to show now
again i'm just saying what i've already said the main exceptions presence of hidden common
i guess it doesn't really seem reasonable
and we can still learn something if we relax the assumption
the causal embedded faithfulness assumption allows for hidden common causes
i almost hate to put the next
screen up here
all this is the one that i had to put up this one is fine
sometimes the data
tells us must be heading kamikaze missions this is this is interesting
in such cases we know that the faithfulness assumption is not warranted and let's look
at an example
we have four variables
and we have to observe these independencies
is independent of y axis independent of w
y of x and y is independent c
we observe those and only those independencies
i'm going to show that we make the faithfulness assumption
will obtain a contradiction
because because the problem causal faithfulness assumption results in a contradiction
that means that the assumption is not warranted for this particular
variables and probability distribution
i first of all we have to have the links in a
it was obvious that the white was an undirected graph well i started out with
an undirected graph in my learning procedure
i learned that these have to be
one thing that i started learning what direction the links at head
now why do these have to be willing to i mentioned that there is an
edge between two variables
if and only if
other variables rendered independent
ax is independent of y so there's no edge between x and y
x independent of WC there's no edge between x and w
why is independent of that same independency actually
so there's no edge wise dependency so there's no way out
so these are the edges
actually not independence these is not independent of w and y z and
it's just the the first step my learning process for those links
we have to the directions be because x is independent of y and w
this is some of the examples i've shown you before that since axis is obtained
is independent of w
if these links do not go this way
one of these things are going this way this won't whole
the link like this and i might as
i would say that x is in independent of w conditional on c
you know that the causal chain went that way or one this way
what the cause
and the because w
those are all say that x and w are independent conditional on the
only this direction says they are independent
so i know the
we also have to that way
we must have the arrow directions MCA because y is independent of and a
these areas have been this way
because it's the only direction says y and z are independent
so i have to be zero interactions
because it's the only one that's a w independent
after these direction because it's the only direction this is the and why are independent
we end up with the graph today
which is not a deck set directed acyclic graph contradiction and others made the causal
faithfulness assumption
an algorithm which adheres to an end up with something that
going be flattered that
there's no doubt faithful to the observed distribution that's the problem
this is this is certainly valid probability of you know the probability distributions which clearly
have these independencies and only these but there's no doubt which is which is
a perfect map
of that distribution
now how could that happen
how can that happen in the causal sense what what causal relationships could be going
on there would end up making a sincere
independence like these
so let's look at this supposed
the causal DAG in a satisfies the causal faithfulness assumption
lung cancer tuberculosis both because the positive chest x-ray which
it's true
my lectures and lung cancer both cause the peak which is also true say lost
quite a few people are probably sleeping in the rooms are i think
it's so
i suppose that is true that is that those are the causal relationships
then among x y and c and w we have the independencies i just showed
the previous slide
if this is the true causal graph
faithfulness assumption holds for this causal graph
this is what i want to search among these variables
is independent
of y and w
access to be independent of its non descendants given its parents and w and y
are clearly it's not descendants
and its parents is the empty set
if anything y y is independent of x a
right so i would have observed these independencies
among acts by we looked at those four variables this is what i would the
ones i've just shown you
right so that shows how
you can get those independencies
because this is hidden cause which are not observing
we do not have dependency on w
i i don't observe that
i'm just showing some very sad actually
the causal DAG containing the observed variables is the one in b