I'd like to start with some short introduction about the place of convex optimization optimization in general and
then an overview of those three tutorials
so I think everyone's familiar with the standard nonlinear mathematical optimization problem
very optimize and only a function at zero subject to a number of constraints and
and it's clear that's a very general problem that doesn't need to be motivated because almost any
engineering design problem any estimation problem can be written in this form
now unfortunately the General optimization problem is also very untractable
so in general this problem is very difficult to solve
at least if you mean by minimization you really mean find the best solution
subject to the constraints
convex optimization is useful or important because roughly speaking the nonlinear optimization problems
that are tractable coincide with the ones that are convex and the boundary between the convex and
unconvex roughly coincides with
easy and difficult problems
so in general the general problem's difficult to solve and
it's also very difficult in general not always easy to recognize the problems that are
and so that's why one of the major topics of this lecture
so there's one the important exception to this
so a class of problems that's well-known to be tractable and also quite easy to
recognize and that's the linear programming problem
there you minimize linear function
subject to a set of linear inequalities
so that was
so actually the study of linear programming more or less starts with or started the feel of mathematical
optimization in general or the study of numerical methods for optimization with dantzigs simplex method in
in the in the end of the
so dantzig introduced an
efficient method for solving linear programming problems
by computer
the applications had in mind were in logistics and operations planning but then since then
the applications of linear programming have
and now it's widely used in engineering and operations research also combinatorial optimization and a
wide variety of fields
and that's a little surprising because the problem itself it's clearly really very specialized because
everything is linear
but that hasn't stopped linear programming from becoming a very important
and widely used technique
and the reason of course is that it's easy to solve people can solve linear programming
problems of very large scale and that makes it interesting to look for applications of
linear programming exactly or with approximations and also it's makes it useful as an
subproblem or to solve subproblems in combinatorial or non-convex or
discrete optimization problems that you solve combinatorial problems by branch and bound and then every
subproblem is a linear programming problem and then the scalability of the entire method
comes from the
tractability of the linear programming problem
so for convex optimization it's more or less the same story except that this
it's more recent so convex optimization problem
been applied for maybe at last twenty
years or so
and other differences with linear programming is that it's a of course much more general because
you can allow the functions in the objective and the constraints to be nonlinear they
have to be convex so it's a very substantial extension of linear programming
therefore is also more difficult to recognize simple linear programming problems
but many of the other prop properties of linear programming also hold for convex
optimization so it's very tractable and we see that methods that people have developed or
some of some of the methods for linear programming extend very easily to
general nonlinear convex optimization problems
and it's also
it's used in a variety of applications but also in for non
convex problems as the basis of either
to be used in
exact global optimization problems or heuristics or
similar techniques
so some brief histories I mentioned linear programming at the start of the whole
development of mathematical programming then during the fifthies people extended linear programming to include an
quadratic objective function so the first extension they made was to replace the linear objective by quadratic
convex objective and that's a quadratic programming problem
at the end of the nineteen sixties it was sort of a maybe a smaller development it's called
and let's take let's take an example and I
and see how these and as an example let's take sulfur real chloride
so as to make it a little complicated
the to
right so don't worry about it
these compounds and I will tell you all you need to know we we have
accepted and how to draw and it says OK center the element with the lowest
average valence electron energy well if you look in year solvers less than chlorine which
is less than oxygen solver has the lowest average valence electron energy so
that's what the sulphur in the centre
right to put the sovereign is count of valence electrons well solver has 6 that's
the 3 s 2 3 to 4
on oxygen from 2 times and that's 12
because it's solvers to pass through to the for
and calorimeters to those
that gives us 40 and has 3 2 3 . 5 so we gotta come
up with
we have 32 electrons we have to use
OK and there's draw a single bond from each surrounding to the central atom and
subtract 2
valence electrons OK and let's just put chlorine here current year options options here so
2 4 6 8 minus and that gives us 24 so we have 24 electrons
we have to we have to come up with an answer is OK
distribute the remaining electrons in pairs so that each atom has a place the nonbinding
pairs on peripheral 1st which the higher average valence electron energy
right well oxygen has the highest valence electron energy so
let's go and put them 1 2 3 4 5 6 here but still 1
2 3 4 5 6 here and Tokyo and last but but but the around
now the the chlorines glorious have set right so
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 1 2
the war
and says OK so now you got
take an electron from that solver but here's electron from that soldier put it here
so we have solve we got 1 2
3 4 5 6 7
so 1 2 3 4 5 6 sulfur
1 2 6 we have 6 we use all the electron
but what we have here as well
this chlorine has taken 1 electron from the self
but the oxygen has taken 2 electrons from the
this is a kind of a special but when and you might expect that option
has the highest average valence electron energy so it's gonna wanna stop and take these
and take these electrons this is called data
I want this is what it's called when when anatomist takes both electrons the bond
right so what have we have 1
we have 1 2 4
binding domains and how many bonding well 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8
9 10 11 12
12 non bonding nonbonding 12 nonbinding domains
OK so this is looking pretty good we now have we got octet stability we've
got to know each each 1 is has a has an inert electronic structure
but a few things to note we notice because the sulfur and the chlorine in
the auction have different average valence electron energies of different electron affinities
this bond is going to be a little bit different than this bond we have
to account for that in some way because we know they don't have identical average
valence electron energy OK
OK let's try another
let's try something like
for which is what method
that what we know about nothing what we know is stable
but we also know
that is symmetric right it's symmetric
we know that it's not
it's polar right so those are the things that we those things that we know
about we also know that carbon
it is 1 s 2 2 s 2 2 s p 2
and we know invited we know hydrogen is and so if we look at our
our box
or box notation right we've got 3 states in the p orbital we got 1
in the in the s orbital if we apply the hunt the hunt the hunt
rule but we got a barrel down Arrow
but something else that we know
right we somehow have to take hydrogen attach at the carbons and we have to
make it symmetric and we have to make it not
we have to make non polar
and yet we know
that the shape of the shape of the s orbitals spherical
the shape of the p orbitals however not spherical it's it's asymmetric and moreover
this one should be easy because of this the total revenue
f double prime site why
times one times one
but what's there
but it's the y white
of this thing you see what's happening it's got a factor either constant
and now want i take another derivative get f double prime
and i had the old five from the first derivative but now the chain rule
for the next the river also producing and i so there's a nice query and
which is the exactly the minus one were hoping so it all
i really felt
fell apart when we used icebreaker minus one
so i i'm
i'm happy and two or three ways here one way is that we've got this
good list of solutions
except that they're getting somewhat messier
to describe
so we would really like to have a better
description of this specialist
where the function is just the power
and now and then the second thing i'm happy about is to have
begun to see
the magic of these of living
having this perfectly real equation but solving it by means of complex
which is just like which by the way everybody might say OK what about three-dimensional
UX experts pursue libraries uses equal zero well that things don't happen don't work
so it's really quite special to two dimensions
unfortunately but
everybody is tried but nobody is going to work
i i come back to this list from it just make it just to improve
the the
the looks of it
and how to do that
go to polar coordinates
go from x and y
are in state
because we're in the plane so we have a choice and x y is rectangular
are and say to you know of course is
polar so let's write in what is x in terms of our fate
just remember
remember this picture of polar according
here here we go out x
right we go up y and distances
or the and was made
so the point is
it just is given by the numbers are inside
as well as by the numbers x and y
and then x in this triangle is you were saying
these are times
cosine theta
and why
these are times something
in other words i can now
replace every x y are costly theta and every y by our science
and what i want to say is that all come out quite beautifully
i mean that this
br cos they this is our science this one will turn out to be
are squared cost two things
so let me put
race one and zero three this is a list of
the end cos
this is a list of are actually and
yes sign
and theta
so this is the
the ones on this list which looked like getting message here are really not in
polar coordinates
those are the
those are quite
why did why is that true
how do i see that OK
i'm economic so i should just do this experts i y to the end
let me just to do i'm i'm taking the real i got that list by
taking the real and imaginary parts of experts i y
but now
what's experts i y if i go into polar
that's the key what is experts i y polar court that's that's
the beautiful
so if you think that have come out well
and what is to come out of it are times in the i think
see that that's right because
this is the i say that is
this is
this is are
it the think as we said about the the i y is cos later
plus i size
sure of our cost they agree with x
and are assigned to a degree twice with a beautiful formula
so it's really just the real and imaginary parts
or either i think
to the and power
so you see how to tidy it is when the thing is i guess the
rule is when you're like multiplayer taking powers polar is really nice
because when you're multiplying complex numbers
just multiply the origin and the angles
it is that it's going to happen if i multiply are either i say the
times TV i alpha then all multiplayer and t
and all the exponent although they have
so all in this case whereas adding complex numbers is better over this
px y sus
multiplying is much better here in taking powers
even better still because we have articles and power
e to the end theme
and we can sure take the real part of that
because at all split into
just like this
now i have and say this so little split the cosine and say that and
science i science data and then
the real part will be
cosine part
so these sorry that these two
steps are so widely separated on the board
that these this pair
in polar coordinates is exactly the
so far into the board the real and imaginary parts of or the
so are cost
that's where there
that's a lot of what i wanted to mention
about explicit solution
we have this terrific list here
which is pretty nearly pretty much a complete list with its combinations or we can
jump and take something like this example
which might be appropriate for a particular geometry
what do i mean by particular geometry what the
with our knowledge of talk
come down
on knowledge of torque and angular momentum
we can now
rolling objects which roll down
a slow
for instance the following
i have here
senator or it could be sphere or for that matter
this angle is been
i prefer not to use all five because that
angular acceleration
and there's this friction coefficient with is the surface you know
and this
going to roll down
going to get an acceleration in this direction
and i will evaluate
the situation
when we have a pure role that means the object is not skating and is
not slipping
what is pure OR
if here
senator sphere
was israelis are
and i'm going to rotate it like this
role in this direction
centre got
called on q
once it has made a complete rotation
then the point q
has moved over the distance two pi r
we call that
if you're role
when we have pure all
the velocity
of this point q
and the
of this conference
you can read that this policy there
i had the same
in other words
exactly the same
it has to be
the conference
and these are conferences is always omega are this part always holds
but for pure
this holds
you can easily imagine
that if there is no friction here
if you object could be standing still
rotating like crazy
but you wouldn't go anywhere
but then we have skating and we're slipping
and then we don't have the pure all situation
if the object is getting was slipping then the friction must always be a maximum
if the object is impure role
the fiction could be substantially less
then the maximum friction
now i would like to calculate this you
the acceleration that the cylinder would obtain
when it pure rolls down that slope has mass and
it has length l
it has radius or
i would like you to use your intuition
and don't be afraid it's wrong
i'm going to roll down this inclined to silliness
they're both solid
they have the same as
they have the same length but they are very different in radii
good ever race between these two
which one will reach the bottom first
so i repeat the problem
two cylinders both solid
same length
same as
one has a lot is the
it's going to be a race going to roland on bureau
which one will win win real with
o things that the one with the largest radius will win
think the large with the smallest radius win
well things there will be no winner loser
the intuition is better than mine was we'll see how it goes
keep in mind what you thought was
and you will see it come out very shortly
OK let's put all the forces on this object that we know
this one is mg
and we're going to decompose that
in two
one along the slope
which is and g
sign beta
and one
perpendicular to the slope we've done that still zillions times
and this one was and he
cosine data
then there is right here
normal force
and the magnitude of the normal forces and cosine data
but there is no acceleration in this direction
and then we have
frictional force here
which i will write f of f
there is an anger
velocity at any moment in time omega which will change with time no doubt
and then
this centre point q
which is the centre of mass
it's going to
velocity v
and that we also change with time
and the
of the point q
which changes with time
of this conference because that is the condition of pure all
that equals omega ark
this is always true
but this is only true and pure all
i take the time derivative
the derivative of the velocity of that point q
it's for definition it's acceleration
so i get a equals only dot
times are because of our of being the angular acceleration
so this
is the condition
now i'm going to take to talk
about point q
when i think the talk about point q
on the first page
he has an address
and it's an address
for unicef
which is the united nations children's fund
and he starts his book
that address where you could send money right now that was very impressive put that
on page one of the book
because it puts the reader in moral dilemma
he points out that it's estimated that for every three dollars you to unicef
you can save a life
that's because there are people in this world who are not getting
medical care
there are people who are dying of diseases for which there are no known cures
because they don't have
the the best method which are often not even expensive but they living in such
so he says
why don't you
stop right now
and send a hundred dollars to units OK
and it was very impactful to start a book that way
because i doubt that hardly any readers
actually write out to check on this perhaps the unicef
and if you don't then you are in some sense responsible
for the loss of thirty lives
and so it's quite striking that helps you to reflect
and what makes us
what makes us
behave the way we do it by the way
when you go back to your computer
the unicef
and you can get one hundred dollars to unicef
with you can do it within the hour OK
maybe i could ask for a show of hands how many people do
i expect that not many of the world
i don't think that proves that you're bad people this is a very interesting philosophical
but what it means is that
there is a moral dilemma underlying all of our economic lives
and i think this moral dilemma is the same as the moral dilemma in finance
in the financial is just the people in finance are sometimes very successful
and they could give a lot more than one hundred dollars to unicef
the one thing that i want to emphasise in this course
i'll try to emphasise his
part of finance
it is actually full philanthropy
and so
the most important most successful people
in finance i believe and
giving the money away OK
and that means
you can't consume a billion dollars
there's no way that you can do that
what they end up you you can only drive one car at time right hand
if you have five cars
well i mean that's kind of
all right you could have five cars you you could drive a different one every
day but it's starting to
similarly ridiculous right
and anyway are not using them in the end up used by somebody else
i think the the outcome should be
and so those of you who are successful
really ought to give it away
so i'm bringing in outside speakers as part of this course
and i'm going to
among them bring in people who i think have been
philanthropist that that's the
that's the mode of thinking that
that is most attractive when you think about financial markets
so let me tell you about i have slots now for four outside speakers have
lined up to them
and then we tell you
about the two that have already lined up
the first one is our own david swenson
david swanson
came to
yale university
in nineteen eighty five
from wall street although he's yeah he was a year graduate
at that time the you know
the above
actually slightly under one billion dollars what what's the endowment of the endowment is defined
as the financial assets that yale university owns
yeah also has an art collection
which is worth many billions
we don't count that as part of the endowment because they will never sell it
and so it doesn't provide income for us and you also has
the physical plant like this beautiful building that we're in
that's not part of the endowment either the financial assets that has
at that time were
about a billion dollars
since then
david swinson has invested has managed investment
of this and that
it has
done phenomenally well so it's now
over twenty two billion dollars
that you know has in its endowment
and so he returned that he got
from nineteen ninety six to two thousand six
seventeen percent a year
and investment
last year
the return on the portfolio
it was twenty eight percent in one year
now i don't know how impressed you're you're before that it was twenty two percent
in one year
now some of this might be like
but i don't think it's all love because he's done this consistently for so many
if you look up around this campus now to see a lot of construction a
lot of things are being spruced up and improve well that's
you know i think david swanson has had a big hand in doing that
it's having the money that makes it possible
and so
you know the endowment yale is something like two million dollars per student now
that's just sitting there
as money that could be spent
and so
how did you do this one of the amazing things that it seems to have
something to do i think with academic
that being part of the university community
is a good thing for investing
and you can see some evidence in that in that
harvard university princeton university and and other universities have done extremely well on the endowments
however not quite as well as you know i think is the number one performer
so it is very interesting that we're able is very significant that were able to
get david swanson
he doesn't do a lot of public speaking that he is willing for for
young people like you who to do this
that's one of our outside speak you also has two books about investing
here's the wine glass
the same series is
that one
by the time when he got it to work with about five hundred of those
classifica article discount by the way because we were wanted to be sure that we
can do it for years to come
so here's the wine glass
and here is the loudspeaker
and we're going to generate sounds very close to the resonance frequency of these class
which we
i have already determined before you came in four hundred
eight hertz
good you see the glass there
and to make you see actually this wonderful motion of the class we'll struggle with
his lights
at the frequency is slightly different from the frequency
of the sounds of it you see
the glass moved
very slowly
and then we will increase the volume of the speaker
and then we some look if we have right of residence
the glass may actually break
i think this is the sound that you're going to hear at low volume
and i think i can on the
strobe light now
you can make it dark
and i want to warn you
that the sound levels
it's going to be quite high i will have to protect might use
and you actually may have to do the same i will first increase the
volume of the sound see where i close enough to residents
artists motion vectors
is the result
this trail
which is not exactly the same frequency as the glass
i can change that
all right
so we're very close to resonance
classes community responded to this song
and i will
some ideas
and slowly increases
sound volume
take take you you'd do you know that it was ik ik r by or
won't stay in d in s impaled thought in or about getting thoresen but get
in get in document d and e rhe mm
the cost less
i think you will probably agree with me now that
multiplying out this product you know explicitly one plus X 1 y 1 bracket one
plus a x plus 2 y 2 bracket and so on when you multiply out basically
at each bracket you have to say whether you're going to include or not include
the the explicit features either you gonna use one or you gonna use XI
YI so every combination of including or not including XI YI will occur in that
multiplying out so they'll be two the n possible products and each will correspond to
some subset of the XI YI being selected and the others being ignored and that
corresponds exactly to the sum over all of the subsets of XI of 1 up
to n up with the product of those that are selected so this now of course can
be evaluated very efficiently in the input space here you just gotta multiply the
corresponding feature together at one and product up so it's basically pretty much the same
as doing a an inner products a normal inner product in the input space
except that you have one extra edition for each hem feature and you multiply them together instead of adding
them together normally you would you know just sum XI YI now you're producting XI YI plus
one but clearly this is not a big overhead and you've evaluated this you know
exponentially large sum in a direct way
so this is this is sort of a very sort of archetypal example of the kind of
tricks that can be made in order to do these kernel evaluations in these very
complex feature spaces efficiently and you know many of them involve swapping some products so
one way  to think of this and to sort of think of these types of algorithms is
to make a graph representation of them and the way I I've drawn the graph
that would correspond to this kernel here and what we see here is essentially the
each of the stages in the graph corresponds to one  of these elements in this
product so in this we have either one or X one plus X one
Y one in the next element we have one or X two Y two and
so on and then the features that we're actually summing over correspond to all the possible parts
between source and sink so the source is the first vertex sink is the last vertex so every
path through this graph corresponds to one of these features and the the evaluation
of that feature corresponds to multiplying all of the labels on that path so here you know
say we've selected one times X two Y two times X three Y three times
one  etcetera and so on so obviously now it's even clearer that the parts exactly
can be characterized by whether they go on the one path or the X one Y one
and so they're characterized by a subset of the of the features one
up to N  the subset selecting when you go in the lower arch and when you
go in the upper arch exactly every subset corresponds to one path and so there
are two N paths and and so those are the features that you're actually evaluating over and this
argument that I made here about the equivalents of these two corresponds to summing over these
features by dynamic programming method okay so that's a very simple case but we can
also do it for the polynomial case so here in the polynomial case we have
D vertices corresponding to the dimension the products that we're thinking so this
is the polynomial kernel dimension where you take a constant plus the inner product add them together
and then take it all to the power D and now so in this case we have archs
one for each possible thing that we could have in this bracket here so the
bracket is X one Y plus X two Y two plus R so there's a
arch for each of those possible terms in that and then there's one
step in this graph for each of the multiplications the outside multiplications D steps here and
notice in this case all of them are the same and again every path
corresponds to a one feature in the feature space and the kernel corresponds to summing all
of the possible  overall of the possible paths the products of all of the
features one that path and again this corresponds to a dynamic programming algorithm that
essentially computes the the thing step by step and it turns out it's
just a product of each of these each of these components so it's just race
to the deep R here okay so now there's a quite well known kernel called the anova kernel
which is a slightly different arises from a slightly different graph and what
this does is trying just select up to D features so the same types of
features we're selecting and so the way it's organized is that the rows correspond
to not selecting a feature so if you just move along here you
don't select the feature if you select the feature you drop down to the next
row and what you have to do is to drop down D times to get
to this final vertex here so essentially  it's a bit difficult to see but
this is much longer than it's deep if you see what I mean I haven't drawn it very well but
it's sort of  long and thin and you basically have to go down D times
to reach the bottom point and  the point at which you move down corresponds
to the particular feature that you selected so you have to select D features from
among the N possible features and each path because you can never go back up
each path corresponds to selecting exactly D features and there's one path for each possible combination
of D features and so again that corresponds to the that is exactly how the anova
kernel is defined as the features being every possible combination of D features and
again you can evaluate it by a dynamic programming you basically start with the kernel at
this in this row and then evaluate over each row in succession until you
as long as the solution curve stays convex concave
well that's probably
two optimistic is probably more like this
so in other words in this case if the curve is convex
the soil oilers going to be too high
necessary to low
let's forty four
oilers too low if it's concave then oiler is too high
OK that's great
they just one little problem left
if we don't have a formula for the solution and we don't have a computer
this busy drawing picture for us
in which case we would need any of this anyway
how are we supposed to tell if it's convex or concave
back to calculus calculus to the rescue
one is a curve convex curve is convex if its second derivative is
positive because
the first to be convex means the first derivative is increasing over time
and therefore the second derivative which is the derivative of the first derivative should be
just the opposite here the curve the slope is
the first derivative is decreasing over time and therefore the second derivative is negative
so all we have to do is decide what the first and second what the
derivative the second derivative of this solution is
let's of we should probably call the solution to y of x will today
why one means the solution that started at this point so in fact probably would
have been better from the beginning to call that y one except there is no
why one would say that means the solution which started out at the point zero
so i'm still talking about the solution like that right
so i want to know if
this is positive the second derivative is positive at the starting point zero or negative
again you calculate the second derivatives do
and even if you don't know what the solution is explicitly and the answer is
you can do it from the differential equation itself
i do that well
easy why prime equals x squared minus y squared OK
that tells me how to calculate
why prime
if i know the value of x and y in other words the point zero
what would be the value y double prime well
differentiate the equation
two x
minus two y
why prime don't forget to use the chain rule
i want to calculate and zero one
in other words my starting point is that curve convex or concave
let's calculate y is zero equals one
OK what's what primers zero well i don't have to repeat that calculation using this
i already calculated that it was negative one
now the new thing is what's why double prime zero
well it is this
it's right to
time zero
minus two
negative y which is one
two times one
times y prime which is negative when you want to see we're pulling ourselves up
our own bootstraps which is impossible but it is not impossible because we're doing it
so what's the answer
zero here
i've calculated without having the foggiest idea what the solution is and how it looks
i calculated that second derivative of the starting point is to
therefore my solution is convex
at the starting point and therefore the soil approximation if i don't carry it out
too far will be
it's convex boiler to us
now you can argue that the world would the
the you know
i it
so you go like this is that then
but then it see it catches up with them so
well of of course if the curve changes from convex to concave then
it's really impossible to make any prediction at all
that's the difficulty
so all this analysis is only if you stay very near by
however i wanted to show you the main purpose of in my mind was to
show you how to use the diff it's these equations how to use the differential
equation itself
to get information about the solutions without actually being able to calculate the solutions
so that's the that's how to find out something about now what i'd like to
talk about is
how do i handle
so i mean that's in now in a sense i started the year analysis
in other words
the error by definition of the area is this difference
the arabic
so in other words i'm asking here is the are positive
as it would be
it depends which way you measure usually take this line is that so you the
here would be considered positive here would be considered negative although i'm sure there's a
book somewhere in the world which does the opposite
page by just using the absolute value of the year
what's the statement that the method is producing answers which are too low
or two i
the question then is naturally
it's not the world's best method it's not as bad as it seems
it's not the world's best method because that convexity in concavity means that you automatically
and do
introducing a systematic error
if you can predict which way the error is going to be by just knowing
what the curve is convex to concave
it's just is that what you want i mean you want a least have a
chance of getting the right answer this is telling you you're definitely going to get
the wrong answer all it tells you is
and it's telling you because your answers can be too high or too low
we'd like a better chance of getting the right answer now
so the question is how do you get a better method
searches for a better man
the first method which will occur i'm sure to anyone who looks at that picture
look if if you want this yellow line to follow
the white one
the white solution more accurately
it's difficult to the thing i have always trouble explaining
maybe i've never found a good way to explain to me it seems clear what
it means but it doesn't help you
one way to put it is this you have a program which consists of zero
and one bits and you want to measure the amount of information in a algorithm
in the program
but you see
in a way with the old definition from the nineteen sixties the program size complexity
where most and bit strings need
need programs of of
above very close to and
in you really had three simple alphabet because in a way what you had was
a blank at the end of the programme saying this is what the program
but you see if you have three simple alphabet which is zero one in blind
you really are not using the blank
now if you just have it at the end of the programme you really want
about one-third you know to to use
all the bits you want zeros and ones to be clear likely and if you
have a black you should have blanked care about a third of the time
you see your really cheating
when you add a third symbol
so if you want to eliminate the blank have only two symbols instead of three
then there's the question of how you can tell when the program not when it
stops running but syntactically where the program ends
you know whether this stuff
and there's no problem in doing that what you have to have is you have
to have a programming language or you could say a universal turing machine
which reads a bit by bit the program and decides by itself when i read
the last bit without having to read beyond and see that it ran off the
end you know
you know they got a blank or the the program is that's that's all the
bits you know and the final condition something and you can do that
what you have to do is one of the many ways to do it and
one way to do it is to put the prefix in front of the programme
saying how header which is how many bits are
coming behind there are many many ways to do it there
infinite number of ways to make programmes of
the main thing you do is you just have to decide
the universal turing machine i pick
has a live program at the beginning of the prefix
and that parts of the limiting
you know because you just put a special character at the end or or if
you like with the parentheses balance you know where the program and
and then after that you have real binary data
and the
the prefix which is self-limiting indicates how to interpret the raw bits come afterwards
and it will have to read them bit by bit and you have to decide
by itself and in the prefix you can put any way
there are many possible ways of deciding when
you know how many bits the
as you read the bits you know there are many ways of encoding information in
the program
and all of them are equally good
this is the notion of a self-limiting program so when you do that
and the typical and the string is more than and bits
it is how many this will roughly you say ten plus the number of bits
you need to specify n
in in fact the exact result is that the most ambitious strings need and plus
h was order of unity
and n is the size in bits of the smallest of the program that calculates
the number and
and this is roughly of the order of base two logarithm of n
so this is what the number of bits you need to add to the programme
to make the programme supplementing to indicate within itself many big program
now this
this may look like cheating i mean it may not be clear what you need
to do this but there are a lot of reasons for doing this i mean
one reason for doing this is you want
complexity or organic information
to be so bad idea in other words you want this to be the case
this is the size in bits of the smallest program that calculates a pair of
objects should be bounded in size by
the the sum should be bound by the sum of the sizes of the
the individual smaller programs for each of the objects but i can't with the content
is basically do this and do that and then produces result pair
OK so that's a fixed number but this is not the case for nineteen sixties
program size complexity but with learning programs this is the case
so you get this program size complexity of this algorithmic information content it is about
it which is very natural or you could say additive
i mean you can combine programs
you can
you can take subroutines and just put them together concatenate bit strings and there's no
problem because
each of these subroutines indicates its size so you can then split up the bit
string into some programs without having to add this that's the idea really to be
able to build the program from somebody
OK so this is a key factor
another key fact
is that with this you can define the whole probability omega which i haven't done
yet with programs you can define it with this approach
so in my belief in the nineteen sixties definition of program size complexity is just
wrong or
you know it was a mistake it was it was a good first attempt
it was OK but i think the best thing to do is forget about it
completely thrown in the garbage forget about that some of the people who work in
my field do not share my view
and they like to for example they like lead to technical questions so there is
some good people now
what are the names right down the
in new zealand as someone
he is the co-author of the book
which is a highly technical book and one of the things they love to do
because they need problems to work on this is to compare the nineteen sixties
definition of computer program complexity with the nineteen seventy definition and
this gives you no homework is given the mathematical exercises problems to work on and
they can prove theorems but i basically considered the it's a mistake and you should
just forget about this it was a mistake to find this OK now
i think it's fair to say that lane eleven sort of had this idea of
self-limiting two
roughly at the same time that time but he did miss out on
this is not enough there are more correct and you have to make the theory
so let me tell you about
there is a notion of relative complexity
so this is the size in bits of the smallest program to calculate actually if
you're given y for free
this is an important notion in this theory that i haven't mentioned the now
now that the
but no i do what i said in words
by the way use h because h is used by shannon
you know in shannon information theory
and i like to use the same age but interpretation is different because
he's talking about ensembles and all kinds of stuff and i'm talking about the size
of a small bits of the smallest program so the notation is the same but
the the interpretation of different so the this relative complexity what is the right definition
about complexity
OK it's the first of all i will be the size in bits of the
smallest supplement program to calculate x if you're given y for free
so long
for his
o thing
and so on
my that
so far
point that could be generated by the distribution
you don't see the point which is
in our case
time some cluster labels
the the data and then you change in the world
i'm very unlikely to be the core of the clustering but then you changed
and in such a way that
it's more likely to create
to improve
but you can actually make it worse
however the you'll
the probability that to improve what we already have is higher than the probably destroyed
and then you keep doing this random the too small changes to what you heard
o thousand pounds of
and then eventually you
look at
the final cycles and get a and
the samples the pain
later in the distribution and the independence of the not independent samples so you have
to actually take them you can take them all you have to take this to
the board but eventually to get samples from the true distribution and then you can
compute averages and do other things
and in particular it may happen if you're lucky in that you're not going to
converge and instead of going all over the place they will stay in small neighborhood
and so that will be probably closer to what they call the two
so this is this is that there are other methods of doing markov chain monte
carlo markov chain is that you
changing your changes from the previous sample to the next
so not growing independence of this particular one is called gibbs sampling
i like it on the
so how do do it in the case of judicial mixtures
it is incredible but people who actually fit additional mixture state it works
actually they recover true parameters
so it's not as hopeless as you may think
so these are the power input of
that's good
you have to have state the state is that
the description of the current current sample data
and that is the cluster assignment for every point you have a cluster label
and for the cluster parameters
i hope this for the images rather sloppy notation because the positive labels may not
always be one two three two k that does this thing numbers
and you see why because some clusters disappeared sunglasses disappear
so the class label on make
i don't have
and the patient goes into space and you can think of it is very similar
to to the surface of the year award more of the k means algorithm one
step is to
reassigned the labels and other historians find the parameters
and then you
so yes and the labels
you think it's pointing to
and this is the point is clinical sort of all utilities cluster because you're going
to create a new
anyway with a single point or you use the cluster labels based on this
so before so it can go to any clustering
probably to large cluster with high probability to larger
or can we create a new cluster of
note that in this formula the
depends are i
the former number one equation and the probability of sampling
OK dependent i
here it doesn't matter which i is already
alright i is equal to
because sample based on
on the end points
when you resample the clusters
and then you will be something gives us a new cluster so if you don't
the point in already existing cluster that to create a new
so we have to sample the thing
from the function
this is from the edges
the second
one is that we have a new label for class
forty point
this can this can happen to be told about
it is not guaranteed
the will result is at least half gamma
and what does this mean in words
it's saying that when we take the max over
columns distribution it's saying that there exists a distribution over the columns or equivalently over
weak classifiers
so that you we have the mean over examples xi so that for every example
x i y i corresponding to a row of the the matrix
this loss will be at least half plus gamma so this loss
if we translate it based on our definition of the matrix this loss is the
when the column j is chosen according to q
of choosing weak classifier which correctly classifies that example
so what does this mean it saying that there's the distribution over weak classifiers
so that
at least half hapless gamma of those weak classifiers as weighted by the distribution q
correctly classify every training example
it's saying that there exists in other words there exists a weighted majority vote
of the weak classifiers
which correctly classifies all of the examples
and in fact because
aleister hapless game of them are correct that actually means that the marginal blps two
OK so summarizing this
but we argue here
is that the gamma weak learning assumption is equivalent to the value of the game
you know minmax equals marksman being at least the hapless gamma
and that in turn is equivalent to every example every training example being
correctly classified
with some positive margin ips
some positive margin by some weighted majority classifier
so it's saying that
the weak learning assumption because of game theory
not because of anything approved before but because of the fundamental results of game theory
the weak learning assumption says that boosting should in principle
the possible it should be possible for their press to be able to find this
weighted majority classifier which correctly classifies all of the training examples
and what's more the weights the majority vote classifier not arbitrary the weights are actually
a maxmin strategy for this game they're not arbitrary their particular yes
close to what equilibrium OIC i
i you yes i didn't get there you bathe that's what it's going to show
so the
yes so these minmax maxmin are the same as the nash equilibrium
because it's a zero-sum game
OK so
the idea then for boosting is to try to find this maxmin strategy using the
general algorithm designed for general games in one which has the property that it will
find the maximum strategy by playing the game repeatedly
OK so we can use the general repeated game-playing algorithm
for finding this maxmin strategy and that's really what adaboost is doing
so adaboost is actually a special case of the more general algorithm for playing repeated
games and it has the property that it will converge to the maximum strategy
to see how the boosting process is repeated play of this game
so what's happening in boosting on every round booster chooses the distribution over examples
and the weak learner chooses the weak classifiers
and now we cluster should have high accuracy with respect to the distribution dt
so we can view that playing this game repeatedly
right because
the boosters using this distribution over examples but that's the same as choosing the distribution
over the rows of the matrix because the rows of the matrix are the same
as the examples
and the weak learner chooses the weak classifiers but that's the same as choosing the
column of this matrix
and the column can be viewed itself as a distribution over the columns the distribution
which is
pure which is concentrated on just a single
column of the matrix
and what's more
finding the weak classifier with high accuracy with respect to dt is the same as
trying to find
weak classifier distribution qt with high loss for the row player
which is the goal of the column player
so the point is that the booster the weak learner really playing this game repeatedly
and this turns out to be a special case and i can explain this part
but this turns out to be a special case of the more general algorithm for
playing repeated games and it can be shown in general that if you look at
the average of the peet's that are played by this algorithm in general not just
for boosting but in general the average of the pcts will converge
two an approximate minmax strategy for the game
being played and likewise the average of the cuties converges to maximin strategy
so this algorithm in general
finds maxmin strategies and that's exactly what
adaboost is doing which is a special case of this algorithm
OK so to summarise this so the weak learning assumption what we've shown is that
the weak learning assumption implies that the maximum strategy
the rest combinations covering not certified satisfies this
setting here know
comm can compute is
entries here then we compute
the optimal coefficients and was that
we can actually can't repair
the combination technique same example of before
ten to the minus sixty on the right
the graph here before
this graph we know that was optimised commission so this is the least square error
which goes down all the way
the function of the reason
situated at some point
so this way
was optimise commissioning which is a bit more competition effort to compute is
scalar product small but it's not too bad it's not
but too much more
it really does depend on the number of dimensions
we can now repairs that
and now we compare with some
other approaches for regression using benchmarks but by some other guys
i'm going to read it's experiments
this is now
they don't mind if and regression examples needed could do six he has this really
couldn't because of too high too many dimensions or to many categorical variables
so these are the results of all methods
this is the best of the results in this the the ranking of our method
and we can see
over the mean when for cases where the best
although these nine or ten methods two other cases we still
doing quite good
and even again this only a very small datasets only about eight cells
so i was really sings that for more data it's more suited but even for
the small datasets but quite
and if you look it's
one hundred thousand datapoints synthetic datasets
usual friedman examples
we can also see that we're doing
so we compared against used the best for them on this dataset used masterly
and we can see OK let's first look at these two that we do
the same as as we have much less time or better than SVM
always better than mars
what's the freedman one
this example has the status that has ten dimensions five of these are noise
obviously we get a bit disturbed by noise could do doing better than the others
if we constrain ourselves using only five non noise variables we can do better
there is no
what we're working on now
is to find ways
automatically detect
this kind of studies that we've always have this
so that's
some of the things i will talk bit later on
what also trying to do is use it for semi supervised learning
that we had that anybody talk about before summer school anybody you heard about semi
supervised learning
so that was semisupervised learning is that
besides using as before all the
data points where we have
data label
also try to use the information of the unlabelled data as well
the different different approaches to that one approach is to use it
dramatic distribution of the data coming from
o thing ideas for money for learning
one one ejected from some
other guises
OK if you only answers to labelled data
promising OK
this is probably quite
class boundary but if you have the unlabelled data as well
it's much more obvious
class but probably should for look something like this
two groups working on that
we essentially picked up to approach from back in you
it was a use ideas from manifold learning
two at the national organization come to the setting
OK so
very short manifold learning thirty years says that you have some
yes you that you want to have a three-dimensional
but you assume that the data lies on submanifold you want
find some something wonderful
a couple of days
it's also known as the nonlinear dimension reduction
manifold learning so a lot of others in the last couple of years isomap locally
linear embedding depression i'm obsession
and so on
they essentially
a similar things so the
computer neighborhood the input space can nearest neighbors or something like that
matrix based on
the the differences in this part
how to from this neighborhood how to come to this
matrix was which represents is these membership relations of the distances between the different points
then make betting we have the top or bottom i values
they also can be viewed as
kernel PCA
one way to
use it for money for semi supervised learning
is too
the normal setting before
well we just
and intrinsic regulation terms which should describe the data distribution
so this this way was also proposed by picking u
and they also can show that this is again an refusing kind space
some other works by the people japan consumed
for example
but in a different way but using also manifold learning ideas
it's essentially the same trend extrapolation german we want to
plus you know the manifold authorization approximates
these relations so there's a senior
function relies of this you see these are the edge which operates on the data
into is the graph so we take our nearest neighbour so we have to be
the adjacency some ways of these constructs are binary distance so he
so you
approximate system for this
and then you can
prior is the graph laplacian so if the graph laplacian which is
he was w just some
user biometrics was the sum of
he graduated from
want to possible for each
this we no introduce into our setting
so again we have two terms before
and houses
it is a regularisation to
what is the discrete space
make it linear equation system out of that
well so i will continue the curvature announced kaesong of
days in kernels because one of the ways
you can
and i'm the going to focus on the idea is that there is this which
so here we are in the family
you can also try to find by a disease
just a combination so that can in some of the
features or strings there is
there is no way to make
just space by making it by looking
so fast
example of this is feature space he's not thinking here using dictionaries which is there
is no one
this processing
i also illustrate the for protein sequences so here it is kind of similar to
to camera is actually use can use
on the day
we some parameters following may just space make feature film five peace
you choose dictionary
of sequences of these in the case of of data OK that you will use
the consequences for some reason was
what does this article in the dictionary is a dictionary of for sequences and this
then you should measure of similarity so you also can because the image of p
and this is a new tool
to describe what your statement is OWL
the world is very prime so this could be sworn by using
he is be the with suppose
when you string fuzzy and what she really that kind of thing
five is in the expeditionary
or was actually that day by waltz
that correspond to the image in your stream is there was the dictionary
so it is natural that should because from this it has been used in different
ways the first one
my biography
caucus was something called the motor control
so the common that by committees we know that
we we have something called lot these which typically corresponds to so many that can
have different definitions of history and there's not many things but he is this short
sequences that some function of the structure
so there are different ways of monkeys and be natural way to transform
as protein sequences into vector is to take a database of these
and to assist with which is present in a string of impressive scoring so you
have one thousand images
then you can check whether each of the one thousand
is not is on is in the place on all or part of the corpus
christi can score which was a sequence and this
the sequence by the sets of scores dictionary
which is a bit related to what you get us on
i measure between strings is to take a dictionary
so far away but been used pudong is taken training sets so here is that
is the
is it really so will
a nationally prominent for a set of n sequences
and in fact use these sequences as dictionary
so as to indicate the rest
of strings and you assume that for some reason you have some measure of similarity
between strings this could be
as mentioned earlier
what are you
and then you're represent each sequence
your training sets and also to the set of tall similarities
the same thing being computed for background
so by using these we are the strings in the training set
OK so here for the training set as purposes easier both for training and machine
learning libraries and it is also
the representation use
so it was because when you would have to classify new history that is not
training set the history can be
to this because you region
princess so you can point your finger
the symmetry we all
princess and then apply much here
so there is no longer just just mentioned because it is common useful commonly used
sometimes called the account
so there are some
so different positions behind but this is using is going play with us
visual similarity is not positive that you want to use as you and i want
to do that just computes matrix similarities but instead of saying that he not the
just symmetrical
and then there can be no peace
thank you transfer the
between your toes and these deposits the
because it is convenient to have some measure you can use it to define the
vector of features
and then use the central position make machine
OK so these few examples of explicit
future vision for strings and move on to to family of approaches that be more
interesting terms of mathematics vols and interesting because they make use of
things we have seen about the policy but you are
question is supposed to be model streams how can make anything between just modelling good
of good kernels
so what we call in this these methods we use the world pretty models what
i mean by a model
it is the sum of those in the family of distributions so typically approach the
family of distributions p what done is assumed to be a finite dimensional vector of
and for instance of the features on then you use for and by the way
is already become models that we saw now
i think statistical models so here we assume that someone has been able to design
a probability model
bans on any parameters we call that benefit parameters and the question is can we
use the model
to make it clear
so this singles but not to mention the markov models full strings in committees when
you focus on RNA processing there's something called stochastic on the graphs that have been
used a lot
and which also for ontology can use tools
two to make better
so what can you do when you have such a model of what is the
link between these and the possibility to make the kernel
i would describe it here three
three can also be protocols that allow you to derive positive can from your so
called so historically the first one
which is probably the
the most difficult
two is it justified but which is a convenient is the official journal
it was but i think it was the already by the nineteen ninety eight by
jacqueline house
the for
but the thing is between i mean it just model but it is it we
tried explicit features so it could be related to the various approaches to to mention
how many features anything on this three which is also when you suppose to use
it and then you know that you can follow strings of different things
OK so this is the right
they want to represent a by a factor of essential
the importance weight
you look at the expression of the importance weight
so what you see here is that remember in the previous case in the second
but something case you i was in the case where the importance sampling time and
was importance sampling at time n minus one times this quantity
because of some examples
previously according
to the weighted sum of weighted empirical measure the new particle approximately distributed
according to p x one given y one so i don't need to have this
tell me more
and this is simply from the fact because if you sample at time n minus
one then you particle approximately distributed according to the target was stereo ten minus one
so in the explosion of the weight you don't have the weight importance sampling weight
at time n minus one
any more just have to compute these k
you we normalize the guy on the
some again
so very very simple algorithm
any question at this stage
OK so
so what is possible
so this is a graph where trying to illustrate the second but importance sampling resampling
o particles in right
i assume you start time
instead of time on the document to the court of
so at times are all your examples today
you sample
articles OK so this is x not one x two x three x four c
that time when you've got the poles of salvation y one k
and the idea of salvation while
he's basically you're going to put in the case where essentially e
x is close to y then g of y given x is large so for
example you could be in the case where y is equal to explore some gaussian
noise so that essentially the g of y given x is gaussian mean x y
and z one
you've got to particles at time one OK
and they all have wait
so one two three four
on you sample
from the
distribution of these particles OK i'm basically
the bigger the size of the dot
the most likely you're going to get many offsprings OK so in these cases where
you not very lucky say on despite the fact that these particle as it doesn't
have to we evaluate your we sampled two
o springs
in this dislocation these particles as wonka p
this because has what he here OK
if you evaluate NASA this is the resampled particles
now you evaluate essentially the likelihood of this new
OK so basically this one because it's very close to the salvation
it doesn't very
essentially a potential
so so this thing i weight whereas those guy that kind of a region of
low quality mass so they have lower
so for example four times
from the empirical measure of
of these four particles
we this guy being
large weight this once more like this one which is one small weight you resample
and that's that you're one small quite unlucky because this guy
as tools supporting this one despite having a low weight as one as bring on
this one as is well offspring
OK so despite the fact that this algorithm is doing quite but actually not because
it doesn't always on william good original space still don't really you don't you don't
lose talk
of the of the white regions so policy full OK so these guys going to
very lightweight this one no lo and at this stage it eventually always something is
doing something quite sensible each every three copies into i probability mass this one makes
it situated at the very simple reason so
you move from
if you look at your weight it you essentially all close you are from the
tallest on you if you in the white region you have a chance to have
multiple copies otherwise you die
this very simple
so i'm going to forget about that
what if could mention
is that in practice you're not need to at each iteration the only time you
need to resamples is when the effective sample size is getting below a given threshold
OK so
be able to borrow information
across users i need
that singular vectors be spread because if they are not spread
there's nothing i can do
we need to be be able to see all the entries in that column or
in that row
so for example if you look at the netflix database they are actually few users
that are completely orthogonal
to everybody else and there are few movies are completely outside the body for example
that napoleon dynamite
it's a good example of the movie that is orthogonal because people don't know what
to think of it so you have this problem
you have people who really like movies and the like it and all the others
on what you think
OK so to kind of
make this notion a bits
we can kind of introduce the notion of coherence which is a very simple notion
so you give me a subspace of rn of dimension are which is presented here
we're gonna look at PU which is the projection onto is that subspace
and so we can define the coherence of the subspace of is the canonical basis
as i'm taking the inner product the
canonical basis i project them onto the space and i'm looking at the size of
this projection
and i'm just going to renormalize this by the dimension of the ambient space divided
by the space of our
OK so that's essentially the definition of the coherence of you and we have again
like yesterday was the coherence in compressed sensing we have two extreme cases the maximum
value of the coherence is achieved when you contains one of these basis vectors in
which case the projection is one in which case
the coherence is an overall
the other extreme case
it is one in this subspace i can find an orthonormal basis such that the
the basis elements extremely spread out
and so if i can find the basis of that subspace such that this is
the maximum entry of the vector UK
is of size one of his code and since they have to the l two
norm has to be one
then in that case the coherence
is minimum and is equal to one
so when we see that when you is aligned with the basis vectors coherence is
and when you is kind of orthogonal to this kind of basis vectors then the
coherence is low
and if you take a random plane if you select the plane at random of
dimension are then with very high probability is the coherence will be very low it
will be actually order one
OK alright so
so the first result i want to present is what can we do and what
can we do not do so what is information theoretically possible
so give me a matrix i'm going to introduce mu not which is the maximum
between the coherence of the column space in the row space and we've seen that
is the columns case centre was based on highly coherent
we is
the basis vectors then matrix completion is not possible
and the first result completely formalized these results
this intuition it said that
no method whatsoever can complete matrices on less as the number of samples that you
get to see is greater than the coherence
times the number of degrees of freedom which is the dimension time the rank
times the luck factor
OK so this is telling you where e is the fundamental limits of recovery said
it depends on the number of degrees of freedom we've seen that matrix of rank
r depends on about two times and times of degrees of freedom and so what
this thing says if you take a number of measurements which is ignoring log factors
smaller than coherence time number of degrees of freedom there's nothing you can do
you can now complete the matrix
OK so we're going to be interested in
matrices with low coherence
such that the coherence order one so roughly speaking would be interested in matrices who
principal components are spread
and this log n factor comes in from
comes from the coupon collector problem it's to q
all right so
roughly speaking is the coherence is one order one then no method whatsoever can succeed
if unless the number of samples exceeds
the degrees of freedom times logan
OK so now
i want to show you kind of the positive result now
so we see and what we cannot do and then what is it that we
can do
so i see very few entries that's a point one percent of the entries of
the large matrix i'm going to try to guess the rest by nuclear norm minimisation
and so
we cannot just assumes what assume what we've
what we've talked about we can assume that the singular vectors of the unknown matrix
m are spread
that is that their are top magnitude is of size one of the square root
of the respective dimensions and we can assume that the rank is small of order
now i'm getting two psi show you a set of size and that i selected
at random
you'd like to get the rest how do you do it
you minimize defined as matrix that is consistent with what you've seen
the has minimum nuclear norm
again the results we have we stand is this
it said that surprisingly these works and his works extremely well
and the price the result is is that first of all the minimizer to this
optimisation problem is unique
and will be exactly equal to
the matrix that you're interested in
with very high probability as long as the number of samples
these figures and the dimension of the matrix ten logan square so i'm showing you
cannot do since the rank is of order one you cannot do better than n
log n and all what loses compared to this
optimal result is perhaps a lot factors that may be we've been sloppy and we
can improve
and so what he says is as soon as matrix recovery is possible by any
method whatsoever it is possible by semidefinite programming
now the problem there is the probability of success because of course we have to
account for his adversarial sampling sets so here i set the probability of failure arbitrary
two n minus
one of n q this could become one of and to the one hundred if
you wanted to
provided that in the constant you multiply by one hundred so if you want to
probability of essentially one or and to the one hundred and you need to see
a hundred times and logan square examples
OK so
interestingly this is connected with is
lots of
the graph problems
so it is connected with the coupon collector problems i think it's a bit of
a simple connection now i'll skip it
let me show you something more interesting so
our results cover lots of stuff
there are no in graph theory and i'll just present one results
if you give me a rank one matrix
it is known
because i could never grown a mustache
this is like eight days growth
so i'm glad i'm not edwardian have
and as i mentioned already that
this debate is really about computing numbers and really mad mathematical statistics is is the world
we are interested in it
so machine learning and probability with probability coming into machine learning where the world is
an uncertain place for example i got up today
expecting to sit quietly in the audience
six thousand lectures and you know things happen things change and you need to deal with them
so epidemic uncertainty is one type of uncertainty
so this uncertainty arising through lack of knowledge
so what colour socks is that person wearing so what colour socks and my wearing
thank you
normally works better in england when you're giving lectures in the middle of winter
and then aleatoric uncertainties uncertainty arising through an underlying stochastic system so if i if
i take a sheet a paper hear
and i drop it where will fall
well i could do it
similar way many many times and i wouldn't be able to say
now there two broad categories of uncertainty and here's the really this the right way
to think about these uncertainties right
two ways watching a football match right
you watch it live
and that's aleatoric uncertainty
the other one is you can't watch it live
because your work something new
on your video recorder or you all
sky plus box or whatever
and then you come back later orders on really early in the morning and you
play as if it was like
now as far as you're concerned
if you don't know the result is a bit spoiled it somewhat
they want you know
but as long as you can maintain illusion that you don't know the result the
uncertainty is the same there is an actual difference and this difference
it was brought home to me when i was doing this with rugby england versus france
in the world cup the
semi-final i think it was
i tried to forget about it
ah we had a really good and quarterfinals it was i think you get the
semi-final we had an excellent run to the
the team is rubbish but they decide to be france the were looking good and
i started watching the game and they would just appalling
and they were down by a certain number of points and i thought i can't
you know i'm gonna go and check what the final score was
so i left and went and looked obviously you can't do that's a trick you're
watching it live but i was watching recorded so i do not watch a recorded
and that's epistemic uncertainty because i can always go and find out the result is
no i just don't know it
with aleatoric is
the result is on now this is a little overlapping here which is the
why does this thing drop in
different ways every time i drop it
it i assume it's slightly different initial conditions chaos theory
very small variations in initial conditions
even in the deterministic system so actually
ali or i think pretty much unless you get down to the quantum level i understand quantum mechanics
enough to make a claim about them but let's ignore quantum levels let's just assume
that this is chaos causing these things
all aleatoric uncertainty in some senses epistemic uncertainty if you knew precisely the initial conditions
with which i'm dropping it and the state and everything
in the room then we would be able to compute without would land
such small variations effectively make this
noise aleatoric uncertainty
so le plus this is called the places indeterminism
like the origin have been like awful to take the origin away
why is that
so i need the origin there because
i have to be allowed if i had these other factors
i have to be allowed to multiply three two
this was three two
by anything by any scalars
including zero
i'm going to be allowed to multiply by zero and and and and the result
is going to be there i can do without point
and i have to be able to add three two
o two
then the opposite guy minus three minus two
and if i have those back to the origin
no way i can do without the origin every vector space has got the zero
OK that's an easy vector space
because we have a natural picture of it
OK is similarly easy is our three
this would be all me go up here
this would be
r three would be all
three-dimensional vectors social vectors
real come home
let me just just to be sure
we're together
let me take the vector three two zero
is that a vector in r two or r three
definitely is or three
it's got three components one of them happens to be zero but that's perfectly OK
so that's a vector in r three
we don't we don't mix up the i mean keep these vectors straight and keep
our hands straight so what's already
are and
so this is our
big example
it's all vectors with and components and i'm making these time things column vectors
can i can i try to follow that convention
there will be column vectors and their component should be real
real numbers
later will need complex numbers and complex factors but much later
OK so that the vector space
let's see what the what do i have to tell you about vector spaces
i said the most important thing which is that we can add
any two of these and we still in r two
we can multiply by any number and we're still in our two
you can take any combination and we're still in our two
and same goes for rn
honesty requires me to mention that this
these operations are adding
and multiplying have to obey
a few rules like we can just arbitrarily say OK
the sum of three two and pi
it is zero zero
it's not
the sum of three two
and minus three two is zero zero so all i'm not going to be the
book actually
with the eight rules
that the addition and multiplication have to satisfy but they do
they certainly satisfy in rn and usually it's not those a rules that are in
what's what's what the question is
and we do that those additions and we stay in this space let me show
a case where you can't
so suppose this is this is going to be not
a vector space
suppose i take the x y plane so those are two that is of vectors
now suppose i just take
part of it
just this
just is what this is one corner
of the vector space
all the vectors with positive
or at least not negative component
can i add those
if i had a vector with
like two three two
another factor like five six
i'm still up in this quarter
no problem with adding
but there's a problem with
multiplying by scalars because there's a lot of scalars that will
take me out of this corner points like negative one
if i took three two and i multiplied by minus five i'm way down here
so that's not a vector space because it's not
closed is the right word it's not closed under
all real numbers
so the vector space has to be closed under multiplication and addition of vectors in
other words linear combinations it so it means
that if i give you a few vectors
look here's an important here now we're getting to some really important vector spaces well
our and
like they are the most important
we will be interested in some in vector spaces that are inside our
vector spaces
follow the rules
but they we don't need all
of c there we
we started with our two here
and took part of it
and mister
what we got was not of vector spaces
now tell me of vector space that is
part of our two
and is still
we can multiply we can add and we stay
in this smaller vector space so it's going to be called a subspace
so i'm going to change this bad example to good
so i'm going to start again with our two
but i'm going to take an example is a vector space
so it will be a vector space inside are two
and i recall that subspace
of our two
OK what can i do
it's got something in it
i suppose it's got this vector in
if that vectors in mind
come from the same distribution
there you have to find so
a way of looking at that is dynamic is to define a timescale where
something is preserved and then try to find structure at that time scale
but you can just take these islands and apply them to the that the changes
because they assume that comes from the same distribution
if there is any distribution
and in particular here i i believe myself and that the division should be small
so that theoretically the
the prime could have come from the same distribution as me so one way of
protecting the data is
actually sampling from the data which replaced
then you get the best that contains the same points but maybe if you are
missing and if you are just a few
repeated one supplies
and that actually called bootstrap is very
a widely used technique is statistics
OK so these are dissimilar
we should suspect both because we know that one of them is wrong
at least one and in five people
well if we repeat this many times and this city over and over again and
the two clusterings are similar then
maybe there is reason to believe that they have found something that
especially the more similar only one k and also more valuable different k
so this idea was implemented for every k
we resample the data many times
look how close this clustering
for this you have to have the distance to measure clustering to talk about this
and you have actually this clustering because the data descriptor may not contain
no it it may not be about the same number of points they have to
take only the points that are common to the to the
two clusterings but these are all details
and in fact they the experiment so that very often what happens is that
for the UK
all the clustering together seem to be similar whereas for other values of k that
is more much more variation
there is another so this can work for any clustering method provided the hard clusters
because we don't really know how to compare clusterings that
another idea which works
and has been implemented by
for model based clustering is the following
i divided into two halves
and they both with the email
so i get both the clustering and take
and of course you get soft clustering but you can always transform them into hard
plus the purpose of comparison
and the
the next thing to do is to take the parameters from the second said
and class again the first
with that
that's because if you assume that data sets bold
come from the same distribution
the to just divided data
and in the true distribution of the data what that want should be very simple
but you don't think that you compare the results of the cluster so just likely
that two
to be one and get another clustering of the first day that allow you to
if there are almost the same are similar then it means that
you have two independent witnesses the first the
secondly on which you have got the same
the same structure
so maybe you have found this the
and then you can repeat several times
make sure that
that not
that's one logical system that we have this huge numbers systems infinitely many of them
called non-classical logic and we sort of put them on par with one another doesn't
seem fair does
one system over here
a lot of people study in a huge mess systems is the few of us
that we study
over here
why is that why classical logic got that positions anybody know
one classical logic so important what is it about classical logic
there's a few things
OK here's some properties you some things classical first of all the historical reason classical
logic was developed in
my whole bunch of people we respect lot
the ball
george boole
gottlob frege bertrand russell great that mathematicians and philosophers
there's a whole bunch of results known about now because people studied it and it
became sort canonical the logic so historically this position but historical reasons are good now
that they just that that's that's the way it happened to have to go to
some other interesting things about the mathematical property of classical logic that's very important
anyone think of the mathematical property that of classical logic
that makes it
so important
well almost limitless part of
that has embassies logic in a couple minutes the projects that is another property isn't
in you know it's an ongoing of book
i was to this
well it it was used to develop mathematics in particular set theory which was is
the a foundation for mathematics and brilliant that
it's done a brilliant job
OK so that's the mathematical reason was another mathematical reason
i mean may not have heard
its post complete
the words and we know that means
OK is reason one that's the reason why you can come up with that
you don't know what i'm talking about
what happens
so as you have
some acts some axioms of a class for classical logic
all right and
usually three axioms and rules ramsey at any length scale OK let's said
this book accent
OK now these reaction scheme so it's closed and uniform substitution for variables
OK now what happens if you have any new wax into a new axiom that
isn't already theorem
you know what happens
another approve this here usually
yes we get a contradiction and what happens if cognition classical logic
you get
everything it trivializes
so there's only one
properly logical system that is bigger than us
and that is the system contains every formula
and that's not of the system
bob myers who was a professor here for many many years
i still lives in canberra did come in for any of the summer school
he sometimes does is quite a right now so
he's to call that logic the logic of absolute irrelevance
so that's the but it's it's very easy for me
that's the axiom scheme
it also so people used to say
two will look it's very hard to prove things in relevant logic is very easy
to prove things classical logic is it here's logic is much easier to prove things
it's extremely zero proof is one line long
so of the logical right because it gives us too much
so i suppose the fact that classical logic post complete means that it's sort of
at the top of the pyramid
there's is a lot of other logics need that
so classical logics essentially no not always
and this it here in australia especially the the monash university is
this was cumbersome and is one of the few people and his students eroticism there
are too few people and bob myron and john slaney in fact are among the
four people
who study contra classical logic which are logics with
axioms are rules that are in classical logic there are additional two
but of course something from classical logic has to be rejected as well
but most classical most non-classical logics
at least the propositional level and quantifier level
that those logical systems are
usually reject just reject something in classical logic one or more
of the the
axioms and put in weaker axioms of some kind and so the weaker systems they
have fewer theorems
and then
but they contain only theorems of classical logic and completeness
gives classical logic etc