the first two
all to it
kind of my name
in one thing all a document
you will of course these all these men to one identity is bill clinton
because then you have one
guide and you can do to my
this is what this guy
we have
seventy percent of occupancy levels
there but it's not
the company
so you have a different and people like OK multiple alignment in the corporation
you want to detect what is the relation between these
they are completely when you have completed their
previously announced
completed marriage you you could you would know what's what is the relation between
and then
the fact that the number of that which is quite popular so if you have
any news or if you want to know
if they are about things so again you can use the information together make it
into the and some minor
for instance
so here
microsoft wanted to combine
the offer by how we are doing the right
we're not ready to be
it's not for me
it could be important we can take
we might all the information on
classification of these we might be able to like for me
we might
so you can look because we could expect no which is
but the the
declining job of which is not explicitly stated in the metric because they were not
it's not actually a you will
we could extract
santa that's also quite popular fields information extraction
we're going to be little playing one game
so that you can extract that live in the sense that maybe the
also we come the because language quite this but to extract the positive sentiment with
got to his car
what car
so this might be
in especially for marketing for people who want to create the blocks the web
to see what what others
on the the tenth grand on the system
so the problem but it may be on a certain politicians
that you want to my
so the
the book
four morning as i that you can
do you know how to fix them
i'm looking for a medical doctor might be of
in one of the web one
my e-mails availability of road
you want to my first opinion
you want to mine scientific data from publications so there are lots and lots of
applications meals in the whole chapter
remember no
o bank
information retrieval we have a tendency to look a lot like
but actually we have these other sources we have also according to english sources
people do the same thing as we do in
so actually for information retrieval is very important that
so we talked quite a bit about different
markov random field problems yesterday and the idea was
first of all to persuade you that markov random fields are
somewhat common currency in vision problems and i really do
cover number of the
the big problems
and secondly
just to give you some idea of the details of what
these models might look like these are some of the simpler
versions of the models
but today
it's all going to be about
optimizing those entities that is finding minimum energy is
under two different
kinds of assumptions one is four
before the break of binary problems so problems where all of those
values take the value zero or one as in the foreground background separation
and then after the mini-break we'll talk about
the doing the same thing using a similar mechanism to solve integer valued problems
so for example
solving stereo vision we want integer value
optimisation because the disparities are integers
the disparity sitting on each node x
except all the x and say takes an integer value
OK so let's think about this
is the situation this is the
form of energy function which we
i see a few times now
the k and k primes are
pairs of adjacent pixels
and we define ahead of time what
pairs of pixels will be
regarded as neighbours for the purposes of this adjacency
in terms of graphical models which
i suppose you must be
very familiar with
we can write this energy function here
all the in five probability distribution in this form here the
the unobserved variables x
xk is that we want to infer and here are the observations and as usual
the graph runs backwards from the unobserved to the observed but inference runs the other
way how to use the graphical models
so we want to do this optimisation
in order to do that the graph cut methods
constructs a different kind of graph
which will represent
the same energy function but in a different way
so now
the nodes
on the the xk nodes appear explicitly on the graph is these orange notice here
the zk is not appearing exactly where they going to
there are two new nodes the source and the sink
you can think of this OK and every every xk no here is attached to
the source and sink
and also is attached to its neighbors
as in the definition of neighbourliness
we were talking about here
so i i drawn everything
played by
this set of orange
notes here could itself be two-dimensional two-dimensional coming out of the borders were so you
got to play in nodes interconnected according to the neighbour neighbour properties and then all
of those nodes connected up here to the source and down here to the sink
so now
we can to think of
he is in terms of forcing flow through the network and the loan originator not
surprisingly the source and gets back down to the same here
but it's not quite clear why we're talking about flow
so let me first of all talk about cuts
the red
because here is the cut which separates all the nodes in the graph into those
that are connected to the source and those that are connected to the sink
supposing i cut this edge here the graph
so what does it associates
the node to the k no with the sink
which is sort of synonymous with the value x equals zero because remember with doing
binary optimisation here all the actors values zero or one so the convention is that
when a node is associated with the sink sink it has that means it has
binary value x equals zero well the cost
making that association by definition is f sup k of zero
in other words have some k applied to xk equal zero and zk
so the zk is
i have been dropped from the graph here because there now
implicit in this
k function we think of this as k functions being just the function of
vx case because there's a case to fix that all happened zk nothing more sinister
than that
so now
so it's a it's a associating this note here with the single thinking about having
the value k equal zero
we incur the cost of cutting this
eight years the cost of this age here has to be fk of zero
so things are going to swap sides even though the sink is on this site
this age has the called edge cost typical zero and this page has an edge
cost skr one
and so now
possible energy this e here for evaluated for particular configuration x is simply
the total cost of edges
by the by the cut
a couple the cut line here so in following the cut line we accumulate
a whole lot of
FK costs which are appropriate to the assignment of particular note to the single but
we also accumulate
cost so the the gk is
this a little bit
texting isn't it because the geek's are actually two by two table
because the UK is a function of x kxk prime rather the function x kxk
prime so there should be distributed by two table you shouldn't because there are two
possible values of x k two possible values a prime
and yet i'm proposing to put just one value
on this horizontal
how on did two by two table
of costs get collapsed on two
a single value
well here's how it happened
first of all
we are going to make the
if you like the off diagonal values of g
with zero one one zero
we're going to make them equal for the time being i might retract this later
but the time being i will say they're going to be equal so this is
simply the cost of taking two adjacent nodes and giving them different labelings doesn't matter
which way around the different they'll
now out get the same penalty
but that being different
g one one g of zero zero have nowhere to go
doesn't seem to be any way to put them on this graph so the convention
we're going to need is that they are zero and we'll see that that
can be true without loss of generality
say what
you get five that's about what might be an image
you have this in the spotlight yesterday
this one point two million training images so this is the first series of tasks
in which we had big enough data sets for neural nets reach
and it's the first time we have fast enough computers to train
many the best computer vision to try this
and the results look like this
the error rates
predicting the label correctly in your top five but
they all cluster around twenty six twenty seven percent
the some other people who are pretty good but not quite as good as his best systems
and then if you look at what you get with a neural net with dropout
you get
this is an analog representation
you do a whole lot better
and actually if you give some more training data you get at fifteen percent
so this meant that is very happy with more training data these methods a lots
of hand-engineering if you look at the descriptions of these methods the pages and pages
if you look at the script this meant that we use to denote the dropped
that's a bit unfair because actually the description of this methods is we use every
trick that yan invented over the last twenty years plus dropout
every three billion invention in the last twenty years
plus to be used again about hear
and then drop it gets to the last few percent
so drop is probably worth about three or four percent on this but that's still a lot
here's a better way to think about dropout
one going much too fast like can but also for the end of his i
could even tell my joke about tursunov ski and
here's a better way to think about dropout
if a hidden unit knows which other hidden is can be president
it can cut down to it and if you think back propagation is doing
is pushing it's trying to make each hidden unit fix up the mess that is
left over from the other the hidden units
the small this if you're doing regression
where basically you take what all you other hidden units will make the answer be
if you look at the difference from the target
and that's how you change the weights this hidden units so everybody's trying to fix
up the mess left over by everybody else
and that's a guarantee way to avoid overfit
what's happening when you do drop out is you're saying i don't know i'm gonna
have to collaborate with is gonna be some random subset the other these other guys
so i don't know what mess they can leave over
now if in general they leave a mess in one direction of exatt up
but i bet do something that is individually useful
and particularly in classification but means that individual hidden units
will tend to do things they tend to be more like rugged individualists
and like namby pamby socialists
and actually socialist that's an unfortunate analogy but they go
then when you've got all these rugged individualist and you average them you'll get a good job
and joel you went of it
if we compare this with thee
bayesian approach
in embase what you're doing
if you're gonna have lots of separate models are gonna be samples from the posterior
because you can do monte carlo
in the limit the basic things the right thing to do and will win
and we have found an example where bayes beats drop
it's unfortunate that they go
the problem with basis that the test time you have to run only stand models
we drop what you can do is you can learn
exponentially many models
that's you know you can have many more models in your
mix test time
and you've got a very efficient way using the test time
so that you don't suffer from this problem having to run lots and models are tested
you can read about you can read rejected science paper
on my web page
it's a nice easy really because it was written for science
and it's befor eleven twenty
so here's an alternative to dropout
suppose that's on
in terms of what we're gonna do it again taken typically a logistic unit but
also use other consumers but suppose it was a logistic unit
you take a logistic hidden unit it computes the probability pe
and then you might send back to the next level
the computer number people you put the logistic
new might send this number to the next level or you might not faster packed
see send with the probability of not point five
now you get exactly the same expected value
if you send a naught point five with probability p e
so let's suppose we call a spike point five
and we send out with probability p e
that's very similar to drop out
so that's the raises an issue
maybe the brain is doing something very like drop out by using stochastic spikes
so if you look at the variance if we just send one bit
what we discover is so what we can do now is not to drop out
just taken all feedforward neural net
but instead of sending the real valued output the logistics for the next layer
we're going to send
either one or zero without probability
so we drop out you get a variance apiece could over forward spikes are half
and with this stochastic you get a very incipient one month period before
which are likely the same when p equals a half m
when p is low stochastic is actually have more variance
and the limit wimpey's but we a plus one you
these small probability events so actually pass neurons with low fine it's actually have even more variants than dropout
so these terms before and now we have this additional terms
some the transpose graph laplacian
and also with this additional terms
we still scale
only linear in the number of data
because for computing
to counter this threat to can reasonably efficient graph
we only have
i complexity of k times the number of times the basis functions which are nonzero
for this point
so it's still linear in the number of data
some first
experimental results we have some for some pictures show approach works at all
so we have some
the point here
this is the normal setting so was out
the new addition normalisation terms
and then we slowly turn on
intrinsic motivation to
and we can see how since
you can
these two
one is
i just want to discuss for you
we have a little
o point virginia to the point
point origin the same label because of the same
so what you you see the light
the is
the trust
he has
this is a
on the floor
why not just for them to work
it's more the problem is solved according to the
we have
the business park
how much
what has happened
one small
i did try some some real life data
i would imagine this kind of things happen them
or better results not much better some of the success of the
real life data from
two thousand
direct mail campaigns of customers
we know is that response to main
the first part of the city itself
so what is the called
five eight ten percent of the five eight ten of the perimeter wall
sent only to these five top five percent
advertising that are very
from this data mining cup for responding
correctly predicted the game hundred eighty five which was
for non responders a lose twelve deutschmark because of the cost
data mining cup the winner of what the student competitions the one got sixty seven
so the data mining specialist got eighty five cells and then the normal spots with
classification approach about about eighty seven thousand
and we just try to do the same standing in the same way use thirty
five thousand eight as well
they manage not to
go up to
ninety three cells we improve on of
results before
if it
if this really is belongs to the same as it was part of our adjusted
to fit the parameter fitting differently
o model parameters to fit because of interest intrinsic terms
and the somewhat frustrating stuff but in this setting we
for real life data we also managed to get better results
the motives of the men of the combination technique set
for example the three example ten dimensions five noise
we would like to be able to figure out that these five dimensions noise
documents back by
you need to you need to be
no the validity of the source you one of the most important things is to
find sources that you trust
but you you really need you find reliable
although the only internet information comes first and the information about the source comes second
which is the exact opposite to the human intelligence for example where you only trust
information you get from this person
but on the internet you kind of
you don't know whether it's true or the it's alive
and this whole thing now room
falsities propaganda
it tends to fly across the the world in minutes a good example of that
was the
the danish cartoon so
there is a a room or a accusation and it spreads across the world in
many cases why
the need to know fast this is so important
OK there's another way
minefield of copyright
what exactly you can you do with information taken from the internet what
it's a very grey area and something that
that we have
struggling with as well because we are monitoring news reports
the whole legality whether it's you can take information from that authored by somebody else
who owns that information it's a very grey area google got the exactly same problems
and they've been sued about
OK so
OK so it's not just about text i want to give an example here which
is actually taking some work in the JRC
in this case is
which is more to do with it
intelligence gathering on the iranian nuclear program this is what we've been doing with the
which is basically keeping people like salama informed as to what's happening
in that area
this is the area image intelligence well
the first example here is
again buying satellite data which you can do on the internet and this is a
actually refugee camp
the or the office of humanitarian aid wanted to know
whether they were over to overpaying for the number of they're playing basically to keep
this refugee camp going they want to know
whether they were overpaying so they wanted to count the number of ten
and then
image analysis like this automated software which will go on to identify
this these of this is that the resolution of the imagery
try to identify the which tends
the council attempts
and basically
by enhanced by using pattern recognition software
you can find the computers recognizing
individual parents here which you can count
and this is something that is the procedure that you can automate
this is an example of what you can also use it for counting houses in
cities and so on
that was formerly
important information derived from
data which you've got the basically porcelain
the iranian nuclear program
is and is it everyone is trying to understand where the building a bomb and
so on so they are monitoring as the americans and was continuously so
but he can combine
information you get from the internet with satellite data
in fact the original whistleblowing on the only iranian programme was done
by a dissident group
caught everyone by surprise and that was done through the internet
data mining is by in conventional search engines now in order to one because you
need to know about the nuclear fuel structure to understand what's happening
i a
are very because they need to know how far the iranians are from having enough
enriched uranium to build nuclear weapons
this is this is a site this is the site in isfahan with making uranium
and this gives you an idea of just how
accurate this satellite data is and here you see any building being put up and
they want to know what that was
and the
lo and behold the search on the internet
in farsi for the right
information we had the woman working with who was iranian
you find
exactly that town
this is on the site which in english is why multilingual it is very important
the english version of the same size of course doesn't have that link because they
remove only the nuclear
the removal in the information in the english version but only in the past especially
but the second example here would be this is damage assessment and the
lebanon war
we were asked to
do damage assessment
for this for the donors conference in stockholm so
again you
you by the the data you basically can task satellite to give you
in this case because you don't want
you have to have the data afterwards
and if ideally one of the data before and after
then you could do change detection
and this was the data was derived in ispra basically from sample from commercial satellite
data which we bought
and we found out how many has been damaged
o and call them the same if they're referring to the same entity
so there are about four entities being mentioned here i think
is it about
that's right it's about sort of my or
so so the key here is to figure out which
this is called a part of this is called the reference problem but it's also
sort of you also have to detect all the referring expressions
right and you can see this sort of chunking task but there's this higher level
structure you link you link things were denoted here by color
OK so detecting entities and deciding which ones corefer and then depending on what type
of text you have you might want to link those school referring expressions back into
some kind of ontology representation of the world so
where there's something comes up for examples in biomedical literature suppose you have an ontology
of all the genes known in the human genome
or some of them you might want to look at scientific articles and link back
the references to those genes matter how they look in the tax back into the
OK so
we're going to run out of time if i keep going but there's a whole
another dimension to this
that's worth
bring up because there's there's another sort of data which people have been kind of
fascinated by since since maybe twenty years ago which are parallel comparable corpora mostly parallel
corpora so parallel corpus is a collection of texts in two or more languages which
are translations of each other
these these come about as a natural byproduct of the working of international organisations like
the UN and certain news agencies also the the european parliament and the really nice
because they show you how the same thing is expressed in two different languages
so one idea that's been kind of fooling around for a long time is that
you can you can build better models of language if you can kinda triangulate if
you know how the same ideas expressed in two languages that gives you more insight
into what the idea might be and how it might look so there's a ton
of work on things like aligning sense well that was kind of easy we kind
of solve that about ten years ago aligning the words between the two sentences the
words that mean the same thing or phrases or aligning the parse trees or
finding finding the the underlying bilingual dictionary or are and so on and so on
the biggest application of this course translation
being able to take one of the sides as input and produce the others up
so you can think of that itself as the structured prediction problem
that was a very gross smattering of some of the problems people are thinking about
in natural language processing and some that they thought about a while back and sort
of stop thinking about a lot of these things not everyone agrees that all these
problems are important
so for example
you probably can't you probably going to have a hard time publishing and part of
speech tagging paper about english
now it is because it's mostly solved it's not clear that you know that any
advances really going to make a difference for any real applications
people who focus more on applications like machine translation or summarisation are often skeptical about
any new kind of linguistic analysis and may ask how is going to actually help
my application does does does this particular step deserve its own intrinsic evaluation so one
one that's got a lot of attention is word alignment
you've got two sides parallel tax you can use there are many algorithms are trying
to figure out which words on each side of the text line up with which
each other words mean the same thing and then people started evaluating its
so people who work on machine translation can scratch their heads and said well you're
word alignment got better but in my ceases system get better
so this is this this kind of debate always is going on should we can
evaluate passing on its own anymore is the question it's kind of a controversial question
but it's one that comes up
OK so
so right everything in natural language processing comes with controversy i here's here's a suggestion
that there are some problems that have really been viewed as structured prediction directly but
but deserve to maybe so one is to find the entire predicate argument structure of
a sentence
a sort of rough approximation to the semantics along the lines of the first order
models i was suggesting earlier for the whole sentence that that has really been
tasks that require generation of text where text is the output
answering question translating we talked about that or you get it you get some text
in and you want to simplify just clean it up fix its grammar fixes spelling
people have really structured prediction models for these things
that wasn't generation as it
but it wasn't a
the what they are you write what were mapping two was was sort of the
first order logic
that they use to transform into single queries
right which they could then post the database
so that's fair
hasn't been done it hasn't been done open domain
that was very restricted domain
key challenges how to come up with ways to compute these functions very quickly in
an online fashion so that you can evaluate ten thousand fourteen seconds like the top
four that's that's the main challenge in these areas so even though you get very
good accuracy
that that's again another problem one needs to think about
one could also be something like local models so again this is also not been
done but i'm just trying to solve maybe it's about idea but i don't know
so instead of fighting the global logistic regression you might actually fit local logistic regression
so you might say that a single logistic regression may not be a good idea
if you want to build small logistics patched him up so for a given class
of any given class of edits
you might have one logistic regression for different classes of course different loss of that
you might have another logistic regression but you don't want the user to really tell
you where which class
you don't want to users to really separate out these clusters for you you want
the data to build that automatically for and so again that can be done by
fitting a mixture of local logistic regression so this is again something which needs to
be done it has not been done but may be a good idea
so we have be sort of hierarchical models with a single tree
but in general there are a lot of trees that are available in the system
so there is that hierarchy you also published a hierarchy if you look at the
user interface that is analogous general venues solving this problem multiple hierarchies so how do
you use these multiple hierarchies and then come up with an efficient smoothing out so
move from one hierarchy to multiple hierarchies by doing this that's again another open problem
which is quite interesting you know as soon as you have two hierarchies you start
working on this cross product space you no longer have tree now you have it
single a single naughty across further hierarchies can have multiple parents of the tree structure
is lost and all the efficiency in the computation
has to be hard to get you can't do the competition in linear time anymore
so you see
so let's say there is a lot so there is a hierarchy
and that is the publisher hierarchy
and now you want to estimate the click-through rate in the cross product space right
so for a given had publisher pair you will have multiple parents so you know
for a given publisher you will have about multiple parents and their hierarchy of another
set of parents in this hierarchy if you start looking at the image of the
cross product then there is no single parent multiple so
this is no longer the tree and you can't use the tree smoothing algorithms anymore
that are very efficient
you have to
you have to come up with better algorithms to do that if you start using
belief propagation that's the complexity is quadratic it's not linear anymore so
knew something like n log n sort of complexity to solve the problem how to
do that is
open question
OK so finally before i end this section
i would like to get mention so one could do a lot of research in
improving the machine learning algorithms that are already out there but take
the more challenging question is addressing these are the fundamental issues
that are inherent in this
area right positional bias selection bias correlation dynamics these are you
more important to solve then actually take logistic regression and improved by another two percent
OK that's that's also important
saying that's not important but
there is very little work in
these areas
i think that's more important before we can come up with a more holistic solution
to this whole problem
of click-through rate estimation in the context of computational
so yes sort four online learning again DP there have been some work
looks like
so in so first of all
here you get binary feedback on things that you shortly the user in recommender system
like movie recommender systems
users select what movies to look for the great
here is that is an ad serving system that decides what i want to show
so that is one difference that the difference is that a lot of the information
right about users and about what is in the hard problem for stock problem is
you know you get millions of new queries every day millions of new sort of
course start problems have to be solved in many collaborative filtering application that's not really
the main focus it has started to become the focus now but that's disassortative and
binary data itself makes it more challenging
it does not imply statistics expected the binary feedback has explicit acts
there is a i agree that is close relationship but it has not been applied
in this context
using the semantic information i mean i think that's why mention that is close relationship
and does not seem like those techniques have been used a lot for solving this
problem and so there is there is there is opportunity
i read the
that's what this online learning is going to
actually address the exact same
we've looked at
i based approaches to match at school
but they just look at how we can incorporate historical novel
click feedback using machine learning mortars and now we look at the online learning setting
essentially the problem we are trying to solve this is
all the previous approaches just of historical data
now this
a couple of drawbacks one is
the you girl constantly have to retrain your models
as new things become
certainly there is some basketball game which became very popular that people are talking about
you want
you have a model that learns the sorts of things very quickly
so this means that the system needs to be changed periodically
and if you want to stay up date you need to retrain all the which
might possibly be very costly
more important that that is what you get the book called the selection bias
there are some initial systemic biases in system
which might never get fixed so for instance
suppose that system must learn that
my hands should always have lots of words matching the query
so if
this is the case and someone came up with the but i thought that they
never learn that and add that starts about sound system about
is it good at for this particular way because of system that doesn't show any
keywords in the query set
are there is that more folklore example that
if someone is looking at golf pages then you should show in
luxury watch because
in some sense people who are looking at good pages
rich people and then you might be interested in luxury watch ads but this is
something that you would never get if you had a system which
if if you're gonna system never showed such that
then you will never find out that such goodness but set
so what we really need to do
you have
the following content is provided under creative commons license
your support will help MIT opencourseware continue to offer high quality educational resources for free
to make a donation or to view additional materials from hundreds of MIT courses
visit MIT opencourseware OCW MIT that EDU
it's a couple of announcements
tomorrow there will be a quiz six based on homework six
just on the crystallography there's a little bit at the end of homework six
on x-rays and we'll just start to talk about x-rays today
so i think that i believe that out just be based on crystallography and i've
as the recitation structures to administer the tests at the end of the period so
you can have some chance to
ask questions
last day we talked about
crystallography we were introduced to the seven crystal systems
and the fourteen grammy lattices which are showing up on
taken from the lecture notes and we saw that if we want to describe the
arrangement of atoms in a crystal we could do so by combining
the notion of the brevity lattice
of which there are fourteen distinct
with the basis basis could be single atom could be a group of atoms could
be an ion pair could be
and we saw that got us through an elaborate set of crystals
and then towards the end we focused on cubic crystals because cubic crystals are representative
of large number of metals
in the periodic table and it's much more tractable
mathematically so going to focus on cubic crystals
i want to continue along with that today and in particular one start looking at
notation the reason one of notation is i want to be able to define a
point lying in the planes so that we start characterizing crystals i can give you
a mathematical notation that represents
the faces of the cube
the body diagonals of the cube aligned going
on the body diagonals
a line going along the edge
instead of writing it words i want to be able to do so mathematically
and so for that we're gonna
turn two
this handout
which has the elements of crystallographic notation quickly go through this last day we started
talking about position so run little sketch here
this is the unit cell
the unit cell is the q because we're talking about a cubic system and this
is just the letters i haven't put adams here
OK so i'm just talking about lattice points in space
and just to remind us
a b and c are the unit vectors in a cubic system a equals b
equal c
each of them is equal to a the lattice constant
this is the lattice constant a
that's the dimension a
lattice constant
and all angles are right angles so alpha equals b vehicles chemicals nine degrees so
just to just to practice the origin
as i've shown here the origin all we do is right
zero zero zero as you when your math class but don't put parentheses around
because parentheses are reserved for
playing use parentheses later on the crystallography crystallographic several notation
OK so here is point a
here's what we say it's out
it's on its in the
the y z plane
by the way i've chosen a set of coordinate axes that are in conformity with
the right hand rule
i don't care which axis you choose to be
actually doesn't matter i generally like to make the
but i don't care as long as you use the right hand rule
we need to observe the right hand rule because
in physics are going to find that there are certain vector forces the are product
and cross product and if you don't use the right hand rule convention you get
identically backwards so the farm is your x axis y axis is the axis however
you want to do it so i got the x axis coming out of the
board of the y axis and the easy access are in the plane of the
if we come here this point a is zero units on the x axis is
one unit of the y axis one unit upon z axis to the one one
and b is i've drawn it looks like it's one unit out on the
on the x axis it's no units on the y axis and a half the
up on the
of course you can ask the question now which one which is right
and the
following so this website where you can enter these stages and you get
a lot of it's meaningful sequences sequences that stuff like this
so you can ask the question which one is correct
between generalizes
and of course you will see this is sort of a stupid questions
lot intelligence tests are built on this kind of thing
and there is no not really a way to tell for the the problem of induction
in philosophy
now statistical learning theory which is the
maybe the most
complete theory of of generalization that we have
after slightly different question
it doesn't matter which one is correct
but it asks more and better question you ask what are
how what kind of principles one should use
to come up with laws that are probably correct
and there should be a bit more accurate here
come up with laws
but probably as correct on the test data as there are the training data so
this how to come up with laws
where the training error does not mislead u about the test that you should expect in the future
so that's slightly simpler problem and also this problem has been studied philosophy
it has been called the demarcation problem
so that both
this kind of questions have been discussed extensively by pope
because this
then they probably not only public public class this induction problem all humans problems from david hume
and because this demarcation problem all kinds problems this was
this is what kind was interested was one of the things come to mind countries
interested in so basically the question
and what are
the methodological
principles that distinguish physics from metaphysics
so what what should we be doing to
valid uh natural scientific knowledge
okay end
i think i'm going not to not talk about this not because i will talk about it
in more detail later on so moving out my latex lines
them to the course about kernel methods but i will actually start start with a of learning theory
because i always think it's nice to have a bit beautiful learning theory the beginning of the summer school
so statistical learning theory
this stuff about the time when it is in the sixties
we have a model
which is that we observe data generated by an unknown stochastic regularity
it is unknown but fixed
i'll say more about this in the mid
and learning
consists of extracting this
and the interesting thing about this area maybe maybe after closed is a bit more
so this is that there are
basically started about the contaminants during the peacetime feces it
the they
they were interested in this problem of
it turned out that that that in in a
relatively simple scenario but it turns out that a lot of structure is already there
there's a lot of interesting stuff came out
and they found notions of capacity of complexity function classes and i think working in machine learning
you all know about these even
even maybe for your work and not gonna need
things like we see dimension
sorry for taking the cebu here
okay so
let's see
so let's start with the problem of pattern recognition
so in pattern recognition and there's also the problem of determining the start with
you want to learn
the function is a function that just takes two possible values
so we have some input domain which could be
he said
of plus minus one
and you make the assumption that
there were generated i i d e from an
unknown underlying probability distribution joint distribution
so that's
so the
random experiment
so have a random experiment uh this includes a special case was
because we have a deterministic relationship between x and while it usually we don't have that
this is a general relationship between x and why
and the goal is
now define a function
takes an input x produces output
why which is somehow similar to those
and all which somehow typical under this distribution and by this we mean
that will minimize
if fix this loss function between for fixed and why
this is a particularly simple loss function
such that the expectation
over the unknown distribution
of the loss
we minimize this is called the risk
and this
most function here is called the zero classification loss function
like a zero one
so if you plug in why why is plus minus one
x or y f of x also takes values plus minus one
so this bus lines one this past minus one we take modulus and divided by
a factor of two this quantity is zero one depending on whether
if x is equal to one
all different from why
so we want to minimize the expectation that this
but we cannot compute this quantity
p is unknown so we need an induction principle and principle
to get us to a function which is close to
the minimizer
or function which has a risk is close to the smallest possible one
want to find the function based on the internet
and the simplest induction principle is called empirical risk minimization
this what about generally started to study in russia in the sixties
and this principles basically just says we replace the average over the unknown distribution by an empirical average
over the training example training example
so training examples
is whole set is called training sample
and one of these is an example
always see people
calling sample
you want to
minimize the training error
it's going to be the empirical approximation is
find a function that minimizes this quantity
and then the question is
with function one or
when with the risk of the function
converge to the minimal risk
well first you might think that this is trivial
this thing called the law of large numbers
which says something about
the convergence of means to expectations so
remember that this
this thing here is just an empirical mean
for some random variable is the expectation of the same random variable
so we we
should think that you should be easy
the large numbers tells us that such a quantity will converge
its expectation as the number of observations goes to infinity
when we have some fixed function in here
unfortunately there is not enough was this does not imply
the empirical risk minimization when he still can result in the limit for that called consistency in statistics
the somebody here is that there are several orders
and there are several advertising settings
which one you use depends on what you want to achieve
so if your goal is just around the bend
get users to nokia product norm company knowledge especially new promotions they were just interested
in display advertising you want to get access to internet users and you willing to
pay for the fashion
so CBN is that everyone gets
as it is this if you're interested actually attracting users to use particular product content
management sponsored search what you would like to do and here
you will typically pay per click so CBC mode use some
you pay per action so CPM or get
let's take typically CPC what seems
i think that everything would have some
in this should be
in the late in which we use to solve
what is the goal of view advertising campaign
so we have looked at them and you want to look at the advertising setting
next we look at
new and upcoming
well this is an ad exchanges
and this is very new and has
very significant problems
and open problems
everything that you have discussed up to now has been like
there users
content providers and networks advertisers all of them are separated living in their own words
and then this fact that each other in some very structured
but this need not really be so
we could essentially be them all tour them together in one big exchange but they
are a bit first
a certain amount what have there is no need for me to
we could think of publishers being an impression of forces
publishers seem to all have just gotten use it what was interested in the product
i can show one that
who who wants to
the the highest one for this
and now it's advertisers this could say that all i believe p
one and for the CPM sort of setting but i'm willing to stand stands for
CBC city and so
all of these available and we have the word of these together into one auction
mechanism and the ship
so an example of this would be that
it the publisher
and has an impression sense
and the different networks
bid for this information so
accents could for this impression on behalf of the users
some of the books could be done this
so advertiser
could be this impression
via network
and that what
it about from the data and so on or something it would actually be effective
for this information
and all of these books could be four different rewards and somehow combine all of
these only one together to figure out which is the highest
and what this gets us
is some sort of transparency some sort of value in the system so the publishers
that you get so high so close to
residents and so much
well what goes into it because of the volume of the force
that the class
breaks i'm going to try to break glass with you
you see that it is not easy
i have here
one class almost the same as the one i have you there
and we can illuminate the glass with strobe lights
which you see here
and i'm going to show you there
the display
well that strobe light and the reason why we strobe this
that we want you to see as we excite exact frequency
of the class
we wanted to see the motion of the class
and the way we can make you see the motion is by stopping not exactly
at the frequency of sound
but a little bit differently
so you will see the stroboscopic motion then
of the class
so i can
already i will make it darker shortly but i want to see at least
most of this i can
generate and the
four hundred and seventy which which is very close to the resonance frequency is the
tongan people use
we will increase the volume and then we'll try to get the resonance just right
we may be off by a few words
we have to be right on was in words
and and then we'll see where we can make the glass right
i wonder what you sound is going to be very strong
so you may
as time goes on as we go to higher volume you may want to to
you may want to closure is in fact i will use this
to protect might use
even use this
to protect my eyes case the glass migrate
which i doubt whether it will be who knows
all right so let's make it very dark
so you see here the glass
not doing very much
and i'm not going to increase
the volume of the sound er going to cover my is now
prec began to sing some unction now i'm much shorter crop one cross and sherwin
win lose error whom these erued increased false move then now with we'll do o
error world move error now i'm not trying to plant
very well the two rules for
area of
i mentioned that residences can be very destructive
and there are some striking examples in history
in fact you may have when this story you may have seen the traffic signs
just sign on all
the traffic signs started doing this
so i can write down now
in general that he e
and i
drop the wordnet now from now on whenever i write e
throughout this lecture is always the net electric field
they both into account
so you can write down now
the three electric field
divided by capt
one minus p
is one of the cap
so you see in this
experiment i did in my head
the first
bringing charges on the plate
so the potential difference
removing the power supply
shopping in the dielectric the field will go down by a factor cap
kappa for glasses about five there will be a major reduction i will show you
that later
if the
electric field goes down
in this particular
experiment it is clear that the potential difference between the plates
i will also go down
because the potential difference between the plates
is always the electric field between the plates
times t
and so
if this one goes down by a factor of kappa
if i just shoving the dialectic not changing the
then of course the potential between the plates is also going down
none of this
is so intuitive but i will demonstrate that
the question now arises
gauss law still holds
and the answer is yes of course
i was will still hold
gauss law tells me
that the
closed loop
closed surface i should say not closed to the closed surface integral
of the dot the a
one of the absolute long
five some
of all the charges inside my box
all the charges
the net charge is that must take into account both the induced charge
as well as the
free charge
so let me write down here next to remind you that
q net
it is of course kill free
plus killed in those
and i will remind you that this is my minor
and this was passed
the free charge
positive there
this process and at the same place
if you have you gaussians surface at the top
we have the negative charge
here we do
so therefore
gauss law
simply means
that you have to take both into account
and so therefore
you can write down one of epsilon zero
after all three
now you have to make sure that you take the induced charge into account
and therefore you unified the whole thing by kappa that you've automatically taking the induced
charge into account so you can amend next gauss law very easily
by this factor
of kappa
the dielectric constant is dimensionless as i mentioned already
it is one in vacuum by definition
one atmosphere
gas is typically have dielectric constant just a hair larger than one
we will most of the time so this one plastic has the dielectric constant of
and glass which is an extremely good insulator
as the dielectric constant
of five
if you have an external fields
that can induce dipoles in molecules
substances however
which themselves really dipoles even in the absence of an
electric fields
if you apply now an external field these dipoles will start to align along the
electric field we did an experiment ones with some grassy perhaps you remember that
and there's a line in the direction of the electric field they will strengthen the
electric field
on the other hand because of the temperature of the substance these dipoles
these molecules which i know
dipoles by themselves
through chaotic motion
i will try to is align temperature
trying to this online and so it is going to be a competition on the
one hand between the electric field which tries to align them
and the temperature was tries to
this alignment but if the electric field
strong you can get a substantial amount of alignment
a permanent dipoles as the rule
wayne stronger
then any dipole that you can induce by ordinary means
in the laboratory
and so the
substances which are natural dipoles they have much higher value for kappa much higher dielectric
the substance is i just this past
which themselves do not have
dipoles one is an example extremely good example electrons
spend a little bit more time maybe oxygen
then near the hydrogen
and water has a dielectric constant of eighteen
it's enormous
and if you go down to low temperatures you take ice minus forty degrees it
is even higher than the dielectric constant
is one hundred
i'm now going to
son hugh
through before
demonstrations for experiment one of them you have already seen
and try to follow them as closely as you can because you missed one small
you miss perhaps
a lot
i have two
parallel plates which are on the table
as you have seen last time
and i have here currently that i put it in a in that means and
and the great have certain separation d
i'm going to charge
this capacity up by
these ants
two power supply
and i'm going to connect them
two fifteen
a hundred volts
already going to set my
light because that's where you're going to see it very shortly
i'm going to start off with the distance d so this is going to be
like them one
is a distance of one millimeter
and the voltage v always means the voltage
the potential difference between the plates
it's going to be
fifteen hundred volts
forgive me for the movies i can help this means you potential difference and this
is the unit impulse
once i have charge
i disconnect
this is very important
i disconnect the power supply which i write PS
that's it
so the is now trapped
as i charge it as you saw last time
you will see that the and
shows is short search of current
because as i put charged the plates the charge has to go from the power
to replace
you see a short
search of current
which will
make the
and the hand of the powers of the amulet you'll see on the on the
wall there
as a
might as one
and divided by p
just rearranging
and then you will find
because credit
omega zero squared
divided by omega supreme
look at this
and convince yourself
that this equation
is identical to this one
if you look in french
french will take you
from here
one step further
which is huge on trigonometry
and i decided not to go that route
but you can
use the values for a p
that we have find
this one
so you can now
besides the trigonometry
you can find this ratio
very simple
twice the cosine
so this whole thing
like the cosine
of and by over and was what is correct
and this one so it has no physics there
it's purely a matter of trigonometry
we can now called and nancy
because we know now that we're going to get solutions as a function of the
number and
and then with a little bit more trigonometry
you really want to
check up on french there which just page
on the then forty one
he then comes up
with the normal mode frequencies which are
our goal
so i will give you the results but really is this is already a year
you get two omega zero
so by no means intuitive
five sign
and i
i'd like to
i this one
and of course i'm going to
look through that result with you
as of now
looks very
so this then
is the solution
omega and
i think one color
show you how these link this is the solution for a
know mode
you know it's particle is
and you have specified the amplitude
of the sinusoids that this tells you
each particle picture is
if you know the mode and
you know this is going to be
the frequency
so you can write down now
y which is the displacement as a function of time is amplitude
why is this place
now we can put in
the amplitude that we know
it has to be an amplitude
and i have also
the cosine omega and
i'm still
course you can always phase
and upon equals zero
what the article is doing
this one
if you have to
this one frequency
this then
is the time dependence of the displacement
particle number p
involved and
well i want to do now
is to take a specific example which i also
i will try to demonstrate
which will give you tremendous insight
and actually do it on the left
because this is all very opaque
but when you see an example worked out
you see actually how would also is comes to life
i'm going to have
five weeks
on the train
one two three four five
next year
six one
two o
four five
and two
that each one is
the separation
his l
so n is five
you might and
six by writing down
going to need and this one
and then omega zero
the square root
he divided by an
so i'm interested in knowing what the frequency is in the lowest possible
it's going to resemble something like this
so that frequency omega one
is then to omega zero
times the size
and equals one
capital and was one of six
on the eighty degrees divided by twelve fifteen degrees
is the science
fifteen degrees right now in degrees because
i have a better feeling for degrees than i have
four radiance
and that is o point five one
another omega
and i get the same thing again the reason i get o point five correct
exactly only one
omega zero
because the science degrees one half
and that itself
this one
omega three
now we get the sign forty five degrees
is approximately one point four one not exactly
is the square root of two
is fun and predict the outcome is unpredictable
so just to give you an idea of what this particular game looks like this
is a screenshot of halo two and you have these various people running around killing
each other for various reasons sometimes they want to capture the flag sometimes they want
to take possession of some strange skull that they carry around like football or sometimes
which is called free for all
they just want to ramp up as many kills as they can
and as you see they have competent instruments for achieving
so here's the problem setting which of course is not specific to video games but
is particularly prominent in video games we have katine's
and for each team where the number of players
and the outcome
is is essentially a ranking between teams
so let's look at the typical outcome from the game
here this was the team game a red team versus the blue team red one
fifty two forty against the blue team
see here for players on this team here for players in this team this team
so these all have some of the first places these second places and here you
see some extra statistics but in particular it's important to know it is that we
don't take into account in the system the particular school that was achieved but we
just take into account the order
with which the winning order if you like
the ranking that comes out of the game that loses some information because
the test scores last but it makes the system very very universal so this was
the team game alternatively you can have these individual games
and then you get the ranking of the players in this game eight players participated
and these are the game attacks these other ranks and you can see here two
people share third place in two people share fifth place because they only killed pathetic
eleven people in this game
and about the same number obviously and so it would obviously be desirable to take
into account these draws as well in particular because draws give you a lot of
information because if people draw
then that's an indicator that the playing strength may be very similar
so the question we're asking is how can we assign a skill as i to
player to player i want to all players really such that
if skill the skill of where i is greater than the scale of the j
then some of the probability that i wins over j
is greater than one half of the probability that i wins is greater than the
probability of j with the interesting thing once we have these numbers is how can
we then from the pool of people
combine them into games
such that they have been a good match
where we
define a good match
roughly as a match
where the outcome is unclear
he is a very rough idea of how the approach works so
just to see how bayes law ties in here it will then tie in the
more parametric formed but you can think of two statements statement a maybe that player
one's ratings between is in this intervall here
prior to his writing is in the central here
and statement b is the player one wins against player two
so b is a game outcome and a is the statement about the strength of
the of the players and now what we're interested in is the strength of the
players were interested in the distribution over a given what we observed namely the outcome
of the game and bayes law of course of bayes rule is used to invert
OK so i've got three more sections to cover
and is a little bit shorter than the to cover earlier
the next one is the one that relates most directly to the to build menczer
tutorial this morning and also francis box tutorial last year
really cover this topic i'm just going to focus on a very narrow algorithmic view
of this and that is regularized optimisation with thing you minimizing is f plus some
parameter tau time some regularizer
and i'm really going to talk about one kind of method but it's a pretty
fundamental kind of method and it's sort of the basis of a family of methods
and that's not to say shrinking uses the shrinking slash thresholding technique
so what's the motivation for all this
often we don't really want to minimize f what we want is an approximate minimiser
of f that in some sense nice
so know what i mean by nice
that all depends on the context if you're dealing with compressed sensing for instance you
want to find an exit has only a few nonzeros
a very tiny fraction of nonzeros if you doing matrix completion problem for instance you
might want to find a matrix has low rank
if you're doing an image denoising problem or deep learning problem you want to find
a solution that has low total variation so by that i mean large areas of
the image have constant intensity of the same colour something
and there's also this concept that showed up in that next book where he talks
a tradeoff between the quality approximation of the given data and the complexity approximation function
so if you can formulate the trade-off as
as in this sort of fall
well this so the terms so covers the fit to the data
and this site and somehow covers the the the complexity
deals with the complexity
so this is one way to sort of force the solution to have these nice
properties you want you point that i want to make which again came up in
this morning's tutorial is that often it's really hard to pick the town advance you
can get a lot of information about what roughly what size tau is but often
you really don't know exactly what it should be up front even if you have
a good handle on what sort of noise dealing with in the measurements
so you often want to solve not just for one value in isolation but maybe
for a range of values
so the basics of shrinking method very closely tied to what i've been talking about
and also extremely simple
and they work when this that when the regularizer is in some sense simple
and so what they do is to take
the after
and say well
is this easy to solve if i replaced by a linear approximation plus the quadratic
in other words i just replaced by
first order approximation right maybe around the current point x palais is the length of
the move to norm squared minor sex scale by one over two alpha role for
some parameters
and and leave the regularisation term exactly as it is and try to approximate it
just leave it there
in its original state
so if i can solve this problem easily
shrinking method is is definitely one one thing that
you should try
and we'll see in a moment you can solve this problem easily in some sense
for a lot of interesting choices of site so you can rewrite this problem by
just gathering the first two times together and putting it like this and that i
can define from this i can define
the shrinking operator to be the admin of this thing here
the vectors e that minimizes one of the two alpha times e minus y two
norm squared plus ten times size is OK
again the regularizer p is explicitly
and therefore if i'm using this then the
the step that i've described here
i just get the by defining y to be x minus alpha times g
and by setting alpha to be off
so the simplest sort of shrinking algorithm simply takes the negative gradient step from x
along some great subgradient g
and then shrinks using this operating here
i said that these are interesting when this problem here is easy to solve
and the classic case of the one norm it is really easy to solve
in the one normally do to get this to compute the shrinking operator is just
it is the explicit solution you just take the vector y
you take the absolute values of all its components you subtract out times of
if it goes negative you replaced by zero
i plug it into this formula and then multiply that by the original why
so this is all done in order in operations where n is the length of
thanks tony
so over the next two hours going to be hearing about dimensionality reduction
as tony said i'm at the university of manchester school of computer science
but i was here in sheffield before
up until about a year ago
OK so
apologies for one thing i was going to be over the last couple of days for that
summer school
i went to school but i had bronchitis
so if i have a coughing fit at any stage that's the reason why i'm
not sure exactly what triggered by but it can also be triggered by difficult questions
so if you ask difficult questions have a coughing fit although that's why
having said that i do stop and ask questions
this is a new way
as far as i know presenting some of the dimensionality reduction suffered a different way
from what we normally do machine learning but hopefully it's going to give you background
to understand a lot of methods we use i'm not really going to talk in
detail about some of the more
recent machine learning methods the hopefully going to say give you background for which you
can understand those methods perhaps in unifying way
OK so
we start off with some motivation
and then we'll do a little bit of background and then i what i want
to really talk about is
dimensionality reduction three distance matching now this is the sort of all the idea and
it comes from statistics
then i'll briefly sort of talk about
when we get those distances and how we can try make distances come from along
the manifold
they're now
briefly show some stuff model selection for trying to choose what good dimensionality reduction is
and then we'll and some conclusions
so all the source code and slides are available online
this talk is also available through from my home page slide that examples are use
i made little toolbox
called the dean red dimensional reduction toolbox
i just put up their last night and any man commands i'm using for example
via given in typewriter font so i think you should be able to recreate all
the diagrams i'm showing you
all results show you are not showing you significant results in serious datasets it's all
this stuff
by downloading that software
OK motivation
so this is the sort of motivational slides i tend to use for dimensionality reduction
for machine learning for period we were completely obsessed by handwritten digit mainly because they
are used for zipcar recognition in the united states
this is a a and d six
from the US postal service dataset sets handwritten six and this is the raw form
of these data come in that typically
preprocessed them using machine learning but this is the overall form you see the data
this is the sixty four
by fifty seven columns
thirty three thousand six hundred forty eight dimensions
to this
data points
obviously the space
contains a lot more than just this digit
and if i sample
randomly from the space
using the probability of pixel being on
equal to the number of pixels are in the sixth of simple model of sixs
and this is what i see
another example
still see the six
now that's not surprising because even if we sample every nanosecond from now until the
end of the universe you won't see the original six
that space is so large its two to three thousand six hundred forty eight
that's something like
there's more possible things can fit in that space than there are
particles in the universe
that's how big that spaces
so working in that space
is extremely four
it's not a good thing to do because you're trying to model
with such an enormous space
there's no possible way that you can get a good idea of when these pixels
are on when they're off
what correlations between
OK if that wasn't sixty that the final sample
just to prove that point
OK so what's the alternative model of digits
so instead of that model is try something as well let's say that
all six
perhaps made up by taking a prototype six and rotating
so this is my way covering all success
you can run this script here and what you'll get
is this result now
one of my showing you here
so i've done is i've taken that six
and i rotated at three hundred sixty times one degree each to create a data
them with a data set i taken the first and second principal components of the
and i'm plotting along those components what you immediately see is
if the data lives on a circle
and i'll show you some examples of the six it's the closest point here getting
here the original six is up on the top right here somewhere
and as we rotate
around the circle three rotating in the clockwise way we actually move
coincidentally clockwise around the circle as well
that's anti-clockwise rotation six move clockwise around the circle
and we see all the different sixties we get in the dataset
now if you keep looking at the principal components
this data you keep saying that this is the one dimensional structure until you start
to get very low numbers of principal components
and when you get those low numbers of prince components what you get is artifacts
in the rotation algorithm so this is an image rotation so when you rotate the
it doesn't quite work perfectly look at these two pixels here right
as you rotate them a sort of separate
so there's some sort of interpolation you as you rotate is not exact number degrees
of some sort of interpolation so that leads to some sort of a little bit
of noise
on this circle is particularly visible there
and there
and so you get this little noise which is to do with whatever algorithm the
image rotation
and this is just an image rotation i downloaded from the web is using to
interpolate those pixels
OK so basically
this is one dimensional structure with some noise
now you could argue
those are all sixs and indeed these guys down here nine
so this is the most sixes in nineteen effects because it's really not a full
in one step right
from one step they do it most people work
do more than p work
and so
if they can do most people work in one step
then if the
if the number of steps was in fact less than t one over p they
will be able to do more than
they will be able to do more than thirty one work in peace steps
there's only t one work to be done
OK i just stated that
almost as badly as all the responses i got from the i OK
p processes can do it most people work in one step
so if there's t one work to be done
number steps is going to be at least tp is going to be released t
one over p
it's not that hard just like i get a certain amount of t one work
to do
i can not copy at most p on every step how many steps to provide
was going to have to be at least that amount
the other bound lower bound is tp
is greater than equal to t infinity
so explain to me why that might be true
if you have an infinite number of processors you also have
you know that p
so if you could do it
in in a certain amount of time with people certainly do that time with an
infinite number of processors this is in this model where where there's lots of stuff
that this model doesn't model like communication costs
and interference in all sorts of things but in this simple model
OK which actually in practice it works out pretty well
OK this is a node
you're not going to be able
to do
more work with p processors then you are with an infinite number of processors
so those are helpful
those are helpful bounds for
to understand when we when we're trying to make something
go faster
it's nice to know
what you could possibly hope to achieve
OK as opposed to
now being ahead against how come i can get it to go much faster maybe
it's because one of these lower bounds is
OK well richard how fast we can go
that's the main reason for using
multiple processors if you hope you can go faster than you could with one process
so we define t one
over TCP
the the speed of
on p
so we say how much
you know faster is it on p processors than on one process
so that's the speedup
if t one over TCP
is or
we say that the linear speed
in other words why because that says that
but if the
if it means that i've thrown keep processors at the jobs
i'm going to get a speedup that's proportional
i mean speedup is proportional to pay
OK so what i throw p processors at the job and get tp
if that's water p that means that in some sense my processors each contributed to
within a constant factor all measure of
support if this in fact is we're equal to p we call that perfect linear
so but here we're looking at at
so you know giving ourselves for theoretical purposes
a little bit of a constant buffer here
if i t one
tp is greater than p
we call that superlinear
so we can see somebody tell me when it when can i get super linear
when can i get super linear speedup
OK well never
we by these
lower bound first lower bound there exist tp is greater than equal to t one
over p
if i just
take t one over p
that says is less than or equal to k
so this is never a not possible in this model
there are other models where it is possible to get super linear speedup due to
caching effects
and things of that nature but in this simple model that we're dealing with
not possible to get super linear speedup
not possible
now the maximum possible speed
so amount of work and
critical path length is
is what's the maximum possible speed up i can get
over any number process
what's the maximum i could possibly get
three by three
as the rank two one stores
still in the rank two things
if three by three and with eight specifying eight x well problem where
that's a only one left
only one freedom left but i want to get only i'm aiming for rank two
i do i do it
that's right so in terms of linear algebra
so this is unspecified in the
are some combination of that well
another quick way to say it is make the determinant
make that determination
the whole of the three by three
if the three by three determinant is zero what's the rank
less than three
take two right
no no no no
lesser evil right to less referring to i to achieve right to but of course
if i made if i specified stuff
you know if i specified that rho exactly the same direction as that role then
all sorts of stuff like could maybe even get lower right but
but i'm shooting here for rank two something saying if you give me a i
can certainly tell in nine one one way the way we saw it was some
combination of role in that role close to write and tell me what that has
to be
and this i'm just saying to say the same thing in another language
some number that will make the determinant zero
number there are making a zero-sum OK
so the three by three completing the rank two no problem
but for by four with twelve specified completing the rank two
a big headache
OK so can i show can come back to this one now this is my
last case that i know of
the goal is to
get the theorem to work
rank to completion where this for OK here with the idea
suppose i look at it
this and this
three by three
and i certainly have to complete that to rank two
what will it take
let's look at the determinant
so i'd like to complete this so what's the determinant have to make the determinant
zero right
five a three by three and trying to get lower rank rank two surely means
it's singular is determined to zero
turns that will have to be zero so what's what is the term a times
a time b time something
and then what else do you remember the three by three determined
what's it going to look like it only involves is the maybe term and then
there's b and eight times something
eight times some
specified in the times something specified
another constant other specified terms that don't involve a and b has to be zero
that's the term that's the three by three to ten
OK but the thing is that involves both a and b
i mean that's only one of the many equations many three by three determinants but
it's the one i want to look at
and the other one i want to look at is
this one
circle the another three by three that's interesting
i just want to use a and b i want to use this
a b were gone
help me here
looking for and this is the right
i'm looking for us three
no not here
and this
there's another three by three
so it's determined also has to be zero
and it involves its independent because it involves these three numbers and these three that
work that appears here so far this is determined to be zero OK what's it
was that the terminal again
maybe looks just like this a b time some other specified thing plus a time
some other specified thing q plus the time some other specified thing or plus some
specified thing has to be zero
out of this second here's the
punchline them out of this i can determine a and b
because of branching time logics we need to talk about trees
if i manage to show you a lot of good theoretical results powerful things on
binary trees
it will be after you understand the place on the by which we could be
a little exercise only to imagine that you also would like to have logic which
ideally talks
i mean the trees that are obtained
and i structure which is not necessarily binary in four
thank you
the tree that have drawn locates binary made it pretty well because i have only
two outgoing branches of
from each state
so i made a binary
but it's not fool for example this one has no
i mean if you
trust me a bit
i see that the the content of the theory with the full binary tree
and then if you want i mean we can quietly with having coffee we can
how to make it with
some more general trees like structures but it's not so
it's not that difficult part
so we're gonna stick to
the full binary tree
i went to be labeled
that this information would correspond to the information
well it's any kind of information you can think of but if you want to
understand the binary tree as
and objects
which has been derived
from an unraveling of some cryptic kripke structure which itself has been obtained
but in the fraction of a given program text lines and numbers encoding so this
isn't sorry
what i want to have is that i want to have labels node
and the labels the labels like a here
you can think of it as a set of propositions
propositions that hold
i mean at that at this moment here
this is just the certain moment in the future but of this particular future here
and what is true here
look at a set of propositions
and the propositions that whatever the i i mean the critical section the other one
is expecting to and
so the
the objects were going to work with our
which structure is
the binary tree
but i can have
arbitrarily many
by choosing different labels of the nodes
so you find the most no
so only binary trees
so this is the formal definition
so how do you define treated you have it already
during the summer school
did anybody trees now
so i don't trees
trees are easy to
to define issue on binary trees you have to give me directions to go down
the tree
so if i want to be binary any two directions left or right
o zero or one
say if i want
the trees of degree k
i need k directions from zero to k minus one of the one to k
is like
OK so here what we have is that
if want to characterize the position in the in the in the tree in the
full binary tree i have to tell you
how to go down
so i can go down
so instead of left and right there was easy one cyclin goes he was he
was he was you why
so i go left
three times and then turn right
times l square
so i go to this equation and so i ask what is the period
of the pendulum
and you're not surprised that you find
two pi
and the square root of fellow which
we've seen that before
but of course
it also comes out
if you do it in this more complicated way
so here we get to buy
times square
that's now do the
the ring
david about point b here
here is the centre of mass
right in the middle in the middle of nowhere
here's the centre of mass
and so the
distance be
is the radius
of the rings
so we have to calculate the moment of inertia about point p
again we used to have have to use now the parallel axis theorem it is
moment of inertia for rotation
about this axis
two points in the centre of mass
that is m are
these are the the ratings of the ring
all the masses at the circumference
all the distance are from the centre of mass and then we have to
after that
according to repel axis theorem the mass times this distance squared and these distances are
so you get a mask
so it is too and ask screen
so what is the period
of an oscillation
i of p
that is to a masquerade
divided by
BMG these are are MG
lose one hour
i woosnam we've seen this before
i derive this
lecture number twenty one
i remember everything by-election number believe
so the period now
is the same as the pendulum
with links to are
this is the ring
so here we have two pi
times square root
two are
guided by geo make a comparison very shortly i just want to
finish them all
and i would like to do
but not least
put it this
all we have to do now is calculate the moment of inertia this was very
close to you
the problem we had on the exam
you have the disk
solar disc
this is point this is the centre of mass but now it's solid
so again be
these are
separation between c and b
and the moment of inertia for rotation about point p
it's now moment of inertia for rotation about the centre of mass
which you look up in the table in the case of u examples was given
on the front cover
one half
are square
that's the moment of inertia for rotation about the centre of mass
now we have to add
this grid
and the are
so we have to
so we find
three half
so what is period
times three half
m ask red
divided by BMG
these are
and that equals
two pi
and square root
lose my and there's always and was are
i get your free half
five i g
so let's write that down here
so we have two pi
and square root
we have are
five advisor
so we have them all for their
so we can now
make meaningful
we want to periods to be the same
so we can hang on to those numbers