subset of variables so that we can kind of propagate
one one message in one way and propagate message in another way too
to marginalize one one of the
one of the element of a group of of of elements in the graph group
of nodes in the graph
OK i'm not going to have to go further into debt into the data was
just to give you a taste of what is it
it was also
so it was simple but
in fact we haven't yet
talked about what's
we have this nodes which are really
model of a full of of probabilities what's happened when now we we we
but true
actually probabilities of these isn't and or in the conditional links
nineteen two
depending on what kind of probability distribution you choose
the exact inference is not always possible
so in this case there are severe
so i approx
we get approximation for inference
most most
common well versed emitters
in which instead of of taking this particular one you will take one was less
and various other parameters which we make the
the inference to be lower or upper bound of that
the more that you actually want
and or you can use sampling method for inferring the
approximating the value of one probability of one event in the your change here
new graph
so let's say that now
what we want to do is to
to learn
the the
parameters of the
conditional probabilities
and in the graph
so we have a couple of examples which come which are generated from from which
we assume are generated from
these graphs
in this graphical models
OK if if all the random variables in a graph
our of nineteen for example in the markov chain
we see have examples of of sequences of states
we can simply use maximum likelihood estimates for estimating the parameters
which in the case of the chain will be only county count and taking the
frequencies of of its
when on some of the random variables are observed and the other
latin or
so i called him
we will do
it's the station maximisation
or also
when when inference a in the graph it's not it's not
very similar the
i'm going to two
to talk about
true graph
so graphic and others
traffic analysis and particularly
what happened when you
actually to use
conditional probabilities
in the in the graph
so for that i'm going to do
to prevent the true problems
which is
it was the one of my is it is the text representation and three different
mothers that are
use for decision for solving this problem
so what is it
text representation in which sitting the need for representing text right so usually really in
text processing
automatic text processing applications were given database of n documents which after some
so we have this and the command
we do some preprocessing like
OK for those flaws stemming stopping
and we extract from this database also
dictionary of
and if we
that appear in this and the command
we would like to find a good representation of
document words
four four for example
document retrieval
text categorisation text filtering
text sentiment there's a lot of
text processing tasks
so the usual way of of
the relation
word document is by the is using the vector space model
in which
document is represented as a bag of words
which is the vector of the size of the dictionary
was a lot of zero and
turn you
are a function of the frequency of the
word number and in the dictionary
publishers was equivalent
your application offline in and online and what is actually make it work in the
state action
what are the incentive
to have people participate what makes a community grow what makes community that
all of these fundamental questions
we don't know the the scientific
methodology to even know how to approach
how do these things involved in the
this section like you yesterday from
jon kleinberg
examples of you know tend to study the structure of these networks and trying to
get a feel for what
huge activity today big business now
fourteen billion dollars c
i refuse to believe
we would like to interact with the world knowledge is by issuing to point eight
looking at the top ten results of six hundred thousand different
if any of you stands up and says that if i were you know that
would like to
i believe actually removing
very very fundamentally different directions
and the game still wide right over
nobody knows how to do it right
so areas community microeconomics which i want to talk about a lot today but you
know whether you know i to search businesses options business there's a lot of people
was of the underneath there's lots examples in our products well
when we started writing some of these economists
you know they ten product meetings
and then we shot
decisions made by engineers
d profoundly deep economic decisions are made by an engineer doesn't even understand basic economics
actually i could use the example of that one of the one of them
our are stars and yahoo research michael schwarz
comes from harvard berkeley
his early meetings with their personal which is a bit
service on the internet
he said OK
tell me what your problems are
so started talking about the fact that it is
problem is essentially stop right because you have
they have fewer women than men and typically each woman gets proposed by
a lot of men
let's focus on the female side of the
that actually makes experience
but for me is a few minutes because for the you should get a whole
bunch of them is gonna get ignored most of them
she does not which was to pay attention to attacks
it is as i understand the problem
so they all look at him he said
you know scarcity in the system
and they are
essentially blank stares what the house scarce
well is that web concept
and the scarcity means
there's no cost you just posting
you're bit everyone so we actually came up with a very very simple solution to
about it he said what are you introduce something that actually makes a message special
so what
you give
somebody a budget of i don't know ten digital roses
four months
four special messages natasha digital rules to
so what does that mean that means you only get one of these search messages
as you know important very few so have to think hard about what is best
and that's it
we know that at least you can do to put something special message right so
hopefully she would pay more attention to it
the very very simple doesn't cost anything
it's all the virtual
but change dynamically
i can actually think about the very quickly they love actually resulted in some amazing
user feedback
advertising sciences we we wanted to do too much that's so
and for this is two
invent the future of the internet basically by developing the sciences underlying these areas i
talked about
and our philosophy is just a very focused
areas that are not covered by others
new and emerging
but be very even though they have the best people in in the world there
my first job was to hire person was the leading the higher prabhakar raghavan for
that he did an amazing job
started search area hired some of these folks by the way
it's actually very hard to just two random sampling right
the people i left off this list
it just me everyone in fact to today i urge you to
invited the
one of the best research paper award also from research at three fifty PM
by environments which are
in the area of
online communities
got like all
duncan watts martin slater
many others
i mentioned microeconomics person might be from text
i'm sure
i talked about
the blog friendship graph study so i'm going to skip it today cover
but that's an example of essentially
trying to understand
sort of a
online and you heard about that get
but the basic
the observation that they came up
first of all the people
observation by climate himself
is that
surprisingly short pasta
exist in these graphs in these huge
and doubly surprising
there are efficient algorithms for finding the short path so it's not quite so that
you can actually stumbled on them very quickly
and what the reason that price
this is over and over this that notion of distance to be one over number
of people the intuition by
you know
if you live one mile apart
it's like
you probably know anybody intimately
if you are a mile apart place like new york city probably have no idea
who person is is right so the idea is that it's not geography is the
number of the people who are close to you
one of them
and this
and that actually shows that there are small short pass all over the place and
it's very easy to find the right
the to
social search
show something about the wisdom of the crowds
computer vision
very hard problem
get image
segment to understand what it's saying
and come back and say this is what it's about
well done for a long time so mistaken for the talk about this game was
rolled out at CMU
a couple of a couple of years
what is the game
it's again
you're going to get matched with random
but for two minutes only
and you get your images
this was the
getting images
and if you want to see
you move to the next image
you get some points
and you go to school
and your score is published
and the reason the linear programme is exact in this case is the linear programme
that just has these local constraints
you have this local so that the reason it's exact is because trees have this
local consistency implies global consistency property
sort of pictorially what i've shown you with this example is that if you instead
think about only in you now the graph has cycles
and you only impose local constraints that's all that you do
what you're actually doing is you're you're doing a linear programming relaxation of the general
so your answer is not going to be exact anymore and the reason it won't
be exact is because
you should have been optimizing over the smaller set with blue vertices
and what you're doing when you only enforces constraints are somehow relaxing the set to
making it a little bit larger so that means that there are things that fall
outside the the set and that you're interested in
that's what you'd like to optimize
and they fall inside the set l l means locally consistent
and this factor is exactly the set of sort of the marginals anymore there's sort
of pseudomarginals you might call them some people call them pseudo beliefs
that's exactly something that falls in this gap between the exact set in the relaxed
OK so
yes i haven't defined vertex accenture let's let me explain a little bit so the
the vertices
the sets that we're looking at are defined by linear constraints that all the constraints
are linear
there in very high dimension so they're hard to picture that this picture is very
misleading that's partially because i'm about artist is partially because it's just impossible to
you know high dimensional things behave very differently than what low dimensions would suggest but
what sort of important when whenever polytopes you cut set by human set by making
cuts with half halfspaces that's what we're doing you make extreme points of vertices
now when you solve linear programme it has very nice geometry i'm not sure if
even show this to but essentially linear programme says
you've got a certain direction in space
that that data is specified by a compatibility function so whatever your data
whenever you have
the village model to have a set of status
and it says walk in the direction stade as far as you can and try
and make that
goes far in that direction and maximize this inner product
so you have a direction state and what you want to do is walk in
that direction as far as you can
so if you think about that walking procedure
if you walk you're always going to be able to
hit a maximum one of these vertices
so that's an important fact about linear programs they always obtain
their optimum might be able to attain that many vertices more than one but you
can always find at least one vertex one extreme point where you get the maximum
so what are these blue things
these blue things are exactly the probability distributions of the marginals that correspond to delta
if i took my original distribution i put all of its mass at one point
i could compute the marginals
and i would get a set of zeros and ones
right so in this example suppose i took a probability distribution that puts all its
mass on the configuration one one one
if i compute the marginal zone get the vector zero one i would get the
zero zero zero one
zero one
you can sort of read off what you get so those are called integral vertices
called integral because everything would be zero or one right it's sort of the delta
function point those are good vertices if you had that vertex and you've solved the
original map problem exactly
when you relax what happens is you introduce other vertices that don't have zeros or
ones they might have in the binary case that have things like as
so the vertex of the polytope a fractional vertex if you make if you take
the extreme limit of this you make these two guys zero
and you make these two guys i have
and you do that on every one of these you take the point four new
pushed up to have point ones down to zero
what that becomes is it becomes a different vertex of the relaxed polytope it becomes
one of these red vertices
right so the problem is that if you choose the bad direction in a certain
direction if you maximize you might hit that red vertex
and if you had the red vertex then you kind of lost you know it
doesn't mean anything it doesn't give you configuration or solution to the original problem
right so that's the sort of geometry of of what a relaxation is doing
so that's a great question so
what i just said so far is let's just do the relaxation that uses the
obvious sort of tree constraints
and he's pointing to the fact that there exist other constraints for instance things are
known to cycle constraints that sort of check how things behave around individual cycles
it depends on the graph where the cycle constraints will tighten it or not
obviously for a single cycle you the cycle constraints then you'd get the exact set
over the cycle constraints are are one way of trying to enumerate the true set
the true said in general is extremely hard to characterise
it if you don't have the tree
the picture should have is that
you have the original set which is very complex
this tree relaxation this our set one relaxation
if you add some of the cycle constraints
what you're doing geometrically is writing extra hyperplanes will start shaving parts of the polytope
office get something that's in between the dark gray thing and the
the tree set which is light grey my picture
so there's actually a whole sort of sequence of relaxations that you can imagine a
lot of people have studied how to sort of titan LP relaxations that's that's one
reason why this perspective is interesting that
to understand the max product or reweighted max product as we'll see is actually doing
an LP relaxation
animalistic way
three input output associations as a shortcut or they can be done through these higher
mechanisms of
let's apply that now
once again to this example
and throw away the directions on the arcs throw away their actions on the arcs
and what you have you have the connection this representation
of the mind
all of our beliefs have conditional form if condition then conclusion or conclusion of conditions
are goal similarly have that forms
the big difference however
if you like is that goals can be expressed in full first order logic
so the conclusion here with the disjunction which gives rise to the search space
of alternatives takes far outside
the realm of
logic programming and takes us into the world of first order logic
expressed in closed form
so here we have connections between conclusions and conditions
and these connections
as you'll see later can be activated in any way we choose there's no reason
to activate them as i've described
first forward from observations
and then finally old work towards actions
we can compile shortcuts
the right heuristics and we can as you'll see later employed any number of alternative
ways of activating the relationships between our beliefs
and our goals
so for the record the syntax of beliefs
in abductive logic programming is extremely simple you all know it probably by now atomic
conclusions and conjunctions of conditions
most of which are are probably atomic others of which may be negative
all variables are universally quantified so we typically do not write universal quantifiers
goals and a LP agents maintenance schools are like production rules and production systems like
plans and BDI agents systems
they generalize first-order logic clauses
they too are universally quantified they look like logic programs except they have disjunctive conclusions
it suffices to restrict these clauses to universally quantified but as it turns out
when the conditions hold
because of the state of the environment it's convenient to have existential quantifiers and the
conclusion you want to find the state of the world in which you're you achieve
your your alternate in
one of your alternative
now this is i think philosophically
which is the minimal model semantics associated with abductive logic programming
the beliefs are logic programs and they don't describe the world as it is but
as the world the world as the agent believes it to be
these are descriptive in nature on the other hand goals also in logic but not
first order logic clausal form described the world as the agent would like it to
there's no modalities associated with this
separation between goals and beliefs
conceptually it's like database integrity constraints the integrity constraints constrain the data
which are like leaves to those which
the database to two so that police conform to them
observations are the only point of contact
that the agent has with the world other than its actions which may or may
not achieve their intended effects
so the agent's task is to generate a set of actions and assumptions about the
world so that schools are true
the observations are true
in this world which is made up
by means of its actions by means of its assumptions and by means of its
so it's a made-up world that the agent lives in
the world is mainly of the agent's own creation the only point of contact is
the observations that the world
throws at the agent
so let's look at that same example again and see how the semantics works we
saw how the proof the so-called operational semantics proof theory works
more or less
here's some
the way the semantics works
we have a goal whenever there is an emergency i should deal with it
either alone by myself
or with help
or just run away
we observe for example that is smoke
smoke so what
suppose i believe that
if there is a fire then there's smoke
so suppose i believe that if there is a fire then there is an emergency
so the smoke might be assigned to fire
if it is assigned the fire then there is an emergency
but i have the goal that says whenever there is an emergency i should do
one of
three all alternatives at the level here
so what is
the agent got to do the agent has got to
make this goal truth
the agent has got to make this school true
and it does so
by generating assumptions in this case an assumption that there is a fire
which explains the observation that there's smoke
so this observe this
assumption explains the observation that makes the observation true
now remember that I mentioned before this shattering coefficient in the worst case the function is maximally
rich and will grow exponentially the growth function is logarithm so if we translate this into
growth function language that means the growth function will grow linearly
which means just to remind you briefly because we need it on the next slide which means that
we can generate all loss vectors or in other words we can we can
find points no matter what is M we can find M points such that
by using functions of the learning machine we can generate all those vectors or that
by using functionl learning machine we can separate them in all two to the M possible ways
now there's this surprising result also due to Vapnik and Chervonenkis but also this
has been proven by others by Sauer a little bit later and by Scherlach
so this is sometimes called Sauer's lemma eventhough it was first proven by Vapnik and Chervonenkis
it's a cominatorial lemma about the structure of this growth function
and the surprising thing is that it turns out that the growth function so I told
you before in
the worst possible case or in the case where the function class has maximum richness
the growth function grows linearly
even in the limit so for all M but it turns out that if this doesn't happen
then we have this nice upper bou this nice logarithmic upper bound so there's nothing
in between linear and
logarithmic it can only take one of these two behaviours so either it has full richness
or this function grows linearly for a while
so after some maximum M
this number is called the VC-dimension and then afterwards suddenly we have this
this very slow growth afterwards so suddenly after that it's only logarithmic in M so it starts
linear in M and then becomes logarithmic so this growth function will typically indicates that
we are interested in of course it indicates where we don't have
maximum complexity because if we have maximum complexity we cannot guarantee generalazation so we are interest in this second case
and the surprising thing is that in this second case the growth function grows
linearly up to certain point and then suddenly
we have this logarithmic upper bound so then the complexity of
the function class grows very slowly suddenly
so that's kind of surprising so up to a certain size of the training set it
looks like the function class is very rich and afterwards it's suddenly small
and that's the regime in which we can generalize
so let me give you an example of this
so-called VC-dimension
so remember I said VC-dimension needs a point up to which the growth function grows linearly so up to
which the complexity of function class is maximum so let's take this function class which is
the which are half spaces in R two
so they separate the space into
an area where the value is a plus one and area where the value is minus one
to specify this last functions we need three parameters
and we can ask the question how rich is this function class so up to which number of
is this maximal average maybe I'll drink a bit while you meditate on this issue so let's let's try it out
let's take a three points
so if we take three points
we put them in general position
now we try to realize different separations of these points so we we can
assign these points to different classes three points we have two times two times
circular orbits
the centre of mass
it means that and one are one
it is and two r two
i don't remember go back to a to one nodes
and now you observing here on earth
optical spectra
you see the absorption lines in doppler shift you see them moving like this
and so you will find
from star number one
sustainable one
you get the period of the orbit
you get it velocity in orbit and you get one just like we got from
the sound is no different
now we have star number two
you get the clearly or it's nice
you can check now to get the right answer
you have the two
and you have two
all of that comes out of the doppler shift measurements
but there is more
you know newton's law of gravity
which leads to capture capra's third law
which is that the squared
equals four pi squared
times are one plays are two to the power three
divided by one class and two
times g which is the gravitational constant
now look
you know what you know are two from the doppler shift measurements so you know
you know the period from the doppler shift measurements so you know this
so what you don't know
is what and one class and two
but you know one or one is and to actually
so we have two equations with two unknowns you find n one and n two
think about this for a minute
out of the doppler shift of this binary system
you get their orbital radii you get their velocities
you get to play with in order to produce
we get the masses of the individual objects
now when you observe from earth
you are probably not in the plane of the orbit notice what i did very
cleverly i put you in the plane of the orbit i said you you which
is the plane of the blackboard
in reality you will probably not be in that plane you will not see the
orbital period and john like this is also and so on
but it will be tilted a little
and if it is still states that the radial velocity which is the only one
you will measure will be lower than the two
in fact you can easily see that supposedly orbitals like this
so you on earth and they go around each other like this
just like this
then there is no radial velocity at all so inclination of the orbit is very
but i will not for to address this today as it doesn't affect the basic
principle behind doppler shift but you can imagine of course it is a key issue
for astronomers to get a handle on the
in our galaxy
there are a few hundred
i low this and get it back up later
there are a few hundred very special binaries
one stories
more or less like the sun
pretty common pretty boring
but there is another one
very small in size and neutron star or black hole you'll see very shortly
which is very close
so it's a very weak of close binary not because they close to us but
the two objects are close together
so this one could be a neutron star
as you will see very shortly black hole
and they go around a common centre of mass saying the blackboard the plane go
around like this
there is the point here between the two
where the gravitational pull in one direction towards this star is the same as the
gravitational pull in this direction has name we call it in the lagrangian point
there is also such a point somewhere between earth and the moon is very close
to the moon but there is such a point
and so if you in a lagrangian point lies here
so that the force in this direction on a test mass
is the same as the forces that direction if it lies on the surface of
that star
then the matter that is on this side here wants to flow towards the report
it's more energetically more favorable
because the force
in this direction is large
now since they go around each other it cannot fall radially and so what will
happen is that this matter from the star
is going to spiral in
for this
and finally finds its way onto neutral state
so it's unsurprising therefore
this star is called the donor
it provides the mass
and this small object
could be a neutron star
it's called
o creator
and this this is called the accretion disk
let's take a closer look at these neutron star
i'm going to make it blow up here
this is a neutron star which has mass and
and it has radius are
and i take a little bit of matter little test mass
from very large distance
and i let it fall onto the neutron star
now the question is was what speed
really to reach the surface of the neutron star
that's an a one question that all of you should be able to do in
no time whatsoever
gravitational potential energy is converted to kinetic energy
and when you object which is here
the amount of
gravitational potential energy that is released
is MG divided by these are
and that's all converted
one half MV squared
this is the speed with which it hits the neutron star
so the little and cancels it doesn't make any difference whether this is a large
mass so small as it always reach the neutron star start with the same speed
and you'll see that speed
is that the square root
of two mg
divided by or
you've seen this
a one
you may also have seen it in terms of what we call escape velocity
if you ask yourself the question if you were on the surface of the neutron
star what is that you need to make it out to infinity
in other words to break away from the gravitational pull of the neutron star that's
exactly the same speed of course
it has to do with the conservation of energy so you could also think of
this as escape
now comes the amazing things
if you take a neutron star
the mass of a neutron star
is very roughly
one and a half times the mass of the sun
this is the symbol for some
and the radius is for neutron star is about ten kilometres
if you substitute those numbers in there
you get the phenomenal speed you get two hundred thousand kilometres per second
which is seventy percent of the speed of light
so whenever antimatter falls onto the neutron star from a large distance
it's the neutron star with seventy percent of the speed of light this is kinetic
it's the surface is all converted to heat
and so
if enough kilograms per second fall onto the neutron star
the surface of the neutron star gets very hot
and we know there are cases where you can get as hot as about ten
million degrees
and the ten million degrees this neutron star will radiate almost all its energy in
the x-rays
very little in the optical almost all in the x-rays and so becomes strong x-ray
make you appreciate
the energy released when something hits neutron star if you take a marshmallow
you throw marshmallow from a large distance on a neutron star when it hits the
the energy that is released that means explosion that is caused by the impact is
through the energy that was released on the atomic bomb was thrown hiroshima
just shortly after
so at the end of the second world war
that enormous amount of energy
because this
incredible explosion
it's comparable to the energy that is released when marshmallow
hits the surface of a neutron star
of where these electrodes or in three-dimensional space
before this it was done with pictures
we're sitting on neurosurgeons remarking photos that were taken with a hand-held camera in the
to try to mark the location of these electrodes
you know i think
in brain surgery when you're trying to localize seizure focus the three most important things
are location location location
right so
i think we have a small improvement here just by having an algorithm to detect
where exactly in the brain we measuring this electricity
and then we went on to do sort of you know fancier color mappings of
power spectra across the brain during different states and seizure states how phase in different
frequency bands is transmitted in this is a screenshot of the graphical user interface applications
written in gtk
for doing this kind of spectral analysis of epilepsy and this is part of the
neural from the neuroimaging sweden and pi is called and i one i PI
so some components that i wrote
the three d component was pretty easy there's really powerful three d library in c
plus plus called BTK that
you know does more with everything you could need to do in three d the
situation for two d graphics was different there were probably thirty or forty two d
graphics library
all of which were good all of which had features
none of which we could do everything that i needed to do
so you know the situation is a little bit like this seems to be in
machine learning everybody does machine learning has a machine learning package everybody
plotting in python have their own plotting package and so i figured i would join
the club rolled up my sleeves and wrote my own
client library
but i had some fairly specific requirements and one of the most important requirements as
i was writing the user interface applications so it is something that can be embedded
into a growing and a lot of the tools
for example the new plant
i don't i hesitate to say can be but i don't think they can be
embedded into google is in a lot of
the plotting solutions had limitations on is something that can be embedded into growing
as well as you know ideally you would like to you can interactively from the
and figures made public location quality plot so those are the kind of three things
i was looking for a user interface applications could scripting good interactive shell used in
public publication quality graphics couldn't find anything that all those components and that's basically what
matplotlib was born
the an interesting story the least funny to me
fernando perez who i python which has the potential of using a lot today
support for new newport nice sentiment patch
i added some features to the ipod interface to point to make it look more
like matlab
and she wrote me back and said you know i'm really busy right now and
that can be able to look at this for six months i can deal with
from my phd so
natalie was born as the patch rejection two two i pi
so this is the first
the picture the of the epilepsy viewing application we roadmap to live showing
you know the time series of EEG on this axis and the time dependent spectra
histogram spectral density plot on this exercise procedures you go starting to seizure activity you
see these high frequency bands start to dominate
no harmonics and then they become very regular in this region procedure properly
so many is a
class library that was designed to be embedded in gtk in in a
user interface application initially was gtk
now is we support other toolkits as well
but for the shell component we know what we want to scripting initial component as
well and i was matlab user so
i decided to write a sort of an interface to the library so basically procedure
interface that was stateful in the way the matlab stay for you know when you
say supply you graph into that and
essentially the same magic going on on under the hood is managing the state of
your process
and so
matlab worked for me is as an environment and i just decided to emulate matt
for procedural interface so we set out to be a matlab clone and the
i don't really strive to be a matlab clone but essentially at the
coarsest layer we provide a lot of the matlab functionality
as you drill deeper and deeper we depart further and further and we try to
do things in the iconic way as opposed to a matlab way
and most of our users appreciate that because people using matlab
i mean should be used by the user because they like the language they like
its features like object oriented programming and they don't find the you know the matlab
language terribly rich but you can see if you're coming from matlab
there's a fairly close correspondence that you know you can learn one or the other
fairly quickly
and we produced in fairly similar outputs
so edward tufte whose vision has worked on the visual display of quantitative information
has this phrase copy the great architectures and
what to do
and this was the general idea of based approaches so
you just search for outliers at the border of the data space but independent of
the data distribution
i think you should have to use the microphone because of the sorry
all that all sorry i know i can repeat it just it just go
that's right that seems to cut so the question was that seems to contradict to
the cause of dimensionality because it's completely right in high dimensional spaces the points tend
to move at the borders of the of the one of the of the data
space usually these that based approaches are only applicable to lower dimensional points not only
because of the model but you will see that these points rely on on convex
hull computation and again
those are the only have a efficient algorithms for convex hull computational some but you're
completely right also from the model
a little bit contradiction to the cause
dimensionality but in low low dimensional spaces
it might work
anyway i'm presenting it trees so i'm neutral about all these approaches but of course
you can ask my personal opinion
i would say this is just for small
four low for low dimensional
so yeah the that's what i said the basic idea is to organize data objects
in convex hull layers
and objects on how to
players are outliers and
on inner layers
are the outliers of the normal
points and obviously basic assumption is that the others are at the border of the
data space and the normal objects are insights in the in the middle of the
day in the centre of the data space
yeah some
things to the model year how are these convex hull layers
find well
you just compute the convex hull of the full data space and all points on
these kind of this convex hull for example take this picture here so this is
the convex hull
for all the objects and all the objects on this on this whole have that
layer one
then you remove these points and compute again the convex hull
which end up ends up in this convex hull here all the points in this
second convex hull have two or layer two and so on and so became
and then you can say OK points having a depth of
at most k
are the outliers and the rest of
so this is the basic here and there are some simple algorithms that
differ in how to
efficiently compute convex hulls
in terms of not too
the data all the times four four four new
convex hull layers
but to do it in one
this can all in one run so here is for example is of that but
also the seed
maybe there are other about but
the some
potentially the most
one of the social discussion the idea is very similar to the classical statistical approaches
for one distribution
one distribution of normal objects
but independent from the from the type of distribution
convex hull computation of course is only efficient dispersants only in
low dimensional spaces
really efficient in low dimensional spaces and well the output
it is usually a label but can easily be
two scoring output for example we take that as as the scoring well you done
you can think of course even
more sophisticated scoring space that can be done very
and obviously the scope resolution is global so to global
approach to my actions
because it considers all
obviously i it that so the question is would it be would remove some normal
objects and obviously yes so again the basic assumption here is outliers are at the
border in liars are in the centre
if this assumption holds then
good work
if not
i strongly doubt
you are completely right
so then we already approach deviation based approaches so
the idea here is that
we go a set of data points of course local group or the global sense
i don't care about it
and then outliers of those points that do not fit to the general current characteristics
of this
reference OK for example brands of the set is minimized when removing
the outliers that would be one
characteristics the variance of the of
this set
and if you remove the out less than the variance
significantly decreased
and this is meant by
the let's do not fit to the to the strength of characters
and the basic assumption again is that the outliers of the outermost points
the dataset
it's taken
a little bit more closer look at the model so usually you are given you
have a smoothing factor
and the smoothing factor just computes for any
from the time you have use a model
and for example for this model here dpfp model
we see that
performance was done by about ten percent
it as you increased from two point two to one
these are models you should tune for four
to get good performance
his comparison in one experiment from one of the original papers which i have the
between vector spaces and l
and you can see
this is a different of recall so this means at the very top of the
retrieved list
the top ranked documents
what happened to them this kind of means
four very
larger prefix of the rank this what happened for it
and so you can see that the top of the range
the improvement of language model compared to vector space
are these but small then
for higher because they
they are quite substantial
and that seems to be the case in general
that language models two
don't hurt for precision but they do much better than recall on vector spaces they
are tuned by
OK summary
the language model approach to IR
view the document as a generative model
that generates the query
we define the precise generative model we want to use
estimate parameters different from parameters for each document model
small to avoid zeros
and then apply to query and find document most likely to to have generated the
present the most likely documents to the user
OK so now a comparison of the
the two probabilistic models and also the vector space model
that have covered today
and actually i also want to compare to naive space because i'm assuming that many
of us who are somewhat familiar with naive bayes
the models i actually name space so i want to
connected back to space so quick recap of what nine based on the model is
in particular the text classification
so let's say i want to use my face for text classification
so text classification you want
if you use naive bayes for that we want to classify document d
human divine assassins
maybe classes like politics economics sports
and you assume that d was generated by
the generative model that corresponds to one of these classes
the question is which of the classes class models which of these class models
is most likely to have generated the document
also which class to have the most evidence
does that equivalent this framework
language model and the language model approach to IR
the object you want to testify is actually the creator is another document
in each document in the collection is a different class so we have a lot
of different classes because each document is the class
we assume that q was generated by the generative model
and the question is which document
is most likely to have generated here
and then offer which document we have the most evidence
so in terms of formal framework is exactly the same but the mapping from
the formal concepts two
the objects in information retrieval system
another important distinction is that two different naive bayes models actually and they correspond to
the two information retrieval models that we've looked at today
one of them is multinomial model
in the multinomial model and simplifying somewhere here but in the multinomial model we generating
tokens one by one
let's say we have to five a class and once we have chosen the class
we generate tokens for this class and
so the first token in the document we generate might be beijing and taipei
and then joined the
she so we generate talking but talking in this model
model is the binary independence model
which corresponds to the naive bayes manually models
and that is what we generate is not trying to tokens buy
we make a decision for each term in the vocabulary the decision is does this
protocol the document yes or no
so we're generating a term incidence vectors
and the
tom indicators and the term incidence vectors so in this case you might choose china
for this class generate document by first making decision does the alaska could this document
and so no
the celebrity apprentice
document that says yes
and so on and so that's how we generate document in the
in the
finally my
and so these two models are exactly the two models that were chosen for the
two competing probabilistic framework here this was chosen for language models
and this was chosen for the binary independence model
so they are they model
documents differently and and the the key difference is that
this is a binary model binary independence model and this is a token based model
that takes term frequency to con
and different numbers tokens
his comparison of the two
i think most of us have already said
and because the bernoulli model does not take token token count call it works best
for short documents that's what i said earlier that
it works
well for titles and abstracts but not for long enough for long documents use
are better off using something like
and i language models
one very nice factoid to bring home the difference between these two models is if
you look at the parameters for the
the parameter for the in in the multinomial model is
what's the probability and going to generate the ad for particular token in the document
and the problem zero one five because in english
about one in twenty words system
and eventually models
how to choose here and that is a very important problem in machine learning is
accidentally or for answering this question
there are two extreme for choosing p and l
OK with the length of the nearby if he is one
and the
one thousand or four and
it is that after what the average means that are rock which
if k is small
and this are a large
then you have many matches
in the body
the variance will be
many similarities in the
in the average
but the
could be large for example
you can imagine that this the market sequence has the memory
longer than k equal to one maybe the court case is is three
there would be a good and is the function of the sample
for the one that the
that you have many matches
the other extreme
that you have few matches
is large
you the quantizer is find xs are small
there there is no but thought
in this case the bias is it more
but the variance is extremely large
the question is
how sell hall could chew
he and al
we depends on the problem the good choices
and the band on on on and
but the sample size
and here comes the machine learning guy i am very grateful who
nicolo and cobbled was she
i i learned this idea from from his book
they do the following imagine that
i somehow these these choices of the and the
among u
here you the first row corresponds to k equal to one
the second row key
but so and so on
and within a here and is equal to one two
three and so on
all of fuel make a portfolio selection
you need that you follow the the algorithm
at each step you calculate your amount of money
starting with one dollar
at the time you and there
and you are my
my place
i see your actions your choice of portfolio
and in each step i see how much money you have if you make an
on the
and then
the question is
hard to aggregate these portfolio selection
and i'm actually learning curve
there are not so many
coming up with the idea but i don't know what the were the best
maybe a duty can you if you are interested in
the aggregation presupposes is the following
it's again a simple principle
i aggregate portfolio selection all of your
a portfolio selection
such that
it's a linear combination of your portfolio that or b
we're in this linear combination
somebody has all the way
if on field and minus one
he has a big amount of money in it
if somebody is has the less money than in the aggregation this linear combination has
a he or she has much less weight especially if their way
it it'll be was but how to make these the weight
five each
we make an aggregation
but this means that the
combination of experts i advertised the good book maybe that and that our
and and the
i is the
we have
for any k and we have a sequence of four
in fact forests
choose an initial distribution over the expert we have infinitely many experts in in the
you're and in practice we have finite dimension
the chosen arbitrary probability distribution or in and out every tree
it doesn't come
the word is more important if it appears in less it several times in a
target document so this is said by this first factor and the second factor was
saying that the word is more important if it appears in less documents so if
we have a word
some words which appear in all possible documents than most likely there are not too
informative like the would be such a which appears there and certainly is not too
informative but so we are normally so in this former like this
which produces one real number physically captures this to concepts and usually have some kind
of balance between this
two factors are written in this weight vectors
so it's called TFIDF
so this is an example of such as TFIDF vector so if this is the
then this document would get transport transform in such vector and this relates behind here
would be TFIDF weights
this idea came from the information through the
from the beginning of eighties i think
another important thing which
appears everywhere but in text mining also information she will similarity how to measure similarity
between two
the document vectors as we said so each document in this vector space model is
represented as a vector of weights
and now
what similar what is similarity now between two documents are presented
in such a way
it's simply to
cause i'm
core zone of the angle between these two factors which is calculated with a simple
formula which we all know from
in high school
so there's no big magic in this and this works very well
and this is used in
i would say most of the products you can buy in the market this
why is this simple formula so interesting because it can be calculated very efficiently and
has a couple of other very
nice properties
next presentation is so-called language models just briefly mention it so this language model representation
is basically this formula and it captures this the fact that language modeling can be
also about the probability of a sequence of words so basically what everything gets reduced
to the estimating probabilities of a next word given one or two
so this would be called three try model and this is this simple formula so
we have two frequencies and we can estimate this probability and having this
three calculated and this can be very
efficiently used for speech recognition OCR
handwriting recognition machine translation and spelling correction as well so this very simple formula actually
it's also a lot of problems and this is also quite quite old already in
text mining is not used so often but let's in this other related fields would
be a little bit more
full parsing also just briefly tragedies so what is full parsing surpassing of
text basically provides the maximum structural information
one of the sentence was the scenario so on the input we get this put
the sentence and on the output together past three so this would be an example
of past three so
john hit the ball
and the possibility was these three in the structure of this sentence is nounphrase were
in nounphrase we determine and now
now what's interesting is that this is a lot of structure which we get a
which we get to the top of the text is actually quite hard to use
for most of the tasks
later on we see some examples where we can use this information but this is
that this was a lot of discussion is still a lot of discussion how to
use this additional structure information usually we just remove it to be on ninety we
just made this
some some of the labels
last syntactic level representation will be something which
usually not even mentioned but i think it's quite
what's relevant is called i would call it cross modality so
the data in which we can get out of the
let's say up on the web for for our application can be represented in different
modalities so here we talk
the main about it
textual documents and the most common with the english text in some kind of textual
documents but that text can be also multilingual information can be provided also in images
and video in social networks
sensor networks are getting very popular nowadays so
the question here is now if you have the same object described with several modalities
of the same time its ability flickr would have image photos of keywords maybe some
additional text dump with no question is can we exploit all these different information
to get better results so one this is one example and say if we have
the word by
they can have several representations for this work by just actual work bias it written
here multilingual
so in different languages we have to be able to get different representations then audio
suddenly have just audio files with the work by this is another representation for the
same object or image or even you don't like here so these are alternative representations
now the question is
can we benefit out it so i want to go here much into the details
about this is method which we use of but often when we try to relate
images that image text or
actually presentation in different languages
this property influences the future outcomes
so what you do with the TED so with this model
this is what i explained before so that was the induction step
what you do with this model later you want to use it for prediction
so why don't use it directly for prediction
so what is the probability that the next outcome is one
given our past outcomes
i mean this is what we really want to do we want to predict the
of future events
and this conditional probability you can either
computed from the posterior
or directly from the ratio of evidence
because i mean you just use the definition
and then you features this ratio of two evidences
so you see
how they can be used in the answers to her
which is actually more reasonable than the three four but i will not go into
this now
expectations of you all know i mean expectation of functions just the function times the
probability and then summed over all
all the sample space
so here the expected value of ten because one problem the posterior is that it's
a highly complicated object i mean this is the function here
but if you have many parameters
then i mean it's not the answer but what do you do with it to
begin summaries of the
and so in one summary is to compute either the maximum
so sum up estimator
or you compute the mean
and this would be true for this
if you want an estimate of the accuracy
over estimation then you often variance which is defined in this way
then you know this is things with probabilities of probability densities
just i mean you take the probability of a small small interrupted by by the
length and let me go to zero
i mean that's not the most important to the density
OK OK i'm running late
time for coffee break now so we will always have the first coffee break in
the morning will be some
real coffee break
you can go down there is coffee and tea
please be that in time so we
even if some run late
you should have stopped
we started even if you're starting time
and the second break
is the smaller i mean the times the same but you know the only instant
coffee and so on in the same in the afternoon
they you back in
ten minutes
there a bunch of
and most of them will be explained in detail by the lecture so if you
if you can't follow one no problem
you we get mostly of full lecture about them anyway later
the metaphoric ration
already mentioned
this is a very exciting to be the line through data
but it's really really important and it's more powerful than you think of
some methods for regularisation
linear methods for classification and linear basis function regression and this is the reason why
they are so important
for instance blind faith let's they're all linear methods for regression
kernel methods local small thing
let's start so the
the classical
classic problem regression problem
yes some input feature vector x
in some d dimensional space
so you have the components x one up to the
the particularly you add another component because and you said that identical one that this
just to make matters easier
you have a response value
it is often noisy
and you want to infer a relation between the input variables the features and the
output variable
and if the relation is linear or you assume this
relations linear in the most general linear function is this year
justice coefficients w zero after to
so remember makes zero is just one
OK so now we have data
so the appears of features of feature vectors and labels say and
o thing you need is the loss function
if you don't specify then it's often implicit and often quadratic
if you look for the
the real
and i'm sort of conduct continuing this because the process until a particular cell so
what's the probability of meeting the cell is exactly the product of these decisions i
made two to descend into this and that's exactly the sort of thinking continues is
of some kind of
compatibility matrix thinking of you as a sort of you have some kind of coordinating
is binary space or in this binary tree and then just narrowing down down
and the probability of hitting the cell is exactly the
the product of this element
so that's another view how you could think of this kronecker graphs
what is nice
is that you can go and estimated from data so the idea is used in
the UK g
the graph you ask how should i say this four numbers
so that you know that was that i would get something similar like this
and there are many different ways to do this so for example one way to
do this is to
use the method of moments where the idea is that if you if you set
this is the values of these guys
then you can analytically workout
how many edges
open tryouts close brian's riots and this is what is called the things will be
there in the network so that you can work out analytically what the expected frequencies
of these
of these of the subgraphs
given that this is the value of this part of this made values of this
matrix so we can see seem you can simply take the network count the frequencies
of these subgraphs and figure out what is the what is the
what are the values of these elements are given sort of the same subgraph comes
so so that's the first
one the method the second method is to apply maximum likelihood
the idea is i started
k one
i kronecker multiplied something to to get something bigger
and when i get this stochastic adjacency matrix i want to say these guys so
that when i sleep is going to get this sequence it this now the challenge
semantics i get this sequence of
coins sort of force of heads and thanks for this particular realization of edges appearing
in the network in this way i can sort of find the most likely thing
to do that would give rise to myself my observed data
and then the last way to to go about this is to use SVD
well because it turns out that you can minimises froebenius norm so basically can minimize
you can solve g minus
OK chronic OK right so you can you can you can figure out what is
what is
OK one that minimizes this expression
right so basically you are minimizing the
some kind of euclidean distance between this matrix and the adjacency matrix and now we
can do this recursively and you begin and you get a solution
and if you do that so let's keep this
and then ask
you know
this is for example if you take network and seventy five thousand miles and about
half a million edges and you know these are the four numbers you find and
now we are in now generate a kronecker graph using this initiator matrix
and now we compare this to the video
opinions networks it is like a big who trusts whom network and you for example
compare in the distribution of degree distribution triangle counts
shortest path distribution this is the first eigen vector this is that these are the
ideal values
you can see that you get things very close
so basically you are able to generate the big network that this somehow
using this microscopic measures very close to the network
and using just four four parameters
which is kind of surprising that setting four numbers correctly you can sort of get
something that's at least in the ballpark very similar to the to the end
and you can do this efficiently like a laptop in two hours so
it's not expensive so much
OK so
why what what consequences that now we have a model that can generate such networks
right i can use this for example is a very good not model for simulations
where i have new algorithms or something that i would like like to test on
the network and i would like to figure out how does it perform as i
as a very the structure of mine and i can use this for hypothesis testing
for sort of predicting how the network it will evolve over time i can take
and then it generate smaller or larger versions of the network using sort of the
same category and i can use this for
anomaly detection
you can make a break or i can go on
any thoughts
so so so far what i was talking about was this sort of more physics
type models of how to generate this landscape structure what they want to get into
now is how to
think about leaks so basically what we focus now is more statistical models on how
one of the network of the structure of links and here i probably have to
skip lot because a lot behind
so the idea is
i want to predict missing links in the network and then sort of two types
of approaches for some shows something that's a bit more heuristic method based on how
to estimate some kind of distance between the nodes in the network and then the
second one i'll talk about is how to sort of become model and somehow model
the links in a statistical way
come to think of link prediction you can think of is in the fall in
the following way you have an evolving networks that you observe up to time so
some time and then what is like to present we predict so given the network
up to particular point in time you would like to predict what new links will
appear in the network
in some other time call subsequent binding
and then evaluation that you're doing is basically you predict this number of new edges
that actually appear in the network and asking how many of them did i guess
correctly and how many of them to this
so this this particular work
the time that he was done by david liben nowell and jon kleinberg you know
three they looked at the evolution of co author citation and recorded
or basically collaboration networks in physics between different areas of physics and the other thing
they did the only consider edges between the people that have at least three other
edges just because of sparsity
and what they they they they decided to do was basically become pair of nodes
that somehow
quantify the distance between them rank the rank or ranking do not seem the in
the increasing distance take top n and consider this is your prediction right for example
what do i mean by distance you can use the shortest path distance
you can use the distance between the between the nodes as the number of common
neighbors they have the number of shared friends you can use the same thing but
do it as a coefficient
you can use a measure that was proposed by damage not and you can sort
of think of it as some kind of IDF right you're going over all the
shared neighbours and you're taking one over the log of the degree of that should
neighbours you can sort of considered you know
three sets of size and the size
we get a small
so this is
in addition to
that is all that you feel
so you
with support vector machine
necessary you the whole thing is one line is
that's why
features of cells to the site
the these history
the problem is that we try
so now
training and testing on the side
so that they
and are course to estimate how to keep the eyes sometimes point one
on the second half sometimes point two
expected same
this is very
five years
you can see the
get one
the same progressively deteriorated
five years
o three
this is the average generalisation about one
o point one five sixty five
red light
in this particular article
small you mention
this is
what about
to the right
the problem
sounds like my work just
and mean that picture
he left behind you by space shuttle
and we use machine
also a large march for
so if you imagine this
what does not just pick
one of them
which is the the one that maximizes the marginal
intuition is that you
and this is the just as
the whole examples might be
then we may not be possible that one
what they are
i've left my heart actually signed that the usually
the tradition
you don't know
and space is still separation
hard to see that these
no it's time
and also
should be
you can also
the solution is that you want to minimize the way back home
and know
you will
and one to
and i think that the resolution
actually by the way
it's not a good
the station is actually not quite a lot
they said they had to measure
and what was going
she was saying the
the same input does
he in as you know
the standard of using exactly the same
you know the
actually power
we seem what to have on generalisation of this histogram we should
see already decided to find
i mean should
we will not detail
this for things you find those
he was
the same is happening all
nasty tales
he be there in the hope is that for the one two one thirty part
of the lab which is different setting things right and after that the lab begins
but that's enough about administrative stuff you need to say a few things
OK so i'll give money and after that i will introduce the next big because
he doesn't actually
just one thing watch welcome to seals somewhere chap money with money father-and-son administrator here
since intelligent edges
if you have any questions and problems and we are not there for three twenty
four this some people would get some you still need to fell out we needed
to come to the office when you get a chance maybe in between the break
or right before you go to lines some user need to go over to like
student employment or international of some of the people work
so if you have any questions you may have any questions for me
no questions no questions and more
you see
so if you you
what think is going
you can hear the good OK so no time productions because we've got a virus
to sticking your neck out
i want to tell you first this morning in first half of the morning of
the things that i wish somebody had sat me down and explained to me at
the beginning grad school fifteen years ago or so clyde figure them out myself and
try to boil them down to lower forty
i want to start with a little is that this is something that people this
early program people often right when they start realising the probabilities and language might have
something to do with one another so here are generated some text
see what this say of arrange key article or safety limited fool zeros the estrogen
so had no idea how to do this well i think the latter to start
with let's say we start over here with and i took out my trusty owned
guy by
and role
to find out what the next letter would be of the next letter was an
OK so i took my and i next on world to find out what the
next letter would be i see in the next letter space and then i took
out the space that every letter is being chosen depending on what what the previous
so how do you think i think the weights for these days
what matters usually followed
more likely to be constant yet so you can't quite see here because some of
the slides are very small but this is actually like twenty seven sided dies the
twenty six letters in space of a few bits of punctuation as well and the
probability of landing on a particular side is proportional to the fraction of letters
the fraction of times the fraction of those
in a sample of english text that are followed by that letter so this is
the ODE
it tends to land on letters
so we generate you know this is kind of pronounce evolved because you say constant
and bells and alternate we can do better
so this is what is called a two parameter or by graph model
because it takes about two hundred times when it takes the letter conditions that whatever
the previous lecture what
so let's go up to
three grams or tri grams
so here
i picked two letters to start with
let's start over here
is so we start with
o t h i n decided well since it's t h
let's roll the t h di and we pick the next letter being and is
actually quite common following t h
so what policy age
well we got a lot of via this that
these so it's almost always valves
the valves are almost never you
in the following h eighty is pretty common in following eighty space is pretty common
cause as a good way to work
and this is starting to look a little more like english
this is called a
i'm get try to to model
and we can do a little better if we got the foreground
so now this is starting to look like
it's rather interesting
market by that in the vocal it choosing between created from those not present up
in class inherently days lovely voice or the words i mean we're getting a lot
of actual english words
we can even go little bit further this point you may be able to see
what the text was from which i chose the probability
that someone would like to guess
let's see the breaks out of oppressor of all which the proletarian coalesced into germany
will give you one point it generated the work reactionary
to leave you with that sort of thought-provoking idea
and let me o
oh sorry i have memories of my slides are everywhere so one more example then
i get to my was just so
this is this is another good example of what i meant by the
understanding the precision and recall problem
here's a typical kind of thing you might want to do with the knowledge based
system you have a question like this the answers warren harding
and we're not getting the answer with search because you know the right words are
in in the document that actually expresses this
so we use some kind of query expansion knowledge query expansion it says OK president
is the kind of leader
and the speech you know what kind of talk to someone gives presentation if someone
gives an now you kind of have a wider net to cast and you might
find something that doesn't explicitly say speech and president in it but may mention the
and all we get the
his data
o thing here it is are going to live that down the
that was actually my
closing joke so we need to
we need to measure these things i mean does improving recall actually improve the quality
analysis search the returns status name is wrong but the the idea is is that
when you open these things up by improving recall when you limit them by improving
precision with these knowledge based methods are you actually making an improvement
thank you
i can hear what he said
turn the microphone i can't it's
i can hear what you're saying because there's a bad girl
that's better
all right i'm making this slide
for that one
so it's not just about credit OK
got it
OK thank you
so i guess is then just showed it doesn't have to be a question it
can be a correction
as as then you just showed you don't have to ask a question you could
also correct some
there's no questions i do have a section on ontology called t
where was this
i e
was my slides anyway
so this is about reasoning what i said about reasoning having having difficulty selling and
i have a hard you know when i started doing this stuff i my first
reasoning system was something called knowledge crafts which was developed by mark fox at CMU
in the eighties it's one of these expert system shells around was machine
and i used to love your writing will rules and building of hierarchies and then
just watching the system
you know show me all the things that can be computed automatically from what i'd
written that i had a explicitly said i thought it was great so i started
building knowledge systems just to see those things happen
the the result lot of people spend hours tweaking their their web pages just you
know to make this font goal of half an inch
and and i love doing that and when
i'm certainly convinced that knowledge and reasoning is important but on how i'm saying is
i'm having a hard time
convincing people who want to adopt who want to know whether or not they should
adopt semantic web technology or semantic technology in general
when they ask me what do i need reasoning for
you know i try to give them some examples high how you can check the
consistency of the ontology and i try to give them examples of how they might
find errors in their data
you know but it's there they're not swept off their feet and most of the
people i talk to are interested ontologies for expressing the semantics of the data
but they just don't seem to be motivated by having any kind of inference or
any kind of automatic automated constraint checking
you know they want to be able to express
their semantics so that other people can see what this stuff means
and if we can automatically some query engine can automatically process changes so that their
maintenance their applications goes down they seem to be excited by this but
you know there are there are in
people interested in reason and i don't mean to say there's not
at all i mean there's certainly are
especially the medical community seems gung-ho
but outside of their it's really tough sell and and i don't i need help
these people to tell me or are we just start selling reasoning because it's school
or do we really think there are problems out there that cannot be solved any
other way
that's information i'd love to have
yeah i guess i should add that to my slide two i think that's
is that problem arose a trend i think i think that's more trend
i see people starting to put a lot of different things together and i think
that's great the work that we're doing in the rules working group
you know we started with this basic logic dialect and then
you know the
it as a companion to we we felt it was important to publish how you
would use this with some of the existing technology that's out there i think that's
what DBP in freebase and you know IMDB in wordnet don't actually real me wordnets
coming around but IMDB is
not really in the semantic web from the perspective of using the technology but there's
a lot of ways that you could combine some of the things that we have
to to make these things work better and and i think that's incredibly promising
i saw about eight months ago
i think the message from
one of the DBP you guys announcing that they were gonna
try to integrate the cyc ontology which by the way i think is really an
in order to do that i have to talk about
about representations for a little bit
usually when we in parametric statistics
want to build a new model
and what do is
we write down the density
that is how we define a probability model right on the density
one of the you know one over the year
the real obstacles in designing nonparametric bayesian models is that that doesn't work
you can't just write on the density
and the reason for that is is the following what what is the density what is the density mean
density is
representation of some
probability measure on measure in general but let's say of some probability measure
with respect to
and other measures
and what this is what does this formula mean so this here for example
imagine that this you say is girls in distribution on the line
and this year is
let back measure which means uniform distribution on the line something flat flat
and this year then is a ghost density
so what this density mean
it tells us
how we can
this distribution here at each point
it's a pointwise reweighting formula
to turn it into a girls in distribution
and it's very
we need to work with density density is very convenient
because they they are defined pointwise
and if you've ever done if ever seen any measure theory then you know that
measures are functions that are defined on sets
so we have to take the real line
and now
takes realign put a measure on it brought
how do you do
you can actually draw because what you would have to
what you have to draw near x axes are all possible subsets
of the real line and then you would have for each of them you would
have to draw value you can't really great
this representation here is something that actually is is a function on
the domain on which measurements so that's very convenient
okay now the but the problem is that
such a nice that
in order for this representation to be useful we need this distribution here
so the first problem is if we have some
parameter space and bayesian nonparametrics some infinite dimensional space
and we want to put
we want to define this distribution on that space
then we first need some other distribution on that space to
to write down density
right some reference distribution which is usually
so usually that's called a carrier measure
sometimes just a reference methods
so we first have to you know be
we first have to solve the problem of output solution on that space anyway
that's the first problem
the second problem is
this this measure you should have certain
so if you represent the gauss in distribution
what do use
you're always use something uniform
right and for good reason why did you not why do not use and other calcium
because we use another calcium
then this density is much harder to interpret
can imagine we take to go since which are located which have peaks at different locations
now we could represent one of them
has a density with respect to the other one it's possible
but what with this density look like or what would it mean if the density is
is very small and some at some point
what does it mean it could mean in this case you always means
this probability measure has small probability mass in the region
if we use another girl you with another location
it could you know mean that's could mean
this one is very large in that region
doesn't make any sense
if we do something if this distribution is not
is not flat
if the density
increases somewhere put you mean
the distribution becomes larger
but it could also mean that this one becomes small
so would like this to be to be flat neutral
just to get some sense of interpretability
such such uniform distribution turns out mathematics that such uniform distributions only
exist on on certain
spaces and roughly speaking is a finite dimensional spaces
so that's exactly result the parameter space and nonparametrics
that the technical term for this flat distributions are you
uniformly ones is translation invariant if you just take it and shifted around on your space
and that doesn't change the value
and that just doesn't work on infinite dimensional spaces
yeah but remember the parameter spaces and bayesian nonparametrics
are always infinite-dimensional
so we can do something like that
representing the prior and the posterior
has a density with respect to something nice
and the second problem is
in order to do that we first have to define some probability distribution on that
anyway with respect to which we can we can represent this kind of a
its own tail problem
okay so that's the first the first representation problem that we have to cope with
and so
there's another one
and the second one is
so i affirm
yesterday i talked about
about all this clustering models
general bayesian models
but you may have noticed that throughout this like this whole part and clustering
we didn't see using bayes equation
now usually when you define a bayesian model when you see the definition of a bayesian model in the textbook
it's defined in terms of the basic relation
right bayesian model is like
the basic question the different parts of the basic creation other based on
the reason why why didn't show you any basic operations yesterday is because
four these nonparametric models based theorem is actually
not applicable in most cases and so they don't have a basic question this the
bayesian models but they don't have a basic reaction
let me try to explain what
what i mean that's okay
in general the bayesian model is
is given by
statistical learning theory approaches
so here we are part a OK so
the set of start with some thoughts about what theory should be doing for some
why we're doing theory in you know i don't
i think i
and sort of pushing an open door i think most people appreciate the need for
theory but but sometimes it's good to sort of reflect on why what are we
trying to achieve with this is it
is it really useful and what's the what's the purpose
so in statistical learning theory the main idea is to view learning from a statistical
and by that i mean that
you know the core of much of learning is about trying to find out
some truths about the world or about the phenomenon you're observing
from a finite sample i mean that's the key sort of ingredient here you're taking
some observations
a finite sample of observations and your hoping from that finite sample to learn something
that's actually true about the generating process that gave you that sample
so you sort of going from particular to general in that sense
and of course the danger is that you misinterpret some feature of the sample
as something that's a fundamental and true whereas actually is just a coincidence that particular
sample that you had that particular
feature present so the
the aim of learning theory is to try and
you know gauge that likelihood that you'll be misled in some sense by the sample
to conclude something that's actually not true
from you know some specific configuration of the data that you happen to observe
because you could take a second sample and do the same thing but you're
you that would just check for one
one sort of thing you might be interested in the
in learning were generally interested in checking for
a whole swathe of properties at the same time
you know trying to fit the whole
the function class and picking out the best function in the whole class
after that data so we need to be able to check if you like how
we're being misled on any of these functions not just on one of them
and that's the key behind much of the analysis is trying to see how much
information we can actually squeeze out of a finite sample
that will allow us to be confident about our conclusions we make over a whole
swathe of
functions or analysis that we might make
so in many cases in many ways it's connected to multiple hypothesis testing if you're
familiar with statistics of hypothesis testing where
you might have a no hypothesis you want to test and you observe sample and
you see whether it's likely that hypothesis will be true
given that sample
and you might do multiple hypothesis testing away machine learning can be seen as doing
very very many
multiple hypothesis tests and trying to do that in an efficient
and reliable way
OK so that's the that's just point one one point two aim of any theory
is to model real world
an artificial phenomena because we want to exploit them we want to understand
why things are
the way they are in order to leave the that
knowledge so for instance if
we can be confident that this inference that we're making from a finite sample is
then we can be
exploit that to analyse new data
and you get accurate predictions on new data
until we have that confidence then we're in the risk of not being able to
in accurately predict data
statistical learning theory is just one approach to understanding predicting exploiting learning systems
others include is i've already mentioned bayesian inference inductive inference is another
statistical physics has been used in this connection in scottish traditional statistical analysis there are
many competing theories here
and i'm certainly not trying to imply statistical learning theory is the best
in any sort of absolute sense it has
each theory will will have its own
strengths and weaknesses
so each theory will make some assumptions about the phenomenon of learning and based on
these derives predictions of behaviour
and as i have already sort of alluded to every predictive theory automatically implies the
possible algorithm because if you know
about your prediction
then you can simply optimise the quantities that improve the predictions
so if you know for instance that the number of features will impact on the
quality of your learning
then you can try the smaller the better than you can try and keep the
number of features small
and survive algorithms that do that
or if you you know if you know your VC dimension is is something
critical feature you try keep that small while obviously getting a good fit on the
so these these sort of natural consequences of any theory
and this would be my argument about why theories good here is good if it
drive you to new and better algorithms that will perform
in more efficient and more of efficiency isn't dealt with here but more and more
with high predictive accuracy
so the theory is have strengths and weaknesses of already mentioned
generally speaking the more assumptions you make the more accurate predictions all the more sort
of refine predictions you can make
but of course
predictions will be dependent on those assumptions being correct or approximately correct mean most assumptions
that you make can never be
exactly verified
and probably untrue
so the question is how few abstracted some assumptions that are reasonably good
and actually capture the key phenomenon what's going on what have you put in some
if you like poison into the mix that actually is completely miss
skewing your analysis
and making your predictions are inaccurate
so it depends on capturing the right aspects of the phenomenon
and obviously you want to try and keep it as general as possible but if
it's too general then you won't be able to say very much and
in the way you know the the
maybe the distinction between the
bayesian and perhaps statistical models the bayesian typically will make more assumptions about some prior
distributions and noise models
but in many cases they seem to be
maybe not exactly right but good enough and you get good results out statistical
learning theory makes the rather less assumptions in that it just assumes an underlying distribution
and the training data is drawn i i d independently identically from that distribution
so it seems like a weaker assumption and
typically you may get weaker results for that reason but
in fact you do get surprisingly strong
results given the weakness of those assumptions but even those assumptions are not necessarily going
to be true in any practical application it may not be the case that your
training data is independently generated
true beliefs he roughly seems to know where the red
here's another video which is much more famous that's a classic in social psychology etc etc
two psychologist heider and simmel in this study that was published in the nineteen forties
just curious how many people are familiar with the site and some of it
i mean it's it's it's so striking
if you haven't seen it before r and all you remember from this talk is this video great
so again you could pass this has two triangles moving in a circle moving
and some other lines but you don't see it that way you see
objects that are beginning to each other in any again you feel like they are
intentional agents with stories and desires it looks like the big triangles kind
was displayed again kind of maybe billing the little triangle
we are bringing in him and then is gonna be sort of the
the circle kinda seems to observe and now is going to hide inside and once
the big triangles kinda scared of the little triangle there
he goes back and goes in there and sort key ominous scary music
if you haven't seen this video you can watch it on youtube and now we
are left a kind of moment suspense don't worry it ends happily
these are the two and three characters
right so what's going on here again
you know
from just what what you can think of is you just a few numbers in
time these are low dimensional time series if you think about how many what how
much information is required to describe these movies are not nearly as rich as the
full natural scene contrast
strikingly with what sebastian's services the really massive data coming in
you know to it from a street scene to google's self driving car
here you have very little data but look at how much you see you see
real physics objects with forced dynamics you see real psychology beliefs desires intentions emotions and
even more what you might call things like sort of morality in sociology like who's
on who's team who the good guys bad guys most people here see the big
triangle is kind a bad guy and the other two being on a team so
how do you do that how do you get so much from so little
this is the kind of thing we want to understand and i think if we
can even make progress on just those last
steps and then building up the things like
you know kids with air with their blocks and building up to real common sense
physics and psychology in natural scenes
would be somewhere
OK so the approach that we've been pursuing
well i would say you know over the last ten or fifteen years or so
in computational cognitive science is very much one i think many people recognise here is
is in common with a lot of the state art
a clear recognition the importance statistics both in data entry inference but the really the
heart things is about the interaction between statistics and knowledge in all these cases the
data on its own it's observed isn't enough to make the difference is he makes
something else have to fill in the gaps some other kind of abstract background knowledge
and the key questions have to do with the interaction between us how does background
knowledge guide these inferences from such sparse data what forms that knowledge take across
we all these different domains and tasks and maybe most interestingly how like how many
get in there if the brain is you know doesn't isn't programmed by a smart
engineer r in some sense has the program itself learning about technology is absolutely critical
so the kind of ideas that we've been pursuing
are shown here in red
i broadly were taking a bayesian approach you know probabilistic inference framework wear
the heart of things is some kind of a generative model some kind of hypothesis
space ways to to account for the data
and some kind prior over those but you will go well beyond anything that looks just like bayes rule
work hours and they i would not talking about exact bayesian inference we're talking about
some kind of approximation because these computations are going to be intractable to do in
any exact way
on end again has has pretty much now
i think you know
well recognized in this community
but it's one that say the statistical machine learning community has only more recently coming
to and sometimes not even at all
and is and is also still quite new in the cognitive science and neuroscience community
statistics is not just something you do with numbers it's not just something you do
in high dimensional vector spaces but it's something that you can do with real knowledge
with representations of the world and data that look much more like these were earlier
classic i approaches
what various kinds of symbolic knowledge representations graphs grammars schemas predicate logic
end i think in in in common with a number of people in this community
but the number one thing we need to do to understand build tools that allow
us to understand this kind of these aspects of human intelligence is understand how statistical
inference and learning can operate with these kinds of representations and that's that takes us
beyond what is an unfortunate common legacy of these two fields which which is you
know decades fighting over statistics versus structured representations it's nice that you know in the
last decade we've seen how these approaches can interweaving really deep in interesting ways
maybe most exciting is this idea which i'll try to get to by the end
of what we call probabilistic programs so we're doing probabilistic reasoning
not just over things like grammars predicate logic but actual programs in particular be looking
at functional programs so list is is come back and our work in a certain
and don't try to argue why this is
i think an approach that subsumes a lot of what we and others have been
doing with other kinds approach structured probabilistic models and in a powerful way for common
sense reasoning
and this this last maybe most compelling question how much knowledge itself acquired well here
we've been drawing on ideas have become very popular in these
bayesian machine learning community and themselves to run the business statistics community what are called
hierarchical models hierarchical bayes we don't just have one level of the hypotheses generating data
prior there but but multiple levels hypothesis space of hypotheses and priors on priors and
by doing inference at all levels of the hierarchy you can explain how some piece
abstract knowledge in a certain level isn't just useful in guiding inference lower level but
itself might be learned over say broader timescale are proper sources of data
up by inference at higher levels of abstraction and when you put all these things
together you put hierarchical bayes together with the idea of a probabilistic programs as a
basic knowledge representation then you're talking about these hierarchies programs that generate other programs again
an idea that has has very important early precursors if people remember the work of
people like feldman
warning on grammar grammars the earliest probabilistic grammar induction approaches
and it's sort of a kind of a hierarchical bayesian approach to learning as programme induction
this is just something we can glimpse at this point and maybe at the end
of show you a little bit of demo going without but it's that's just
you know that's mostly and
as sebastian so you invite me back in two thousand twenty eight or something and
maybe will actually have that's all
OK so
i let at what i wanna do here is in in this talk is to
give you a bit of the tour through the way we've been using these ideas
to understand
these these hard problems of human cognition
of things like learning from very few examples or common sense intuitive physics and psychology
i want take one step back just because you know you're coming from a different
field and just a little bit again in the context still see a parallel with
with i feel when i got into cognitive science was in the mid nineties basically
in grad school
i'm just as just as in any i there was a lot of skepticism over
whether statistics and and probabilistic inference was even relevant probably many people are familiar with
the work comment averse key very important work justly deserving of the nobel prize the
column and one in economics in two thousand two
but the headline this work for psychologists was basically people aren't bayesian
they gave people and a lot of other researchers in the field of judgment decision-making
around and following them people very very basic bayesian stats questions like these things simpler
problems like you've drawn a certain sample red-and-white ships had this surname veteran and they
the battle scale region average force of about twenty militants
four times five
if you want to males but if they were super bowls which would bounce up
then the momentum change would be doubled and so the bathroom scales would indicate
forty newtons
so this is a real thing it's a real force that you can record
now i'm going to be
a little bit unpleasant to you
i'm going to throw
rotten tomatoes you
u i
and i have here
the tomato
and this tomato
has zero speed to start with
let me make your little bigger otherwise i won't even
and even get you
so this issue
and so i give this domain always certain velocity
the of x
the tornado hits you
maybe it stays there is possible
it will drip down
but in any case
the velocity actor action is gone
so it's you
with the velocity vx
and then
the effects
equals zero
and may make a mess
you will experience a force if i keep throwing tomatoes at you all the time
and this is the force you will experience
and that force
is of course
in this direction
all these tomatoes
you feel that as the fourth
but now look at the symmetry of the problem
here the velocity goes from px two zero
but i throwing tomatoes
as to increase the velocity from zero to three x
so for obvious reasons
i must then few force this direction think of it as record
you fired a bullet
so i experience exactly the same force
but in this direction
and that no
is the idea
behind a rock
a rocket
is spewing out tomatoes well not quite tomatoes spewing out hot gas
in this direction
and then the rocket will experience a force in that direction
that is the basic concept
and the higher the speed of the gas
that it throws out
the higher the velocity
the more kilograms per second it spits out
the higher the MDT
hi will be the force on the rocket
and this force on the rocket is called
the trust
of the rocket
so if we have a rocket in space
use the rocket
and the rocket is spewing out gas
with a velocity
which is fixed relative
the burning of chemical energy
chemicals are burnt it comes out with a certain speed
and the rocket will then experience
a force
which we call
the trust
and that is given by this equation
if you know how many kilograms per second that spewed out
and you know what the velocities which i've called you you
this will tell you about the thrust this of that rocket
if we take
the case of
the centre rockets that were used
for the landing on the moon
for the saturn rocket the
speed you