so the cooperation requires summing over x or conditioning on the observed value of x
xi if excise and evidence note and remember that those two operations can be made
formerly the same by this book keeping track
so something that x y is going to leave function
which depends only on the parents of exile on the in general the neighbors of
x i
and so they the neighbors will become connected because there is now a function sitting
in equation which has both of those things as arguments and therefore
in the factorizations sense are connected in the in the ground
so this original graph which is augmented by the edges that we ever added
is called a triangulated graph just as a reminder
triangulation is just a sort of definition from from graph theory it means that every
of length greater than three
has a clear which breaks the which breaks the cycle
so in terms of the picture i think i have a picture here
so imagine we take six no graphical model
and now what we're going to to do is is we're going to try to
eliminate these nodes one by one so the first thing want to do is eliminate
node x x we're going to try and some out the distribution and x xx
is connected to x two and x five so obligated to introduce this edge here
between x two and x five
and we can some x xx and move from the model k
and then the next one some is x five
and so we have to connect x two and x three here
and then we can semantics five now we can semantics for
and then we can some x three here x one and x two already connected
and then we semantics two and we get x one which is what we wanted
to get the answer for now
this graphical picture corresponds exactly to the algebraic operations we were doing before
so when we say that x x what we're left with is some function
which has as its arguments x two and x three
sorry x two and x five and function
is recorded for us by the edge in the graph so you can see that
everything that don't know the graph here has correspondence in the summations
and this is just the
point that i made here which is that if you take the union of the
edges that got added during elimination step the resulting graph is a a is the
triangulated graph
and that's true
for any elimination ordering now
there's good news and bad news as always
the good news is that if you have a graph is trying
as this graph is
you can apply to very general inference algorithm called the junction tree algorithm and was
sort inference in this graph
the bad news is that it's very hard
to triangulate graph in which induces a small clique size
remember that we realised that the very beginning and we started looking graphical models that
the size of the graphical model representation of the joint distribution depends on the maximal
clique size is exponential in the maximum clique size which is much better than the
exponential in the entire number variables but if you screw up and you think about
elimination ordering triangulate the graph yes but will triangular with a huge interior clique size
and you really get killed at inference time and the problem of finding a triangulation
of a graph which induces the smallest possible clique size is hard
in very
formal sense so the the best you can hope to do is to have some
heuristics to do that
so that was just too
but and they save
and the median family has zero star was pretty shocking
so the idea
that i'm trying to find somebody to to
work with the registered myself on implementing this
the idea is that people would set their own yearly savings goal
and they would make weekly deposits towards the same goal
and every week that on or about the target they participate in the lottery
and this displays of hyperbolic time discounting is people
immediate reinforcement plays on
some players and some other psychological effects and i am worried that time here but
it plays a bunch of different psychological effects
last slide
so in my opinion
public policy not not neuroeconomics but public policy is the most important application
to to me this i realize this egocentric because i do it but it seemed
to me it's the most interesting application of behavioral economics right now
i think i try to persuade you that it's possible to design a light paternalistic
policies that help people
without reducing their autonomy
many of the most successful
interventions use the same biases that typically hurt people to instead to help them
i are
although i have a question for the
i'm going to
that was
there seems to be taken into account
the fact
it is
not be
i have
it's all right
one thing
well to be honest
hundred four
the negative class on earth
so that's the big difference
you would never
it seems to be talking about different incentive schemes talk
we would need to
in all these incentive schemes are people want to
we generally people
it is very fast
i believe that they should be taking their work
we want to lose weight
and can do it
and we're trying to help
to me it seems quite different
it is
this nation
one idea i am very worried worry about
whether people
stop stop until they were
i mean i think that people it's hard to imagine people's intrinsic motivation
the sides and this is
in order to be able to
but i think that is
on the other
i think one of the literature on
how do you in principle this is pretty
not notable prize for research by psychologists is pretty simple
only only
so let's take a child for example
so what you pay your child
to do homework or something like that
first suppose that we
or if they were paid
so what to do or a
and i will always lose interest
if you have
well just
all to begin with
and maybe they you get the pattern
so one of the things that could happen to you
even if you withdraw to make
i intend to do it
and one of the things that we're looking at all studies is we're following people
have started to work on to see what happens
my guess what we have data like they actually do better
people who
but the story
the first so it's interesting
so i just
this is
so that
so what there
what makes
we actually
for many patients
we want to see how well they were here before
they start to out tour program so we gave them the many monitoring
months before
we start getting things
and we
and i want to give you you some ideas
it doesn't our initial data
i suggest that the model just a reminder isn't in this model first sentence seems
to work
i this
for reasons that neon
has ten electron so you have
many more bits
many more ways that
electrons can
play musical chairs
a lot of lines in the red i'm not blocking your hope
a lot of lines in the red
and some beautiful lines in the yellow i see some in the green i don't
see much in the blue and a little bit in the blue
but the key thing is i wanted to see these lines
i discrete is not
just any
wavelength that can be generated is only allowed
with its
musical game
when the
from one orbit to another
and that gives you this unique discrete spectrum
now these flies back to well known long before before came with his daring ideas
but before quantum mechanics these lines were great mystery
they no longer i
i suggest you
use this grading
use it when you outside nights look at some street lights
particularly sodium lamps and
mercury lamps and of course the neon lamps
a quite spectacular keep in mind
will not very nice straight lines on this you light source itself
it's very nice straight narrow
light source
according to mechanic talker be clean
in the twenties
and it would be impossible for me be available
amount of time to do justice to all the basic
i will discuss some consequences that i rather not
prior to quantum mechanics there was a long-standing battle between physicists
whether the light consists of particles
whether they're waves
i believed strongly
if particles
and the dutchman organs
i believe that they will waves
and it seemed like in eighteen o one the conclusive experiment was done
by young
which demonstrated unambiguously
the light
what waves
organs was right
but as time went on
this concert was growing
as there will also experiments that showed rather conclusively
that light really was particles
and it was one of the great victories of quantum mechanics
that it showed that light is both
they behave like waves
other times it behaves like particles it all depends on how you do your experiment
in nineteen twenty three
the broccoli
i made the daring suggestion
that's a particle
can behave like waves
and he specified was very specific
but the wavelength
now it is called the broader wavelength
h mark strong's constant
divided by the momentum of the particle
moment is the mass of the particles
the velocity as we have seen
in a to one
if the momentum is higher
the wavelength is short
very high momentum was ridiculously low
short wavelengths
and one of the startling consequences is that
protons and electrons which everyone at that time considered particles
can also be considered
has been waves
in nineteen twenty six
the austrian physicist schrodinger drove the nail in the coffin
which is famous equation schrodinger's equation it's called now
which is the ground field of quantum mechanics
and it unifies the wave particle
character of
returning to my baseball
they come as baseball
of say half a kilogram
and given the speed of hundred miles per hour
the wavelength that you would find
according to quantum mechanics
that wavelength is so
absurdly small
it is twenty orders of magnitude smaller than the radius of an electron
so it is completely meaningless
quantum mechanics plays no role in our macroscopic world of pots and pans
and baseballs
now take an electron
you take the mass of the electron ten to the minus thirty kilograms you give
the electron speed of a thousand meters per second
now you get away flange which is comparable
to the wavelength
of visible
white red light now
something that becomes very meaningful something that can
now you may argue
she will differences may who cares
something is the wave whether something is part of
it makes a huge difference
because when
and they have valleys
so if you take two sources of waves
you want to waste two sources
tapping up and down in the water or you can take
two sound sources
there are certain locations on the surface of the water
where the crest of one way
right at the same time
as the family of the other
so they cancel each other out
there's nothing there's no motion of the war
we call that
because there are other places where it is constructive interference where they support each other
now if
particles can do that too
it is very hard to imagine how can one particle
with the nanoparticles
and finish the two particles no longer exists
learning by learning via trial and error in prediction errors
these stored q values in the q values are
prediction for future for some of future rewards right
now in this case because we already have
q values choosing actions is really easy to have to compute anything you don't have
to solve the dynamic programming problem you're at state zero you look at the two
q values and you see that left is better done
so this is the kind of quick reflexive behavior that we could imagine from individual
one thing is you need a lot of experience to learn you need to go
through this many many times to get the correct q values
the second thing is this will be inflexible right if i now change the value
of the cheese to zero
it's not immediately clear which q value should change without experiencing this made again and
and having prediction errors update these values
so the idea was
that goal directed behavior is actually
model based reinforcement learning where
the four where the rat learns the model of the world and plans in it
and that's why we see
evaluation sensitivity
mitchell behaviour is model free reinforcement learning
in the brain
but now the question but now this answer raises two
new questions because we're still stuck with the question of
why the hell should the brain use two different strategies in parallel
why not just use the best of the two
and use that one always
and if you do decide to use two now what do you do if you
have two parallel systems telling you what to do and they say that if they
say different things so one system is so i press left another saying no don't
press whatever
now there's a new control problem of like which controller to listen to
new decision making problems are
and so and here
it was
that one way to think about this is to look at the pros and cons
of each of the of model based in model free
reinforcement learning so
each of these two systems is best in different situations what you really want from
a robust
smart complex brain is that would be able to use
each system in the place where it's most
so for instance
if you have very limited training model based learning is actually does better with with
little data compared to model free learning because model free learning bootstraps and uses you
know it's
it uses its own john to learn basically and bootstrapping so it it takes a
lot of time to take that chuck out well
o model based learning put each piece of information in the right place does better
limited training
on the other hand model based reinforcement learning
will do better when it's close to the reward so this tree are the dynamic
programming problem is much easier to solve than when you're playing the game of chess
and have to you know
some of the tree of all the possible actions until the end of the game
so in the case where close to the reward or have limited training the brain
would do wisely to use goal directed
two years ago directed is model based
forward search mechanism and the opposite after a lot of experience when the reward is
really far away it would be better to use a caching q learning
model three
or starts to model free
so that's the answer for why have two systems
and now if those two system this this as a kind of says in one
situation use one system and other used other but you have to have these two
systems learning all the time you don't want to waste experience and teach only this
system with some of the trials in the system with others
so that learning should happen in both in parallel
then if you ask yourself
they have two systems have already learned
rather than decide which one to use apriori by the constraints of the problem i
can basically ask each of them
to tell me based on everything they've learned so far what do they suggest that
i do
but as them to not only say what they suggest but how confident are they
in this suggestion
and trust the one that's most confident in you would help that
this one would be more confident only after a lot of experience and this will
be on more confident only when it's close to the
so the idea is
okay welcome everyone thank you very much
coming to
this we first lecture
of course
information theory pattern recognition
hand neural networks
this first lecture is an introduction to information theory
information theory was invented by claude shannon to solve communication problems
the fundamental problem
that Shanne defined was the task if reliable communication
over an unreliable channel
so that's a fundamental problem
and all give some examples
right now
so some examples the channels
one channel way using right now is
the channel
that goes from my voice
and the medium is
another channel that we may be using is channel goes from our eyes up to
the bits about nervous system
and then medium is the bags and cytoplasm and local employment impulses
another example the channel the world carrying around a this is the and i got
ten to thirteen copies of our genome on board in
each ten to the thirteenth cells
hand every time and cells
we spend
two copies of the genome into
cells are repeat about forty times and you've gone from the egg
to a human being
hand maybe on the next generation
another example is three
spacecraft saving mars rover or something like that you have
an antenna
on earth
and we use the vacuum
transmission medium
then signals
the mars rover and make it content and sends back
signals so is a channel
and it can go in both directions
anne d another example it is i phone line so you may be have
copper wire
if you are old fashioned
connecting one phone
another and
another example is the disk-drive so the medium is some sort of that still
in a standard
hard drive
hand in this drive
use store a message which might be
the file
anduse and that
to yourself
at another time
many these channels go from one place to another place
one place to another place but you can have channels go from one place that
strive to the same place but at a later time and we're still trying to
the message from one location
to another location
all these channels have
in common the property
that's the received signal isn't identical to the transmitted
because the noise or are
other processes are received signal
is maybe
approximately equal to
the transmitted signal
but we've got some noise
added as well
maybe you know some of these channels
maybe there's no relationship
no simple equality relationship at all you just have the transmitted
the received signal depending on the transmitted signal in some way but for toy channel
we might say let's assume the received signal signal differs by
adding some sort of nice
hand in most these applications
you might say that's bad news because we would really like reliable communication we would
like to be able to deduce
at the receiver precisely what he
original transmitted signal was
we would like
have communication systems
received message
is equal pay
the original transmitted message
would make far better phone call
about disk-drive
communication between lecturer
an audience
so imagine that's
we're trying to achieve this goal we're trying to make a reliable communication system what
sort of approaches could we go for what solutions our
while we can perhaps categorize
solutions to this goal
in two ways
e there their physical solutions
where you throw away and allows you describe and replace it by a better one that's more expensive maybe
you take your copper wires and you put better insulation on them
new users
cold a magnetic field you add cooling so change the physics to reduce the noise
so this physical solutions
we could talk about system solutions
and the idea of system solution is we accept the lousy channel has it is and we had
applies only
because is the only
and here
those people
well the results of applying them
well the result
for example i just want to get the two
so when i like that
and here is the outline
if you put down here
and they may be the case this big so we use them was what they
were no longer
so if you actually check only
my four
others because we can't apply
now what
otherwise we will have
one like the
these people large
the ball
they are about
in the segmentation
you you disagree
some of the
in which
like this the walls which are the images what
they like it just put it all the way to image
because the bombers
much more
i agree
or the be
problem when have more than one in which he would have a lot of money
laundering in my
page twenty one that will be a lot of
what we can do
we can use the call the mach
what matters
we also that
and is always a
two percent
what can we can
i can be in turn things
with that in mind
i mean
and one
one of the not very good at all
because the
great light weight
and that there
all were
and that's
a money
in march
the image
and then we can say
so we're not allowed
you don't have
that is
how much more
between these two
which one of the body
can be also
vector by applied
thank you chris
so process
we yes
we can have
one of the first
from which
you feel like
on the one local
the model
and the rest of the page
and that is
of segmentation which
will be like
and the
the lake
thank you
o thing the page
so about the limitations
so that's where i'm going
what we need
to my
what which can be be
so there is
the long range
the that by the way
so again
i think that
which of the two
and the
you can
one particular
and for
the area around the world
one one
the the fraction of original surface
features of
the point of
which one we
that images
ten million
while men
but i think it's
o point
you should be able to
the object which is the
it to
x one
if we use some information
the two
there should be a
and the same true
so i would keep should be
in very
that's amazing
the water there
this approach is that he
you just have
which was proposed by
the main
what those
and the brain
scale depending on the room where we were
this step is called people the village
average takes different values on Gaussian data and Laplace data and the best function
here subject to this constraint of course that the length of the function should be
at most one measured in the reproducing kernel Hilbert space the best function is this
red function so here this dotted line is the laplacian data the dash line is the gaussian
data or distribution generating the data and this function distinguishes them this red one so you
can see this function takes positive value as where the laplacian is
more likely than the gaussian it takes negative values here on the side
where the gaussian is higher and it sort of goes to zero asymptotically so that's interesting function
and we can generalize I'm not gonna go into all details here just wanna
mention we can generalize this from data sets two measures so we can
takes two I mean  this is a little bit more mathematical and maybe you don't
have to follow all details if you're not interested in mathematics  but instead of
data points you can take probability measures you have to make certain assumptions and
some things are finite and then rather than mapping a set of points into their mean
in the feature space we just map probability measure into its expectation in the feature space
so you can think of this as taking all the points from the measure so
X is sampled from the measure mapping them into the feature space and
then we take the average of all those so that's a single point that characterizes
probability measure of course it's a point in a high-dimensional space and like
before this point represents the operation of not taking the average but taking expectations
and also to a probability measures will map to a different points if there's a
function in the reproducing kernel hibert space which takes different expectations subject to these two different
distributions and  interestingly it will also turned out that this characterizes the probability measure
so we can if we do things right  we don't lose any information in
this procedure and I want to mention this because it's related to an interesting issue
that you might see somewhere in the kernel research world it's the notion
of universality of kernels so it turns out maybe I'll stop with this down here if K
is a universal kernel I'll tell you something about this in the second then two probability measures
are the same if and only if that representations in the reproducing kernel hilbert space are the same
now first of all it's clear that if two probability measures are the same then their representations
are the same that's trivial but if the representations are the same it turns out we
can infer that the probability measures are the same so again this mapping mu does
not lose any information about P and Q here so why is this true this is
true because we can reduce it to a classical theorem of probability theory which
I'll briefly mention because I think you will all get the intuition for this and this theorem
says that two  probability measures are the same if and only if we can find
some continuous function which has a different expectation according to the one measure and according
to the other one so that means well first of all let's assume F
is the identity mapping here that means here we have the statement that the means of
the distributions or the expectations are the same here we have the statement that the distributions are
the same now clearly if the distributions are the same the expectations are the same but
not necessarily vice-versa but but this theorem says that if you are allowed to transform
the data non linearly with some general continuous function so if you are allowed to take
nonlinear transformations of your data then it's actually enough to just check whether the
means are the same okay and this can be translated into the corresponding statement for our
case simply by taking a reproducing kernel hilbert space which is dense in the set
of continuous functions which means that it's a reproducing kernel hilbert space which is so rich that
every continuous function can be approximated arbitrarily closely by elements or by sequences in that
reproducing kernel hilbert space and it turns out that's exactly what this notion
of universality  is good for so universal kernels have this property that the reproducing kernel
hilbert  space is so rich that they basically contain every continuous function okay so I'm not expecting
that you follow in all details but I also wanted to mention a few things
that are close to the current research and it's nice if you have these things
already and see where they belong and what they're good  for so in that case if
we have a universal kernel  this mapping mu is invertible on its image and its
image actually is also of interest in other domains in machine learning it has been called
OK let's let's read restart
welcome back
OK so i'm going to pick up where i if you remember i kind of
didn't quite get to the end of my first
section part a that i was going to talk about so out of start by
going through the rest of that picking up where i left off and then go
into the
rademacher complexity section that
i'd also like to talk about
which is you know the sort of second second part so just sort of you
know recap
bring it back to where we were
we were looking at these basic sort of scheme of
analysis that supplied in
extending these analysis methods to
infinite classes of functions
and the idea was to first use this double sample trick to sort of replace
very fancy
it is OK agree
get rid of this test point and replaced by a a sample
so we're now just looking at probabilities over double samples
there's just an event here which we can analyse
and indeed we can now just choose ourselves by
looking at the possible
behaviours of
the function class on a sample of size two n
we actually find out there's only BH of two n possible behaviors here
and so we can do a union bound over that set of behavior so rather
than having an infinite set was suddenly down to a finite set and it in
fact very much immeasurably sized finite set this h two n and then we can
treat this as if it's a fixed function and we're just taking the sample
relative to a fixed function and then there's this observation it's pretty weird that all
the errors in the second half
that's the so-called growth function
which was the number of different behaviours
that the function class exhibits on that set of two n points
so if you think of behaviors you know classifying the first one positive second negative
false positive etcetera
you know binary sequence
there are two to the two m possibles
but actually a function class
of VC dimension you know lopez dimension will actually exhibit much fewer than
actually a polynomial number in that case so that's that number
OK and
you don't you know you don't actually need to calculate the numbers just there to
get the band you see i mean you need to calculate if you need to
think about actually you know enumerating in any sense
so then this symmetrisation trick which is basically just formalising that intuition that it's weird
that the
errors all in the second half
i should say that you know i've i've treated the zero error case but you
can imagine here
if this was a low error
in the first half and high area in the second half you could apply the
same argument is weird that so many more errors in the second half the first
and you could you know about the probability of that happening by random mutation and
that's exactly you know what to do for the the non-zero error case and so
this formalizes that in symmetrisation and and we can see that there is actually to
to the EM permutations and to to the probability of actually putting those guys in
the wrong half is to the mindset slonim over two
it's this number here
and just putting all together gives us this this bound
so that was the the sort of standard VC bound
and this was the corresponding lower bound which sort of made this
slightly nervous because we
i feel that
some sort of implies that things are
closed out the that's that's it you know characterization mathematically is is finished
and this was the result you get if you consider the non zero error so
if you make k errors on the first half
you wouldn't expect to make more than this number
are on the on the in the test
are you know test probability
yes strictly speaking the non-zero case treats the zero error but i haven't seen anyone
overpressure here
for your lungs
and the water is one atmosphere of pressure
here is one atmosphere
barometric pressure
was one of the few high static pressure plus the barometric pressure
you have to have this
research which forced on chest
inside your lungs one atmosphere
outside these two atmospheres
and there's no way
that you could break
the area of my chest is some thirty by thirty centimeters with thousand square centimeters
it would be like having a hundred kilogram weight on my chest and also on
my back and forth
in both directions which is like this
and pushes like this and like this and like this
really being squeezed that
so what do you do when you go scuba diving
repression of a which
thank you
and that your brain
so now with depression there
you can obviously counter
the hydrophilic pressure
the water
now suppose
we go snorkeling
the difference
then we do have a little too
you know
and we store
how do you think we could work
are ones could easily accommodate
i that pressure
and the idea
i think we could snorkel maybe three years
all things we could easily do three new
how things
maybe only one meter
well things
well less than one
you know it's not way less because no because that long so you know you
can at least thirty centimetres can be what that much less
we can measure
how did we could snorkel
and we can measure
what the capacity capabilities
of the are in order to counter
i just added pressure
if i'm underwater there is pressure on my chest
so too
let the air out is easy
just screen right that goes out
but in order to inhale
so in the air
i would have to
push out my chest
voice that counters
the force
and so the question is
what kind of pressure could generate
with my lungs
it added pressure
and we are going to measure that they
which an instrument that we call an anomaly
it's a simple to
could be made of anything less two find
and we have liquid in here
open year
it is open here
put my mouth here
i'm going to see
how much of pressure
i can
using my lungs by pushing by blowing
so i'm going to blow in a year
and then this level will go down
and this level will go up
this height difference
let's call the age
and the density of the fluid
we'll use water for that call it what it
the pressure here
y one
because the one
depression here
y two
of the two
so p one
minus b two
times age
i apply
the law that we still have a few one minus two
all times age
i've seen
i know that the
two level is
one atmosphere
that's correct
one atmosphere that often
the world
so p one
because one atmosphere
was rho h
so what my my to indicate
how much pressure i can generate
over and above the one atmosphere
and we call that overpressure often work with over pressure gauges when you go to
gas station and you have pressures
measure the pressure in your tires is also
o gauge which measures the overpressure
right there
we have such an knowledge there
i'm going to blow it here
and that's going to tell us immediately how deep i can snorkel
if i was able
to make this high difference
ten metres
then i could
snorkel and the depth of ten metres in the water
because it means that i could generate an over pressure of one atmosphere
this would only be five metres then i could only snorkel down to five metres
this is only
said one meter
and i could really only confidently brave
one meter below
the surface
that's what you see here
and i want you to
and here
and he
you have
so what we do
and you can use
i mean
in any event
you can be a
in the
you know
we can
i mean
at all
less than one mile one
how do you
he always
and then be to
so you need
OK at the last
well one way
one one three
and the graph is like this
graph laplacian you can just basically think of it as the adjacency matrix is very
similar to the adjacency matrix of the graph
so it's some matrix and the key property of this matrix
let me just reiterate if the following that this quantity so when i some
my so if i have a function on the graph i want to check whether
the function is small and when i sum of all adjacent vertices
i get something which is small that's the nicest most function so i only from
about adjacent vertices i don't care about sources which are far so for this graph
in particular described
and this is the same as f transpose l
OK so
now what do we do
and again if this
we have some points
this is our point cloud this maybe
the ones and nines
we connect points which are close together in some sense
and this can be epsilon ball that can be nearest neighbours nearest neighbour seem to
work well
and then you put it this way
on the
and then you construct lot
now let's proceed with
semi supervised learning
what is the problem now of semi supervised learning
you have day labelled data x i y i
and a
i assume that this simple from some high dimensional space so this may be images
and image is represented by its pixel greyscale that's a pixel wireless
and then there are some outputs which may be minus one and one for example
for classification or real number for regression
and plus the unlabelled data
unlabelled data if the a bunch of point a bunch of say images
but they have no choice
so we would like to use this
purposes of our
inference so we would like to construct a function which takes
the labelled data center
and unlabelled data sets
and construct some sort of output which will predict new point
OK so this is again a reminder
so i will be working in the kernel framework and this is
in there for support vector machines regularizes so this is the square put hinge loss
here for support vector versions you have fit to the data
rkhs penalty which somehow controls how much the function calls so you have fit to
the data plus most of
and the penalty is what we're going to change
the panel to somehow incorporate else most this assumption about today
so as standard algorithm and again i'm just repeating this very quickly you do this
you can you have to represent the same so you get the solution in terms
of kernels of you labeled points
and fully squares you can compute it by matrix inversion for SVM the quadratic programming
so you compute alpha cen this is function
so here is the example i have for more examples later but here is a
very basic for example
this is the support vector machine classifier
it just
separate this point
this school it knows nothing about unlabelled data of course so it cannot
this is not necessarily a very good classifier because somehow
this unlabelled data doing something
to change your perception about where the boundary so you might want to
the is some of the boundary
and here is what you get was
the with this modified algorithm basically depending on the value of parameters to control how
the geometry of the data affected by
so you have this extra nor
which allows you to to torn up
so when of unlabelled data
and then i will explain what the
so now
so this is
the first the
framework called manifold regularisation
so it's basically the same thing as before with the coral what the differences
we now want to say we actually want our function not just a small everywhere
this term here the chance that a single
function doesn't make mistake is actually not so small it's one over the number of
e to the log f is one over
so what we get is that actually it's quite likely that one of these that
functions will be there and will soil
why because each one has like one or have chance of filing as after them
so it's actually
quite reasonable that one of them will fire less and will pick one of the
bad functions instead of this great function
and we'll get air
about log f over
and that's what we saw in the online setting so we're starting already to get
was starting already taken a sense that the online setting is a bit like batch
and this is something that there is a lot of research in the online setting
of research in the best the thing and there's been many times everyone in this
area is kind of observing that very similar
but but today i'm going to show you way in which they are actually the
OK so
let's not just
go over what happens to the naive algorithm the batch algorithm which is very simple
you take an examples and now let's look at it in a noisy setting or
not and i said with there's no perfect function why should we sing perfectly so
we just choose the function that minimizes the error on the
i don't know i don't think it's quite we're through with me to go through
the analysis but let me just tell you the punchline
the point is that the regret
in expectation of this naive batch learning algorithm on the distribution mill
is going to be
something like one over the square root of n
and what's the intuition behind them
it's if you flip a coin n times
you can expect to get about another two heads
you probably get like and over two plus some something which depends on the standard
deviation which is actually one of them you probably get like and over two plus
and minus one of the n
so now we have this we have a bunch of functions we functions were measuring
the area of each one in the dataset each one's estimate of variance is pretty
but actually there will be some that that are
some that are ranked too high and some that are into low
and it turns out that when you have f of you can expect some of
them to be off by as much as this term
this is
so this is kind of what you expect in the back setting when you just
use this very simple algorithm in these things are similar to what you see in
the analysis of VC dimension
here's is the analysis of why that's the case but i think i'll skip
OK so now let me show you an online algorithm that's kind of nice very
famous algorithm
i'm going to start with a slightly modified version that simply so the weighted majority
i because when israeli prime houses this algorithm working online setting again we're not assuming
now that the data is perfect is have
this data and these functions and you trying to do as well as the best
so the algorithm just assign a weight to each one of the functions
for each function we start with its weight being one
in each period we're going to just predict according to
the majority of the functions but now we're going to take a weighted majority because
each function has always associated to
and then what are we gonna do how we can update the weights we're going
divide the weight of every function areas by two so we have the weights of
all the guys together and wrong cut
actually this point you might be wondering why don't we just take the function that
does the best so far
on the data
that's much more intuitive right if you're living in online worlds baby you get a
bunch of examples
why not just you know if you considering a bunch of candidate functions when i
take the function that is the best
at least theoretically and in many cases especially in game play six games
nine cases that's not going to work so i'll give you an example of a
real world example is kind of like when you're driving on the road
and you have two lanes and you have to decide which lead to go on
don't you always feel like you turn into the lane
that stops see you on the highway in one of the lines advancing the other
one isn't so imagine a situation where you have two choices and you have to
choose between them
and you just take the one that did the best so far
so in that case
let's say one of them does well on the other one as well and the
first one does well in the second alternate how well they do it
and you take the one that's the the best so far
if you just so unlucky that there really alternating which one is doing better
you're always going to go to the one that's about to get stuck
you're going to go to the to the lane that's not gonna that's going to
keep moving back and forth and you actually get make any progress
o thing
and that's what happens right when you try to strategy you just just keep changing
lanes to get into better life
and the same thing can happen in the case of learning we have a bunch
of functions and you're trying
but this is a rare
a reduction
in very simple
not separable
this reduction
can be applied to show
you start from an ongoing has the mistake bound or lot about
four in the separable case
reduce any nonseparable
OK so that was used in general nonseparable case the separable
so basically you can
with no way for you can
did you can derive bound that is the version of the parable is the modification
of the separable but will hold in general purpose
it because the perceptron algorithm remains the same
you have a you have about the perceptron in the separable case and turn it
into a ball in the separable case
which is different but the argument
for this one year
the other which which is slightly and then we show how
this technique was introduced first by class number class now
and has has already been on
ninety five
and your friend roberta theory
in the discovery gain a few years later four years later
to prove
another version of the of the general board
you might think it to the perceptron you don't get the bound showed before
you get about that involves the square the squares of the input
and so if the different about
but there is a bounded
the same goes for the
and now i'm showing you will be studied
OK what the so
OK let's look at the
yeah i agree
the algorithm makes an update
we get this
we take it as an arbitrary
not linearly separable
and we fix the samuel
and you guys
and now we know that you will have some on each example has some loss
and we do not help you put his loss of you on what
so now we
so next time constants
the figure on the right hand
we see that the total we take the stream and we just put it into
a different frame that would be parable by u
so this transformation this mapping is done in that if one we observed by dr
and we have to show that this is actually true
so we redefined the stream so that it is linearly separable
with a large margin but you
it we take every example x and we might be all x b prime
so a prime would be a vector
it was first the components of the components of xty
and then we are adding component
all the wrong
up to what he called for the people
last component
which would be
one of our squirrel pups
so this is the component that he
and then we feel out with zero
up to to the
the plastic
so this vector now using this space which is
as people have been become boring
would be the the the length of the string so we have at dimensions
one-dimensional bridge back
for example in the
OK here
but it's one of these guys will have but in the experiments that would be
all zero but the one that will be
that's that
now we do similar thing for you
your prime
you prime is the mapping of u
which is
the the following types
it's a game that the first component of the components of u
and then we feel
components of the former square root of c
l one
l one is one of the
so this is the hinge loss of u on the first example
we're about see
l two
up to the root of c
again this guy
with be the with either in the article that must be
thank you
but think easy checked that
you prime achieves
has zero involved
on the same for the primal scream
with the brain and this is
seen as follows
so if you look at on a generic example why the new prime
x b prime
we want to check for any this is bigger than one
but this is what this is why we
now if you
in the
and then i have
x being
so these are the
first the components of new prime in the first component next prime
then we have just the one non-zero component connected prime
which is the one associated with the people of the
but this is going to be
of one over the
and this will multiply
plus component over here
which is square root of c and
OK so we have y
x anywhere else
which we can write so if healthy zero then we know that this mountain is
already because then one if there is no zero then it can be written as
plus one minus y u
x t
which is a set of objects we're talking about
so that's the set
so nonempty set
don't talk about the the empty universe
it is a boring place
we take the universe to be not empty which is not very extravagant assumptions
and we want to take thing that's come
that's got objects inside it
and we want to be able to do things we want to be able to
name objects
so we suppose that in a in our language we've got some sort of names
robin ince things like
kevin rudd whatever
proper names
picking out things
and it's not enough just to be able to name them we want to be
able to say things about the
so we want to be able to form some
assertions such statements some sentences
therefore we need some way of getting from names
to sentences
what we need is some predicates
well we assume that we're dealing with a language that has pretty kids
is some expression
into which you can plug names
and it
OK so
the type of the predicates
it takes
names possibly
possibly all bunch of names
and gives you
a sentence
so if i have names like a camera
sydney golden
you might predicates like
is a city
into which you can put one of those names and get the sentence
is larger than
in two which you can put two names and get things like canberra is larger
than sydney which is false
sydney is larger than golden which is true
by plugging into names
you get a sentence
we assume that we can
at atomic
in that way
that doesn't yet give us a lot of logic
what we need to be able to do
this put those atoms together to get molecular
will exhibit some regular behaviour
we go into is from here
first of all we had
we assume well we assume we dealing with a language with some connectives in
these are
apply to
to form
longer sentences
so the things of type sentence to sentence or sentence sentence to sentence
and natural languages have lots of connectives in everybody's favourite connective is and
as all the others are a bit
unruly but and is
what the
this takes two sentences and forms along sentence
or as the logicians say it is not the case that
which takes one sentence and forms along sentence
that says the opposite
which takes
sentence and forms along sentence that says that the first
could be the case
john believes
OK which is again
one place
you put in a sentence here
express some proposition
and you get out along a longer sentence
the truth value of the long sentence in that case is not very interesting really
i've been noticing you around and this i find you very attractive
would you go with me tonight would you come over to my apartment and i
would you got the bed of me tonight
experiment you wouldn't think anybody would have done has been done in women
about the two very attractive man over half of the women approach
so yeah i will
very few agreed this and nobody agrees to this
four men
but there are like this
they got that
in this study
twenty five percent of males
who said no i apologize profusely this at all you know my feelings in town
until you
what about behavior
you know if interested in sex differences
you can actually
figure out what people want male-female differences by looking at simply the the average number
of times people have sex
it male and females have different priorities than heterosexual sex is a compromise
between two groups of people of competing interests
what's more clear reflection and is gay sex
between women between two women are between two men
because then you get pure reflection
of sexual desire
the data tend to be very messy again to survey studies
but by and large we study done tends to find the difference in the expected
direction which is that females tend to be lesbians tend to be much more monogamous
then game
some studies prior to that prior to AIDS
so many years ago
i found came into to be extremely promiscuous often having over one hundred over thousand
partners you wouldn't find this sort of promiscuity in
in females and the way to think about this is what is gay men are
doing is exactly what you average heterosexual men would do
if he had that degree of willing females were is willing as he was
and this all suggested or some sort of different along lines expected
in sexual choosing in humans
what about
sexual attractiveness
what about make preference what we find attractive
unlike the choosing to study here we actually have some pretty good cross-cultural data
so one study for instance was done
in ten thousand people
from thirty seven countries
ask people who want
we want to be one
and there's different studies some of them who do you want to marry her other
studies one as of may twenty one is the sexual partners
and one main finding is
kind reassuring
everybody likes kindness and intelligence
or everybody says like kindness and intelligence
these are value pretty highly
but at the same time there are sex differences
on females
focus more on power and status
and more on interest investing in children and think about that from an evolutionary point
of view it makes sense it doesn't matter hugely
from the standpoint of reproduction
how old the matters
the difference between fifteen and twenty five thirty five forty five matteral offer status in
the community physical strength is lifespan but from the standpoint of the sperm it doesn't
matter hugely
later on this drop off
and it does begin to matter but doesn't matter hugely
what does matter is interesting being a good father
in protecting u
from predation from murder
from assault by other people and in taking care of the kids
women's brains are wired up to five males those properties similar
focus little bit differently they're more interested
in all of these things but also inability to have children
so from an evolutionary point of view there's actually a very big difference between a
twenty year-old and a fifty year-old
from a male standpoint looking at the female because the one can have offspring another
so this is the difference
what i want to focus more on right now
is back to another similarity
everybody likes beauty
and i want to devote a little bit of this lecture to talking about physical
physical beauty
as these beautiful people say
is the curse
so she's she's like a big models supermodels
in the super super model
points out the arbitrariness
of finding her devastatingly beautiful
famous actor points enough respirators
people only
ignore his accomplishments and focus merely on its physical beauty
the very first
so what is really what does this mean when we say we find we you
we really are very attractive people
what is it about that makes you look and say yes that makes sense
we kind of know that we know some universals
beauty seems to signal two things
you're using signal u
i mean not preschool
but but
because the
the cause effect relation
this is the more
many things
the last major applications in the future
this is a lot of plants
the only forty seven today so thanks for coming so what are we talking about
is how to detect the virus outbreaks in networks effectively so what we will be
thinking about is how do things spread over the network so for example here i
OK here this would be for example this is a network of how people recommended
DVD sufficient to each other and this this the second one is a network of
how some disease i think spread over the social network so what what should be
sure what should be thinking about so diffusion or some kind of propagation social network
is one of the fundamental processes and basically the idea is that we have some
behaviors something
so that the spreads through the network so this could be like new spreading over
the network or like all through the social network or fans or urban legends or
some kind of what the mouth effects or diseases can also spread widely like flu
and so on so this is this is our setting and there has been many
empirical studies about this diffusion in social networks and the two most or the one
of the first two are the slalom the spread of new agricultural practices where they
were asking far machine highlighting i think how they were adopting this new kind of
gordon's seed and then the second and basically what would be conclusion was that diffusion
is a social process so basically this adoption of a new type of seed was
was was a social process through like discussion so far as to each other in
sort of decided that they would try out this new and something similar was then
for the spread of new medical practices where the idea was that
again they were studying how the adoption of a new antibiotic was done between the
doctors and again it was the social power of peers that's all sort of made
some some youth orchestra start describing this
this the this new new vaccine so more precisely what do i mean right so
when i say diffusion what i mean is that what i mean by that is
that we are giving some kind of social network we have some set of initially
active loads and now nodes sort of go and in fact
the nodes and these and these are behavior
propagates through the network and more precisely what we will be
talking about today's is given a city water distribution network right so these are the
houses and there are pipes like physical pipes through which water flows
and what we are interested in is if there would be some kind of contamination
start because one particular note this contamination spreads through the network right and what is
our goal is to
four percent of some of the nodes so that whenever this contamination starts
and started spreading around
we detect it as quickly as possible and when i mean by that
i mean we will raise an alarm and say hey there is infection or some
kind of disease spreading through the network
and the raise the flag and the question is when should we place sensors to
detect this kind of outbreaks as effectively as possible or a second scenario
that will cover comes from this online media
the idea is that if we have if we have some blog
the that talks about something than other people who refer to it so they cited
so this information spreads through the blogosphere right and the question is which blogs
should we need to detect these stories as quickly as possible so to be most
up to date which which are the influential bloggers blogs that captures the most important
story so
more generally
what what what what we want to be talking about is that we are given
on the any process that spread through the network and we want to select a
set of nodes to detect this process effectively and i will go into more details
what effective means on the next slides and you can imagine that this is like
a very general formulation of the problem that has many different applications right in epidemics
and we want to know which people wanted to detect the
disease outbreak as as quickly as possible in network security again you would like to
select the set of machines that i know you want to very closely monitored to
detect that some something wrong is going on in your network so so
that is
could be i don't know how much
this cascading is going on because i was heavily rely on the problem structure so
now i start talking about what is what is what is like seemingly unrelated things
what they have in common and you know what we have is like we have
the reward and we have the cost right the reward mean some function that you're
trying to optimise so for example in the water distribution scenario you for example you
you may want to minimize time to detection rate whatever intrusion happens just want to
detect this is detected as quickly as possible i know in the fewest number of
hours possible then for example you may want to maximize the number of the active
contaminations which would mean you just want to detect these contaminations
as they happen so you don't get whole i just want to say oh that
now are
this the
so here is an example that we studied and others studied a number of times
over time series that is inversely related to
northern hemispheric temperatures global temperatures
going back from now over the last two-and-a-half million years
and you can see some periodicities in there that are well known
simply related to the earth orbital dynamics
they have a major influence on on
on climate including me ice-age cycles various kinds that really other keep pieces this data
so when one
it's a state space model
and the state space model here is a trend
a locally varying trend and here's an estimate of the trend
temperatures are increasing over the two-and-a-half million years
anda twenty dimensional signal that simply a represent an empirical representation the signal is no
attempt to model specific components
at different frequencies is just an encompassing model
and then of course measurement error
this is an extraction all of components using this decomposition theory
just three or four the components so that in terms of error
the wavelengths coming down
and all on the same scale so you see the relative contribution
that they give
after the overall data as a result
and if you look at posterior distributions for wavelengths you'll see that they lived in
the they cover the range is a v
a thought orbital dynamic periodicities that theoretically
well known
this is the data with the trend simply superimposed let's look at this picture
what we have here is is an investigation of the wavelengths over time this is
a time varying models so each of these is a quasiperiodic process with a time-varying
well in fact they look pretty stable
the colour-coded to correspond
they look pretty stable
but at this time point and there's a faint dashed line it about one point one million years here
there's a funny switch what happened there is that
at that time point there was a
an inversion of the dominance in terms of the estimated amplitudes between the first two components
this is a nice example of the use of these models
that's another nice example
and this fit in in the early nineties to the conversations that were going about changes in ice-age cycles
and whether there were a discrete events about one point one million years ago
in the overall dynamics
a virus
somehow ruptured
these cycles and simply change the patterns that
been evident before and you see that in these components you see
they greater amplitude is then much less predictable
after this particular time point
whereas this component goes goes through a few
a few thousand years interesting behavior but becomes the dominant way wasteful there's no change
modeling there's no intervention modeling there's no mixture modeling it simply comes out the slowly
varying nature
a that parameters
that these models
have built inside
second example context and this has been
very well explored over the last several years very active area current eiji studies in other areas of the neuropsychiatry
so here we've got
electrical fluctuation measurements only
on a one point on the scalp a patient undergoing treatment forever
at about
undergoing a brain seizure that's been induced on the various
to understand response to electroconvulsive therapy
and this is a really nice example of a
why these this particular class of models that just exemplified in thee any oxygen isotope data are a really
very widely used
so in the early part of this is is very high
amplitude fluctuations
whatever wavelength is implied by the red one
and as you go through time this is your changes certainly amplitude is very variable
and its tailing offices caesareans ends over here
but you'll see
the same
temperature going to fit into this equation i don't see any temperature terms
temperature must be buried in the rate constant and that's what we're going to go
to look inside the rate constant so will increase yield
temperature and that was known for
many many years but it was finally
the swedish
chemist arrhenius
one eighteen eighty nine
announced a relationship that bears his name when he found was that the relationship between
the specific rate constant and temperature was exponential through an equation of this form
exponential of the ratio of some energy which he termed the activation energy
divided by the product of the boltzmann constant temperature and pre exponential factor which we
write as a in order of arrhenius
or in another way
right in this manner a e to the minus
e over cables TV so there's the relationship and another way of showing it is
to put on a semi log plot if you plot the natural logarithm of the
rate constant
the function of the reciprocal
of the absolute temperature
you'll find according to this equation
you should get a straight line
one over t is increasing from left to right so high temperature is
on the left side and they should be linear with this slope of
i minus e eight which is the activation energy
divided by
the boltzmann constant and just to give you a sense of order of magnitude the
activation energy for typical
chemical reactions is on the order of about one electron volt which is on the
order of about one hundred kila jules
per mole
so if you take this and choose an arbitrary rate for room temperature
plug in the value of one hundred kila joules per mole which you can show
yourself is that with this activation energy you
o double
double the rate
double the rate for every ten degrees
rise above temperature obviously this breaks down for large
excursions in temperature but in the vicinity of room temperature
if you have an activation energy of typically of about one electron volt you can
expect to double
for every
ten degree so what's the physical meaning of activation energy what i try to show
it to you in terms of a mechanical analog so
what going do here is show you
what we can say is going to be used a loudspeaker
so loudspeaker and what i've done by putting the axon on the loudspeaker at the
the intersection of the x will say that that's the centre of mass of the
so speaker is now in a gravitational field and we can argue that i can
represent this as a point
zero dimension at this hypothesis table
now clearly phili this on its side
the point has fallen
so it's now to lower gravitational potential
really if the box that's where the box for line side so how can the
box doesn't just
following side why doesn't the box just line of sight since the decrease in energy
when i do that
you see the photo
i will it's absorbed now
looking to go see
OK so why does the box fall inside
well this is the box is zero kelvin
so now let's put the box at room temperature so what's happening at room temperature
the boxes doing this room temperature
but even so the box on the side
because in order for the box in free space to go from the vertical upright
and locked position to the supine position what must the box do
the box must first rise up on one corner
only one rises up on one corner gets to discuss
does it have the ability to fall freely
so what we're looking at in terms of gravitational potential is activation so i can
give you the same thing i could plot this as the extent of reaction
extent of reaction
and some energy relative to gravitational potential on the ordnance
and i got three positions here i've got the box
in the vertical position i got the box in horizontal position and clearly
there's a decrease in energy right this
this change is the delta p of the reaction
but the box can get to the right position from the left position without first
rising up on its side
it must at some point rise up on its side and when it rises up
on its side it's
centre of mass has risen and this energy is the activation energy
right hand side
I just cooked it up by adding this 1 this 1
now what's the solution with this the right answer
the solution but there's no right hand side is clear it talks now I took
1 of the these
1 of the and none of those so so actually just changed around like this
when I took this new right
so that in the in the role picture I have 3 different planes
3 3 3 new planes beating now at this point in the column picture I
have the same 3 columns but not all
and combining them to produce this guy and it turned out that column 1 was
column 2 which would be somewhere there
there is the right column
1 of this and 1 and this would give me that the new
OK so that's like we squeezed in extra examples but
now think about all
all right hand side
could I get cannot solve these equations for every right-hand side
and it can I say that that's the question so that's the algebra questions
can I solve a x equals b for everybody
but the write that down
can solve
for every
right hand side it up I mean is there a solution
if there is
elimination will give me a way to find understood I really wanted to ask is
there a solution
for every right-hand side
so now can I put that in different words
In this linear combination words so in linear combination words due
linear combinations of the columns
three-dimensional space but everybody
means all of these in three dimensional space
so that that juicy that I'm just asking the same question in in different words
solving a x 0 that's very important
a times X 1 and multiplier
and matrix by a vector
I get a combination of the columns of the old right that
down it in a moment
so that it could use it but in my column picture that's really what I'm
doing and taking linear combinations of these 3 columns
and I'm trying to find
and actually the answer for this matrix will be yet
for this matrix for this for this matrix A for these columns
the answer is
of about
up but yes but other
this matrix is that there is this matrix that that the I shows for an
a good matrix nonsingular matrix an invertible matrix of those would be the matrices that
we like
there could be other
and we will see other matrices
where they answer becomes no
all actually you can see when would become known of the could
what what could go wrong
how could go wrong that out of these out of 3 columns
and all their combinations
when and when I'm not being able to produce
the software
when when could go wrong
do you see that the combinations it's supposed to be say goes
if these 3 columns all why in the same plane
then their combinations will lie
in that same point
sold then we're in trouble if the 3 columns of matrix
if those 3 vectors happen lie in the same plane
for example if column 3 is just the sum of column 1 and column 2
I would be in trouble
that would be a matrix A where the answer would be no
the combinations
if column 3 years in the same place this column 1 and 2 I don't
get the know from that all the combinations of in the planes
and the work on the right hand side is the that I could get it
would be the ones at that point
so what I could solve for some right-hand side
when b is in the in the planes but most
right hand sides would be out of the plane and unreachable
so that would be singular
matrix would be not invertible there would not be a solution for every be the
answer would become known for them
I don't know if it so we take just a little shot thinking about
9 dimensions
imagine that we have
vectors with 9 components
it can be hard to visualize those
I don't pretend to do it but somehow
pretending to
that pretend we have if this was 9 equations in 9 unknowns then we would
have columns
and each 1 would be a vector in 9 dimensional space and we would be
looking at their linear combination
so what we really having the linear combinations of 9 vectors in high-dimensional space and
we would be trying to find the combination that hit the correct right hand side
and we might also ask the questions
can we always do it