i'm going to encode u one
zero zero zero
so we send
passing the clear one zero zero zero
and then we can send three more bits afterwards
and those bits are determined by writing one
zero zero
zero in order
and then
we find the parity in this article
which is
one and we put a one there so that the total parity is even
put zero here
one there
we read them out in the right order one zero one
thank you
that's being oder
let's do
one more example
one one one zero
so long
one one zero
parity in here
three so far it is also put another one that's even
and this is even already right here
and this is even so he write zero
so that's encouraged to one one one zero
followed by
one zero zero
that's the encoder
and we need a decoder for ourselves
just at the repetition code for the decoder
is going to be
the decoder that spits out a guess
the defectors
transmission sorry with spit at best whose transmission ti events differs from what we received in as few
flips as possible
black cat
so the general idea is
estimate of
is you are given a
thanks to an overview of and this likelihood
term here favoured
where we had the fewest conflicts
so we want decoder that comes up with a hypothesis that involves the smallest number of flips
and we'll be that's
by writing what we receive into the same diagram that we
created over there
so we're going to write them in the same order
are one
and therefore
and ah five
and seven
now because the noises come along and could afflict anything
this article could be
any vector tall
and it may not satisfy these rules that we had over here the rule being
that the parity in each circle should be even
and what we're going to do is identify
which those rules are satisfied and which are not satisfied
and were then reduced at
to identify
which bits we think being flipped
anything could happen
let's imagine that we send the signal this transmission
let's imagine
along the way
is received
so what we receive
one one zero zero one zero one
i have a markov random field defined on the chain
and now
i want to compute p of x one
just the marginal probability i have the joint the joint is given by this factorisation
joint is given by him to play for you
so here it is
i want to compute this thing
so how to compute the marginal probability is sum over all the other variables are
perceived as saw the marginalisation in to compute the sum from x two to x
of these ones
now i'm going to use the distributive law
so what's the idea
conservative law
whenever you have
in the bunch of some
you just pull that fact out of those
so basically what this means is that these sums are from x two to x
in but each factor here involves only two viable
so you don't really want to keep all these factors in XML
smart if you just keep this factor here because all the other factors not involved
you know the viable XML
that yes no the viable they don't have all the viable here
so basically what we're doing is pulling
most common factors or if you want to think in another
i mean we are pushing these sums as far as
they can go in the set until the heat
a factor
which has
viable with the same index is that we are some
OK i cannot push some forward because there's too he cannot push this forward because
there's three here
and so on
and when you're doing that we are exactly using the distributive law
and then i will point out the paper that they just for you yesterday again
the generalized distributive law
the search for it
and you be able to have a nice oil on the distributive law
so what's the difference of
obviously if you just compute this thing here naively
you have an exponential complexity on the state space of everybody
but if you compute these things well
we need to solve these here
which for every
and for every n minus one because you will need
the for everyman one well is quadratic
then you will think just
in minus one here
and then this function is multiplied
another quantity
and then you keep on going in basically you at the end of the day
you have these quadratic complexity
the number of factors
but you need to
you know
take into account so basically
but you really have this
is a number of factors the complexity basically
in this case is given by
just the product of four
number effect
what is important in these
computation here
is that set is not the function of x
it's a constant
it is a function
o of any parameter that i have in my models
but it's not the function of x because
if you remember
you have the factorisation of
for markov random field to have a product over all cliques of some function of
the viability and clique
and you have a normalisation constant one
well z
here z here
must be such that
when you some these things before
in all acts you get one
so these
so need to sum this thing here
that's not true
how are you doing this how are you dealing with an underdetermined system you're doing
it with uncertainty again so the answerphone determine an underdetermined systems is to use uncertainty
before we didn't know what the noise was so we put up
in fact prior over the noise
you could think about has it seems a likelihood but it's a distribution and the noise
he was putting a prior over the parameters
now point i i can finish but just a summarise my last point is i
do think about distribution reporting over the noise as an aspect model i do think
of this prior i'm putting over
they on
parameters as the aspect model and i don't really believe in the separation between likelihood
and prior that most people like to talk about i think this is just a
and it's all dealing with the same thing uncertainty in my parameters there is uncertainty in my noise level
there's a model mismatch that's separation between likelihood and prior ones about model mismatch ones
about dealing with uncertainty in the model but classically people don't see it like
so you deal with these
underdetermined system
we prize overrun europe
parameters just as you dealt with the overdetermined systems with distributions over
the mismatch between your data and what the model says
and there
just ask if there's any questions from around
any more questions
i mean actually is a good thing i've
i'm happy to listen bits if anyone because i it's a lot of things which
you know not everyone believes and that's fine you know you can disagree so if
you think anything i said is wrong
i'm very happy to hear
uh your comments or thoughts about anything i've said
that i'm sorry you got it
you mean uh bayesian decision theory
what is it isn't because you've already messed up
because it's fine if you're if you're probabilities are well calibrated about what's going on in the system
if you probabilities are well calibrated you're then dealing with
a broken estimate
you know the that's bayesian decision theory assumes you've got the right probability
and if you have the wrong model you don't have the right probabilities
and i think that these the right solution is probably to have kind kinda formalism includes
the cost of inference in with thee inference process but i don't know what the formalism is people do
chris holmes recently talked about it
i don't think it helps optimal decision theory it's like the other side of the
coin now i've got the probabilities i should make the right decision
you more
no because my my brain is not big enough
so the question was can i add more flexibility and zoubin radford neal can
well and i think also if you start dealing with something as complex as speech recognition
production process for speech recognition
generate a generative process you want to do inference on the complexity of your model is immense
very very difficult to deal with
you are
the room
okay gas so that the question was a guassian process with an obvious give you
all the small variance schedule flexibility one
so probably you can show that guassian process and obvious can will for any function in the limit data
but i mean one of the questions about when i talked about casting process is
what happens when two data points are very are on top of each other
but the extension to that's what happens when two data points are very close together
and you're right that if u i have so much data
i mean it's the wrong model there is no i mean
and i should astonishment like if you're right if you got so much data
but you can see
and this is like this is a frequentist thing not bayesian thing because the model
is wrong so let's say that you know your data overall is doing now but
was helpful i can't like you can always added to the hyperparameters
that you're you know exploring over even both use so you could have
the sum of the regularization with its own weight loss l
one regularization with its own weight but
this ten like all compared to say tuning like the number of hidden
units or the learning rate there's much as benefit you will
observe in tuning regularization weight
so to start with our almost advised not even considering one
and l two regularization and use early stopping that's going to
be most of the job yes for the
yeah if you looking at the weights later on looking at filters
stuff can make the filters look nicer but that's a quite superficial
reason for using
no the book is but you stopping and dropout
as that for the yes
yeah so the question is whether you should just use the last
values of the weights the training
or somehow think of the whole trajectory of weights
during training somehow combine that together so
as there's the method of pull the averaging which does something
like this that put acc ridging is essentially
you keep track of a running average of all the weights
as you try and i know in some situations it's actually not
like commonly used by def aware of its cases where it
what perform much better i think there's
i can only assume there is actually theory showing that so should
situations get even faster convergence
assuming doing pull the averaging at the end
it's not it's not use a whole lot but but it is a good idea and
yeah it could be helpful
so that's on the set of bat trick to consider using yeah
other questions
so the question is you know sometimes you would observe that
the validation set performance might tend to stay flat maybe will
increase another whole lot and are cases where like will
go up very quickly i think it's essentially a function of how much
capacity your underlying model has how quickly essentially the difference
between these two curves is going to increase
i have a better characterization of the relationship
between that then the things about your model
yeah yeah that that is true yes so just mentioning
that possibly if validation set performance slat maybe it's just
because your optimization is actually barely progressing and maybe
and the plateau or something like that that's a good point that
might be evidence for that unless your training error is actually
still going down like substantially then something else
must yet play
right move yes yeah
ok so so so is your question is why is dropout
right so i guess the question is like
to know why yeah i guess the reason why yeah strong advocate for
and if
the vector sum
of the
of the orthogonal complement of s in the absence of differential is closed back the
sounds of closed sets are not necessarily closed
but if in indeed they are close then you have
strong duality
and the there's a special case this was an interesting special cases here we assume
that each one of these have either
real that
boys polyhedral or it's essentially one-dimensional depends on only one value or domain is one-dimensional
then you have to to study was a star
and then there is that this is the dual statement
the point i want to make here is not so much the details of this
but rather that there are strong conditions
and that guarantees strong duality
and that
in order now you can expect that it's rare that you would not have duality
between two strong duality between the two problems
the more interesting conditions for our purposes are necessary and sufficient condition for optimality
this condition says that x thought and lifestyle is an optimal primal and dual solutions
if and only if
they both feasible
the lies are slopes
at the axis
of the corresponding components
and these are symmetric condition
where this is inverted by the by subgradient one
to give this
so for the dual DMP you get this
but these two conditions have the same problem
now our algorithm is going to be explained this condition
we're going to be getting feasible axis and enwise but we're going to be trying
to enforce
subgradient condition by adding more and more by defining the approach to politics approximations
so let me format another linear decision i have defined already in
another linear position of the function f
it is defined by a finite set
is the finite set of dual points
a finite set y
i use lower bar for
linear station
and the maximum over this linear functions here where x and y
the points of contact of f one y is a subgradient
what i then remember this definition is easier to remember a picture
we have
capital why
is a finite number of slopes we fit those slopes to the graph of the
function take the maximum and we obtain the other administration
know that natural innovation is always real valued doesn't have infinity
an innovation is similarly defined
for a given function
we consider a finite set of breakpoints
we consider this phrase
take the convex hull
it defines
a function f over bar
and that's the
in the linearisation corresponding to this finite set
all breakpoints the finance this that the point here that x
and there's some more complicated definition in terms of the convex hull but
when we're going to skip
here's the output from
we have the extended model programs
and we partition the in this is
the blue investors are going to be out o linear i
green in this is are going to be in the eyes
and what's left is going to be left untouched
at the second iteration
we have
blue out the linear decision but is a finite set of wise
i'm out of line and then in a linear decision agreeing linear decision
defined by corresponding breakpoint sets for each a in this index
and now we consider the
forty hill approximation to this problem defined by the blue approximations the green approximation
we solve this problem
find the next happen why can't that optimally do appear
and now we large
so that x and y by differentiation
for each blue set
strategy you give demonstrations of
all the whole
CR two
so we should be
i learn
wikipedia is talked about that i'm not sure if he
preceding that right now
but i haven't been involved in
i see yes
yes you right so that's actually examine explains so simulators on rewriting if simulators that's
great and we do do a fair amount of training simulators one the lessons to
that there was pretty surprising to me was for many problems to work on
how hard is to get at later so i wonder how many of my sons
and i really wants to me at this point what the whole hearts quite a
long time and we were genuinely highly motivated to get the best simulator that we
could for helicopter and were published papers showing you about the the power of whatever
but over the years i actually obviously do not think we have got similar the
whole-hearted to sack right so the second idea want talk about is i think there's
a consensus of open problems are forced nothing one the one of the
the things that i find exciting is idea how do on
is from if you trying to dynamics model but just can't get good dynamics model
which we can offer helicopter and for several the robots show talk about can modify
the enforcement running out of them to do something reasonable even though you really can't
come over dynamics model which like we could not
in order to explain this pisani i'm going game you know
revert back to this team of apprenticeship learning or learning with the teacher demonstration
so here's the idea that you want to drive the car
and let's say that you know the teacher demonstrates trajectory activity shows you you know
this is how you make a ninety degree right turn
suppose you can't come up with an accurate model of how carbon behaves
so this is what you can do you can then feed the teachers actions in
tulsa simulator
and c
where the simulator where c where model predicts the teachers college go in this case
let's say the model predicts the teachers car you ends up as taking the trajectory
whereas in reality it to the geometries
it turns out that is a very simple way
to update the model to fix the errors namely political dynamical model
the computed error in the predictions
so the model and subtract the air out from one model to say she has
all the and this is the gateway way to do missionary work attests that you
test you just take miners to the area at that the up and you have
you know make perfect predictions to you
so step one is on way to pretend that you know the first step the
out of all that is forced shopping your cart to the right this is unexplained
force w because the right hand semantic model he added this residual term and so
you don't snap to predictions
the first step to the actual position
and it is something here
i assume that you have to add in this mysterious force not just a the
second time set to what was actually observed
it turns out that if you do this you can then get out from too
much better to follow the teacher trajectory
one way to think about this is that you learning a local model
but what i want to do is this
the skip that we want to do is convey can based on the intuition behind
behind what sort of doing this
which is that the the bad moldova carbamoyl the whole heart
so no matter how bad your model is the science and derivatives are likely to
be correct so no matter how valuable the car as you probably know that if
you turn the steering wheel anti-clockwise you go left me to understand clockwise to go
right mother so that you can get that makes up the priest right on so
the incision idea as follows
i suppose this is a desired trajectory
but of
suppose you actually trajectory suppose cars currently following the trajectories of the introductory then surely
your model should be good enough to tell you that what you need to do
is to use during the for clockwise and optimised for the anti-clockwise
as another example of this is another example
from the goal
the show you want try to evolve to do not explain the intuition
clock walking one small
so i updated their ties may show you what we're trying to get the robot
so this the robot this this is the final word behavior
but he co
programmed to climb on top of sets of the sort jumping
this is the result and it turns out that during the learning process how development
process in fact we have to failure modes one is the robot of jumps two
horses the the the hostages child that both legs simultaneously to play so what happens
is that one of the family's jump to harness his robot actually flows backwards in
time back downstairs to families of don't jump hard enough
in which case you study see the robots sabbata space into the into the into
the step in front of it
o and
over the years work robot we actually could not get academic and simulator of
of this robot were try on dynamics very complicated but no matter how bad our
model was surely you know that if you see fatima one flipping backwards in time
about downstairs oscillators is going have to tell us the you jump this hard and
conversely if the robot is smacking his space into the into the wild front of
it then you need the job harder to get if you don't
OK so is in the sense that even a very bad dynamical model on can
tell you what's the right directions has
it's not right
they have some matrix and a symmetric positive definite and that means that it can
be diagonalized it can be written in the form used in the u
where u is unitary matrix
like a rotation matrix essentially india is back home
this is an algebraic
intuition about these matters is the fact that all symmetric positive definite matrices can be
diagonalized by the corresponding geometry which is that every matrix square symmetric matrix like this
actually looks like this
in some high dimensional space
where these directions here are the directions of the idea in
the vectors of the matrix which are the columns of u
and these links here
RBI values which correspond to the diagonal elements here right so every symmetric positive definite
matrix has a corresponding football geometry to an ellipsoid
high dimensional space
what does it mean that matrix
right what it it means is that there some notation here
which if you multiply
you'll get
a diagonal matrix what i mean you get a diagonal matrix i mean the matrix
and its actions can be interpreted as the action of rotating using into the special
space in which the matrix does work in that special space to work
matrix does nothing more than that it just the axis stretching and squishing and then
you transpose return back into the original space
so every six doesn't do anything more complicated than rotate into the space of its
eigenspaces due stretching and squishing and rotate the basis now
what is the problem of simultaneous diagonalisation
the problem of simultaneous localization is
well first geometrically what's the problem of diagonalisation from diagonalisation is to find a linear
transformation of this
ellipsoid that makes it access online
so this is
end up looking like this
and of course there are very few writers rotate ellipsoid
and due to a computer i can vectors
the other thing that make you is just the matrix rotates this selection
into that
so what is simultaneous diagonalisation simultaneous localization is
very difficult looking algebraic problems
which says i give you the matrices m one m two
and i want you to find me
a single matrix u
so that what
if you need to know transposed one
two is equal to your comments
the two use the same matrix you that both
well i think it's going to be very hard to find you out right
but i'm going to show you geometric structure which allows you to find you very
very easy
so what's the corresponding geometric problem
the corresponding geometric problems i give you one football like this
and another football like this one a single linear transformation that makes both of these
axes aligned
everybody watching this is the key part now they tend to
i think we're going to change everything so this becomes axis aligned
so i'm going to take this guy
so this becomes axisaligned like this
and when the rotation was also applied to this matrix OK
so let's say that gives me something like
this means that was a bit too much but you get the right
i'm going to scale this down so this matrix is spherical
so i scaled down so this is supposed to be circle by the way you
might want to do
OK so i scale this down to this
so whatever the scaling also apply here
so maybe i'm going to get something like this
i rotate this thing is diagonal
and then i think this this thing is already spherical right that's the trick
so now
things they are called
and that's it
this is actually alive because there is axis aligned with four one i can now
scale this sort of two become identical that's the way that that does it
you get
two exactly identical ellipses
these days
there the matrices have matrices of the same size obviously does this problem develop
if you paid attention to matter
you'll notice that i never scale
when this thing was a sphere except the very interesting symmetrical
but what i did when this one was the sphere i applied to rotation and
that's the key point is we rotate the sphere things it doesn't change still stays
one was
and what should we do it again the only thing i can think of
or should be backed up to read
at the very end is just
remember that it
to be diagonal you don't have to be sphere
you just have to be as this one
so what happened at the for the area what we have to have a spherical
matrix and some diagonal matrix but that was the situation of asymmetrical because this one
no reason at all ended up here
so just to keep things completely balanced world-view
it's all stretch this vertically
and structure this one vertically and just trying to match their
this is so
i mean image in our case this one ended up horizontally structured unstructured otherwise
i compress it in so well with this one like this and one like this
one like someone like this but they have the same is interested
the story
OK so
now we know p
that's the thing
thank you
thanks for coming again
and i hope you know what they are
because it's the last editions of the week
of course of i need some generalisation to biology bioinformatics which were like
use of this knowledge what
process to focus more machine learning approaches that could that's going to be
few equations and if few concepts across process
so you know
so find to when i will tell you something wicked this way the UN would
involve those that are
actually i did not do a good job is set in terms of time because
you can do all the three major what would resign
and the next word and the rest of the lines
and the fundamental insight
we spend a few hours more is so obviously what we do is we will
not cover everything but i hope that size you would have enough material if you
want to
look in modern days of some of the space willow
we know that they rules
fifty three sided testing afterwards
so we talked about biology and one of the problems we are able to solve
by pigs
and today i want present you want what you want to use very often by
many is that was the reasoning using bayesian four
predicting this problem is that just one of many examples of results involving as you
can see in this this and so the before i show you a whole
as you can also find the balance between the building and graph would start with
see another or can also kind of i think it would be complementary to what
we had to this you
and to be o or a kind of it
next week
the next week so violates some kind
so are you said that one of the magician the reason why because government that
what you are
is going be useful
is set of tools to process data we which are not always the truth about
her with the same
so let's train cross on the rest of the true that's all the main reasons
why will focus on
for the
you get some idea you what was in a simple one rules over all the
data can be seen as the example of
we have a set of sequences of protein sequences
and we we want to live in
from the clustering process regression classification
so let's assume that you have a set of sequences of the feature set is
going to be the set of where you're well suited to used be the set
of finite state sequences and we assume that we have problem with three sequences of
three box sets
in many
what you need to develop an accuracy
one that
if you were there with the computer software
from experimental based in both so of the most useful way to start working on
these three sequences is today is sequence encode representations of your presentation or
right sequences years and then write your computer programs that they put
set of sequences and trees
the idea of cannon et cetera different because these different
right well
this is where the trees
the size is the number of sequences on the way to handle
and in fact
the first mention
six of similarities
so the question based on your three points you see that need to find something
which is what i here and so these
decide between three sequence is what
two three and you believe that
we in on your computer sometimes you'll see programs will mysteriously crash with things that
say things like you know tried to access legal and illegal memory address when it
does that because the virtual the program tried to address access to memory location it
was mapped by the virtual memory system
so let's see now let's this dive a little bit more is actually how virtual
memory abstraction work so we can try to understand a little bit more about what's
going on so
this can be simplified
as a simplified version of a little bit simplified even what learn about in sixty
four so the idea in this simplified hardware is that we have our processor
OK and then we're going to have this
bm system which is sometimes called the memory management unit MMU and this is the
piece of hardware that's going to help us to do this mapping from these logical
addresses in a in the models address spaces into the physical memory
and then
we're going to have the physical memory
now the idea is that
when a instruction tries to access some virtual address so for example suppose we execute
instruction load
some virtual address load into our one some virtual address what's going to happen when
we do that is that the microprocessor
is going to send the virtual address
to the to the VM system
and then the VM system is going to translate that into some physical address that
is can be resolved within the memory itself
thank you and the way that the virtual memory system is going to decide which
is going to decide this mapping between virtual addresses to physical addresses is by using
something that
that we call the page map OK so
so this table is example of this is this is a list so of this
is the page map what page map basically has is just the table of virtual
the physical address mappings the the virtual address to physical address so the idea is
that when some virtual address comes in here the virtual memory manager looks up virtual
address in this page wrapped finds the corresponding physical address and then looks that physical
address in the actual memory
now there's one more detail that we need right so we so with this gives
us is that we have this notion of a page map it does this mapping
for us but we're missing in detail which is what we wanted was for each
one of these different models is running in the system to have a different address
spaces associated with it so we want we want to have a separate page maps
for each of these different modules over a and b
OK to have a different page map and this differently so when we're going to
have this sort of same we might have multiple copies of the same but of
a particular virtual address a twenty page maps and then we're going to do is
we're going to allocate a special register on the hardware going the processor we're going
to add a little register this can allow us to keep track of which one
of these page maps we are currently looking at thank so this thing is called
the p m a are
or the page map address register
and the web address register simply points at one of these maps case so what
happens is that the
the virtual memory system when it wants to resolve the virtual address
looks at this page map address register and use that to find the point here
to the beginning of the page map to to the to the page map is
currently in use and then uses the page map is currently in use to resolve
the current visitor to get what what physical address corresponds to its logical address
OK so this is really the core concept for virtual memory so we have now
is we have this page map address register they can be used to select which
one of these outer address spaces we are currently using so and when we have
selected for example the page map for for model a
then model a can only refer to virtual addresses
that in the page map and those virtual addresses can only mapping to physically only
mapping to certain physical addresses so for example suppose
because of the
either the six or something like that
and six
article constant is circle
so that this is the guy
this is the good solution
and if we
o pin down more details we could show that actually
it's like that well i think we may be there's two pi comes into it
to two pi comes into maybe if we maybe if we would have to be
a little careful
we have to do that the green's function stuff
to see i mean what's that
what's the idea of this delta function what will be the
here we go if this right side is the delta function at the origin that
means that hikers sending out
it small pipe but it's ending up one unit of
one unit and where that
stuff go
flows out right so having delta function there we can check that we've got right
if that
what should the flow out through
on the flow out through this
search out to every circle actually
like that one
it should be
should be able to source right right maybe there's two pi i i one
i think somewhere in here comes
right so we would to see that we really have got delta function i should
i should figure out what is the flow through it would come out right constant
and that concept might be able to
i probably would be
so OK
so that that's that says yes we OK now
very happy with that solution that's quite
remarkable that this is our you have access to do if you might like in
polar coordinates
rectangular u of x and y will be the logarithm of this group of expert
so far
and as of x and y
will be
the site
which is all
what's that in x and y
for nothing nice
maybe we can plug that and say that satisfies a path integration
you know
take two tutors that would take a little while but would work now what about
this one was so what data
y where x is
think is the
the angle
most ancient is why where x
like that and you know you have to know the formula for derivatives of our
ten but
like it in it it will work except of course at one point one point
there's one point x and y
where the derivative blows up everything blows
that which which is that point zero zero
right and we can already see the trouble is zero or we would be taking
the log of zero we things will be good zero here and of course we
don't expect them because they're right side has a spike OK
now i just
i would like to say a little about very little
about supposed
suppose the
delta function is somewhere else
cool well
we could just take the log we could just recently interest shifted over to that
that would be a solution
now what i saw as for something more
and so this would be
like to say that the boston harbor
in the atlantic ocean or something about boston or maybe when the point source mound
so that's really
suppose you
let me say this again
suppose we are given
the plot is great
what we should be given boundary conditions right
that is p
a circle of radius one
that say my boundary condition is you people zero
on the circle
now i've stated whole problem i've given
the equation and i've given the boundary conditions on the unit circle
OK in my
my point is that we found the answer
this is this is is perfectly was log are r
the answer the answer is you was log r
log of on the surface where r is one log one is zero so it
we captured the boundary condition as well as the equation
you see what i wanna do next i would like to be able to i
would like to be able to solve this problem
with the same circle
and the same boundary conditions
o point load somewhere the point sources somewhere else
that's maybe not so clear
take your favourite mathematical theory of everything you know you attempt ismail franklin tends to
be a theory for all of mathematics
it uses the notion of set it set theory
it tends to get all of mathematics from the notion of set
and let's say that this theory has a certain number of bits of axioms when
you convert it into a computer program that systematically that use of all possible consequences
very slowly
if this computer program has a certain size in bits
i can only prove the programs are elegant individual problems are elegant using that theory
if the program size in bits
is smaller than the number of bits of axioms and music
if approved the program is substantially larger size in bits the number of bits in
the mathematical theory
then that theory cannot enabled me to prove the program elegant
OK that's the result
you get there is also another with any given mathematical theory including similar frankel set
theory or whatever can only prove infinitely many programs are early because it is an
upper bound on the number of bits
in a provably elegant program that means
you know there are only two to the end and the bit string so you
have the bound of this only a finite number of programs you can prove his
elegant in any theory but there are an infinite number of other programs so in
other words if you're trying to prove the programs are elegant mathematical theories only enable
you to establish an infinitesimal part of the true
you know you can only you can essentially only proved results with zero probability
OK so let me prove this
result which i hope you find somewhat shocking
and if you want to go back to your terms it can be stated in
terms of
you can never prove there is no pattern but but but i'm trying to make
it easier to deal with by
formulating in terms of can you prove the problems our OK so now what i'd
like to do
is try to
give you the argument to prove
that that you
but in end the theory cannot enable you to prove that a program that is
bigger than n bits
is elegant why is this the case
well let's assume the contrary OK i'm going to give you an absurd proof
let's assume that this is not the case and i'll get a contradiction
so here is how you do it
you give me a mathematical theory
that has a certain number of bits right
and it's a piece of software that you're handing right which runs to the tree
of all possible proofs
so you had me this piece of software and i look at it i see
how many bits you're hounding me
first of all so i know the complexity in bits
of this mathematical theory
and then i start to run the program that you had me after measuring in
size in bits i start running
and i thought producing theorems
now the only thing that interest me are theorems that a state
the particular programs are elegant
OK the other theorem interest me i don't care i'll ignore
i feel to them all out most theorems i filter i'm interested in theorem that
states that individual to give individual examples of provably elegant programs
and in particular
i'm only interested in a provably elegant program
that is much larger than the number of bits
of axioms
that i was given
much larger let's say i don't know
ten to the ten times larger somewhat action much larger number so then what do
i do so i started running the formal axiomatic theory and filtering out all the
things that interest me and i only look at kansas state the programs the
give examples of provably elegant programs
and i'm only interested in proving elegant programs that are much larger than the size
in bits of my theory
and what do i do when i find the first one
what i do is
i start to run it
i'm actually a computer program i'm telling you one algorithm
i start to run this program i simulate executing it or i run
and i produce as i output the output of this provably elegant programs
which is
much larger than i am actually i described you computer program
let me this whole process that i indicated he was an algorithmic process and let
me let me describe it as a computer program it's a program the bulk of
this programme consists of a subroutine which is my formal axiomatic theory and only a
fixed number of additional bits of main program
you know which is a fixed number of bits and what is this program two
this program
looks at how many bits there are not how many bits are the subroutine
and in fact it only have a fixed number of bits to that so it
can know how the main program knows how many bits it has because that's a
constant you put inside and the subroutine you can measure how many bits around the
subroutine so anyway this program can know its own size in bits that's easy to
this is the calculation we're doing your program
OK so we're going to start back up again
we can't finished off on these spooky looking nice filters
and i just wanted to finish off i didn't get exactly say so this is
like an example of say
holy training examples of one object
and the possibly fifteen do you could have made useful to design and
i don't really come out as much as i like to say that this is
actually the image that you get a lot easier new books if you look at
it but the interesting thing is that what what the interpretation economists is that there
is barely any low frequency information they're all it's kind of
try that's all i'm going to copy the that serves are
that might not have felt
let's try and do this
stuffed things up
since MU
the resolutions of the good so this obviously
trust it's it's very high frequency it's kind of edges and things in there so
it doesn't look very real and things like that and so this is the car
that this is an interesting thing things
that we're going to deal with whatever because sure the pixel coherence assumption so this
is this is a visualization of the district discriminant classifier and here on the first
ones but this is an interesting kind of thing that we can look at
pixel coherence assumption probably
be stable here for this it'll it'll it'll work so i'm looking at these images
and things that i do autocorrelations and i get this nice smoothly sleep degradation
on this i no longer have that property
and so it actually pick it and this is something that are uncommon edging towards
consequence of that is that this restricts
the talk of searching i can do
because this no longer has the property of having the pixel coherence assumption
so actually that i get much better performance but by the actual fact of me
making this more discriminative actually limits
the toughest searching techniques i can use so this i can only really is an
exhaustive search
but i can't use anything else
and i i really touched upon other techniques but
as we talk about exhaustive search
when you get more complex what becomes very prohibitive so i just wanted to point
yes yes yes yes it is but if i want to say that i could
so i learned is delta x and delta y but i can apply the marketplace
for the one i could like applied foreign apply whatever was all these images and
learning rule
o registers well but if you say i've got an image and generally
the way my use they generally disused translation
anyway but in theory i could say that filter in i can apply anymore i
wanted to
things but if i try and apply to fire
i can't use exhaustive search on the interesting thing is under using this is the
case example the
this is is not just a is a lot of this kind of classifiers if
the linear
if you visualize and have a lot of this kind of high frequency information so
that the natural
and the thing i'm going to try to say is that
when we go into some of the techniques for searching they rely on this redundancy
the images to still have have sort of these natural this natural behavior and thus
limits our ability to
two are good search so
this is something i wanted kind of point out because it's a nice
nice visual visual cues
so correlation filters can actually was using the fence along so they can do things
like automatic target tree was and still is some examples of text and you could
train them to be
can someone point various
this is kind of synthetic things so this is kind of like and all the
it's actually one l supervising ivan CMU vijayakumar
and they also found a lot more recently there have been some successful artists actually
in biometrics face and iris recognition essentially filters were used quite recently to take out
the the face recognition grand challenge so this is the technology behind that
and actually works standard output kernels things to them but the idea of my filter
was useful the face recognition grand challenge and actually been used to quite great effect
in our recognition two so it's kind of an old idea but it's it's getting
it's getting some new responding to one another
so it's interesting so encourage you guys to check them out and find out more
about because it's and it's something a little bit different
not many people have been working on and this is the book that
commercial probably pay me for showing the sort of this is the book that he
wrote on and it's interesting going to give you a different slant on some things
are something to have a look at
as we know it as we spoke about correlation filters
the not because they allowed us to sit in the free the main kind of
credits come to classifier that actually having to synthetically created a good example another advantage
dealing state being free domain is actually we can speed up or exhaustive search especially
in terms of translation
it's getting selected for the discrete what you want to run my thing my of
a creation occurring that spatial regions
exist by clusters of low-density liquid the phrase uses the identity
liquid is the mother of ice
OK now let's switch to finance
important can find and sort of the same exact
the idea is born out by analogy
the work in finance also was done by a large number of collaborators is the
former here the ones who got the first started on this was resigned like
more recently work crucial how went on the carbon implemented by and this name is
an upper case because is the real
economist at MIT a junior faculty member until recently
well defined complication finance fluctuations are immensely complex just in case you're going to
there are
you can use your computer right now
type in bbc dot com or CNN dot com or anything else and read about
the carnage
that's a occurred about four hours ago where
the fourth largest bank in the united states
and files for bankruptcy
this is a very major phase transition because the found a few months ago i
was writing
so this is a complex systems and even though there people
the problem
man and woman in the street things that you should
i can understand enough about this complex system to get the money in some cases
even the retirement money
this is a very foolish because even the experts who devote their lives to this
fails badly to understand and in particular i might point out the economists fail badly
just which calls itself the economist cover article which shows the current discusses this because
most of the them and say
the title is puzzling failure of economics social economics is very much applied to complex
system and abroad notably i
i honestly believe basically nothing is known about that works
lots of
mathematically speaking
about models but very little that works in the real world i'd say compared to
physics economics is of much much more difficult problem as much for the last far
the take
is that although we cannot predict the future
we physicists can not but we can predict risk and not only predicted that even
quantify let's see how that happens let's take a simple example of a stock index
will picture one that's used a lot in the US called the standard and poors
index is simply the sum of the market caps of the top five hundred companies
market means the value of the company that means the stock price times the number
of shares of the total value of the company of course that factor it's simply
because the site for and that's why reported in every newspaper the world every day
and here is the results of what you would get from opening this over a
four-year period is shown in red and this is the little dot for every day
of this whole forty years for this index is generated interesting upward particularly in the
last twenty years basically drifting upward
there few
which is
like this one
in october of eighty seven called black monday where most markets of the world lost
roughly twenty or twenty five percent of the value in the space of a single
day or two
but generally drifting up and in fact it shouldn't surprise you too much that the
that parliament model which was an not an interacting random why
has been thought of an economics in fact economists are fond of saying was studied
economics five years before einstein for the random walk in physics which is true
but but nineteen hundred and his phd thesis and that's the a simple random walk
and you seem to explain most exactly like you can hardly see any difference except
these rare events
the idea
this reference the probability of the bottom and it is ten to the minus two
hundred forty eight
so this basically is about as close as you can come to never
and and that except for that it does very well it does something that
have influenced traders to use this model
as trading model
and that's one of the relatively few things economists to actually make it onto the
floor wall street in black shows it is used actively today and one the band's
and therefore the
the paradigm that might only friends described to me is that this works extremely well
except for a few rare events are outliers and those simply can't
and i said well many
physics if we saw
we saw this this one certainly floating up
we need to realize that the laws of gravity had to be revised because of
their lives in physics everything we understand some the outliers
but this is not the case here in economics so one of the motivations of
this work is to try to find some description that more
palatable to build to a physicist which does not have outliers
in order to do that we have to have a look at the data
during the
the same data as before except now what plotted is the so-called returns that means
the change in price from one
one day to the next
for the gaussian we know that those changes have to be very narrowly dispersed within
roughly plus or minus five standard deviations and you see there are
for the real data is not in fact black
in nineteen eighty seven with twenty standard deviations
in this index and even more and some other individual stocks
and we've seen
a phenomenon that was one of the jobs and two two economists
before becoming physics was born may be that
the piece returns are not gaussians
roughly a quarter
now when you multiply together these five
purple numbers
some of them quite close to zero
and so we're not doing quite so well anymore so as to make the red scan there
there is a bit hard to see
risk on the highest it got to isn't as high as
i missed the purple
so what has happened
now if we do a contour plot the product
this was just what they like
you might want to like
five data points of likelihood
seven year and
it looks like this
it looks
a bit like at
so as you model and it doesn't have a scary
bizarre place where infinities happen
and here anymore
and we can ask the question what is need best hypothesis in the sense only hypothesis that had the highest
so this point here
not that got any special status that all this is not an essential thing to
focus on
people sometimes do
you can go find these new and that
have the highest likelihood
and this simple homework exercise to work at the formula
but if you want
the maximum likelihood parameters are shown after this dataset and the green line is showing
what the predictive density looks like when you set mu and sigma to those values
right so
once you got a likelihood you can if you want go and find
the parameters that have the biggest value of the likelihood function
as i said that's not
fundamental the fundamental thing you want to do when you're doing inference is you want
to know the whole posterior distribution
not just
seven use using that happened to maximize this thing
right so that's the maximum likelihood parameters
hand going back to be entire function this is what it looks like when we spin it around
so has a contour plot on the bottom
the above is a a log scale surface plot
so if you do the homework exercise and you work out what we maximum likelihood
value for mu and sigma is
you may not be surprised to find that
new maximum likelihood
and indeed as slide across for any
possible values sigma
the maximum
value of the likelihood for any slicing value sigma
is at the data
it's about being by definition some
and that one hand
x and
and that's something you can derive we didn't have to guess what let's the estimator
review you just write down the likelihood function is a simple homework exercise
the maximum of a function is at this location so
in contrast the standard statistics where when things get difficult and you need to make
estimators we end up scratching your head wondering what's what how should i make a
good estimator
the likelihood function
is a way
have coming up with estimators if you want a point is a point value
what about sigma
the maximum likelihood value sigma is what you get when you press the sigma and button on your calculator
your calculator has two sigma bonds shoved in the data into a little old calculator sigma and
and this is an minus one button and the maximum likelihood
what you get when you press sigma and
that's it
this can't apply here isn't so the symmetric it doesn't have concentric circles that there's
a lot light getting wider as you go up
and the reason for that is fairly intuitive
if it were
actually the case that the mean
is not equal to
the data mean
who were the case that new
the true underlying meaning
isn't exactly like mean
for example if the true value is
there a little bit away
the data mining
i think a
and what the variance probably is given that's
all the data the cluster around here about
the average distance from the mean squared distance to one another data point is a bit bigger
because we've moved away from the data mining
than it was when we were at the data mining that means our estimate of
how big the very probably is
is a bit bigger
and what you would think the variances if you knew that the true mean really is equal to
the data
so that's why
the peak this
likelihood function here
is of that little bit upwards away from the value has
if we assume nu is actually equal to the data mean
so that's why got this lopsidedness
and if we take into account the fact that we don't
and if someone told us look i haven't
the careful what we do i wanna know how big the noise level is because i'm interested in noise
please tell me what you believe about the noise given this data
andy given that we haven't got a clue what new is except what the data is telling us
if we now
put the request into mathematics what the requester is telling us
i haven't got a clue about what new is and i don't care
they're saying i've got a very broad prior mu
okay exactly how broad they didn't tell us let's just use
an unspecified uniform distribution of some with a sufficiently wide that we don't care anymore
and then saying please tell me what i should believe about sigma
and the way you answer the question
we can work out
well we can prove we can imagine proceeding in two steps we could say
what would a newbie
he doesn't want to be let's imagine inferring it anyway
estimates for because this would have seen how to get there from s
and the idea is among all these nodes we have estimates of how to get
from a little as which is some vertex in here
two these vertices we're going to take the one for which the estimate is smallest
the greedy choice
and we're just gonna and the vertex s
so that grows with one vertex per step
each step
and had to s
the vertex
first again this is not a unique the it's a vertex
and the minus as something we haven't yet computer
was estimated distance from as
is minimized
so we look at all vertices we haven't yet at it as just take the
one where we have the estimated smallest distance the intuition
is it that should be a good choice
so if i think the one that's closest as closest to little less among all
the ones i've seen among all the patterns that i've seen as you have to
buy into those are good has but i mean maybe there's somehow i didn't seem
maybe you got here then you take some other path from vertex which we've already
OK the worry is well i better not say that that's the shortest path because
they may have been some other way to get there
this is an something as i declare i solve the problem for that vertex i
can't change my answer later
the estimates can change until they get added to s
so i don't want to have this vertex as because i have considered is well
if all my weights are nonnegative and i take the vertex here that has the
shortest estimate from from s
so the say suppose this one is the shortest one then this can be a
shorter path because the distance estimate least from s to that vertex is larger than
from s to that vertex in no way could i make the path longer
and should decrease the distance this the intuition has little bit fuzzy here because i
don't have any induction hypothesis set up and it's going to be a lot more
work to prove that but that's the intuition
why this is the right thing to do
have to prove something about the distance estimates for
to be approved
but intuitively it feels good
it is a good starting point
OK and then presumably we have to maintain these distance estimates so the heart of
the algorithm is updating distance estimates i mean choosing the best for text that that's
that's one step then updating the distance estimates of
his son where the work is and it turns out we only need to update
distance estimates that some of the vertices
the ones that are adjacent to
the was the vertex we added to us
so once we have somebody to s
we grow as by little bit then we look at all the new edges they
go out of s
from that vertex we update
and that's the key
the idea
so that's the idea for how we're gonna use greedy now give you the algorithm
so this is called banksters algorithm
the famous
recently ways
that makes sense recently late
computer scientists from the netherlands
and this is probably his most famous for
so the beginning of the algorithm is just some initializations
not too exciting
you only tell you what some of the variables mean
square d is array
indexed by vertices and the idea is that the index is a
distance estimates
four x so from
as to x
so in particular is going to equal
the real shortest
pathway from s to x
we've added access to set capital as
OK so this is in particular are going to be the output t algorithm to
order of looking at his real credit card transaction history
over a four-month period knows about
fifty thousand counts which actually had been doing something there's a lot of other accounts
which very low or no to tall
so the first step was system to those out
which is nice to data about the account some other datasets we have to have
not been looking at that as well
i don't have the results for that
and essentially it accounting space is an ordered list of all the transactions
the transaction itself to record the show showed there's an awful lot of data
i have selected some features by hand but this is an example of what you
can find obviously is the amount of the transaction
include some changes and i don't have any monetary value at all the examples
you can just check to balance on your
and on eigen machine that's considered transaction to be zero amount
of the time transaction took place in a second
the top transaction so may have one of the examples of the change in code
the time machine was used for those an ATM machine when these point assumptions one
see in shops
because he things like what the card is present this is kind of like saying
this but what was an internet transaction not
other things whether the
one cell machine in devices in it all the data it wasn't working a lot
of data about
the executions themselves involved
for will give a fraud flag but of course this wasn't the level of individual
transactions it was just don't basically saying that on this day
this trend this account came to forty
one of the take piece of into this information is was called the merchant category
this identified market segment transaction occurred in the game that we spoke about this example
is to bookstores
so four-digit number
but there's only about two thousand two because it means
that's an example of
using a multi dimensional scaling on this this is a categorical data to get some
some numerical value
one of the simple world
of course you shortly we can get over
another way of getting this problem with catego data but just introduce the idea that
this article might be group a standard technical basis to start to find these
so much the categories into groups which are similar things in the market segment for
example all airlines all put together all car rentals of lot of political companies put
and might seem have got a company credit card so you find much groups have
been blocked for using condoms for those circumstances but for
so that you combine the medical staff example but you can buy an
how do we apply this then pick method two
transaction data
the first things the safety council i synchronous
so we don't certain accounts ninety seven one day the might ten transactions another day
and we would like to timeline so very simple way of doing that is to
extract features at this time point so
the distance function and support from measurement between start point and end point estimate
powerful account a
and all we extract from it is the mean of the amount spent in that
time period a number of transactions persons down
and we just looking at the entropy of the merchant category groups what it does
is taken abroad sixteen groups of matching categories
and added one more for fifty for ATM's
and we just to see how
the spread of those transactions so simple measure that is a way of sort
turning to numerical values
so basically we get is a point in three-dimensional space for
for an account
so graphically looks something like this this a simple
diagram showing
four days today ten three which should
extract account i would be looking at all the transactions in this period
and so this this account is only one
transition but here
we have
three and we just look at these values
all accounts
down a column of this
for this experiment i did i didn't actually do the analysis once the transaction occurred
i was looking at the end of the day this kind of fitted in with
the the fourth like we had so this is not wasn't
OK i see your
during my
o thing
in the
these or
the right
o point
that means
they won
o five three
no i'm not saying he
i think
these are
five i
they a
so is he
i e
as well
found proteins
sentences could give rise to both
synthesis could give rise to both and certainly chemical synthesis give rise to book
spend much time on carbohydrates just for reference
the carbohydrates are also chiral molecules
and it turns out that
in sugars
the form only the form
it is
metabolized by our bodies
so you may have heard to invert sugar bakers sure this is simply
the l form
the various
and this passes unrecognized by honey contains the
the l four
of the car because it's process by bees
and the bees have different biological apparatus
this gives rise to
there's there's science fiction work or somebody is
after some time
grand event find themselves in a strange place on it is always going to be
a desert island
and they end up eating fruit that happens to be
chock full of
but it's the wrong and humor and the people
although their field
to satiety they die because they can process the food so that's the basis that
plot line has been used already i'm sorry to tell you can
you can't use it
and the mix of both
when both in and tumours are
both and humorous
this is called receding
and this is very important i said it's a matter of life and death is
very important in pharmaceuticals
there's a couple of
i'll tell you have to tell you one example
back in the nineteen sixties there was a drug was produced by german
pharmaceutical company
called thalidomide
thalidomide was
developed as an anti convulsing
and it and it was also good as a as i said for people that
were severely depressed had one of the properties of thalidomide was that you couldn't overdose
the person took a huge quantity of thalidomide
it would make the person comatose you go into a deep sleep
be an extra on the set of rip van winkle but you couldn't
kill yourself
an unintended benefit of thalidomide was discovered by pregnant women in europe who
i learned that consumption of thalidomide had a tremendous palin effect on morning sickness
particularly early in the pregnancy
so people started using it for
palliative against morning sickness
this is only in europe the food and drug administration in the united states and
it has been subjected to enough testing
and refused to allow its importation into the united states and there was a lot
of clamouring still the FDA is is all
old-fashioned there in the pockets of the drug companies they holding up the advance of
of drugs and so on you hear these charges with respect to cancer drugs and
drugs in the treatment of AIDS people are impatient for solutions
the FDA held its ground but much of the drug did find its way into
the united states
and then shortly after its widespread consumption it was found that this is the trategy
and it produces his birth defects
and people said what went wrong why
did they not discovered this was not testing was not tested on animal models the
answer is it was tested on animal models it turns out that all the animal
models that was tested on
those animals lack the particular enzyme
that process thalidomide the waste processed in humans
this is something that
caused quite a stir at the time
what's the punchline the punchline is it's a chiral molecule
only one and human causes birth defects
nobody no time
so if they known
instead of selling ever seen before
sold form that has only the one and humor
could have had the beneficial effects without the
undesirable effects and now thalidomiders back and the new some people have discovered that may
i have some benefit as a component of the cocktail it's being used in
the treatment of AIDS but the memory lingers on and there is tremendous
and by the way really
red which is used in
the treatment of
but practically are not useful because you can implement them
so a lot of research card researchers sort of looking at methods that are practical
you can implement them they might not be exactly might not always work be treated
like to figure out when they work when not work
so for those of you interested in model selection on friday in the research talk
i'm going to speak about some recent work with pradeep ravikumar and john lafferty et
about how for certain cases you can do consistent model selection in a computationally efficient
way can do it for every model but at least to some class of models
there are ways of doing it
OK so
let me just jump and
OK so she sort of move on to part two now
let me think
this is sort of summarised
part one is
sort of covered several things i covered different kinds of graphical models things like directed
graphs undirected graphs factor graphs we discussed further in inference problems we talked about the
elimination algorithm that it's not something you use in practice but it illustrates why the
graph structure matter so much
and then we saw that some models are easy trees are easy chains are easy
graphs of bounded treewidth are also easy
but we also saw that there are many
graphs arise in practice that are not easy
various applications these sort of tough grass will arise
so this is sort of moving on a bit more advanced material in the second
part it's trying to understand when you're given a graph for which it's hard it's
going to cost you exponential complexity to do things exactly
what you'd like is sort of cheap fast and dirty things to do
you wanted to be cheap fast and dirty but
not bad and
what's interesting is that it turns out that again some pretty naive things that you
can do turn out to be pretty good for certain kinds of models
after all kinds of models
but we're going to see is that pretty nice things like taking
message passing in this running on a graph with cycles turn out to be to
to work pretty well
so the sort of trust here is is trying to understand how do we move
beyond just plane trees and graphs of bounded treewidth
and in order to do so we can actually need a bit of background on
convex optimization so all spend a bit of time in the next lecture developing that
to some extent
i think that's useful for people in machine learning not just for graphical models it's
a sort of general set of principles
i think a lot of modern machine learning much of it ends up being optimisation
algorithms for optimization of course with issues of large scale and parallelism so if you're
interested in machine learning it's also
worth spending some time picking up optimisation background as well
so we've already seen the to let's skip the slides
you've also seen this slide that this sort of various quantities we'd like to compute
what we now understand is that in certain cases we can compute these exactly by
fast algorithms that we also understand the cases in which we can't compute them exactly
and we're sort of and have to think about more clever approximate ways
what i'd like to do is
for instance begin
just to contrast i will be talking so much about sampling methods how many people
have heard about sampling methods things like markov chain monte carlo
OK i know you guys have OK so certain subset of your had
sampling methods are one way in in which you could imagine for instance computing high
dimensional integrals are summations
the basic idea of the monte carlo method is that if you can sample from
something then you can typically approximate an interval or some by
sticking those samples in
computing certain averages of those samples
so sampling methods are are sort of one feasible method that in principle you could
use to perform inference in
arbitrary graphical models but
it's a bit delicate in terms of what the actual computational complexity of these methods
is and this concerns things like mixing will get into this in detail but let
me just give you a flavour of how these algorithms would work
the basic idea here suppose that you had a graphical model that look like this
so what i'm doing now is actually not be doing this throughout much of the
talk is writing everything in terms of exponentials
and the parameters let's assume it's it's binary this is just a simple toy model
got one parameter for every node
and you've got one parameter for every edge
so it it could be for instance a black-white model of an image that would
be the simplest example
this is something known as is an easy model in physics it was used by
gaming in-game for instance in the eighties to model image is a very simple image
but one way you could imagine trying to
generate samples from this model
would be as follows this is the kind of local sampling algorithm
and what it does is quite intuitive it simply says well i'm going to randomly
pick some nodes in this graph
and that node might be at some stage it might be black or might be
and then what it says i'm figure out should i flip maybe i'm black should
i for myself to be white
two values produced w equal to OWL or one thousand one
you always have a randomized lasso to force comic vision years
penalized by so w
one is ordinary wj
how small
the weight class
that flow so
so a causal link between good
this is a list
just take over
the course as standalone defeated absolutely nonsensical
it's like
can color
it's just selection
connection stability
two active variables
which satisfies the strongly
representable condition
one bad
which violate represent
hundred ninety seven always used to
stability selection has
there is a lot
if look around random
what happened use the collections the last you can get rid of guy
violates present condition seems really collection
if you can that the last
you can create it
you have a large threshold here
two two
course for example
what if you later models and
i think this is kind of here are some eighteen percent
reducing the number four
sometimes you can
he was
at least one the thing so far never lost
he was a theorem
this is
variable selection because randomized lasso
well my last week
because the assumptions
assumption is a big design our linear model
or i could do this because y
nick y
through your earlier you wish
delete no such
strict condition
it seems that is much like the neighborhood or even worse
OK then set of land how
so we only need to to make any assumptions on the meaning
all the land four
there's issue that the minimal
number of small
is not what i want to give you three
the much larger
what's allowed in the first frame visual i wish
it can be covered
i should say i mean assumptions are maybe not minimal difficulty here is
the last so this thing
it's my skills i find it much harder in analyzing the last which clearly
so why does it work
i think such a noisy and spread kind of thing
i know her name in
part of
somehow we have also
randomized lasso
it's always the last so can always be rewritten
scale you could be right
randomized here
a our new
career yx w
now what's happening
mathematically is as follows
if you be lower lower
first in terms of
a condition
the ratio between the maximum and minimum before i
small out is that
don't make it too bad there is a lower limit don't go below the lower
the limit being larger
there is lower should make it
OK so i think it's kind of plausible that don't make it bad you still
catch true story
the question is how can we get rid of this guy
part of the answer is as follows
one of the proof
that what saying
in this procedure designed to keep her
surprisingly he
and this is sometimes characterised
he represents conditional holds you don't pick up and always called
i think
i mean it is not fulfilled for the original
and so the noise variance what's happening is that sometimes not so
in some ways
so far we have some
sometimes have small you have
and in two stability selection many times this sometimes means that
it is sometimes do not select you cannot stable