to use in a pretty good approximation in fact we use the very rough this
but not probably no
so this is this is this is how
in the literature a hierarchical hidden markov models define was first first using medical image
processing by by migrated from oxford for MRI
without supervised learning actually
then with supervised learning
what you need to do
it is to be able to actually estimate these terms date
and so
what you typically do
is just go ahead here
what you do to estimate the model
because remember you have empirical data so it's not just pure there
so what you do
typically in these cases as the next to go around and do some notation
this image is extremely large by the way some of them can be
twelve thousand by fourteen thousand pixels
so that do subsections
might do
but for now it gives some data
but then you can apply the whole thing
and so you generate the pyramid
you do the
class conditional clustering you get a classifier for each pixel which is really the vector
from that because you've got a pyramid
he actually compute then the
the BIA matrices
because you've got you've got the labels at all scales now
so i get initial estimates of the eye the matrices from really just just empirical
empirical means
so what you do
to do the IMAP
you simply do the following
new data comes in if you like
new data
i run the bot this double here or get distribution
that distribution
well before the arrival here that's new label this is this was the back and
forth and this is just converges
what to do it every time is taking the most likely
every likely case most the
MIP label this picture here
the necessary become the label for its pixels have been then
activates the click functions here the form another label you come up and down
it will converge
so to summarize form of the year
we can use the junction tree algorithm
again now numbered commentary
i think you can see how that sort of work
but you know what you know from yesterday
it and all this way but is suboptimal
we could use the junction tree algorithm for optimal optimal inference in our setting the
clique size potentials of tractable this is clearly possible when an MRF is defined over
features not pixels
this hierarchical hidden markov random field is not possible due to the presence of cycles
i really can't do it
we've tried many times to try to form a junction tree over pyramid maybe some
of you guys have been able to do that
like we've not been able to
to solve the problem
we can do for markov random field is the same material over time
it's hard to do when the when the when the nodes of pixels
because i can share pixels
when i did when i went to the trent junction tree
so it's still i think an open area
four research happen ideal optimal inference
i remark random field image
i still i still can't solve so we tend to generate to these types of
iterative iterative process
these are the types of result you get when you do this sort of thing
notice the philosophy
segmentation an invitation
come together
you don't have parts and then supervised learning and segment them together what emerges from
this process is an image
two are labelled set apart automatically
the service things work
we look at various performance as you'd expect he's just
stringent conditions
you want to have really want to compare the
observe exact annotation
with the performance you don't get terribly good results
down to
one spruce pretty good repressed messy
well makes is terrible
that's course not chance is not
was exactly overlap
about pixel
exact expressions
so the point is
but anybody who says
i'm going to image understanding
by segmentation annotation
all right so
it was i want to tell you last time about the
work that's going on here at MIT in genomics
it's it's just fun them in front sure what's going on and it's fun that
you guys can understand what's going on already with simply one semester biology which is
is really cool
what i would like to do today is talk about another exciting area one i
don't work in but one that i know many people are interested in and i
would like to lay the foundations for neurobiology and neurobiology is incredibly interesting area
i confess since it's the subject that got me interested in biology in the first
place even though i don't work on itself and i mean can be interested in
the brain
but if you want to take on the brain you really have to understand its
working components in
some real that here
so what we're going to focus on in this course
for the next three lecture
is the specific molecular mechanisms by which
nerve cells are able to transmit signals down their length
how they're able to transmit signals from one cell to the next and how they're
able to change their properties over time that is learn
the fundamental unit of
neurological processing is in nerve cells
which goes by the name
eight neuron
you have approximately
ten to the twelfth
how many bases are in the human genome
three times ten to the ninth civil war nerve cells
then bases in the genome so it's unlikely that all of the wiring diagram is
completely specified in the sequence of the genome
simply because we have a lot of here that's just a minor side point
what the typical neuron look like
so neurons and connections
a neuron
a typical neuron
eight year ten to the twelfth neurons
makes contacts with other neurons it might receive contacts
might get contacts
o ten to the third other neurons
and send signals
the ten to the third other neurons
so that's a lot of connections
if you figure ten to the third times ten to the twelfth ten to the
fifteenth connections in the circuit diagram here sort of
kind of a picture of nerve cells
connections to
another nerve cell
making connections
two maybe muscle
what activates this nerve cell well
maybe in your eye we have of photoreceptor cell
and that photoreceptor cells
wilson apps
upon first neuron which synapse on the second neuron which will synapse on your muscle
so maybe you'll see something
send the signals and the signal activate your muscles to pick it up
needless to say it's pretty much more complicated than that because it will take more
than those two neurons to figure out the appeaser the chalk and how to coordinate
emotional but you get the idea
let's let's take a look pieces are kind of receptors might we have
we might have receptor neurons
they receive white
the photoreceptors
and these photoreceptors in your eye are an extraordinary piece of engineering
you know how sensitive the photoreceptor can be
what's the
absolutely minimum possible detectable unit of light
one photo
it turns out your photoreceptors
can under appropriate circumstances they detect a single photon
clarifying my remarks to that
last lecture which was about using the wavelets supplied frequency estimator now there
may be obvious to most of us but it doesn't hurt to remind wavelets have
the nature of the property of tangible resolution in higher frequencies would have lower resolution
so this is an example of a simple simulated signal companion to assign waves and
the variance so that preference representation go something like this on the right we have
spectrograms computed with different uh time-frequency resolution and what we see here these boxes are
sometimes called the Heisenberg boxes because there uh dimensions stemmed from the uncertainty principle and
signal analysis so in the
the short-time Fourier transform spectrograph we have constant shape of these boxes why in wavelet
analysis in lower frequencies would have prolonged boxes well defined frequency and higher frequencies we
have a good time resolution so we considered the that are here no matter which
way that we're using model that frequency resolution is pretty bad basically about the upper
frequency we can only say that it goes in the upper part because in the
orthogonal wavelets wavelet representation of the frequency resolution goes in the dyadic sequences 2 2
4 4 2 8 8 to 16 16 to 32 right so what we're saying
this was some kind of sampling of wavelet representation this is another simulated signals
from single structures including the
these are again spectrograms of continuous and this is continuous wavelet transform so we basically
template wavelet even at any point of the time-frequency plane that what we're seeing here
is that for example if we look at OK let's look at those
spin that we have here of frequency in the wavelet representation we only see that
something is going on in the upper house of frequency can then what was presented
in the here what stressed before was an averaging of wavelet coefficients so we have
an integral across this line so basically will only see that something goes on in
the upper part of the frequency so be it way you said you were happy
that's something the goes on on the left part of it was perfectly correct there
was no flowing the body of the remark was involved that is sold small in
the latter part now most likely the left part of Europe frequency axis corresponded to
the upper part of frequency when the nature of the resolution was more or less
escorted by 1 wavelet it was obviously oversampled because of uh the logarithmic scale was
located in the because it was always the few over sample this kind of picture
you have a small picture known whether that in reality you can have some things
going on in the game
so that's just for clarification and we started there was the topic this is the
title and my thesis is that about frequency approximations of signals unify most of the
uni-variate computational approaches to EEG analysis uni-variate because this is involved is this I will
show also some preliminary results with multichannel applications and and offer compatibility with traditional visual
analysis of EEG used in clinical applications now this is quite a bold statement is
classifiable and criticism and that's what I came here for again I make it formal
even easier to
criticized because I claim that
this this statement about unification can be also enhanced by claiming increased selectivity sensitivity and
and this is probably the easier part for this
machine learning and engineering community but I will keep on showing examples that simply falsifiable
by the way of course I'm ready when you interrupt that's why they came here
so any questions on the fly and then the 2nd part of the thesis which
also consider quite important is about the compatibility with visual analysis of EEG now this
topic has not been touched here that scientific of neural scientific environment but why I
still uses that we should care about the clinical analysis of EEG and it's not
only because when they we may get sick their 1st of all all of us
can be solved can be reduced to simple regular past tense
so in our case now
the other way to think of these these are symmetric diagonally dominant systems now is
we can still take every off off diagonal edge
and what we can do now
is simply say that we have an edge from i to j
than that though this function w i j is not zero for that value right
this is analogous just allow WID TO BE j to be negative
so now this is just the weighted let's let a be the weighted incidence matrix
is we defined before
let's define the degree
the system to simply be
the sum of the absolute values of the
edge weights
and then we can now get let's call this the generalized plus in things form
ld bullseye so now instead of course this system here
is it a symmetric diagonally dominant
the only thing that is missing here is is that we requiring here that the
diagonal not be arbitrarily bad with respect to a that really doesn't matter you can
actually make the diagonal bigger
but let's just worry about how would we solve these kind of linear systems where
we allow
the elements in here the off diagonal to be positive now they need not be
so this is a simple generalization of rectifier for policy
so the first the first thing i want to point out is that if we
have one of these matrices
we can write out this quotient the rayleigh quotient numerator really quotient
in the following form right this is all the same thing as usual
as i don't go through their mission what happens is you get two kinds of
terms that you get turned when the w i j of positive that looks like
right so
now so this is the standard term we get for the regular plus right we
get things of the form w i j times i i x o minus xiv
j square but now what happens is for the terms for where the the edge
weights in the original graph and negative what happens then this is we just take
the absolute value or you put a minus sign here and you get another some
of positive terms
so this is the notice that these generalized plus interest still positive semi definite
they may not be positive definite
because include clearly the regular policy and so we cannot expect that in general
so what i find that it's not too hard to see that is a rank
is still and minus one if g is connected right we have
so suppose we want to solve the system during pensions and let's consider the following
very simple idea
and that is let's do a change of variables to see if we can get
into the former regular policy
so suppose we take one of these things and we multiply
one of these matrices BI columns
and the i th row
by minus one
then i claim if you work this out because we're multiplying the same the i
th column and row
by minus one that means the diagonal won't change sign it'll will still be positive
and all we've done this flip the sign
on the off diagonal elements which does not change the diagonal dominance of the system
right so what this says is that it is
this is equivalent to doing a change of variables where we slept
the sign on the variable x fighter minus six i the variable and the the
item might be are in the system we want to
OK it was just a small example make sure we understand so i suppose that
we take a generalized graph it has edge weights some of these are are negative
and some are positive like regular plus here
so we make up the matrix what is it going to look like well we
can take the sum of the absolute value of the edge weights out so in
this case we have two minus one to two for this entry to
so they're all who's on the diagonal
this because is trivial example and then of course we take minus signs over the
one it has two edges out
one of the two which is negative so we change that to plus
it has another it which is plus we changed one minus right so this then
is the generalized symmetric diagonally dominant system
corresponding to this graph
one two that
so we'd like to solve such a system and so one ideas is what we
try doing a change of variable s multiplies in the first row by minus one
in the first column by minus one
so if we do that
what happens i mean we change the sign and everyone in the first row for
the diagonal
we chains of elements on the first column by the
but i claim that we can now make up the new linear system where we
put a minus sign on x one
and minus sign on the b one
and if you work it out then
this works out correctly right in the sense that now what's going to happen here
is is we're going to negate this term here this term is negated this term
is negated so therefore we multiple dot this vector times this row
we're just going to get a minus b one
just like we want
and when we do the dot product with any other road we're going to get
the same old value back OK
so the claim that is if you want to solve this system you can try
multiplying a given column in a given row by
minus one and seeing if that helps and then when you got done you just
have a change of variables here you would change the BIC and you would change
the axis accordingly right to at any time you can do that and it doesn't
change the underlying system sold into
so let's make it definition let's say that an underlying graph is orientable if there
exists a sequence of flips such that
all the edge weights go positive
so we define just here
so we should have
so so in general
what are we doing here when we do in the flat that vertex so what
are we doing graph theoretically has a very simple and meaning is simply says
what we do is we're taking graph
these are sources of information
i have some claims
or some kind of connection why any of these
organisations or people would be
involved in the summation of the rocketry and OK
one interesting suspects and then we can say well how can you justify this answer
no i think we clicked for to justify why OK would be
why why would have motive for this of this article
and this this is the explanation
this is the credit which we began before
this is no
basically it says the following
so what i think the was
advocate of living on a lebanese economic reforms and i played
support suppose was opposing li also economic performance and then if we would click here
and is detailed justification which showed sykes rule
which would say that one way how tool
enforce you really is also took in this other guy which is opposing
and this is the general which we call it in any other situation is and
here we have
references to these claims this
these claims were taken from
one from CNN and one from some whatever
some document
so these are references for these these claims and the rule which connects this is
kind of part of general knowledge insight and this is then justification of the
why i that would be the one
unfortunately had this this don't explanation of
the this rule which which connected this fact
so this is roughly what side thus and so what
our plans and now it's like so we try to make it a little bit
open and so
make it also available for other researchers in various ways this current effort
OK then last couple of slides
we have exactly
ninety minutes OK
so now moving away slightly from the semantic web and this is the knowledge that
so you probably spotted that this vector point zero discussions about three point zero and
but there and so i spent some time collecting all these different
discussions about these different versions of weapon so want
and so this is a table which i came
OK so what what this particular that so
that one point zero is roughly what's
basically is what the that was i don't know ten years or more fifteen years
static HTML pages and so roughly technologies which are behind just plain HTML and HTTP
basically we can say that one point here was that this we first learned so
and then became well nobody said this openly but now
this has to be somehow placed in the proper place so this was that one
point five which was small as dynamic HTML code HTML content and this is one
that is we know it's not it's mostly dynamically and this will be connected component
technologies would be on the client side javascript dynamic HTML flash and so on server
side CGI PHP perl and or a fee on all them
now this web two point zero came recently
and the idea of this
that the point zero is mainly integration of all this there was
integration on all levels especially collaboration and sharing vocabularies
so this is the main
the main think especially collaboration sharing
so this i would say that this is being sold knowledge base
we're going say well
we just showed
that if we knew the setting of all the all the variables
this would be easy to write is just counting frequencies
let's do tricky
sort of iterative thing
which is
let's have an algorithm which in one of the steps which are going to call
the eastern
it's going to try to fill in reasonable values for those hidden are missing
so it's going to try to fill in values for these axes
so i'm going to fill in a single valued has to fill them in with
the right
proportion or probability basically i'll get to that in a minute
how but now
once we've done that we can re estimate our parameters
from that field in
from that field in data so the m step basically applies the complete data learning
algorithm to the field in data
now we have a new set of parameters
but now wait a minute we fill in the hidden variables
you may be assuming that our previous set of parameters is correct so let's go
and now
re fill in the hidden variables having learned about the new set of parameters
and then we estimate a new set of parameters from that into a back and
forth between those two steps
so the intuitively that's how we can understand the algorithm
with a bit more math on the page that's how
this is how we can understand the algorithm OK so
that was the intuition let's just do the derivation
we want to maximize the log likelihood
the log likelihood is the log of a sum over x of these things
and now it actually you could just take that log likelihood into some general-purpose optimizer
if you've never heard of the EM algorithm if you can evaluate this thing and
you can evaluate the derivatives of this thing because they get into general purpose optimisers
software things but the EM algorithm is sometimes very fast
not always but sometimes very nice and fast and often very intuitive to try to
here's what we want to optimize
and here's what we're gonna do we're going to say
well that log likelihood is the sum over hidden variables of
this is a joint distribution over everything
that joint distribution and multiply and divide it
arbitrary distribution over the hidden variables so we're going to call that q of x
we multiply and divide by q of some songs were not dividing by zero
wherever this thing is nonzero then that's perfectly valid OK so there's inequality here
and now
we're going to use this equality
to get an inequality to get a lower bound on the log likelihood
and the way we're going to do that is
the log of the average of this ratio
it turns out is lower bounded by the average with respect to the arbitrary distribution
q over the hidden variables
the average of the log of the ratio
and that's an example of something called jensen's inequality
o which comes from the fact that the log function
is concave so if i take two points along the log function
and i take
any bridge
the weighted average of these two points
the log of that average point
this is the logo of the average is
greater than or equal to
the average of the locks
a lot of the average of that
ratio is greater than or equal to the average of the logs
this is sort of intuition of jensen's inequality union since inequality is something that occurs
all the time and she has a lot of you are probably familiar with that
and now what we have is a lower bound on the log likelihood
which is a function of both these unknown distribution over the hidden variables and original
parameters theta
this seems like we just made our life more complicated by doing this
but now we're going to do is we're going to
score of o point six seven
so now we try to see whether it wants to the negative ones so now
what we want to see is the negative
and if you look at
it is the only pattern
is that is of interest to us it appears only once here in the first
instance and no one else
and that is it appears once and twice so it is the only park
that is an emerging pattern for us
so in this case is twenty five fifty and we compute the score is point
three three then we say well
most likely it belongs to
that's one so this is the very earlier
class things we've done and since then more sophisticated scoring functions have been done and
this works extremely well
and i'm going to skip this one because
running out of time
OK what we try to do is we always keep minimal size even with reasonable
support the ones we want to do so you can do some kind of ranking
on these things
so the question is your we can i see why EP based classifiers are good
you can generally you know in in the
in a qualitative sense you can say
first of all you can use a lot of support
that means they don't have to be very frequent
together with high support ones in a in
fourteen you can use them
and you use multi feature conditions not just one defeat time which gives us
much better correlations between the two values
and select larger pools of discriminative one so that means that there an ensemble effect
and one more thing i should say is that now emerging patterns is small
stop space mining and if you do subspace clustering what it means is that
you do the different kind of protection of features to do the clustering
you know like much else
is in fact can do the same clustering it already like
the interesting case these dominant sets
are chosen
indirectly by a human being
mentally thinking of subspace so for example
you know you when you put collectively together let's say
some objects you together because you have a little have lots of features
you know some objects you put them all together because they're all fish
right you know that's where you put the color doesn't matter
in other cases if they not free
maybe you want class
based on some colours
you know you look at the color feature and then based on that you
so that's the what the human things in terms of classification because what happens is
the moment it is a fish object the rest is not interested for the problem
that's how they did the association between objects
so it is basically allows you subspace clustering
and the emerging patterns interact the subspace clustering
using the fetus itself rather than an expert coming in doing so that the potential
is available
and i think that's what makes the system much more robust because depending on the
situation it is projecting different kind kinds of features
and telling the only those features relatively
giving them scores
and that's what makes the system really robust and interesting
so there are other kinds of works that that share a bit of interest like
that is if you look at
in bagging ensembles like you know decision trees people could do
they tend to to
heavily depend on
and on the dominant features rather than
infrequent but interesting features
are not considered in those models
so for example we say here
we have only two percent of the data makes the decision
but with the ninety nine percent confidence
and sometimes decision trees ignore those things because
they don't have sufficient probability
just the of them
they don't they don't do that that's we do
so red class
is that it is a real problem in know that whenever you see especially medical
doctors and also many other cities datasets we have
you have a huge imbalance you know one that cities are very small and lots
of other things
the fraud detection fraud is a very small percentage
but could be quite serious
actually was having an interesting conversation at lunchtime
the discussion that we're having today is sort of a more general one the u
there's the question of
how speech technologies might be able to exploit the
you know whole body of knowledge that exist let's say among speech scientists
and how do we in this question how we sort of do that it clearly
clearly sitting down and
all of us reading reading a paper on of the journal of the acoustic society
of america
and with what with the left hand encoding it up somehow with our right hand
in our our existing systems isn't going to be the way to do that
and then on the other hand i suppose the ability to of those people who
who are doing this speech science who
tend to take more the sort of descriptive approach to their work rather than a
then building generative models they is is really not quite right too
ask those researchers to start
taking their their models and there's their ideas and and putting systems together so raises
sort of larger issues right we and so a lot of the work that so
this is sort of a fancy-schmancy lead into my to this this this this part
is is what we can see is a lot of effort here that can that
that will have
people who try and bridge
gap between speech science and space technology
and and we see it's not easy so you might want to
i think about some of those really basic problems when you attacked if and when
you attacked these neural so
i was starting this topic again to recollect where we were when we started or
when we were on the left
we going look at this problem of detecting a distinctive features
our surface acoustic wave forms and
we started off talking about how how we can define
these phonological distinctive feature systems
and i did mention that there are a number of different systems that have been
defined and each one of them really derived from sort of clever implementation
of different models for
of speech production and speech perception
i i didn't when i went over this the first time thinking that i was
running out of time i i skipped over some things but this feature this distinctive
feature system defined by a simon king and his friends at edinburgh who is is
close to ten years old now but
again is a multivalued implementation of the binary scheme that was originally i think posed
chance came here although i don't think they are the
chomsky here i don't think they are the inventor of the notion of distinctive feature
not quite sure who would hold that
that distinction anybody
would anybody be OK
and then there's a another system that i'll talk about much later was referred to
as government phonology is doesn't have that name because a particular government promoted it's is
because sort of the organisation of the levels of the description
is a sort of referred to sort of metaphorically in terms of sort government agencies
and it's it's a bit closer in its description to the acoustics it it often
many phenomena is described in terms of sort of a form and templates a rather
than strictly in terms of
you know articulatory terms
OK so having gone back over that we were talking about the issue of coming
up with acoustic correlates and deriving surface acoustic parameters from those quotes and we sort
of describe that here is this parameter extract extraction process and then describe the fact
that are distinctive feature detectors will take those parameters as input we i guess i
personally i lamented the fact that that a lot of times the e
specification of these parameters are sort of done
feature by feature in so we can look at the choice of the parameters and
the definition of the acoustic correlates as really being information is provided by the domain
expert and for those of us who who might have been designing ASR systems or
natural language processing systems based on this in the strictly a data-driven way you'll love
likewise from it but
this i think is is one area where we hope that we we might get
complementary information into our systems this is through the choice of these acoustic parameters but
this particular result was for the detection of stop consonants and i can attribute to
carol let's see what's in that will at maryland
OK so
this is actually where we left off
and we're
just to give you an impression
i mean
you create a only one
the first one
so the the first whole image
we can only
what every can
right away
blue you
not band
of course they don't mention
but it did
that picture
the action
second lecture
actually in the
so what
i partitions space
you can
now let me featured before but still quite a big one
but we
we're done
based on independent component analysis
which we i you know was actually be
if you think about
other cells and the feature vectors some level
one particular to someone can to be found the area which revealed
it is the third side
so for every which
the results
here's what
and it is role
the thing to one
so we have the
they pushed
it don't to do
during the image
link analysis
so we know
this particular image like from the
can select that problem one of the
so you want to find
that makes
the population
and commissioned
he was
but images
based on this
the most of the right
not a lot bigger
women have a
the section of the new images where one
the right
and we always
can say
also called
around the world this is where the one
this is the only
all you have to kind of the search for just
because the
most of the similar
the first
small part
the call
so we can
described by
if we look as it
from so
the cause of what i want to find all
so far
and this
and finally the kind of
so we want to find just
images aquarium
july twenty
the right to
i think i can
many all
during which
it kind of three
one of the
one of the weight vectors which
but it is high dimensional the
prior to the
one them
think that in the night to that
or months
so index structure
are very widely
which was
the main idea
these drive
it will be
i was wondering if students were well acquainted
i want to find all
the project is like
so in the
hours later
two domains
there is partitioned grid
and because the one example power
after that have some small
i have
and the
minus one to the are
it's up there is little big number
m to the are plus one
OK so is
the size of a ge
could to m
are plus one
we want to remember that case let's just understand why that is i m choices
the first value of a m for the second and for the
OK since there are plus one things here
for each choice here i have this many same number of choices here so the
OK so this is the product rule in
counting so we haven't
i reviewed your six o four two nodes for
for counting
this is going to be
good idea to
go back and review that we're doing stuff of that nature
this is just the product
so then here we want to prove
is there a
h is universal
mean this is going to involve of number theory so gets kind of kind of
as a nontrivial proof so this is where
there's any questions i'm going on please ask because
the argument is not is not as simple as other arguments we've seen so far
OK not the ones we've seen so far simple
this is definitely
the more involved mathematical art
so here's proof
so let's let
so we have two keys
are we trying to show that universal that by pick any two keys
number of
hash functions force they has to the same thing
it is the size of the
set of hash functions divided by m
OK so i'm going to look at two keys was picked up his arbitrarily
OK so x
i will decompose it
i'm sure base
our representation
and y
y zero one
case we so these are two distinct keys
OK so if these are two distinct keys
so the different
then this space representation
has the property that they've got to defer some more
OK they different least one digit
and this is where most people
get lost
because i'm going to make a simplification
they could differ in any one of these
i'm going to say
a different positions
OK because it doesn't matter which one i do the math is the same but
it'll make it so that if i picked some said they appear in some position
i would have to be taking summations as you'll see over the elements that are
not i i
that's complicated if i do it in position zero
then i can just some
the rest of
so the math is going to be identical if i were to do it for
any position because it is symmetric or the digits are symmetric so let's say the
different position zero but the same arguments can be true if they differ in some
other position
so let's say so we're saying without loss of generality
without loss of generality
position zero
all the positions are symmetric here
so now we need to ask the question
for how many
hash functions
you are
purportedly universal set
two x and y
get to count among
how often they collide
this is where we're going to pull out some heavy-duty
number theory
so we must have if they collide
examples are produced by nasser examples produced by nature no assumption probabilistic assumptions but now
let's go back to the canonical case that everybody else is looking at
the instances are actually generated by a fixed distribution
the drawn independently at random i i d
well how do we have case where you take your
all right out of the school in the worst case and you do
general conversion you do some general electric on top of it and then you immediately
have guarantees that whole expected case
so i'm going to show you a little basically some averaging
OK the simplest so we have set of
the perceptron convergence theorem which by the way
now if want to say well
if things are generated at random what's the expected loss expected number of mistakes of
the perceptron
well the simplest thing to do is you run the perceptron algorithm all and in
a lot of these
it turns out that is not the right thing to do you need to have
a little more averaging
you are slightly
so this is not so what we want to get is now
bound of the time
you get a sample in in the end you want to use all these it's
for small expected loss so no need to
he finds instantaneous loss
all these with respect to distribution is just the expected loss of this of properties
on an example drawn according to the same distribution
so this loss this consists of an instance
and the label the instance
and then you may the loss to the label
so this is overly concise
go away
how do you get
converge to the expected loss so you look at the total loss of the algorithm
right expected total loss and the the following
this one
expand this out is the sum of these losses you take the algorithm minus one
example you get the next you could also use some trials now the expectation goes
this actually becomes
the sum of the expectation expected instantaneous losses
so what's happening is the following
when you do
when you have a stream of examples you have t plus one office one here
one here and here and here and here
right until all the way to the end and what you want to do is
to pick one at random
so you pick hypothesis one of t plus one about random
and you predict
on the new instance
with this hypothesis
and the instantaneous loss of this algorithm is expected loss
expected total loss of the rich over t plus one trial
whenever you have lost found that holds in the worst case
it's it's and
then we have this conversion where you pick one of those
this is a random
immediately you get expected loss of m over t
just going to the end in picking the last part of this is not good
if you only have a guarantee of the total loss
you could have algorithms to go along and then control the loss at the end
which you don't know you only have about the total loss so but the average
trick hedges against
now you could say that is the curve for practical and yes it occurs for
the perceptron algorithm is u
one of the convergence zone due to the loss
two and out of the
works well in the expected case
this is actually a good thing to do
so in this case you take multiple
you take multiple
passes over your data on average
so this is very close to averaging the hypothesis of course
OK this also tail bounds
for instance you if you have lost which has this strange again you look at
it t plus one properties your average
they hypothesis
and then you can show
if the total worst case loss is and then with probability at least one minus
the outcome
the area of the average of these
this picture
so this was the expectation
that's going a little bit further out
and you get a about to get the area is small with high probability
my philosophy is
go ahead
two your worst case loss upon first
and then converted
what i'm going to talk about the next there's lots of applications
and actually it's still quite a few slides to go through
it's not so many from the time
to describe this complicated application all all this will illustrating quite nicely is that in this framework within the build a very complex % of all
the characters complex models for all applications by
constructing the matter simple building blocks and to expressing the whole model graphically and we'll
see that is if we can sort of get the best of both worlds
we can have a look at the complicated graph in which all of
the building blocks the city potentials all the conditional distributions for
a Directive graph all members of the exponential family of put it is very nice properties
for instance the ability to run variational inference in a
very important way of the graph and yet at the same time we
can hold off the this whole distribution represented by the model can be very
complex essentially happening so mentioned this the few lectures and do is that we can to express complicated distribution of
things we observed by expanding the phase variables by introducing hidden
variables and that the joint distribution of observed and
hidden variables will be simply a director graph let's say
that this distributions which is an exponential family when
we marginalized acts the latent variables will be left with
the model distribution of the means of variables not be
very complicated so the major Parisiennes of about a very
very simple example about what will do will use metric acids as also running example of entries
the EM algorithm of all just to write it for you in a very heuristic way and then we'll see role full way of
looking at the end of the process of effectively give a
proof that the amount of the news converging isopathy
optimizing a well defined function I referred to as the
love and the U . sometimes referred to as the free energy
viewpoint again because of some uh connexions with physics
and that allows us to revisit the algorithm understand how
it's working whites working a monster knowledge of doing
something sensible immortal about had a generalised at the
amount of them and red actual generalization that point
will be variational inference we think about the general
isation in something that wrote along the way I see account of the really this year graph that just
remind you of the and the definition of an acid
distribution but also to point out that this has come from
as a as and it is the case for all of the exponential
family members of are simple maximum likelihood solutions
are taking I see and all we have a set of capital and
observations of X only maximize the likelihood that has this very simple closed form solution the new
parameter is just a sample mean is a mistake matrix is just a sample of the variants so nice simple
close closed form solution for for single gas in the
problem with the gas in the course is that it represents a very simple
distribution just a simple on what happens if we have more complex distributions supposing we have a
distribution which is a multimodal so we have the
distribution of X which looks like this clearly would open
represent that very well by a single guest in so natural
things and it is considered a linear superposition events
in some sort of intuition here because it is not some
complicated um distribution of American represent this is
sort of linear combination of scarcity of and obviously
they have also that we choose the um coefficients and that
prices appropriately that in some sense we can get a better
approximations to this very complicated distribution so this is a linear combination of scarcity and that this
is the overall distribution of course has to be both a
positive and it has to be normalized and as a consequence
of that the parties as a positive for um non negative I
should say that I and the fight integrated is the 1 1 left
with that this condition which is that the point of the
some to 1 method nominated in some to 1 obviously they call
it was 1 of the 2 of you 1 and so the piles of quantities
which like between zeroed 1 in which some of interesting because that's where the conditions required
for these numbers to be able to represent probabilities so that is something a simple example this is the 2 dimensional space when I have free and gas in this case so the concert is here the
indexes represent the performance was a constant
probability that that each component separately I'm going to make a quick
since the use of colour of colour and that there some of the colour these components red green and blue and
the idea of the consumers of the joint distribution so the
when I take a linear combination of these with appropriate
mixing coefficients I end up with something which looks
like this so that the Justice of lots of we have than a single gassing by like the by maximizing the
likelihood that we could try to maximize the likelihood
function all the world to the log likelihood before the
mixture of our citizens that an idea data we have a product
on the table we get some the likelihood function which is the ball problem of the
data given the provinces viewed as a function of the
and it has some kind of equipment which is the blackboard
it's also used by
someone or something that is
a member of the faculty
so this thing looks pretty much like lecture
and we can actually
name it as
as such
now because just because you curious we also do the same thing for the other
individuals we have here
for whom number nineteen we also see OK it's also for concept room
it's again useful lecture it also has blackboard but in addition it also has
the project kind of equipment and this time it's also specified
by humans use used by
the kind of professor
he was also a member of the faculty so this might be a kind of
nice lecture hall since have the project and it's used by professors
OK so again
i mean this
most lecture hall
and editors ontology
twenty one
you do the same
and here is your kids again a room but no seats used for quick for
a kind of experiment and not kind of lecture
that's different equipment that kind of thing and come into
and fire extinguishers
as suppose such as this and so this one looks like a kind of
laboratory kind of flat
so we also and this name you know
and you can see what happened actually now taxonomy so now
the reason knows all the concept names that we have used a lot
on top of it also knows concept descriptions that more complex and that have more
namely the ones we have added so
ontology is not containing the ones
the concept names that don't have a definition but we have already
in fact obtained concept
hierarchy here since this lecture halls
that characterize are lecture hall was actually left the phi then the individual that
induced the nicely to hold so in this way we can also using the most
specific concept can also start to populate t boxes starting from the a box
yes i mean basically
the names that are used in there but they don't have the definition
so you don't have a description for
so so we can use the
most specific concept for augmenting RT boxes but we can also use
on these kinds of some of are more enriching ontology sometimes when people start to
the hierarchy is that of concept hierarchies that come out of it look rather something
like this so that this room like structure where you have one concept was very
many sibling concepts
and this kind of structure is actually not so practical because it does not really
inform very much about the categories and subcategories that you have your domain but you
basically models are it looks overview modelling your concepts
basically on one
level of
furthermore if you have ontologies like this it is
the hartford the second use of thirty two
balls in this ontology or to some of find concept again if you want to
look at the definition and find and define something else
in in terms of the definition
so what we would like to have is actually a concept hierarchy has more kind
i has more intermediate level that browsing is actually
what facilitated
so once we have all if we have a concept hierarchy like this
how can we
and i was a nice structured like that well we can proceed the following way
we can just pick some sibling concepts from the concept hierarchy
just use the death is directly
and then again maybe at the obtained a concept description to the two books are
this way of proceeding proceeding is sometimes called the extended bottom-up approach will not really
an extension but yeah but what it boils down to is that the this can't
subsume alone loners already useful to obtain a deeper concept hierarchy in your in your
t box
OK this website model
on the two basic inference is that i've introduced
you are
the next thing is
well we thought that
this comes up some of the most specific concept inference are available for
medium expressive description logic now what now the question is of course what happens if
i want to use a more expressive description logic
in some application eighty or eight million is not enough to to model domain
what can we do if if we want to actually use or can be used
most description logics in a meaningful way in a two
use not to push their also for this is that it is
problem with this way can just directions from the yes if
we do
copulate if you remember the definition of the LCS was also taking into account the
kind of language in which you want to express
the resulting in these concepts concert so if you for instance computing the least common
subsumer in the concept is the description logic ALC
well you have disjunction of concepts
and you you're basically asking what is
named whatever dogs maggie and whatever dog Molly magnesium and let for you you have
no sense of humor with my battery your dog lovers and you're offended by giving
metallic names I don't know are isolated happens what is this engineer give us what
is the yield what is the yield so what we have to do is get
back underneath this reaction and see what the molar quantities are supposed to change chloride
magnesium I've got 200 kilograms here 25 kilograms here
and if I divide by the appropriate quantities of discovery have a little over a
thousand moles of tickle in and I've got about a thousand moles of
of Maggie but the reaction says I need twice as much maggots typical of this
reaction is going to go to completion clearly this isn't twice that affect us even
less than so we've got a problem here this is much less than 2 times
10 54 so therefore imag is the limiting reagent matters limiting reagent and that's the
yield is going to control the obvious be throttled by magnesium so how much rate
how much it titanium can make a can only make as much titanium as is
consumed by the available magnesium so if I look at the mole ratios on the
reaction over there and find that I'll be able to consume at most 10 129
over to
2 moles of magnesium 1 mole of tickle serious 1 mole of time and that's
515 moles of
Terkel consumed and then that produces 515 moles titanium and I convert that to that
gives me 24 . 7 kilograms of titanium if I charge the reactor in this
manner and of course I'm assuming a hundred per cent completion of the reactions which
we know is overly optimistic there may be some inefficiencies at some point you catch
holiday giving a sermon what goes on inside the reactor OK so now the question
is how we know in the 1st place that this is a suitable redacted how
we know that maggot will reduce titanium tetra chloride
all this we have to look inside the attic and as would do many times
and through my once we start unit like this with a history lesson so let's
go back to the thrilling days from the end of the 19th century and just
take stock of what did we know
at the end of the 19th century about the structure of the atom well 1st
of all we knew that the atom is electrically neutral knew the negative charges carried
by some particles
called electrons the furthermore that the electron has a very tiny mass in comparison to
that of the overall added the atom has a tiny mass to what we're saying
is compared to the told atomic mass the mass the electrons tiny of and secondly
the bulk of the atom is positive if the animal is fixed mass the electrons
tiny not massive then does it must be the positives have all the mass and
that's what we know so the question then is what's the spatial distribution of charge
inside the atom why we want to know the answer to that question because that's
going to give clues as to really activity
what do we know about the spatial distribution well people took a stab at modeling
and the 1st model we're talking about is that of JJ thompson JJ thompson who
publish this model in 1904 he was a professor of physics
at Cambridge university and he was also the director of the Cavendish Laboratory obviously they
would still so he was the director of the mobile artillery and
Cavendish made a fortune in the 17 hundreds and will Cambridge and so they established
this laboratory in his name
and here is the essence of what JJ said he said that the electrons were
distributed throughout a uniformly charged positive spheres of atomic dimensions so electrons electrons distributed throughout
the electrons distributed throughout a uniformly charged uniformly charged positive this year
but uniformly charged positive efficient of atomic dimensions so essentially you got a positive ball
which is identical to the size of the atom
this was turned the plum pudding model plum pudding this is cultural bias of course
is that the British term never instead of number predefined funny but anyways there
I'm told that looks something like this so that you have the custody with little
fragments of plumbing inside so this is a positive sphere positive sphere of custard inside
our little negative bets this is the plumber and these bits motion so the bulk
of the atoms positive that's where the mass resides in you get these tiny little
negatives running around so the negatives the user negative they're physically small there are very
light that is to say low mass their mobile they're moving around and all the
worst thing is that JJ in 1897 did the pioneering work that got the Nobel
prize he measured the charge to mass ratio of the electron that you even use
the term electron he called this negative elemental particles the core parcels he called the
core apostle of electric charge
and he kept referring to them as corpuscles I'm really glad that along came Johnstone
stony was electrochemists right the noblest form of chemistry and as electrochemists he chose the
term for that element of electric charge of the electron coming from the Greek word
for Amber because you know if you remember you get a static charge so thank
goodness stoney triumphed otherwise we'll be talking about coal past male you have seen e-mail
you have e-mail parents anyway
so all right so we have various 1904 what's the method of science theory we
do put to the test so put to the test Ernest Rutherford Ernest Rutherford Ernest
Rutherford so he was a professor of physics at well as well but he was
at Victoria University of Manchester Victoria University in Manchester just up the road from Cambridge
alter these were in the UK and early part of the 20th century and he
conducted experiments to test the plum pudding model basically what he did was he took
a very thin metal foil the bombarded with charged particles and
here's the Rutherford experiment taken right out of your text but before I
research say that people should be high and actually find the house to awards
from investigating
more trying to understand more about
what the the system for dealing with
this image is functional dependent for its future organisation and its immediate state and its
current external company if there's anything that's a matter for debate what internal with the
external something that is the major factor
i grew virtual communities
patterns and properties appear at time that people talk about levels slightly incorrect assumption
in there no real levels in nature that is human constructs epistemological two use
so we can see the ontologically
there something like levels
nature of what we do know is that there are different forms of organisation
that occur over time
across europe of what we have we have we as we see things ecosystems
for example we know
their interactions
and forms that generated time dependencies
between third in order for them to actually come here
but then to survive maintain themselves
it does not necessarily mean that this is a maintenance it's not necessary
self organizing system doesn't have to be stable
and it does not necessarily increase
his organisation capacities and capabilities
the properties appear over time
i assert that this is the kind of problem can be collaboration
may appear to be new or emerging but the causal non-linear mechanisms of interactions and
the system is inherent in the system itself as it evolves
the math and this is still
advanced for five months from you understand that it's also we naive and we we
one of these
real life systems we take time model
and i are working on this this we take collaboration to be an emergent structure
which shows the system wide information processing capabilities so we don't
think of in terms of individuals within the system assemblages
and system in white
we look at information can capabilities so pattern is a way of computing information pattern
is the competition basically the system has to like in one theoretical terms an algorithm
the system uses
and in particular conditions organize itself in a certain way and coordination global scale is
results from function interaction
coordination is something that you don't pose
but i something that arise the result of the interactions in the system
so should do we we're talking
so one always change
our way of doing things and so i'm asking is going to another way and
possibly that is correct four
human systems
and system collaborative structured process the form of the distributed cognition
and the organisation is propagated through the system patterns about activation of what we might
call system-wide learning
you see learning instance adaptation when you get longer-term learning that kind of evolutionary stage
given line
well cycle of the kind of system have introduced business in mind
and in from distributed cognition perspective we would actually
examine this kind of causal patterns patterns of activation by looking for
the propagation of representational state across representational here
so we really care about containers
are you know where the information is what creatures
functional interrelationships
now that actually does support
we build an example from international small example results are all the possible collaboration towards
the concept like trust
we show how group impression formation is influenced by processing information
communication stereotyped information but it's actually enhances the story tracking and the positive feedback
and we need to be aware that i'm not sure what the implications are
yet we not too sure of which was to
for disruption
we we can to extend this
two groups decided we take
i think it's actually a misnomer as should will have to be about wasn't sure
if you intended but it's actually an interesting come q because you tend to get
the picture
attention and
so that you because what you have is the notion of group
established as an individual has to interact with and how are you an impression research
could actually be
this was going to be influenced by their search experience included
trust is the kind of sensitivity parameter there are four absorbing new information novel information
and we then also
i look at what happens if we begin to extend
our to multiagent types of connections models
so i'm not going to the commission's modelling
that's called the conceptual right that basically you can play around and above the black
ink with white shorts
OK that's none dynamical system
can have its own article should kind of
perturbations and rapid
train from
all three
for all
try that forms or
it's not for
if are
all of these are
all problem to
what you want
o s
the same
try all
he will be one
the problem is and i
we're trying to say
so so you
so no matter talk
so that's
so i think
four dollars right
here's my
all the
is home
o here
and we
the features
and it will be
so you know
this is
the smallest of the year award on
and this
it's really to
the list
so something
and his her simple range
so we have
we train on
all all
now to make predictions
the show is this one
ten right
ross was just me
so so
so so that the
this is the first track
this is where the
so we have a single
the line search to
and true
i want to
for instance
i need you on
her fall
one which should
right before he
truth this
see also
the world in nineteen ninety
so who just
you know which
this is a fine
the most you because he believed
the reason for this
so we alpha one
what was to
six primitives i can program anything
a couple of really interesting consequences that by the way
one of them is says anything you can do in one programming language
you can do in another programming language
there is no programming language that is better well this is not quite true there
are some better doing certain kinds of things but there's nothing that you can do
and see that you can do in fortran
it's called incompatibility anything you can do with one you can do that it's based
on the fundamental result
fortunately we're not going to start with touring six primitives will be really painful programs
because they're down at the level of take this value and right onto the state
first what we don't tapes anymore and computers
and even if we did you don't want to be programming available CD with programming
languages that were in use higher-level abstracts a broader set of primitives but nonetheless the
same fundamental thing holds with both six primitives you can do it
so where are we here
we're saying is in order to computation we want to describe recipes we want to
describe the sequence of steps
built on some parameters
and we want to describe the flow of control that goes through the sequence of
steps we carry on
so the last thing we need before we can start talking about real programming is
we need to describe those recipes
and to describe the recipes
we're going to want a language
you do not only one of the primitives
but how do we make things
meaningful in that language
language there no
now it turns out there are no john hundreds of thousands of programming languages
least hundreds of programming languages around
true thank you
you know they all have you know their pluses and minuses image in my career
here i think i talked in these three languages i suspect talk more five or
six john
both of us are probably program to more than those number languages at least program
that many since we tunnels languages
one of the you want realises there is no best language this i would argue
that i think john agree we might both agree we have our own nominees for
worse language
there are some of those
there is no best language
they all are describing different things having said that some of them are better suited
for some things
and others
anybody here
for the matlab
the program to matlab
it's great for doing things with vectors and matrices and things that are easily captured
in that framework
but there are some things that are real painter doing that that's great for that
kind of thing i see is a great language for programming things are controlled data
networks for example
i happen to be and john teases me about this regular i'm an all-time list
program and that's how i i was trained and i happen to like lisp and
scheme is a great language when you're trying to deal with problems where you have
arbitrarily structure
dataset is particularly good at that
so the point i want to make here is that there is no
particularly the best language
we're going to do is simply user language that helps us understand so in this
course the language we're going to use
pretty new language is growing in popularity
it has a lot of the elements in some other languages because it's more recent
inherit things from its
progenitors if you like
but one of the things i want to stress is this course is not
strange statement unit you do need to know how to use it but it's not
about the details of where the semicolons go going pipe
it's about using it to think what you should take away from this courses having
design recipes structure recipes how to do things in modes
in python those same tools easily transfer to any other language
pick up another language and weak coupling weeks months
once you know how to do python
OK in order to talk about python languages i want to do one last thing
to set the stage for what we're going to do here and that's to talk
about the different dimensions of language
i have models which learn the patterns within the data
now you might be thinking
alright the difficulty here comes from the fact that handwritten digit could be you know
someone can make
make it make it scratch on the page any any kind of matter and is
also very
was in that
may be printed character recognition is much easier
well that could also be tricky here we've got
number of characters which are all the letter a and when we look at these
we can see
immediately that are all the letter
but if you
if you try to think about what's the essence of each of these what's the
is there some regularity between each of these
patterns that we could somehow encode
you know it seems trickier than it than it might first and this is great
paper by doug cost
is well whether it is quite fun
so you know finding this invariance the pattern interest in
might not be
as easy as we think
so the data could come in all sorts of forms have a video data image
it could be time series data
so here are some examples of
measurements of vibrations in the ground
at different times when they were
here's three earthquakes
at the top and the bottom here three
mining detonations underground
and if you
i had some equipment which was measuring vibrations in the ground and you felt some
disturbance in the US
probably quite interested in knowing whether that's an earthquake or explosion
could have big implications for you
trying to distinguish between these two things if you've got some examples you have some
new set vibrations that's going to be a significant task
and it's not really immediately obvious how to do that from the from the data
you know one thing we might think about here is
the data we're looking at just doesn't
we look at it and we can't see
what information it has about the
but the problem we're interested in
so we're going to think about really representing data in order to be more effective
doing this kind of distinction
OK back to africa
kass kass of viral diseases of the problem in in uganda and here's some healthy
leaves and disease called customers a
and music school this quite distinct visual appearance
which means that you can actually do pretty well in distinguishing between healthy and diseased
leaves given given just the image
and just to reasonably poor quality
image from from a camera phone
so if you have a large set of images like this than other application we
could be interested in is
a survey told someone goes into the
in the field he got some survey team they're taking snaps with camera phone
and if we can automatically diagnosed with the disease which disease they have other crops
under stress in some way
if we can get the information and we can do surveys scale surveys
without requiring a small number of highly trained
experts which is the bottleneck at the moment in search of it
so having
established information like that maybe from the kind of mobile phone based system
there could be other questions were interested in like
this kind of geospatial analysis if we've got some some density in space of
disease disease incidence across the country perhaps
and we have some
inputs from our our survey which maybe maybe this kind of automatic thing or maybe
survey techniques and we see
you know ones if we take that to denote a perfectly healthy planned and five
denote the
the worst level of these possible with the plant actually dying back
then given up points we might want to work out where
what's the coverage of disease
across the rest of the
across the rest of the field so you know points a b and c what
we predict is happening there
we were able to send survey team there but there's a tower that place and
we want to know if we need to make some intervention
that's the question we could be interested in two
his last occasion face recognition
the canonical machine learning task
particularly important if you're combat as assassination robot from the future
these examples have in common is that we're learning some kind of functions
we've got some inputs and some outputs these examples we want to learn
what's the mapping between the two got some kind of assumptions to help us
the limits are hypotheses about what types of mappings there might be
but this this type of problem is something known as supervised learning so a single
will start to get into the details of that
so we did
talk a bit about different techniques we can use to to supervised learning
going to introduce some notation to do that you have any questions at this stage
about the
their applications we've seen the
concept we've had so far
all right
OK so we need some notation to to get anywhere
some introduced and to
to sweeten the pill that let's stick with the termination
all right
to do any kind of
supervised learning task we need labelled training data we need a number of
of samples from our input space and we need to know the corresponding output of
the function trying to learn
so here's here's examples and here's the probability
this being a particular class
so it doesn't always have to be probability but we're going to look at that
given are
training data and test data
we've got
for example two things we might want to
we might want our learning machine two
the first one might be the most likely class what's the c which maximizes the
probability of c given x
we might also commonly be interested in
putting an action
so if we have some kind of loss matrix which tells you if you got
it wrong
how bad would that be
then you can sum up over all those
possible losses
weighted by the probability of how much you think each classes
this notice in off no measure of uncertainty
in part because it's hard how can you come up with the test in high
dimensional scenarios the simple-minded solution it's convex optimisation only
and this kind of maybe simple-minded solutions sometimes
you run into problems with the more trouble but nevertheless it became quite popular to
do it this way one explain what's going on if you do it this way
OK so in my motivation example
is the description of the linear model
n is two eighty seven is one ninety five
the lasso selects twenty six variables while chose the land by cross validation to my
crown land that is kind of geared towards prediction this may be a problem but
i have not another good way to do it at the moment so the last
just selects twenty six variables
and what we could think of twenty six interesting candidate motifs no
i mean there are way too many just maybe one or two or three
but not twenty six o biologically the way too many here from a statistical point
of view would say OK twenty six out of one ninety five that may be
pretty reasonable
OK so let's
again do the analog about it
this list minutes here so what do we know from theory and how should we
interpret result like this
the theory for the lasso part two about variable selection
again i look at a fixed design linear model because he's he's scenario my active
safety is zero
and here are two
key assumptions
and then we discuss them to be the first one is what we call the
neighborhood stability condition is a condition new design x
and in
later paying job new reformulated in an ice forming a caldera presentable condition for design
x to to design condition
it's not to restrict the one i can cannot it's another design condition
and the other conditions will discuss disappeared and the other one
it's kind of
plausible so yes they
the non-zero through
coefficients to have to be sufficiently large if you just have very small signal strength
there's no hope you believers detect variables right
and so actually the condition is the non-zero regression coefficients the true ones either zero
and then the nonzero ones have to be larger than
c times square block purine sy is certain concept
log peeler in square which comes
now both these conditions
are sufficient that's great
but the trouble is essentially necessary
so if they fail
your last will not
give you the right to active set of variables so these conditions are sufficient and
essentially necessary in order that the simple is haviland recovers the through is zero high
so this is what you would like to have it would be a great goal
is very ambitious goal was to choose the land to be larger than for prediction
that's OK maybe
but you have these two conditions
so we proved this quite awhile ago
and the point is both these assumptions are really restrictive
OK i mean
we have in our paper but people typically kind of nice in the positive way
to take the positive part of the paper and say OK they proved under these
conditions it works but we also show if the conditions are violated it doesn't work
and kind of message which i want to pass here as well it doesn't work
if the conditions are violated the conditions are short
OK so this is equivalent for just to give you an idea
this is the presentable condition here's my gram matrix and what it boils down to
you partition your gram matrix
into the part
there you have to active through variables you just ordered these are the first if
zero variables so here are there
the empirical covariance is among the active variables here both active and non active variables
and so on and so forth and you're presentable condition reads like this so it's
very compact it's nice it's beautiful but of course is not checkable you had no
chance to cheque this condition if somebody gives you me at six
so here is again this graph there are this condition
optimal classifiers in a situation where you have the option to to say i don't
so you might have a setting where
you pay
a little bit less
for saying i don't know then you pay for making a mistake
and you know is not unreasonable if you there's not an unreasonable cost model
then in that setting
you know it might
makes sense to have a point of non differentiability is zero right and having a
value at zero would correspond in that case to add to this reject option is
i don't know option
and you know there are some some results along along those lines
OK so
let me
give you a bit of an indication of
how we prove this
this result
right this there what i'm not going to go into the converse result that says
you can come up with the distribution function to show that for every theory you
can't do any better and i won't go through
through this one this can look at the
the relationship between excess risk and excess virus
and some of the facts that
very important in proving that so we've already made this observation that that this
optimal conditional expectation of the value of the conditional expectation for conditional for certain value
either the the conditional probability and the related constrain one h one is asymmetric
about this
eta because the half-point
OK and that's just because
you know we we have beta phi of
f of the five alpha and
one minus the five myself we can put those things around change the sign on
alpha and change e one minus we have exactly the same expression so we have
that symmetry
we also have that and a half
the optimal value is is five zero
right so nature behalf and h one and a half is that they both the
same and so our function
so i certainly takes value zero
zero let's just
hope it up there right so when when theta is zero
we have a major half which is five zero this thing takes value zero you
know is in
as in this example
science theta is
by of zero minus h h
is an infimum over concave function so it's got its concave so five zero minus
h is convex so this thing is always the convex functions
and the last property is that the phi of zero is actually a ge minus
one plus
one of
of any value of the argument
OK so
you know the proof is
it's like three lines once we have fallen example all these definitions
so i
a crucial
in fact
that relies on is this this expression
for the excess risk
and this is the classical thing it's a it's an an easy thing to to
work out by
looking at what happens over the different parts of the domain x already it you
can write the excess risk for a function f that is how much it's risk
exceeds the bayes risk in terms of the expectation
this product
the first part
is the indicator
four if predicting differently
from the bayes rule
OK so we're we're looking at integrating just over that subset of the domain where
has a different prediction from the optimal one
and then when we're in the
in the domain where it has a different prediction the price we pay
it depends on the difference between the conditional probability and half as it moves away
from the half pay a high price
the absolute difference between that half of about
OK so so
you know this is this is an expression of too hard to drive and now
what that means is that when we take this function side of the excess risk
we can use the convexity of that a function to write to write it as
a sign of this expectation
right well that's no more than the expectation of site through
jensen's inequality
but then
but then site of
an indicator time something well whenever this thing is zero
we get side of zero which is equal to zero so we can pull indicator
outside right so this is no more than the expectation of an indicator for
we get the wrong sign
times science the absolute difference between two eta
and one
the definition of
of scientists factor h minuses is five zero
tells us that this thing is just
that minus
h of
that plus one over to which is which is a
OK so we have
you know in here
this function psi the excess risk
involves now the difference between a minus the conditional probability and h right this is
the thing that is large that is bigger than zero when where
when we are classification calibrated
right now
in the cases where where
where are making a mistake
right h minus minimizes the conditional phi risk
subject to the constraint that we make a mistake right so that thing is always
no bigger than five
y times f of x that's from the definition of h minus and the fact
that we're just just concerned with this part of the space where we make
make a mistake relative to the
the bayes classifier
right and and finally
this is just the definition of of