you can calculate
the moment of inertia of the sun
i have used my two face and are squared which is really crude approximations
because the two fifty m square for solid sphere only holds
if the mass is uniformly distributed throughout the sphere was the star that's not the
not with the with the earth either because the density is higher percent
this sort of gives you crude idea
so you have that moment of inertia
which is is
to calculate with that fifty m more square
and i did the same for
this is the radius of the earth
and you see
the moment of inertia of the earth
now i want to know how much kinetic energy of rotation these objects have all
the sun rotates about its axis in twenty six days
using one day
and so i finally convert everything to MKS units
and i find
these numbers for
rotational kinetic energy
now look at the number of the sun
one and a half times ten to the thirty six
great-grandfathers must have been puzzled about where
the solar energy came from
the light where it came from
conceivably it came from the patient may be
the sun is spinning down is slowing down and maybe the energy that we get
is nothing but
rotational kinetic energy
if that were the case however
since the sun
is four times ten to the twenty six watts
four times twenty six miles per second it would only last one hundred and twenty
five years
so you can completely forget the idea
that the energy from the sun
that we now know of course is nuclear but our great-grandparents did know that
that the energy would be tapped from kinetic energy of rotation
let's look at the earth
two and a half times ten to the twenty nine jules
let me try something
some fantasy on using crazy some ridiculous idea and i'll tell you for that is
remember that the world consumption
six billion people on earth consume about four times ten to the twenty two
every year
so if somehow
i thought if you could tap the rotational energy of the earth by slowing you
maybe we could use it to satisfy the world energy consumption
i don't know how to do it is of course complete fantasy
you would have to do
it's slow news down
by about
two point four seconds after one year
we slowed down after one year
it would be that they wouldn't last thing and that would last twenty four hours
with only two point four seconds
but of course after a billion years then
you would have consumed of all the rotational kinetic energy and then use would no
longer be rotated it is of course a crazy idea
but sometimes it's cute to speculate about crazy ideas
there is an object
which we call the crab pulsar
it is a neutron star
and it is located in the crab nebula
the crab nebula is the result of the supernova explosion that went off in the
thousand fifty four
and my next lecture i will talk a lot more about that
for now i just want to concentrate
on this neutron star
so here you have the data on the crap also
the mass of the crab pulsar is not too different from that of the sun
is about one and half times more
the radius is ridiculously small it's only ten kilometres all that mass is compact in
the ten kilometre radius sphere has rule when the density of ten two to fourteen
grams per cubic centimeter
so of course the moment of inertia is extremely modest compared to the sun
because the radius is so small
and the moment of inertia goes with the radius squared
if you look at
rotational kinetic energy the situation is very different
because this neutron star rotates
in thirty three minutes seconds about its axis
so it has a phenomenal
angular velocity
so if now you calculate
one have i omega squid
you get
a fantastic amount of rotational
kinetic energy
you get an amount which is
more than a million times more
you have
and this object
also in the crab nebula
is radiating
copious amounts of x-rays
if gamma rays
jets coming out
ionized gas
and we are certainly
that all the energy that this object is is producing
rotational kinetic energy
and i will give you convincing arguments why there's no doubt about
if you take the crab pulsar
and you
calculate how much energy comes out in x-rays and gamma rays and everything you can
observe in astronomy
then you find that it has power roughly
of about six times ten to the
thirty one what
a phenomenal amount if you compare with the sum by the way weighted sum
is only four times twenty twenty six watts
so the crap also alone
generates about two hundred fifty thousand times more power
the sun
we know the period of the pulsar two very high degree of accuracy
period of rotation
of the neutron star
o point o three
zero two
eight three
eight five
a three
the second that's what it is today
i called my radio astronomy friends yesterday
and i asked them what is the rotation period of the neutron star in the
crab nebula and this was the answer tomorrow however
it is longer
by thirty
six point four
nano seconds
so tomorrow
you have to add this
that means it's slowing down
the crab pulsar is slowing down
that means omega is going down that means one half omega square is going down
and when you do your homework which you should be able to do
to compare
the rotational kinetic energy today with rotational kinetic energy tomorrow
very very toy data mining application i'm doing a linear regression and pretending i don't
know how to do this analytically
so i have a data set and i have
the green line which is
a randomly drawn
the regression line so i'm doing importance sampling and say i'm going to draw a
whole bunch of possible
and then i'm going to from an arbitrary distribution consider sort of all all lines
and then i'm going to wait them is important something to say which ones actually
fit the data so that i can approximate things under the posterior distribution
most of these lines the rubbish like you know they have nothing to do with
the data and so the importance weight nothing really more like ten minus eight minus
nine ten minus fifty one and only a few of them by chance actually happened
to sort of go through the data and a very small number of them pick
up most importance weight
because this would be much more extreme if you had more than three parameters i
fixed the noise sesame something from two primitives and they what happens i be algorithms
running in this order although you could do this in parallel because there is no
really but you know i feel the sampler the sampler of the sample i finally
get one that's any good
and then i completely ignored that and continued during my time distribution in figure city
one again i get one is OK but then i make it worse again i
make it even worse than ever learn from what i'm doing and
shortly once i sort of got lines in the right ballpark i should be able
to do something with
so as a lot of you already know
the idea of markov chain monte carlo is to come up with algorithms that instead
of just randomly during IID proposals from distributions instead of all samples and take small
steps say
here is an algorithm that
i will go into more detail later the
does something different instead of drawing samples independently it proposes small changes to what you
currently got another is the time ordering developments running along here
so we started off
with this screen aggressive here
and the algorithm does protect that propose different regressor
and is coloured red to say oh that was second project
so it kept the same aggressive it and throw it away and can propose a
different proposed regressor was the last couple
we all want again and then eventually
small perturbation the otherwise traditional good
regression they wanted
in the right ballpark small perturbations tend to be good and so you get a
sequence of reasonable samples
the look as though they might come from the posterior distribution over russian lines that
go through the
so this is a series of pictures in data space and then in terms of
the parameter space of our model
the algorithm looks like this you've got parameters for the person that describe where the
line lies and the algorithm is moving around the space of parameters and the red
line shows that sometimes we propose to point in the parameter space which has low
posterior probability and so you don't go that you use the way you were in
in somewhere else
OK so the question is is the same as
what i literally said
sounds like that because i didn't add any stochastic element to it so i said
you know you could have something better go and if it's works you don't and
that would be in error and optimisation method some people call whole climbing this algorithm
if you tweak it
and it's better than definitely go but if you tweak it and it's worse than
sometimes you might go there anyway
and so that stops it from being an optimisation algorithm so we're not going to
be doing maximum likelihood of map nothing to find the best properties we going to
tend to move towards the best practice but also sort of randomly move around a
bit and that's what's going to lead to sample from the posterior distribution the main
this is we do i haven't explained how this works and think this is the
flavor the algorithm we want and then over the next few slides will understand what
actually come from
i have to say
what's the difference between simulated annealing and this algorithm this algorithm predates simulated annealing so
this algorithm was invented in the fifties and the seller must when they're doing developing
nuclear weapons and simulated annealing i think was the eighties
and simulated annealing uses this algorithm in its inner loop but then it does something
else to change the distribution at each iteration so this is a key part of
simulated annealing
OK so here is the key idea of markov chain monte carlo we're interested in
some probability distribution and might lie in high dimensional space we can only
evaluate it
up to you
there a constant but we can evaluate it pointwise up to a constant where we
like and we want to construct
some sort of random walk or diffusion process the will explore this distribution
will initialize i walk in some arbitrary way because often these problems that intractable we
don't know where places an apprentice start we initialize in some way and then we're
going to
follow a markov chain that is the way that we draw the next step only
depends on the previous step nothing else so we have a probability distribution over where
we can next given where we were before
and using that simple rule we going to want to take steps to wander around
and eventually after some burn in period of sort of finding the distribution will explore
the distribution such that if we looked at where all the
the points awarded to darwin to these blue dots after while i stopped during the
black line
but if you don't wear when those blue dots look as though the sample from
the distribution we're interested in
so what we're interested in doing is constructing markov chain finding transition operators all distributions
that if we were to simulate these markov chains have this property
and will
to draw samples for
yes there so i more
he what's they question the the samples are correlated and so in some ways not
fair of you know this there maybe not as good in some sense is independently
drawn samples rejection sampling gave us
is information pathways
so in a sense are two things here one is this complex
time shifting of the views you have other people around you know about friday nine
and this person for that person so forth and the other is that these indirect
paths can be fast potential conflicts in a sense for arguing is that social networks
affect the bound to what you might call
triangle inequality violations right in which this the quickest path between two people is not
the straight line but some other
round about what you see this is a very very very thing
and intuitively progressive rights everything about resemble manager talks each other employees more frequently each
is there going into a hundred and or right to adopt children reach up to
each other by talking to parents things like this
there are cases in which there is indirect routes and like actually is
some kind of of strange into a contact between these two microphones being forced to
wear OK so
in fact the social spread information is
and the out of date views people have each other is so pervasive you see
it and all sorts of areas across sciences social sciences humanities right so so so
of a physicist from about this they merely say anything about the light cone
right the light cone is the sort of cone in spacetime meaning away from point
so it's this point that
if two points are k
light years apart then
literally nothing happens within k years ago here can be here
in sociology and we'll talk about it on the talk this very very influential theory
called the strength of weak ties that occasional encounters with distant acquaintances can be very
very powerful force for conveying information information it's not known within are nearby social circles
and even if you look in
literature other
quite frequently as
literary device this notion of out of date information special time shifting between different parts
of the narrative as for example in this
grim but
now natural passage from the novel
what are the book of
one of the characters dies
finally while
back at home the life went on for a few more hours if nothing happened
the information had reached their home
so life continues the state of suspended animation this notion that information resides in different
places and has hasn't yet percolated to the rest of the world something that really
pervasive and a lot of different settings
i would like to understand
OK so how how we do that we try to take a social network that
which we have lots of people living on a regular basis
we're trying to look at
the views they have each other and these quick information channels through the network
as a formalism we're going to use one of the
one of the famous actually are given
the most worked for thing about information is not in the theory of
this distribu computing the notion of
vector clocks originally introduced by
what's really important to formalize one of the network has an out-of-date view another we
this implies that the next few slides really then you find notion of the network
far substructure the network is going to carry
most of
the potential potential for information flow and finally time permitting think about how all this
confusion could potentially be accelerated by local strategies that people use
OK has made this all talk about is going to a complete email history of
a period of two years roughly
eight thousand
faculty and staff TRB protocol from naming large university
i was ever actually going to focus on the most active email users in that
sense so
a core set of
over a thousand people who sent and received messages at least once in our continuously
for this period of two years OK and how information flow now forces that we
have all phone calls face-to-face communication and so forth and of course it's interesting issue
think about how the boundaries which are so as any analysis of things of that's
going to be
it's going to be
a useful list for this purpose we
done someone else's and other kinds of communication is the enron email communication wikipedia admins
and in the absence see similar results
so let's start with vector clarkson we formalise this idea of outdated information
so first in the century defined
we have no overview node you what it means these view of u at time
it's the most recent was to provide such information originating intuitive prime could still reach
the by time to
these you have a friday five PM was friday night
the vector clock as
the fundraising by important
refine a lot of work in the can is simply the vector he has to
use all strategies node c down here you can see this
at that time five what is seen no of a and b
well reason view was sometimes three most recently appears from time to and is always
completely up-to-date to
be similar some you
which is never actually
and we the information latency which is simply the difference between
now the current time in and the in the
the this
the set of all the clocks in our case the quadratic size structure everyone interview
everybody else we need to maintain
considered as the
ability to read out of this comment and incorporate the ideas into his or her
own books
OK finally the influence of terms
what are termed a appears in
link relationship between posting between x and y can be expressed in in formula number
and if we denote the influence of terms x as kx
we can calculate the influence of terms like this
for example to a
propagated from posting one to two
from posting two to three
originally anyone from posting one so
influence of terms a k
these three
similarly KB is one in cases one the point i want to emphasise here is
that only the propagated terms among link relationships are counted good part of it is
first of all it captures frequent terms
seems to have a better chance to be propagated and secondly
it picks up infrequent terms that are considered to be valuable by consumers
so there's a qualitative screening by consumer here
using this model we would like to
move on to the result of the empirical analysis we applied IDM to blog data
it's collected by both poles
from my nifty research institute in japan but this is a blog mining and consulting
service to advertisers and it collects over two hundred million blogs approximately ninety percent of
all blogs in japan so it's a pretty big coverage here and topic of the
analysis is a new shampoo product launched in march two thousand six it's called tsubaki
it means camilleri flower in japanese and the pack it looks like this
the reason we chose this as the topic of the analysis is that first of
all it's big news in the sample market in japan it was dominated by unilever
which sells clocks
MP and which spontaneous and college and cal you say though which cells wacky ranked
in fourth position however because of the challenge of this project product
it became number one selling company of san so there is a major change in
sample market and that's why we chose this as the topic of the analysis of
social because it features several celebrities in TV commercials it was heavily talked about in
the blogosphere
that's another reason we chose this as a topic we collect the data posted between
march which was the launch of the wacky two august two thousand six we screened
blocks containing the term tsubaki and we got a total of ten thousand eight hundred
sixty four postings input
links and trackbacks
statistical data is presented over there
we are interested in
marketing aspect of the data so what we did was we tagged manually states of
consumer purchase behavior so is
person i can use to research institute opened every twelve days
ten thousand eight hundred sixty three
blog postings and checked whether there is a evidence of purchase on that it like
a weather see
use the shampoo see smell that tried purchased bought those kind of wars and if
book talks about smart key some food but has not reached the
state purchase we classified it as a potential customer some of them more
unable to classify some of them could not be opened we had three thousand seven
hundred fifty four irrelevant posting irrelevant meaning marketing
twice you event some all these
book postings content awarded about key but they these postings talk about back in different
contexts as i mentioned its back is the name of flower so some of them
talked about
it's about key in the context of gardening and some of them of course
i mean many of them last splogs
these are the these are the example marketing armies fought about key she said the
company has used forty six million US dollars that's record-breaking advertising expenditure to push this
product they
i have hired famous actresses and models in japan attacked i of advertising movies japanese
women beautiful
it's called functional forelocks super-rich average which featured hollywood actresses so it's featured
it's meant to
give confidence to jeffries wyman the main ingredient or component of the santa camille oil
resulting bouncy hair like that
it also had the lowest level category
down there and she said also wanted to push that their corporate brand small light
but it it's a down there and they also wanted
they wanted to court remember
course you might remember the package
there is package and we wanted to know
which one of these marketing elements actually reached consumer and spread it in the blogosphere
and this
is the result
this table shows the top influential terms
by term frequency
in the left
and if
it is
they have a good idea
and different ranking
so what we can see from here is that ITN picks up frequent terms like
c don't wish the
three current and important terms but also
you can be in big trouble
your friends going to blow up
because the ideal gas law
works only in very small range of pressures temperatures for gases
we have other
functions equations of state for real gases this is an equation of state for ideal
gases for real gases
there's a whole bunch of equation of state and you can find in textbooks
and i'm just going to go through a few of them
the first one is uses something called the compressibility factor
compressibility factors instead of writing he a book
is equal to rt
which would be the ideal gas law
we put a five factor in
and the bias factor
it's called the
now we can put real incentive ideal for vi
is the compressibility factor
and the
is the ratio of
the volume of the real gas divided by what it could be a way for
an ideal gas
so have these less than one then the real gas
is more compact and then you you
created in one and the real gas
the atoms and molecules in the real graphs are repelling each other
in was behind bigger volume
and you can find this compressibility factors in tables
one of the compressibility factors for water for steam pressure and temperature you table and
if find
so that's one
example of
the equation of state
not a very useful one for our purposes in this class is another one is
the variable expect
it's a little bit more useful
what you do is you take that
large factor
and you expanded on taylor series
so we have
the real
of party supporters in every since they are right
under most conditions
it's pretty close to one
when is an ideal gas and then we have to
to that
and the correction is going to be more important
so the larger the volume is
whether it's the
the limit of p times because to zeros in large body of work large pressure
your the ideal gas rich so let's take
a taylor series in one over the bar
one five
where it's at
and these factors on top
which are going to the temperature
are the virial coefficients
and those depend on the substance
we have this
PDF here
this is called the second virial coefficient
and then
so you can get
you can actually find the graph of this vfd is something
the function temperature
is going to be some temperature would be if t is equal to zero
in that case your gas go look awfully like an ideal gas
something about the temperature is going to be possible
both and temperatures can
generally we ignore
the higher order terms here
so again if you do or
calculation where you're close enough to the ideal gas
and you need to design your
the engineer designing something that's got a bunch of
as is around
there right angles to 1 another that we've learned so somehow we have to figure
out a way to take orbitals that symmetric and convert them into orbitals that our
symmetric now what does that mean it is symmetric so that means that each bond
has exactly the same energy
same behind symmetric bonds means equal equal energy which means equal length if we can
do that will end up a symmetric non polar and non-polar molecule
this stuff people for a while until another fella came along Linus Pauling
the famous for a lot of things 1 of which is 1 of which is
covalent bonding and he said he said well when we take a look at this
1 if I were able to mix
what if I were able to mix the orbital
right what if I were able to mix makes these orbitals
In produced
what he called hybrid
but on the a hybrid
In how would you do that well
this is worth thinking Cantonese let's just mixed let's just mix the 2 s and
2 p orbitals right you to the orbitals and I need I know I need
to come up with with 4
symmetric equally bonds and well let's just say strong structure here
and the right mix the 2 s the 2 pieces and I cut in the
buyer my hand rule if I come up with for
I've got what I've got I've got 2 states here 3 states here to here
and if I came up with the bonds for
by the underlying problem like this and there have
I have I have
of bonds that are of equal of equal energy and he called this s p
3 and s p 3 hybrid right and 3 s p 3 hybrid and I
if the drawing justice
but let's take a look at how we do this this is the of the
group graph left this is the s orbital symmetric these are the p orbitals
and these are what these other the probability densities right our friend Escherichia told us
that this is what that if you solve for the wave function this is what
the probability densities look like if I now hybridise these if I take these and
I make for symmetric just the just the the s p 3 orbitals the hydrogens
non-Aryan notice that this the orbital looks
kind of funny Scott big big but a little old and they're sort of back
into it so this forms a tetra he'd tetrahedra which forms the SP three hybrid
orbitals now
the hydrogen on the other hand the hydrogen has symmetric s orbitals and now
protagonist is another and just another way to look at what
another way to look at it it takes these S P 3 hybridized orbitals and
you a hydrogen to each 1 and now what you have
you have you have a symmetric and
symmetric molecule and would say
we have a molecule where we put
but the carbon to carbon in the center and we go up like this like
this and not the back and now you have attacked region
with people
equal length equal length equal length bonds and
and it's going to be symmetric now would be will be polar and nonpolar getting
a little ahead of ourselves what makes something polar versus non polar well
if this is if this bond has completely identically equal sharing of electrons then this
bond will be
will be non polar
however were saying that that's not the case for hydrogen and carbon these this bond
will be will be non polar so that means we have 1 2 3 4
non polar bonds
in here and yet the molecule symmetric
and non polar
what's going on well what's going on is the carbon is of the exact center
of the tetrahedra and so
the non polar bonds cancel each other out the 2 sources of charge cancel each
other out and you get a non polar you get a non polar molecule OK
so that's what that's what as appalling but he did a little bit better on
Louis by the way I didn't get a Nobel Prize but pulling did get a
Nobel Prize
so you say to yourself well loses the guy came up with the came up
with the idea why did you get the nobel prize what he came up with
the theory but he didn't reduce it reduces to something quantity palling did that
so let's go back and take a look at the energetics again let's look at
2nd look at the eugenics now last day of week we talk to look at
the energetics of the ionic bond right and we wrote something that looks a lot
the energy is equal to minus the Madeleine constant times Avogadro's number
if you want to over 4 pi epsilon zero are 0 and we knew that
if we know the crystal structure we can get the maximum constant not a problem
and what we need to do is to get this what we get that well
if we have a
if we just take for for example energy all let's try and g magnesium chloride
just as an example we put the magnesium 2 plus here and then we put
the oxygen here
to minus and we know that this gives us our are 0
right so we can go and measure that we haven't said much about how to
measure it but you can measure
but if we wanted to get the chlorine we could just put the chlorine over
so there is this nice slogan from excess perception
in fact this is the basic difference between images and text
image in indexed when you don't have syntactic and semantic analysis words
and birds are very useful
if a a lot
it's unfortunately not that useful and isolated peaks do nothing
except which has
o brightness value hundred immediately
there's nothing whatsoever about what's in there
what's in the image so that's the problem we have to move these semantic categories
we have to sort of break up the image into objects labelled them water grass
the labeling could of course be
extended hierarchically
so let's give you a little bit about what the problem is
the problem is what we call category recognition
it's not recognizing something exactly the same but something
is some
a set of objects which
shared a family resemblance
these are all phases of flight these planes and events cellphones but does
we can humans have no problem
identifying this is one category even though they are not identical
so if you just took the images along with the only differences in those vectors
well those would be quite significant here
but humans have no problem
so so let's go and look at some of the some of the key ideas
so there's an idea that goes back actually a hundred years which is due to
someone called d'arcy thompson
who was the mathematical biologist nearly hundred years ago
and he was studying you know this because for example
and what is common to all these scholars
all these ideas of faces
so here is the basic idea was that
you think of the car
describing shape is hard
but describing changes among shapes is not that
so the idea is that you have some canonical shape and then you have transformations
of that shape
which take you to these other examples
and it's mathematically rather similar to the following idea you have some complex nonlinear thing
i mean
you don't know how to deal with it but operating point you can linear is
characterized by
its tangent plane
four years he served in a series expansion that sort of thing
and that's kind of what is going to do
a shape and then we consider deviations from that ship and those deviations are easier
to understand than the shape in the abstract
this of course this idea essentially today the topics because more things from one ship
to another but it really going back a hundred years
some of the observations so this is an example of that newscast capital meant to
illustrate the importance of faith
that's why line drawings works
we have taken this image and to place
got the
it in the country and even the one to be replaced by a set of
straight lines
so it's really been boiled down to its fewest bits in some way
we can recognise this and how and if i told you the person did
the yellow and
and the pixies in this image according to let you know that it is a
so so there's a lot of abstraction and generalisation in the interpretation of an image
this is going to be slide but there are hierarchy in this notion of the
notion of categories
so for example cats in order find a memory members so is a hierarchy
the which we must be aware of
and recognition can be at these different levels of abstraction that could be something which
i don't recognise what i say
point to fall again
OK that's that's a good enough on civil said of the positive was it it
to be able to say
this is my cat one t
then there is another key which is that object parts they have subparts and so
and in fact we can think of this for humans but actually it operates in
a high level of objects to objects are part of scenes so right now we
are part of lecture seen
there are people chairs and so on
and there are some arrangement which is much more loose spatial arrangement
you swiss same immediate partonomy so we have to worry about taxonomies that part of
psychologists have actually given us a sense of
how many categories
humans can deal with this estimate of thirty thousand
so when the scalar
visual recognition system that's kind of the target to which we have to go to
on the order of thirty thousand visual categories the number of words in english and
obviously more
but i mean i would like to create hope charity doesn't necessarily have visual accommodation
in somebody abstract sense
currently we are dealing with more concrete things
so thirty thousand that's what we have to go to
and i'll give you examples which is illustrated that then we have to on the
order of hundred
so we to do the state of computer vision is on the order of hundred
categories and we need to to go up
basically two orders of magnitude from that
and it's not just computing
the axes is being fixed and then you're considering different status
you use this station and so this big l stands for like the that's the
likelihood function
o one
and something that people sometimes get confused about so this probability can be a probability
mass or can be a probability density
if the axes
belong to a discrete space
then they're going to probability masses and if they belong to a continuous space taken
probability densities and he
so it we multiplying all these problems together and if their probability masses and we're
going to be multiplying numbers together less than one and these probabilities so the the
product probability is going to be a number that is very small much less than
one but still positive
and so actually computationally if you want to implement this
you take the log of the probability of b summing them and then you don't
get numerical underflow but if
if the axis belong to a continuous space like euclidean space then the probability densities
can be bigger than one
and so actually the
the likelihood can be bigger than one
so it's not a about your software
if the maximum likelihood is bigger than one
so say had
is the argmax
o the stator
the sum from my cause one to
one of the log likelihood
of state
and and
x i
the the logarithm function
and strictly increasing
and so
the product of
likelihoods is precisely equivalent to maximizing the sum of them
likelihoods so this is called the log likelihood and the principle says that we want
to maximize the sum of money
log likelihoods
so if that's clear then i can move on to an example which is going
to be more relevant to
logistic regression
and this is a very well known example
but it still
worthwhile to
work it out
is it
for anybody who hasn't seen this derivation before it's got some twists and turns
we're going to work out the maximum likelihood estimate
the parameters
of the newly distribution
what's a bernoulli distribution
it's a coin flip
and so it really it so it is a special case of a binomial distribution
binomial distribution is the distribution of the number of successes if you do n coin
flips and the bernoulli distribution
is the number of successes if you do a single coin flips n equals one
and more
let x
but not
random variable
remember the notation capital letters for random variables and then
lowercase letters for outcomes of random variables
so the
i guess is the conflict of notation before used capital explore the space of all
possible and so here x is the random variable
and it's possible outcomes are
zero and one
lies close or some new descriptors that we defined by means of background knowledge to
do so by using the descriptors to extracted we can define a new by means
of the
use new description and discovery can also include background knowledge and they a key
so in that case we have by the corresponding going
the first step is the task the specification of the
a portion of the current testing for the task in december two thousand four the
first of all to be in traditional datamining application to because we simply specify the
attributes of of the table the testing of water mining but this goal
o processor of the notion of the one thousand eight is interesting for all these
indicating our specific case firstly we can simply select that of table because in this
case we will not consider interaction can be between the different objects in the days
of old
because of special that cannot be represented as a single stable of relational databases typically
represented by different tables and express the property of objects and the interacting relations among
so all we have to specify that belong to different tables and the relationship between
these two people the second problem is that classical all the mining one this is
to select data typically OK you can use it to combine ss and processing of
data about it and we have to select the attributes either directly to the input
for the mining could in this case is that the article to will be the
coordinates of the
the boundary of only one of the coordinates of the line percent all of the
point that represents a special objects and perform mining company called it is not interesting
before so it's important to perform a complex transformation inserted data in order to transform
these physical information that is the information that we have in the special days in
and your format is a human interpreter so all
representing the properties and relations that are interesting before the
for specific tasks in this case the first order formulas can be very useful to
is the data transformed form
so the solution that to we have is that is that is one of key
we select exactly the geographical objects testing for answer for example that interact mining geographical
object belonging to you draw graffiti or we are interested in OWL
o atoms on and specifying the descriptors to wind and to use into in describing
these data and and description it is automatically generated by the system is represented in
first order in nature
an example for example is the object query where we are selecting all the objects
that belong to decide and twenty six of them are dismissed object belong to differently
yes and in this case we use all the descriptors of for describing the visitors
so we want to it data we take it to the that belong to these
model for example about this trade and
compute the properties of the industry to for example the extension property until after the
election property and so on
and the notion that among these objects for example we have the line to align
relations between these objects so these salad that we have a selected from the this
is automatically transformed into these the first order representation of all the and if we
think to the process to perform when we look at these images except is OK
i'm looking at major where you have a blue line that is probably another line
that seems to be a street and is line crossing and so on and so
when i look at this image i need if be think to the properties really
i was it using it to describe them on the
the kind of that
that is the same belonging to the idea
o percent before the logical opposite by out of this is the list of descriptors
that are actually implemented in
in terms of the system can be used in the US again query language obviously
the list of the script can be extended in a very simple way anyway this
is the people that we have decided we do the same colleague of the one
is the department that specify what are the properties of the properties relation interesting for
them because they have two different approach to measurement of germanic on topological of the
interaction on the program
the reason
but particularly in the way of looking at the data organised in there is a
relation that is this one
so when i have a very very far see and can make that are altogether
it might be
this also makes sense
you also seem
he is
first one
even then it can be quite
so here is an example of which i took it
the group of christopher myers stanford
there is also mention that it's going to take commission
they compare
which is
well actually
critical edition
he was
two and named entities to
for instance was signed
first look
but if you classify in text
this leaves
for instance in new york location
maybe not
because the
in this form
or any
and both mention
but usually use
so that that's what we
in this course
so we have
it certainly is
you could use this information
the second time see
so you use
like a lot information for this cause
certainly get see this with the
otherwise just look at it
census classes
in terms of some
so in text
that is the
so you can exploit
so this is this is also what has been
the two the two stage approach
and it's quite successful
so this not
they tested data
in natural language
and they have
why would they not
so i'm going to be
for each
but some of them
it's limited
that is the case
he also semantic
which is the
a little bit more
so the first thing to say
and you see that
here we have people from
when one
they also features from the complete this course and from local windows
for me
and they are the team
for all these classes conversation decision to use
the sum is over eighty percent
thank you
f one score
this is all about the same room actually
they have also
we have this gives
this good for approximate in humans we have quite good examples
in this case
are the argument that we to station because even better results
one hundred percent for this named entity recognition task
which was to be
in addition his local features
you're trying to get
which you look for information
just not so that
after the first step for
incorporated as feature
in your next classification
somehow could come
chapter section of unsupervised learning methods
the reason i actually made some results because not all cells
the results of hand crafted signed according to the flight because
it's not all the human performance in some
in the nineteen percent so users
it consists
you team
so they make this this has been shown
well there is a lot of i notation
for instance before by
like people
people were satisfied by their life science and it is shown that
even well actually people like these these persons they make sense they are not consistent
in semantic except for creation
this tractor tyre so we need to do it so there is this great
so usually human labeling well i
the show that it was the and it was
nine ninety five six percent
he is
way that's interesting but a part of the rotation
this slide also has a sort of the point which is the center say that
the data of interesting data we also get multiple prototypes may not be just one
six with rotating maybe another six nine in this case is one six nines so
we have one six to rotating and another nine in another portion of space this
a little bit of of manifold living in this high dimensional space is what the
actually lives on
now in practice
this is a city model right because of course
the data may undergo several distortions far more than we've shown here
for example digits as well as undergoing rotational
they undergo a process known as stating where the stroke the digital becomes fast friends
in translation as well so they move around in that box that's possible too
the point is the data structure
and this is almost how i think of data structure how i define data structure
there's me and so skipping one aspect here
which is to do with conditional independence is another way of dealing with high dimensional
data is to specify conditional independencies and this isn't that the the way i tend
to think of data with structure is that we expect fewer of these types of
and there are dimensions in the original dataset
and and that's the real world
inherent dimensionality by data
not the three thousand six hundred forty eight
pixel space is the number of sort distortions it's going
that still leaves is a difficult question because it may be for example
consider seven zip and modeling all sevens we'd have to have prototype sevens which have
slice across drawn we're slice across the
the upper right portion of the city and that's going to be a slightly different
prototype and that type seven may undergo a slightly different set distortions than the other
types of sevens
so in this high dimensional space where we've got these multiple distortion is going on
in may not be that it's got an explicit dimension even it may be the
different parts of the space have different slightly different dimensionality but
the general conclusion is that we should look
to deal with high dimensional data by looking for lower dimensional non linear embedding
so that's the basic sort of motivation
why you're interested in doing
dimensionality reduction
so just before we go on i want to do a little bit of notation
i'm going to be working with
data space
well my data matrix is why
so this is the observed data the six that we've seen the rotated eight seven
now i'm going to be looking at low dimensional latent or embedded spaces
now attend school in latent space is as artifact of probabilistic sort of language
for a lot of dimensionality my latent space is going to be denoted q
the originality of the data space is going to be demented noted big
big d in six case was three thousand six hundred forty eight
and then i'm going to be dealing with an data points where
and in the six case was three hundred sixty for each degree rotation
now i'm going to draw my data in terms of the data matrix which is
called the design matrix so why
has n rows and the columns
and it's made up of each data point is a vector y
from the first row out to the enthroned this column notation indicates the vector these
should always be filled in this column vectors but not the transpose here so this
matrix here has and the rows and the columns
that's important this is the other way of writing it when it is each feature
of the data
the first feature after the the feature
and the same with the latent variables now this this way of writing the matrix
is important because when we come to write and covariance matrices in matrix notation it's
sort important that's the way around we're using
i'm actually not going really make use of that mapping matrix or the entry matrix
although i thought i might when i was writing this like
OK so these are the main sort of important things the latent variables is going
to be my representation
all the that data in the reduced dimensional space so within
this examples these are my latent variables x one x two
OK so just to sort of recovery capitulate a is vector from the ith row
comma code that sort of matlab notation
and a coal college a is a vector from the jth i column should say
and x and y are design makes now
and all the centring there but the sample covariance this it's important the sample covariance
s is given by one of the number of datapoints times y transpose why OK
so why
that is the center version of data
so the centering matrix takes y
and roses mean that's basically it's effect so why is what will typically be working
with which is a censored version of our data if y had dissented i don't
know how used to this notation you what you can write down the covariance as
one of and y had transpose what happened
the centred inner product matrix and it is important to you already and think it's
been seeing some kernel stuff
is the kernel matrix why hats while transpose so
well there is an inner product t appears on the outside which can slightly confused
people but this is the standard statistics notation for the inner product matrix and the
covariance matrix so that's sort of important message from the notation
OK so
how we get into
dimensionality reduction
the way we get used to do it is by distance matching
so kinds of classical statistical approach
so we represent our data via sort of proximity how near they are to each
different types of proximity data
one type of similarities and the other is dissimilarity one example of the dissimilarity matrix
is a distance matrix
so we're just be using mostly
the euclidean distance
so that's the l two norm of the difference between two vectors so it's simply
this my notation for the l two norm two data points
this is the distance between them is denoted d i and d j
college a
and this is just the
matrix way of expressing which is the square root of this vector inner product with
the vector skin from the distance between the
this attraction between two vectors
now for any given data set can display that distance matrix
well i display in the distance matrix
the sixs states rotated sixes
this is what it looks like
so what we see is
this is zero down here is dark blue
the red dog right here is about
and a half thousand but the scale is really that important here because we can
always use rescale things
you'll notice immediately is about eight hundred eighty
degrees rotation so these are the data point labels remember each one is the degree
so my collaborators MIT in total collapse group use support vector machine to distinguish two
types of leukemia
OK lymphoblastic and myeloid leukemia OK the the sometimes mixed together
now when actually ran the support vector machine they find one patient with a very
large alpha value
and as i said could be an outlier of could be just correct but unusual
point they went back to the medics and query this particular sample and it being
a patient who have been wrongly classified in terms of the senior
OK so you can spot
what's going on from alpha this harks back to a common to made at the
that we have much greater interpretability as this model
then something new network
OK so of course i think to try and get the ends of the support
soft margins and might break
right so my story so far has been nice simple story of data which is
very separable OK somebody else new audience what happens when my data is not separable
they also problem is to exploit the second point in that band which i mentioned
i said that the jury theoretical generalisation bound does not depend on the dimensionality of
the space
and in fact therefore
this means
i can make
my data
from input space into a high dimensional space
and the reason why i want to do that the many reasons why my wife
do it one of them is by mapping from a low dimensional space to high
dimensional space if my data is horribly into mashed in a low dimensional space
in in high dimensional space it will be separable
indeed that's indeed will be doing now
is always the case if i'm at from
not separated data
into high dimensional space it will separate what was found is and always the case
indeed i think it's actually cleared would be
some of you may know the xall
four and parity problem
don't have hands can't quite sketch on the ball but
if i consider q in which i moved plus
minus plus minus on all the edges OK
that date is maximally international OK
now the simplest one is actually the xall
problem whatever
and here just mentioned plus minus minus plus OK
now i can draw line which separates the pluses and minuses OK
however if i go from that two-dimensional space to three dimensional space
i move the pluses in the board the two months is out
i can easy draw a hyperplane that separates the two
OK this three-dimensional i can do is in three
but i can't do plus minus minus plus can't separate the line into
OK so nd if i go to this high dimensional space i can separate the
and that's my trick
to handle
into mesh data indeed i've never found problem
i can't handle
using a support vector machine and the right kind
yes the question
if i typically use come under the gauss income which about to use
again i think i strictly an infinite dimensional space so i've never
i've done in parity two spirals problem
on many different horrible problems with it
guess can never found an instance where the sum sort the problem
non-zero training error
it may be the case yes
for any parity x would be the case yes
some problems where everything is the support vector
typical real life datasets can be down to a of the data support vectors just
depends data OK now
OK probably when she was a good idea to map the high dimensional space
now one point of course is high dimensional space
is going to have to be an inner product space OK now
let's just go back to the object i had
we notice
but my data was here
as i remarked in particular
i could redefine the exit collect xbx prime
and ex-prime y
x OK
so if you like really
all my data is in the four former over dot product x dot x OK
so that's where my data appears
and hence the end of the day
if i'm at a high dimensional space i must match
the inner product x star that's goes to phi x dot phi x
and five
will be my mapping function
four input space to this high dimensional space which we call feature space
why aren't things
about kernel methods
is that i do not need to know what the mapping function is
by choosing kernel
which are due shortly
at thirty frames per second
and idea the freedom domain
it turns out the translation case we can obviously look at cross cross correlation
and in the frequency domain i can do this
order in log whereas in the spatial domain is order in square so i actually
but i still something here
things and so i can i can speed things up to a reasonable man but
that if i actually
every pixel
with in
within the template needs to be looked at
if i need to look at every pixel in the template then this if taken
but bombing what if i can start getting cleverer than sampling to say like i
think about only need to have
in pixels or in different representations of the pixel rather than looking at all the
different representations i can speed things up a lot more but so people use FFT
is also not just for
learning discriminative classifiers but also just even if i did generates empirically noisy examples showing
misaligned examples i could still take that linear
classifier the spatial classifier and
value added very quickly in the fourier domain and this is kind of something that
you signal processing things about the benefit fifty by doing something in regular correlation
have some problems elegant but negative images
so the negative images just circular shifts so sometimes it make sense of the thousand
things objects in natural images very always and scale
then just translation so you only have negative examples in terms of translation what happens
if i wanted invariance scale rotation other types of things the kind of limited there
and it does not it doesn't give you add noise regularized but a lot time
it doesn't give nice graceful degradation if
the object isn't precisely aligned that's another problem
so i think you were left with the problem of synthetically obtaining positive and negative
examples of sort of back to that again
so those two problems with that collecting positive and negative training samples and learning computationally
feasible model with large dimensionality so
in large and a lot of the so what i mean by that is that
if i think of my imply
now general with ten quite generically as you can think of it as an image
but move on to essentially this a parametric representation of my classifier all the time
i'm not going to be able to visualize my template but in vision i'm just
going to keep on talking about as my template
and the thing going have to do is that so i need to have a
way of learning something that even though might imply for the classifier that i'm going
to deal with has a very large feature spaces say like seven twenty one twenty
minutes at the very small four hundred four hundred three parameters and a lot of
examples of hundreds of millions of images you have learn from that and obviously there's
a lot of machine learning stuff out there to do that
generally for objects now this coming through again kind of face because that's where a
images on that this recurring true for a lot of other objects like motorcycles cars
street signs things like that the general problem is if you want to come to
get an approximate what kind of box area of an object like i should discourse
always the scale orientation translation what i mean is that here for instance the eyes
nose and mouth there are exactly aligned its is basically you want to be within
a reasonable reasonable proximity and the reason that you want that's not just because you
lazy you want that noise you're essentially building into this this idea of the graceful
degradation you bucolic giving it a bit to give it doesn't have to be precisely
on ice this happens precisely when i was because i can sample at all always
point i want to give it some people so
and we do that across i mean a lot of space that's out there but
we do that cross arm
a lot of that
one day ones what they actually troll the web interface images and they actually they
keep on showing up in the millions of faces
another object and then generating negative examples is actually pretty cheap
i think it's basically come to get if you've got an image
and you know the sort of place and the i can just essentially randomly sampled
from the threat the negative image in this great databases to do that capture forever
in caltech he's got his caltech one one object database and i think the only
one that too
there's a couple of and they using the generic object recognition but it's actually a
great resource for getting negative images because they got one hundred one different classes of
objects and you basically go through so well
i know that i'm not looking for these and then use basically sample pose free
negative images and since it's actually pretty cheap with the world wide web metal lot
easier to get good images and so
you can kind of do that on and on and on
as the commission
and so it so the brain in sort of positive and negative examples now it
will only classifier to discriminate between large training sets of positive and negative samples we
need an that list sequentially because essentially with one day computers
if we're dealing with thousands if not millions of images we cuts rule that memory
even all the time with the memory hierarchy and computers to we might not want
to because it might really slow down learning things that we want something that can
can learn sequentially or you break down the problem to make it a lot easier
so so cannot obviously boosting boosting something that obviously comes to mind because you might
be able to speak can learn single features going to keep going back iteratively and
reinforcing and other things like if you think but obviously like with within SVM this
so what is the BCI part and that we would like to predict on which
side and when
the thing attempting will happen
before it actually happened
OK so that's the first BCI type thing
the second is that we imagine some movement
and we use it for sake because the control of playing brain pong as you
have seen in the early video
this lecture
i will first
talk about this the real movement
and for this
some of the underlying physiology
imagine if you move your right hand
at t equals zero
this is over
c three this is an electrode on the list left hemisphere
so if i
to a lot of these experiments on average all the signals in c three
then i might get to curve like this
in fact they do it and
the interesting thing
that you that you see here
and do you actually see anything is enough contrast or should
so you see that
about point six
seconds before
the actual typing
there's an activity building up
this is the so-called but i just potential preparatory potential
so with this
your brain has to move
o thing
so this
another thing which is the point two five seconds you actually
your brain
prepares movement
if you react who saw him OK so that would be a reaction thing OK
sorry for that
so it's much faster much steeper
but the integral is about the same
so interestingly somewhere around point three seconds we become aware of all upcoming decision
and there's some
o thing
somewhere here
it's called the point of no return so so until then we can veto the
decision so we can decide not to do it
after we've past this point we have you know issued a command and it's being
executed so it you you smash the the door of your car car the keys
inside you know the situation and that's where you have passed on from return although
while you smash you already know that you know you shouldn't be doing that
OK so
the idea now is to to be predicting you know whether left or right away
that all the movement will take place way before
this time equals zero
OK let me
talk a little bit about this maybe you just look at the lower
set of graphs
and i just play around with it a little bit
so this is
left trying to left and right hemisphere
right and left hemisphere
just explain this a little bit more detail the system knows this is a picture
from above
and this shows so to say that the distribution of the measurements that you too
can get on on average
in the repeated here
the stopping criterion is satisfied we stop adding conditions here
when the we stop
i don't know negative example is covered by this rule
so when we have produced such a clean rule which covers only the positive examples
or some other performance measure are
ten is satisfied like the quality of the rule is
let's say the classification error of the rule is below a certain classification error which
has been a lot
we then had this rule to the set of rules to delete all the positive
examples from
covered by the rule from the set of examples and we repeat
building the set of rules until now
when we stop building the set of rules
until stopping criterion is satisfied like
if we have exhausted the set of all positive examples
or alternatively we could have a certain
performance heuristic measure over the set of rules being
under certain
user defined
OK so this is just a slightly more complicated version of what we had before
where we have replaced the simple stopping criterion
used individual road construction by a slightly more complicated one
and here
having replaced the simple stopping criterion for rule set construction which is initially when all
the positive examples have been covered by some other potentially slightly more complicated heuristic criterion
for stopping the construction of a set of rules
now how do we learn one rule
in the approach which we have
just outside
we said well we say class
c class one
we see i reaches the selected class
let's say one attribute
let it i equals
let's suppose we have a number of conditions
now the question is when we learn such a rule
how do we
decide which
that's the value to add
to the body or to the condition part of the rules
again that would be some heuristic evaluation measures telling us which attribute value is the
similar as in decision tree learning when we had to decide which attribute is the
best to be put in the mold of the decision tree now we're asking ourselves
the question which actually the value is the best
for describing the particular class
of obviously we have
for all attributes
we have all the possible
so we are searching
through the space of all possible values
now again this is the search problem like
everything we are doing in artificial intelligence it's the search problem looking through the space
of all possible sets of of all the possible rules which could be constructed from
the attribute values which are used to describe our data
so which of these attribute values is the best to be put as the
as the first condition
in the rule
that would be some heuristic which will tell us which of them is the best
and in greedy search
the algorithm decides one
attribute value like this one suppose this one
put there
and decide then
once it has sixty set to value which is the next best attribute values to
be put in the condition
that has to do with greedy search once you fix one then you can fix
the one
and so on and so on attentively
that is
beam search approach
used in heuristic search
in beamsearch at each point used for instance a if the being
size is five to say well this is one of the best this is one
of the best this one is one of the best this one is one of
the best and that's one
and this is the
first second third fourth fifth best
we have been size of five
now for all of them
we say well
what is the next best attribute value if we added to the condition of the
and again
for each of these
we have five
and from all these possibilities we against select five
so that would be being search
so obviously greedy search
is more efficient
but through greedy search you can also lose
some better option which you would have gotten if you had
the longer look at
so there is a trade-off between efficiency
and the possibility that you will is me some better option by not doing beam
and of course the most time consuming would be exhaustive search just looking at all
the possibilities but usually you don't have time the for doing that
OK so
suppose we fix the head of the rule
the conclusion part of the rule to a certain class
like contact lenses heart
and now we are building one particular group
namely the conjunction of attribute values
we're asking ourselves what is the first attribute value which is the best
to be added in the condition part of the world
we have a large number of possibilities
content fences hard if i think is in the snow
or if astigmatism is yes or if the production is normal or if the production
is reduced and so on and so on so these are all the possible
if then rules with a single conjunction
in the condition part of the world
so which of them is the best
so let's look at the distributions
well here we have zero zero twelve very good
it's a clean room
what about this one
five four three if look in terms of entropy
we would obviously
be very happy with this rule because it has the lowest entropy
it is also very good because it has a high coverage
namely this rule covers twelve examples
out of
the set of twenty four examples i believe which we have in the training set
so this would be a very good candidate
what about these
some of these may be good candidates
if we add some other condition to the body of the rule
as such they are not very good rules
OK so
shall we
another condition to the
so this rule well it doesn't make sense
adding another attribute value is the conjunctive description here because this is already
nice clean rule covering twenty twelve instances of a class not
so we would no longer add conditions to the body of this rule
a really simple dumb way of doing dimensionality reduction is called feature selection
well this extract dimensions from original data y
and we'll make up
x by extracting columns y just putting them into works
so that's just
representing data by a subset of the features in the original data it's a common
problem in itself but it is a specific example of dimensionality reduction
so select for x
in turn
the column from y
but most reduces this error
user here until we have the desired to the desired number of columns in x
now it turns out
to minimize this area
it should be if x sorry
we compose x by extracting the columns of y which have the largest variance now
what is going to derive the algorithm
and so on
so the squared distance
that's right of
square nasty square root sign
so the squared distances the sum
across the dimensions of the square
of the
the difference between the two data points here
so these are scalars now
this is the
i data points k feature is just the sum of the squares for that
now what we can do is we can only three order the columns of y
without affecting the distances so i can just move columns y around without changing the
so will will choose an ordering of y
to help us in algorithm so
i will say
the first q columns of y those that will best represent the distance matrix by
definition because i can reorder without changing so i'm going to say that the first
q columns of y
those that i'm going to use for x
what we can do is we can substitute x for y
the first k
so now i x is
OK cause want to q because of the ordering
this means that we can replace the distance in latent space
which was this delta square
is equal to x
minus xjx i minus xj
for the k feature
with the relevant wise for his first q values OK
so this is sort of
the relative orderings notational purely notational if i want to do the ordering
so the ordering ordering like this means that i can rewrite this as k cause
one to q
over y
if i was to define an ordering
it was like the last and in the first and then the middle one writing
this some
it would be quite awkward
so it's just simply notational so that i can write this song
equal to this OK
and i can do without loss of generality so that's the nice thing about
OK so our objective looks like this
well because
we can rewrite the deltas as some of the k cause one to q
and the d is the sum of the chemicals wanted to DD necessarily being larger
than q
we can basically rewrite our objective as being k cause q plus one to d
so the remaining dimensions of y basically the sum
of the interpoint distances from the dimensions why we've left out
we can then introduce the mean of each dimension and then put it inside these
brackets here
so i've introduced the mean twice so i can do that
it's just a convenient thing so you can see these the form of this
by introducing meaning to here
like that and then multiplying out
that some sorry should be across all these back into terms here that's not very
should be across all attracted terms
one multiplied allied that i can also bring in some of the farms inside so
that's about all the bracketed terms but here i'm bringing the some inside
this some applies
not to here
but does apply to here
they need to have a factor of n appear outside
guide so
finding the sum over ice over in it doesn't apply to
this i hear but multiplies it by hand
so they bring it past this i i factor and out the front and then
i get some
over j appearing in front of this one
in this case here i get get some of the j there
and then the sum of the eye drops in
inside here
because there's no ice in this out the term here
similarly i get a factor and appearing outside that guy
what you should notice that
is this looks very similar to the variance in fact is n times the variance
all of that column
and that's the end times the variance of the j th column that in time
so the case columns and that in time the variance of the k column two
these guys
so this is the main
this is just the sum over all values both of these guys just go to
because the end up just being the mean minus the mean
and you some with very thick expectation
and the actions come from this policy p
and for convenience we divide by so we can well you which is bounded between
zero and
so that's the value
so the expected reward some of an agent p
which acts
in environment sigma
the goal of the agent should be to maximize its value
it's this
take marks of this round value
are p sigma
and by definition then
the value of this agent
of p sigma
which is defined as we star
it's larger equal than the value of any other policy
in this environment sigma
i mean
there's nothing really going on
well you can do is i mean policies something complex which depends on the past
and so on you can rule that out
and if you rolled out let's do it here the value of the optimal value
environment sigma is just this expectimax sequence
i show you in the next slide
and the optimal action is just you you replace the first
mark's point argmax
so that's a really explicit i mean you have your observation and action spaces which
are not written down there is reverts so there's really no explicit expression of computing
the next action
given the past observations actions
let's call it
expectimax sequence of three or four
OK so here's the tree
so he written in explicit form
and job by showing you how to write it recursively
and he also write it recursively
so the value
at the time
OK minus one
the value given the action
and the maximum of the action because you want to take the optimal action
OK you have two actions
so the value
so these are the
these are the q will use from tavistock and this is the this is the
value of this
state value function this the state action value function
he's is
so sum of all reworked but you can recursively put in the value
for the future so starting from time k
it is the reward of k and this is all the reverts the future including
the expectations with respect to the optimal policy and then you take expectation
so we have this recursive expression you know this
together with this
and then you can go on i mean
this is the same as this you just next
the difference
the standards
notation in reinforcement learning literature they're always talking about state
i didn't talk about state here
i talk about
only observations actions
and everything you can depend on the complete history
so i don't need anything
so you can say that the complete history is my state
but this is not really useful
because i mean if you talk about state have implicit
the idea that space no repeat in time and you get some statistics over the
but history is growing so no history is not observed more than one
so interbreeding then it as a state
it's not really very useful
if you have no environment
we just plugin
so the environment is always move you plug in the first six months
and we have done
so if you move the optimal policy in the sense that no other policy for
an agent to hire me expect revived
and the mean expectations what you want because move the true distribution so
the problem is solved
apart from some computational problems
which i will ignore
it concludes even game
very except for instance
you could model your environment is an optimal chess player i mean optimum minimax player
plays some deterministic game for deterministic
in fact is also probability distribution is concentrated on one
on one policy
OK so i mentioned there is no principle problem in computing the actions as long
as the movie is known
the spaces
and computable the spaces x y finite horizon
of course a huge practical problem and we all know that
i mean you can do
minimax in ingest up to the end
but this is about from the oceans and especially about the philosophical foundations and so
will ignore this computation
because one first we should get the foundations right
but is still not done
things drastically change if it is not known
and that's the real if cut real life case built the robot throw it
somewhere and it should work
we don't have you
precise description of moon or even a probabilistic one
OK so what we do is
if you listen
the other part of my talk the natural thing is now OK let's go to
the basement
new unknown
i mean reinforcement learning you often go to temporal difference learning you do all kinds
of things which sometimes work in limited environments but i mean
two principles are generally
so let's use the bayesian approach and replace the true distribution by the mixture distribution
assuming that the class and contains move as usual
so that's the same as before
the likelihood times the priors some or all the environment and the only difference is
that now everything is conditioned on the action
that makes all the difference for proving things
and the sum is one of
and again it can be interpreted as the prior belief is
these weights
and so on
OK so which question can be asked now
the first
its national now to follow the
bayes optimal policy based on the basis p c
o which maximizes the
the value
in analogy to the pretty prediction case
but what really care about is the true expected value so what we
mu expectation to environment if you use this policy so this
i mean we use this quantity for determining the policy but this quantity is what
we really care about
the optimal policy obviously
your optimum value but we don't know we don't have to optimal policy because we
don't know
so we follow this policy now we can ask their policies uniform with uniformly larger
when i show you like with very short ways you might think
that you'll see blue light violet light and when i show you like very long
wavelength you may think that you will see red light
and that is often the case
but not always
as a start
we all know that you can produce all the colors that you want to buy mixing lights
mixing the light of
so so-called three primary colors recall that
additive mixing not to be confused with subtractive mixing which is the mixing of paint
i'm talking about
additive mixing mixing of light
i can mix red light this
the green light
and i can make you see yellow light
even though
the wavelength of yellow
it's not president
this the whole idea about quality vi
which is three electron guns
and your computer monitors operate
in the same way
let's look a little closer
at these
three primary colors of additive
and i'll show you a slide
of what we call the color triangle
it is called a triangle in a way is a recipe
four how you can make these various colors
using this three
primary colours red
so you see
at the three corners of this triangle
you see
red green and blue
read here
really at the top
and you see below
at the on the corner
and i will make here a poor man's version of the same triangle
very schematically
o no it should really be more of a triangle
like this
and so we have the uh
green here
and we have the red here
and all and we have the blue you
now suppose we want to make yellow
which you see here
so does this point here
then what you do
reporting this much read
away from the red from this point today on the corner
and you put in this much green
and then you'll see yellow
if you make this call here
which would be based on greensboro
you draw three lines from the three corners
you put in this much read
annual put in this much green
and you put in this micro
you'll get that color
and so you see we will even be able to make something that looks very close to white light
by mixing the three primary colors the right ratio
and that's what
the basis behind here
quality feet
i have here
little box
and in that little box i have
light bulbs
and below
and i can
make an attempt
to make some calls four u
so here
becomes the red
the is yet to be read
and i can change intensity little
and here's the group
and here's the green and the intensity intensity
now suppose i make green and red already looks pretty yellow
a little bit amount of
taste but you see only have green and red
so i'm operating there
on the right side here
and i'm seeing now
yellow i can also make
purple for u
this is now we know somewhere here
and i can also go to the purple size
you only have
and read
it is the blue
all too many william green so this is the blue and the red
makes that a little
i can make a nice couple
you guessed it already
turn them all three on
andy changed a little bit intensities you come close to white
so now we're somewhere here
so i put it next in
of these three colors so this is something
that is boring
of no interest to u
and you didn't come here
to learn about
the qualifying
now discomfiting come something that may surprise you
something that you may never have heard of
and something that is not covered in physics textbooks
and that's
that you can actually see colors
using only
black and white
almost only black white
and what i want to show you now is a very famous demonstration which was
done in early fifty by edwin land
the phenomenon was known before edwin but
he really
push issue very hard
he gave me personally two slides
they're both black and white
you will see very shortly
and this light of exactly the same scene
one of these slides
it took
through a red filter in front of the camera was a red filter
but she
man it's a black-and-white slide so there's no random slide of course
both slides
and white
in a short interview
to do that i have to walk back
the audience
and i'm going to make it very dark
we are the load a screen
and we're going to look at these slides
i already is close enough
so you can slide number one
a clown
and i can show you like number two
slide number this this is a black-and-white slide this by the way is the slides
that was taken
through a red filter but of course there's no read the slide it's a black-and-white slide
this was not taken through any filter
taken from the same
two black-and-white slides
you could turn ask yourself now the question what happened if u
hold a red filter in front of
this one slide i show you only one now
the one that was taken by edwin land through a red filter what would you
see a few put a red filter in front of it
well you'll see something very boring you'll see something that all children are familiar with
namely you look at the world through a red filter
and if i'm trying to do that in real time so fun for about twenty
five frames per second
even the fastest computer around
if you're not careful classifier using real probability that so that's sort of like the
fitting issues zero and that's just the translation and scale
born do anything more advanced
forget about it for this sort of this sort of like exhaustive search stops starts
feeding is really important
so that
this this reactor in what i said it's important message the y one it's an
object tries make it useful the object template it's important to understand how the thing
is performed first before thinking about which classifier we use
from a machine learning toolbox and a key understanding of the assumptions and constraints in
vision is required before applying effective learning techniques
so now i will start with what functions now
as i said what function is basically
and you can come the form the far arbitrarily this is a patient is for
people can take note of that
one of the following and things that people but essentially going essentially what function is
anything that takes
the source coordinates
and for the for the purposes of
yeah i think nearly all the all the top of the talk someone to give
will be referring to the coordinates
equally there will be functions the three d coordinates that will be dealing with three
quarters for now
essentially just one to map from my source coordinates to my destination court and you
can see this is in the final
and one of the biggest change in translation little bit rotation
there's no scale change anything in here
and the
the other important thing to note on this function
is that the value is my warping function x
might would say corner here
and p
p is actually the way there are parameterize the war
so so one way to parameterize wall
as well
because the troll here or here
so nothing to involve about like a really really really simple warping function would be
really really simple warping function will be now this x here is also
it it's about to basically two d
four so
let's do this sort of the vector x
but when y here
and essentially a really basic warping function would just be translation so
so far but
actually won why me writing that would just be
x y
he that p is typically to
p that
is p one
p two
so cameron say that is that there are other too small
so that's very simple but the discounting cue because the field of what will be
function is so parameterizing how much corn exchange from my ten so always this never
so this is might imply a point of reference for these points never change the
thing that changes is the warping function of how
i relied might imply points
two something the source image
and so
my goal
really is for me if i know how how on parameterizing the change to the
template in the source image
my goal is to find p
so essentially this is this is my first kind of domain crafting coming in so
instead of me
learning perhaps what he should be
i'm actually defining beforehand and is actually we do actually live he later on but
for all but for now let's say that are either on piece of p is
a little more complicated one would be say
in the final
people familiar with the finals
with the final
it might be slightly different
because what i do with the final
is that
so this i i've got
and the final is typically defined by three points
so to say this is x one
so is x two
this is x three x one x two x three in terms of the vector
form so the x and y positions
things there
i want to walk to say
so obviously there a little bit change their
x y
x two
extreme so on
the typical way to do that with enough on what is and it's very easy
if you go to matlab or anything else you goes to very very simple least
squares why do that in basically we use homogeneous coordinates the this and it's really
elegant solution rather than kind of saying what's the translation what's rotation what's the scaling
everything that this a really simple way to do this
and this is what it is is basically i put this into one matrix same
as my source coordinates
x one
so that's it
that's the treaty what's rightfully
one two one
three one
that's my source coordinates source one matrix
and got my destination
x one dash
while in dash
xt that
y two
x three
y three that one
and if i want to know the mapping between here and here
all i need to do
but but i just like that
the important foundation of pure matrix theory
namely a linear programming
from our viewpoint
and a matrix a is especially structured
class of polytopes
there any
almost any book and combinatorial optimisation
well presented you
with the kind of thing i'm talking about today
i will present
well the answer
matrix theory from the viewpoint of
polly matroids that is matroids as
and polytope now it's not normally give in this way but that's
paper one of those papers just mention gives it this way
and these are pollinate right
ground set
set of nonnegative integer valued vectors
according to space e
it's going to turn out of this is going to turn out to be a
by the way we define down defining it here is as a direct
direct imitation of our definition of matroids
which was a direct imitation of the basis column bases of the matrix
and this is the maltese
and lord
is the class
independent factor the independent vectors which are a
the analogue of the the independent sets of a matroid
in thirty origins
representing the empty set
for any nonnegative integer value
vector which is independent
it is
less than or equal
some other vector
which is an independent
then it's in independence
we say this again
any nonnegative integer vector is
if is less than or equal to some other back to that in end
this is the analogue of the subset of independent
subset of an infinite set is and then
and here the
interesting condition
corresponding every base has been found
size for any nonnegative integer vector y
every maximal integer vector that's independent
and less than or equal to the vector y
has the same sum
it's called the rank of the vector y
so we define rank
any integer valued vector
the rank of the are not nominated for any non negative integers right
the rank is
the size of the
maximal integer vector which is less than
independent factor which is less than
well polymatroid just leave out the word integer say everything here
say everything here without the word integer and you
pollinator there's no reason to have
in reality
to make this work other than
polymatroids preserving