two players passed in succession then we can conclude that no none of the players
sees any value in continuing to play and so it's essentially an agreement to stop
playing and to count
now removing all the numbers here you see that blacks around this territory here all
the points marked by b
and white surrounded all the points marked by w here so you just count how
many bees there are and how many w there are you calculate the difference and
that's the amount by which one side one in this case
probably black one
now if it so happened that in the process of the games some stones were
captured then they also are added to the territorial account so if you capture stone
you pretty much get the territory point on which it was and you get that
x extra prison
so this is the this is the japanese way of counting this chinese way but
they are essentially equivalent
no they don't in the japanese rule set
that's correct you just can't empty territory
in fact what you do in practice is you know there are some black prisoners
that white
court and some white prisoners the black card and you just fill in the territory
with them so if lack lustre prisoner that means in the end he has to
put put prisoner into his own territory which
reduces the territory by the number of prisoners
that's correct yes so this is a certain amount of agreement at the end of
the game which travels people in computer go a lot because positions at the and
usually not play really play to the and so if white played stone here
then black what claims
well that's is that i could i could easily capture it
and what may then say OK that's right
and this the dispute will be settled are what i would say that the
you're blackstone's here i doubt my white stones alive and then
black would take up the challenge
and would start killing this
the white stone
why would have to continue played
and if y continues playing
he would either put stones into the black territory and increase the number of prisoners
for every stone that black place why would have to put prison in here of
why does one that he has to play into his own territory which also costs
one point each
so there's really no in this kind of proving at the end certain stones have
to prove that but it's it's a fair process is not that white can strip
of black in this way
it's a good observation it's a certain amount of negotiations going on at the end
of the game
so there's a few additional things
as you may have noticed in capture go as well as in real making the
first move helps so people realise that and there's something called call me which means
that white receives a certain number of black prisoners before the game even starts to
compensate for the fact that black start play
now usually this is chosen the fractional manner so as to provide a service to
make sure that there will be a winner at the end because it this chosen
fractionally then there cannot be a a tie at the end people are not entirely
they don't entirely agree what this number should be so how much advantage is for
playing first and it ranges between four point five and eight point five stones
there's another very nice property which is referred to as the handicap system in goal
so often we have the situation that two players might want to play but they
are of different playing strength
and in go there's very elegant system of dealing with that because the weaker player
is allowed to to make a certain number of moves before the stronger player starts
it means the moment that i make a
any smaller than one and a half centimeters there's no propagation anymore in that direction
because now i can no longer meets the boundary conditions
for kx and i will demonstrate that as i did
before this is not the first time
that you will see that
before i do that
i want to discuss the issue the meaning now of an equal nancy equals two
what does that mean
in other words
we had here the
n equals one
we also have nancy equals two
so i'm going to make a new plot because it becomes otherwise two club
i leave this all make sure you get that sequence that's very important
and i will
put up later again
so i'm going to make a new plot
otherwise it becomes
two confusing to many lines casey
here is your
o line on this dispersion omega psi times
k of c
we are now
sure and equals one
omega c
because by
divided by a time c
and here exactly
twice as high
is an equals two
by another omega c
is two pi
i'm seeing
divided by a
so i have one line here
and i have another line here
so this is now
the plot of this equation for any one and independently for and
equals two
so this is an equals one
and this is an ecosystem
so imagine that this is our omega
that is the given that's the one that we
i happen to have
this frequency can obviously go through the gap
but now it has the choice out of two possibilities
it can either go through this way
with this value for case
which corresponds was an equals two
that's the most in green there
or it can go through
in this mode with this value for casey
for n equals one or it can do both
it can do any linear combination between
these two because each one is the solution
two maxwell's equations one o based the boundary condition on each one meets the
brief equation
so no two ways it can go through
if it decides to choose this route then kx is together
is by over a if it's
so decides to go this way
and k x is two pi over the only difference between these two is that
kx is different k is not different
because of the same omega
if the same omega have the same k the same wavelength
but this one has a different k of x therefore different k scales e
you see that
and this one has a different k of x therefore different value
for k of c
i cannot be
before i want to demonstrate to you which is repeat
but if i have here electromagnetic radiation three
centimetre wait all arise in this direction
i'm going to send to days receiver which can we see it
if i'm going to demonstrate that when i make the gets smaller than one and
a half centimeters that all of the sudden disappearance radiation
before i do that
i want to ask you a question which is important you can test whether u
i understand this concept
my radiation is linearly polarized in this direction
i love that came all this misery
is there a way that i can send electromagnetic radiation through that gap
when the gap
for my transmitter is smaller than one and a half sentence
i know i cannot do it
what is polarized this direction will immediately disappear you'll hear that is the way that
i can still get radiation through
when the opening of the gap is smaller than one and a half standard
i realize that
they take you a little bit of time
we think of it
two by saying
all these misery is the consequence of the fact that i chose
the direction of linear polarization in the y direction
if i exactly
if i put in
and i will do that believe me
if i rotate
my transmitted by ninety degrees
and i sense in radiation
by vector
is linearly polarized in the x direction
there is no misery at all because all boundary conditions will always be met by
mother nature
because all that mother nature has to do
is to make sure that the normal component
at the conductor
sigma as divided by actually non-zero so all you have to do is rearrange the
charges on the surface but nothing has ever to go to zero
so the moment that i make the radiation polarized in this direction there is no
the phrase velocities c
the group velocity is c
and this is the line
that holds no
it's only the component in the y direction to give his misery
that's very interesting isn't it
because what that means that
what that means is that if the radiation
that use and then
however component both in the in the
both in the y in the x direction
i can do that right i can send radiation through
that is linearly polarized that this
and something unbelievable is going to happen
the component in the x direction will go straight through is the speed of light
and the component in the y direction has to suffer like this
and so to completely decouple
thirty x direction is not this specific group velocity phase velocity c
a different kind of book
the carbon
where mathematics come from asking the embodied mind
it brings mathematics into being
and the reason for doing in the book
mathematics is not built into the universe
so we're not taking in this
o point of view that out there someplace guy
the park
mathematics has a human face
i went to the world and they would have chosen a better picture for the
front of the book there something that reminds me the students
and then that would be more whole
there's too much like
he is a professor of linguistics and he has been involved in every modern every
modern trend in linguistics over over many years i know well
is this idea that you should look at the role
both in linguistics and
i think the quality
politics two so that works
but would
the former
this is the main title of the book i think
it is very good at making up the catchy
we have this quality here
who came from the so-called
really based on
and serious
metaphor and the development of mathematical concepts
and they go through many examples
rather elementary
but still very seriously tried to think
well the mathematical concept come from and to try to trace back some from the
in the
none of the american mathematical society v
order in which states
i would point out
after we try to understand
about them
that was a member of
because it connects up with the way intuitions
but i think it is fair criticism that if you're going to perform
oppose i like that
and to make it into theory
the ideas come about
you have to be
much more exact much more rigorous about
i think that the criticism they may be good stuff
but they would be much more to be said about
this is
i did
many others
it is a slippery slope
and i was reminded of the famous quotation from got
mathematicians like frenchmen
what happens to them they translated into all language
something different
so we have the resources to consider the problem of these definitions and so what
because you have lots of
difficulties with newton's colours and so on and so
i think he was perhaps prejudiced against mathematician
this email
this which has one of the most people the first one is called the foundations
of mathematics FOM less
and he argued that people therefore
almost a couple of years on the map
this is called the edge would
which is by invitation
MIT based intellectuals
they they discussed many topics so you can search on those lists for
the interesting ideas thing about has to find
the holy
interesting point of view which combines
the thing about
cognitive science
these things and so he also feels that
through hasn't found a way of making
randomly but you assume that the data is sampled
i i d so independently
with the same distribution from something
i noticed an unknown distribution
in the transactional framework
we assume that the data is completely fixed but what is one of is houses
is data into
no labelled and unlabelled
and the law you can just read that
the point is is data generation
assumption tell you how you assume that the data comes
now the protocol
i mean mainly it's you know whether the data
all that time like you get all the examples
once for all that offline space or online you get one example at a time
along the way
how the example can't you have some other
things that define the protocol which is you know how
we define the error you're the reason or
whether you
i mean whether you are available to you here or the value of the year
so if you are function of the body of the body of a year or
the year of
related upgrades
i mean this will be probably when you
calls lecture online learning
and i will get into the details here
just to give you an idea
success measures
and will also to define the success
one classical one expected error the offline setting
where you take the average air and there is no distribution
the cumulative error is like
the some of the air jamaica every step in the online learning case
and you can have
a combination of both if you have an underlying probability consumption so if you assume
that the example
one at the time and they are sampled from some distribution you can compute the
expected value of the officer
now the type of analysis
this is what you can do a four
or how you want to find
what is a good idea to more about it
you can study in the worst case
from performance or the average case
the worst case being right
you consider the worst possible data generation mechanism was
the one that you have chosen
or average cases like you know
you find some kind of probability all the the third generation mechanism you you take
the average over them
so it requires some waiting like
using how what is the probability of each
the third generation
probability distribution
all these schemes which is that you are interested in the case that you
and then you can prove several different things even
i mean for tour of each type of analysis
OK so one example that we can
it's a little bit more is a bayesian inference and i'm i'm using that in
kind of very general
and i mean many people would have different definitions or would only consider
the protocol but not the digital data generation mechanism and so on so
i'm trying to
goes through all these things that have defined
tell you what would be
the way
people with the innovation
so as i said before the data generation mechanism of bayesian inferences
if you assume that your function is sampled from some prior
and the data sample i i d
so are from the prior distribution and labeled by function
depends on whether you consider function this
the probability is often offline you you see all the example that twenty
and the last major is expected error and there
this the third generation mechanism
and the type of analysis is again
your average things under the prior
it's kind of fun
average case analysis
and usually also
restrictive assumptions like you assume that the noise officers this evening before like in the
a regression based on regression you would assume that the noises captionologist
well i mean usually you assume that
each instance
is simple independently
from some distribution so i mean that's what might
well it's not very clear so
they usually have a different prior from the data or
something to beat up
but there are two ways either
you consider function
you sample your data and then use labeled data with the function or you consider
so the diffusion of XY
and then the data is just from x y so it's not labelled by the
OK maybe this is a special case i special just because
like some people would just say OK i get time example from some distribution
which need not be i i d
and four
all these assumptions you only need if you want to put things
otherwise you can
well so if you want to apply bayes rule that you have to
she was whether
you want to write the probability of the observation as the product of
probabilities of individual observations which the eighty or you
we define this otherwise
OK so
in our case we will
more of the worst case analysis and we try to avoid assumptions that as much
as we can
and and look for others and that the best under
this only god
we call the angular
don't confuse it with angular velocity
recall angular frequency and the units are the same
units are in radians
a second
same as angular velocity
if i advance this time little t
if i advance that
two pi
divided by omega
if i advance this time by two pi divided by omega than this angle here
increases by two pi radians
which is three hundred sixty degrees and so that's the time it takes forty oscillation
to repeat itself
so this is the period of the oscillations
and that is in seconds
and you can determine if you want to you can define the frequency of the
oscillations which is one of the key
which we express always in terms of hertz
and then here we have what we call
the phase angle
i will return to that that scene radiance
and this
trial functions
i'm going to substitute now
into this equation
so the first thing i have to do i have to find what the
second derivative this
of x as a function
that's my function
i have here
first the
the first derivative x not
that becomes minus eight
omega i omega omega because there's a time
now i have to take the derivative of the function itself
so i get the sign
of omega t
plus five
of course i could have started off he was assigned curve i hope you realize
that just pick the cosine law
accidental or not
now i get another omega out so i get minus eight
omega script the derivative of the sine and cosine
omega key
and that is also
omega square
times x because notice i have a cosine omega t plus five
which itself is x
so now i'm ready to substitute this result
in two that differential equation
this must always hold
for any value of x for any moment in time
and therefore the only way
this can work is if only queries k of RAM
omega square must be
o friends
and therefore
we now have the solution
so this problem
so we have
equals the square
of k over and under period is two pi
times the square root
over k
and what is this striking really remarkable
that is independent of the amplitude
and it's also independent of this angle
five this phase angle what is this business of this phase angle
it's a peculiar thing that we have there
well you can think about the physics actually
when i started this also nation
i have a choice
one of two things i can start off at a certain position
which i can choose i can give it a certain displacement from zero and simply
let it go
but i can also and i let it go
give it a certain velocity that's my choice so i have two choices where i
let it go
and what philosophy i give it
and that is reflected in my solution namely that ultimately in the solution i get
the result of a and the result of y
which doesn't determine the period but
it results from what we call my initial conditions
and i want to
do an example
by you see how
a and phi
immediately follow
from the initial conditions
so in this example
i release the object at x equals zero
t equals zero so i release it at equilibrium
at that moment in time
i given the velocity
which is minus three meters per second units always the MKS units
the spring constant k
equal to ten newtons per meter
and the mass of the object
is o point one kilogram
and now i can ask you what now if x as a function of time
basic structure OK
in the systems that have been built to do this we can model acoustic observations
basically is gaussian mixtures
just as we can design hybrid
hidden markov model neural network speech recognizers we can do the same here
we can
also model the distinctive feature state process
as these higher using these hierarchy
hierarchical conditional probability tables
and this is the key thing here is this allows for a synchronous asynchrony
among feature variables
when training set static neural networks we were limited in
the asynchrony we could allow
between the features but now
we can basically assume that these are sort of the hidden states in this type
of system
having done that we can also implement a embedded training procedure we start off by
the parameters or they can the conditional probabilities basically along the edges of this graph
using phone alignments converted to feature values as i discussed earlier
we could use this as an initial condition to generate new alignments that are and
retrain with these realign transcriptions
much the same as you do
for those of you who are familiar with the training processes in hmms as professor
i described you can basically train train your parameters align your data with the this
this model and then retrain and realigned so and that's basically what we mean by
better training and that's what this sort of facilitates
so it allows then four
i guess you might say the truth
labels associated with the difference that distinctive features to move around
with respect to one another
the it turns out that the embedded training part didn't have a big effect on
phone accuracy when they use this sort of system for for doing for recognition by
there there was they were able to observe and they spend a a good deal
of effort sort of analysing this this issue
the asynchronously asynchrony among feature really worth representative i guess of what you would expect
to see
amongst you know the
i take it you know the the relationship amongst the articulators in actual speech
speech production so
so i think the
this the underlying take away message is that you have something that operates on a
little bit more close then there a bit closer to
the way the underlying articulatory system operates but
it just in their experiments that didn't have a translate to better phone recognition accuracy
OK so
the issue is how can we actually incorporates this distinctive feature knowledge into
model the SR model structure that we're all familiar with
so suppose you've got serious our system that's sitting on the shelf and you worked
very hard in the thing
and it's it's out there in the open source community in written documentation and you
don't want to throw it all away
that's actually not the motivation here but but the the idea is is what can
we do
to incorporate some model structure into into our existing so i'm sorry if this think
the feature model structure into our existing systems
what's a good example
for those of you who are familiar with this hierarchical
decision tree approaches for
training for coming up with the acoustic context
four context specific models in ASR think professor and i talk about that on monday
but the basically those things are driven
categorical predictors
and those predictors are generally
they are often
based on the sort of the questions that are asked in in do splitting up
your data
are generally
correspond to
i particular articulatory phonology
so you could say
you know you i mean this might be a stretch for purest but you could
say that in that sense
there is some sort of articulatory knowledge
in designing the in designing areas are system they occur the acoustic context clustering that's
performed is
articulatory based
OK so there's an example
but we have some more exotic examples here one where the HMM state space
it is actually designed pretty much by hand so that the model topology
it's sort of describes feature spreading each state really is representative of an articulatory configurations
another another
example is where we can actually design our pronunciation dictionary so that it's based on
distinctive feature bundles and we actually have a way of describing pronunciation variability in terms
of the asynchrony of our distinctive features
and finally i give an example here where people have actually implemented this landmark distinctive
me to six of distinctive feature based model of speech perception in ASR we talked
about that
in the first part where we
models of speech perception in terms of sort of anchoring ourselves with these landmarks and
then discovering hughes
and figuring out
how those lined up with our lexicon
so here's an idea that
leading and dunson did while he was still at waterloo the idea here is is
we're going to define the state space
now to chemical techniques
the distance the
can easily be made a thousand times smaller than
and if the distance is a thousand times smaller than you would get a capacitance
of one
thousands might refer
compared with your
which is only seven on the microphone array
so the capacitor like this
one thousand micro for
we bring potential difference over here
and we get a tremendous amount of charge shown here
in fact if i hold in my hands
and if i assume that the potential difference between my left hand on my right
he spent many faults
and i would bring on this capacitor
ten micro cool
that is an tremendous amount of charge
in fact on microkernel is the maximum charge we can ever put on the big
event the graph we calculated last time if we put more on the then the
graph goes into discharge
by simply holding this in my hands
i could ten my control here on this pattern
now you may say well
potential difference between your right and left hand nearly falls isn't that funny
no not really
in the future i will give lecture and discuss electrocardiography and you will see them
that there is a potential difference between the left side of your body on the
right side
which is several medical not artificial
as you
you may think
i will take a chordiogram in class you can see it really working
how much energy
can i stored in a capacitor
we already calculated that
we had the energy is the
this was the
the capacity one f q v
and we can now substitute for
we can substitute in their the capacitance c
and the
c is q divided by p
and so this is also
one half
the square and this one and the same thing
so you take the charge on the capacitor
multiplied by p
or you take back multiplied by
these crazy
the capacitance is never a function of the charge that has only of
you here
that is only a matter geometry
you there
a capacitor is only a matter of geometry never
because the charge
show up in there
so i mentioned that i can bring can micro
cool on this
and yet on the vendor graph
i can also only bring ten michael cool that's the maximum i can do before
it goes into to break down
we can think of the capacitor as a device that can store
electric energy
i will now return
my promise
i was going to demonstrate to you
i have to do positive work when i create electric fields in other words
when i take
two charged plates
and i bring them further away from each other
that i do positive work
and how am i going to show that you
i have
two parallel plates on the table they are going to see them shortly
projected there
we have here
currently there are more eighteen therefore
currently there
and i'm going to
the power supply
and what the potential difference over here
this is the capacitance c we normally
use for capacitor symbol of two parallel
o lines
i'm going to put a potential difference
over the past two of thousands fal let me put down here to remind you
that the difference
between the two plates
as i do that
as i connect the power supply
these two ends
charge will flow on you and so you will see very short search of current
and neither give you only for a short amount of time charging which
was you
i will show you that is
charts flow and you will see that but that's not really the goal of my
what i'm now going to do
it is i'm not going to increase
the separation
the distance d
of these two plates
and remember that the potential difference over the past over the
plates which i call now capacitor is the electric field
and this is an electric field is constant if i charge the capacitor up with
this so can charge there is less skew here
minus q there and then i removed the power supply is no longer there that
charges trap charged can never change and so
all right so
we're gonna
move on
since i heard echoes the the lecture yes they might have been too easy is
going to be some more equations today
not that many after
just to set the scene
i'm going to remind you of of
very rough categorisation of the kinds of machine learning that one can do all right
it's not like to take a vote here
who thinks his doing or she's doing mainly supervised learning
all right
you're allowed to vote twice by way who thinks that he or she is doing
mainly unsupervised learning
all right bit less
sure you can vote tries to find
one of the previous one
that's fine
and who's doing reinforcement learning
another man
all right so
i'm not going to say
anything about reinforcement learning in any of the slides it follows if i i'd rather
do it now then
risk for reinforcement learning first from supervised and unsupervised learning in very interesting ways
in reinforcement learning you can think about it as
you can think about it as the child learning from its environment anyway
so the thing is
instead of instead of giving
your algorithm
dataset some inputs and some targets and saying you from this here's the cost function
you have to minimize and i'm going to ask you to make predictions
in reinforcement learning you give
the algorithm
a reward function is sort of say
whenever you get things right how you can be and whatever you get things wrong
sort of hit you with a stick
all right and it doesn't really know about the environment to much so it interacts
with OK i give you an example that have that i've been working on and
i think it's one that
i think is one that can actually talk about
so so
has any who played racing games with with cars on on the computer
i you very good
this is i think the most challenging of the most exciting thing for the user
is actually going to play online against other players right in racing game that you
play against the computer
i don't know how how often i think you are about
racing games fairly fine i think about them and you see that the computer drives
in the very very strange way there's many things that are deeply disturbing about the
way the computer drives OK
and actually sort of know how the AI has been for for for the other
consonants so the thing is
because they follow perfect lines they don't they don't like humans and where they don't
feel like humans and it's fairly boring most of the time the drug against a
what we've done is we've sort of set a certain set of rules to the
car and we said well you know you have to achieve the shortest
lap time possible OK
and here's the things you can do can accelerate you can race against here and
so on now go on and and do the best lap time you can do
so that's that's reinforcement learning task and then of course in the first let's just
crushes all over the place
but little by little it learns it writes things so basically it also has to
acquire a data set in a way as it was it works OK under the
trade off between exploring the environment which is useful for the future and not and
sort of exploiting
the little knowledge i have to to go towards the goal
so that was it for sportsmen going to say any more about it
what we're going to talk about today is
only unsupervised learning
so i think i already asked yesterday but
it might be worth
asking again
who's ever implemented k means
all right that's very good
who's ever implemented mixtures of gaussians
it's also good
all right
and who has ever implemented factor analysis
OK nobody has
i'll tell you a bit about it
so let's think about some datasets that that one could
what can think of
this data set here in our two datasets where i would
go on want to model the input density for example
so do some
unsupervised learning on them
this data set here
is that where would sort of do
supervised learning do sort of supervised binary classification
i a bit about this data set this episode was collected by iain murray
who was a student at the gatsby unit
i was actually very recently finishes his
and he went out in london and he bought
a set of different oranges and lemons
and then he measured the height and width of each of them and he actually
measured all the features as well
and then just place points in the in the plane according to the height and
width and he thought that that was sort of
exciting data set of more exciting than just drawing samples from from the girls
OK so
if you
if you were to model
density in
in one d what we do
anyone so
the histogram
it's it's just sort of dots on so you have x
and then you observe some
we observe some values
and you want to infer
you know you want to sort of modern density
but in windows yes
but all good old stuff
i mean
i don't know why nobody said you know just try to fit goes into the
now that so much
OK let's just remind ourselves briefly of the good old gaussian distribution so you can
sort of see i call data x let's call y wife now
and probably going to be swapping between x and y
sort of familiar with the with the equation for the for the girls and in
one b has two parameters are right
OK so let's talk about the right these things and so the dependence
jim watson
future data
topic proportions
four sparsity
the bayesian machinery
which is
you could run interesting picture
and laura something
you know
i think
OK so
i also missed
first the current
and what you said also relates to sparsity it sounds like you're talking about putting
dirichlet prior on beta
OK that's that's probably true that sparsity helps matters but i should tell you that
these topics were fit with maximum likelihood on the
we still got this
but i think these are all good points but if there's a more in
you will see
so was
the structure that the i wanted to not confuse order ordering bag of words which
is why translator structure but
i mean to say what you said
so i think
i don't know
well this i don't know if if if the idea is that the number of
topics here to fifty
i did i did strike the right balance carefully like i cook somewhere cook
i put some chili pepper and it tastes like chili peppers
came out but
but you're right that there's something about balance
that's right balance again
that is this is good so remember this feeling of thinking about the posterior when
building and analyzing your next hierarchical bayesian model for whatever it is these are important
intuitions to start to
to foster i think and i think that's
i don't have like a good answer for this question but
i think we've had on a lot of in and my intuitions
i tried to write them down
i the wrong way
here are my random thoughts that so why does LDA posterior put topical words together
one is that the word probabilities are maximized by dividing the words among the top
what i mean by that is that
let's recall the
the joint distribution
that's right hard
i think
so let's say we have the product over documents to assume the topics are fixed
we're going to fit the topics that maximize the product over documents the given alpha
product of words
the topic assignment data
thirty words
and then the fear
the here
the OK so this is this is the joint distribution of the hidden and observed
random variables going to play a role in we're doing inference
this is proportional to the posterior distribution that i'm asking you to think about
right so everyone is everyone see that the proportion that the posterior is you've probably
seen for five times already is proportional to the joint distribution of the hidden in
the observed variables divided by the evidence the probability of the observed variables with everything
had marginalized out
OK so this is proportional to the posterior and
one thought experiment is
what happen what keeps us from putting the all of the words with equal probability
or probability proportional to how often they occur in the corpus into each topic
right what keeps us from doing that what keeps us from from member the data
so here's here topic k
and here's the word the
and and the sum to one what keeps us from putting the same distribution over
words in each of these topics
this is
OK that's right that's one aspect of the prior that keeps us from doing that
so if we have a sparse prior on the bathers then that's not gonna happen
but even if we do ML maximum likelihood of the data is we're not going
to want to do that and the reason is that we are drawing the words
those banners the likelihood term
going it easy to
to be obsessed with properties of prior
properties of the likelihood term are extremely important as well
the likelihood term says that the words have probability equal to whatever the probability of
the word is under the topic i signs were two
if i take all the topics and i put all the words with equal probability
in those topics then
every word going have the same probability
but if i divide the words are equally let's say i divide let's say i
fail to see some words
some words going here is going to and so on until you hear
i got more mass on a smaller set of words so this likelihood term is
going to be bigger
the run see that
so forgetting about properties of priors and sparsity india's slaves and x y and c
it makes sense
the couple examples but not unrealistic example
OK so that's the thing that you proposed by time varying slice sampling i mean
the name of the council one long sold most of the techniques originates actually from
physics well basically MCMC will introduce the fifty years ago OK so the techniques also
which i discuss which are directly related to
the estimation of the normalizing constant of the targets of the timing of told you
well basically
what we're trying to do with target distribution pi x which is known up to
a normalizing constant to this gamma out of x divided by the normalizing constant is
the integral of gamma of the the the the space of interest on i focused
on methods which all why something
alright essentially
estimates of
samples of ultimate sample from pi
if you want to evaluate the normalizing constant versus normalizing constant this is completely different
business actually on celebrate bridge sampling path sampling yes i will discuss the matter to
more related to particle method which which is used to compute normalizing constant estimates but
it's actually quite different
OK so to your current
overview of what people for example are doing trying to come up with the advent
of the calorimeter
so this can be very briefly for example the idea behind what we sample a
slice sampling
the meeting of the county
on pilot comp
what slice sampling does OK for example
well is going to basically
say OK so interest target distribution pi x which is known up to a normalizing
constant because is gamma x opposite
what you can do
you're gonna basically
modify the target distributions
on introducing notes i you OK so you introduce a new distribution prior to that
which now basically known independent of x but also depend one of w
OK on the way in which is already in value on the viability of these
joint distribution
you make it such that by construction
is proportional to
the uniform distribution of u
basically only entails the organics so you can do that
sure so you get is this solution so it seems to be coming out of
nowhere this idea
so get a distribution
o i'm basically what people have done that
is that they said distribution actually can be easier to sample from the distribution pi
t and instead of OK so parts we discussed that later but for the timely
let's consider the interest distribution what is the remarkable property of the distribution
if you look
and the marginal
and apply to the of x
well what it is well basically what you do to look at the marginals
and x the fighting the makes you integrate this guy over u
the joint distribution of u
OK that's going to be proportional
together x
well because the point distribution clearly it means that by two that of x's pyrex
because that you could the new you build the x like an artificial extended target
which admits as marginal distribution and index what you're what you're interested that's the trick
in multicellular might actually we see it again and again actually to more
i know what you think can be nice
OK to sample from
why is it that y cannot be seen to sample from these guys then directly
from pyrex well simply because now
based on this join
distribution by two then you can use all the not essentially multicolour CP to sample
from it so in particular
what you could try to use you could try to give sampled
from basically
these artificial target distribution that is sampling for you given x and apply to the
all then sampling x u one u two u on the by two
on that's going to be the sample
right so some component was sort of not
expressible as a linear combination of the training data
then actually that
component has no effect on the training right because it's orthogonal will be taken into
product with any of the training examples it has no effect
so remember
but we were one of the things we trying to control was the norm of
the weight vector well let's just throw away that components orthogonal
we've got smaller
the norm of the weight vector doing the same thing
so clearly you know it's not going to be sensible to include that orthogonal components
in solving any optimisation of the type that we described earlier
and so it's almost certainly the the case in
all sensible
definitions of learning problems that you can and
with a weight vector that does have a dual representation
and that
is known as the representer theorem i mean i've just given you a sort of
intuitive argument about proof of the representer theorem
so i think you know what i would say you know i don't want to
go into more detail that we can quite reasonably expect the weight vector can be
expressed in this form
in other words
this is not just something
we we could possibly hope for something we can expect
to be the case
so what that means is that we can now reformulate algorithms to learn
the weight vector as algorithms that learn the dual variables rather than learned
actual weight vector itself in other words what i'm saying is
why don't we
rather than trying to understand what you try trying to learn these alpha arise
so again it's not clear why that's a good thing to do
but will see it very quickly why that is is is useful
but for the time being all we've done is observed the
yes the weight vector is very likely to be expressible in this form if we've
written a sensible learning problem
and that means that we
could actually
by learning these alpha is rather learning these studies
so i
what i'm saying is that if you define your problem with the sensible control only
on the norm of the weight vectors
then it will be true
effectively it's going to force those compounds are not in that span to go to
because in
let's do this for the SVM
now in fact with the SVM if you just go to the dual optimisation problem
so what i wrote down was actually
can be viewed as before
let's go back to that slide defining
what have we got well we're minimizing some quantity here
subject to some constraint
notice that the constraints are linear
in the
and james w b
and excite
but the optimisation we're making is quadratic OK sneering sinai but is quadratic in
so it would involve
no squares of components and so on
so this is what is known as a quadratic programming problem so something that you
know if you're an optimisation
guru you know all about ten minutes
by the stuff and
it actually is a nice quadratic programming problem because it actually is convex this function
here of the weight vector is convex which is you know why has this unique
solution optimal solutions
so this is just observing that
by writing down the optimisation arrived at four support vector learning we actually come into
a very standard framework
that is
he studied by many many people
in in mathematical programming
and it's it's has names for program and the properties are the these constraints are
linear and the
the objective is is quadratic now in
in optimization theory
there's a very well-developed understanding of the relationship between a problem and
a so-called dual problem
so the linear programming had the dual linear program
in quadratic programming had the dual
again and
this in a way of deriving this which i don't want to go into not
is not quite the chemical
but if you follow that
you actually arrive at
the dual representation that i i described in the previous slide
the way that it actually turns out to be in this form actually with a
very slight difference that is the why and here the label the alpha rise will
be positive all of them
and i'll will be why i because it back to the negative examples you really
want negative contributions from
that particular example
OK so so there's an additional thing here but you know
to all intents and purposes it is a linear combination of the training examples is
just the
components negative for negative examples positive positive examples
and we choose to
right in terms of these alpha rise now
which are constrained to be positive notice of course
so if you do that translation using that general approach
espoused by optimisation
good news
when you arrive at this problem
so typically the dual
it's always maximizing when primal is minimizing
so the
and here again we have a quadratic function were optimizing subject to linear constraints
the form of the function is
some of the authorized minus two point five and this quadratic forms
alpha i alpha j one one j five x inner product five xj
constraint is a weighted
constraints on the
alpha rise should be equal to zero
and the band between zero and c for the alpha i
so just firstly to talk through a little bit of where these components come from
notice the sea comes from that trade parameter that i described that traded off the
accuracy on the training data is against the norm of the
the weight vector that's what i see comes from and by varying that c
you allow ourselves to get smaller or the constraint and the constraint is often referred
to as the box constraints because if you think about it in multidimensional space
it's actually a nice little box
with the origin one corner cccccc the other one
so this is the constraint arises this one
a constraint that arises from having the
offset b
OK here
the following content is provided under creative commons license your support will help MIT opencourseware
continue to offer high quality educational resources for free
to make a donation or to view additional materials from hundreds of MIT courses
his MIT opencourseware OCW that MIT that EDU
one announcement even though you will have no academic exercises
thursday and friday i know you feel
the sense of
shock and disruption and
there is a dislocation in your life if i didn't
stick to schedule so there will be a skill testing question on
tuesday based on homework twelve
and that would be the last one because there
subsequent week is the last week of semester and since it's the final exam
in this subject there can be no
test during the last week of class
we will
don't have any weekly tests
today i want to talk about biochemistry spend
the next three lectures on biochemistry this is the chemistry
of living organisms
and i want to make several points by way of introduction
the first one is that are
living organisms are
chemical systems
and are governed by the same laws
that apply to inanimate matter we don't have special chemistry
and in fact i came across
comment that was made by the nobel laureate richard feynman
he said that if in some cataclysm
all of scientific knowledge were to be destroyed and only one sentence
passed on to the next generations of creatures
what statement would contain the most information in the fewest words
i believe
that it is the atomic hypothesis
for the atomic fact whatever you wish to call it that all things are made
of atoms
little particles that move around perpetual motion
attracting each other when they were little distance apart
propelling upon being squeezed into one another
the atomic hypothesis
very important
second comment i want to make is that
none of us is unaware of the boom and biotechnology today
what is the boom and biotechnology why do we have the boom and biotechnology it's
really a boom in biochemical technology which the modern biology called it's called molecular biology
and what is the science what is molecular science this is chemistry and more importantly
it is
not just chemical composition but
spatial arrangement
chemistry materials science and solid state chemistry underlie the boom in
so that's why we're going to spend some time responding ten percent of our lectures
and through nine one on this topic
the last comment is wildly now
why did this happen
fifty years ago
what's enabling this boom today
and i think about
well the answer is complex let's get the answer the answer is complexity of the
and if you think about how
materials have evolved over time
you know we day are ages
the ages of man or data in terms of materials we have the stone age
bronze age iron age
you might call the first half of the twentieth century the
plastics age
like all the last half of the twentieth century the silicon age
and we see increasing complexity to work with stone stone is found in nature and
requires only a change of shape
but everything else
the medals the bronze the iris not found in nature nature
so that requires the change in shape after a change in the chemical composition
chemistry is magic
and cameras were revered
as sorcerers
highly respected
not today
there are compelling reasons to be alive today but not for the respect given to
but it's magic to take something to convert its chemical composition that took
to get the fires hot enough to discover the chemistry that will allow us to
the pile of sand and turn it into a semiconducting devices that you could
talk on the phone or
type the letter on
solid state device known as the computer
so polymers come at the dawn of the twentieth
twentieth century
macromolecules it turns out that many of the
molecules in
living organisms are macromolecules necessarily our understanding of this chemistry had two
wait for the understanding of polymer chemistry
finally now we have information technology
we have
our understanding of macromolecules and now we can go forward with
bio technology so
let's get down to
business and start talking about the chemistry of specific
biomolecules and
they fall broadly into four categories so let's document before
by all
so we first of all proteins
nucleic acids
and lived in the three lectures that we're going to focus primarily on proteins
nucleic acids and lipids
and i think this will get you far enough along
enjoy subsequent
but as you might
no i'm a fan of course into so i'm from institute for computer graphics and
at scratching technology
so we may need to do
computer vision
actually we have two groups that in our institute which is a division part is
related to machine learning
and one of the things we use mainly in our daily practices posting an ensemble
have been or looks as in the inputs can so i'm going to
you know the briefly to assemble methods in machine learning
and i think since you have got your formula those today by previous lecture so
i'm going to be as this formula now
presenting as this from the camp
let's just get started so
outline of the talk so i'm just going to use it
ensemble methods then
the main concept behind on some because missus model averaging
then i'll talk to one of the present our first methods
an ensemble methods which is called bagging to move forward turn another perspective which is
called stagewise additive modeling
which we see we'll see that boosting is a special case of this approach and
that i give you a practical example with some videos related to computer vision
OK so let's think that you know
you have the you know in your PC
it's coming without any operating system and then
you have also not in any knowledge of you know which operating system you are
going to choose so that we humans do
is actually go and ask people who knows about the existence
two not for example if you are going to use windows are going to
use for example in books and give you some you know
devices and then you come up from make your mind based on you know your
decision criterion then you know whatever operating system that you do
that you favor
so one of the
simplest ways of our
deciding you know what operating system you have to choose
based on the opinions of the experts is to just use the
major world teams
which means that
there's just
if you come light eleven people and six of them said that she was some
five said that using those just links
let's major voting you do it in
elections in
presidency or other things
so it is one of the simplest ways to
combine the opinions of the person
so now how we can write this in little formal way is that assume that
you have set of experts so these functions here
and each of these experts are going to tell you
based on for example here but it
she in those early
for example
and if you sign
labels to
for example choosing linear says
positive class and using those as negative class and the majority of voting can be
treated like this
so to sum up the opinions
they are binary values and the next is bigger than zero said that i was
in the sixties
less than zero you choose
we know
so this is the main concept behind also matters so
most of the times
but you will see some of that have to combine these
and have to find these
and the interesting thing is that diversity is also important ensemble methods you don't want
all models tell the same story two
so i assume that these guys over here at TED by microsoft to you know
promote windows and when are asking cases in those right so if they are going
to be around all going to be around the same way
better to have diversity
let's have different points of view
on the same problems that it can decided by the way
so we also are looking for diversity in our
our set of experts
in some locations
so this training set
and to discuss about binary classification
problem but all these methods can be applied to recreational multiclass problems
so have a data set pairs of
inputs some call the corresponding labels
so sample comes from a d dimensional
space samples are binary find some plus one this is a set of experts
i mean by that
so this the experts
this the
you know
i assume so one says
if you are is reflected in it validates all instances of t so that's the
one on the right so what
two right
i suppose
are these reflexes
what is it mean it means that every world can see itself
contradiction suppose
for a contradiction
it doesn't validate
in the i mean stones
say box signed life
forced by this frame
so the frame
that's right does not force a particular instance box size but
so what does that mean it means that we can put value h frame
such that there's some world
let's call it likely w w norton w no
OK some which makes this guy falls
so it makes foxi in i
how do you make an implication falls
the left part
we supplies for all
since OK
evaluation right so
what i'm going to do now
he satisfy society with w node v
why is that well if box size true then whenever you have a successor
o thing to be true
we know
that is actually an arrow
from w no now
one of the world's that you can reach from w no
and we have to be able to put aside
because box size true
so here and claim that's it's true
we get a contradiction
nineteen eighties this is
what does it mean that this frame
doesn't force box on the fly so there's some valuation which makes this guy true
at some world we don't even know what means
but we know that makes it true
well that makes it true that
whenever it makes bauxite i true it makes it true
the book strauss bauxite resources
so it makes it follows that makes bauxite room makes it falls for bauxite arbitrary
here every once they pass success has to make excitatory but it's it's only one
step six it so i can't true falls
is OK let's take the other way
right to left
so what do we assume we assume that
the invalidates all instances of so i suppose
the frame
all instances of t
and again for contradictions risk risk reflexive so for
not reflects
what is not reflexive me is at least one world somewhere there's one world which
doesn't see itself
doesn't mean that every world doesn't itself it just means is at least one god
knows this can have all sorts of successes but we know that you can't do
that's the forbidden age that's not in the market
now what we do
just to condition
on the frame
we are free to choose the value by any way you like
it says that the frame is not reflexive so there the world
so what am i gonna do
i'm going to define the valuation
foresight paid so he has been not groups
and the action is
i need to give evaluation
so here's my p one p two dollars minute take on or
evaluation is going to be that
every world that you can see from here
is going to make pain or true
right so this evaluation
each one of these evaluation
do is i'm going to say
if this guy can see you have to make this guy
what's the truth value of box peano at this world
i just defined
a real action so that wherever you can go in one step from this guy
pinotage true so i've got to know orchestra
that's fine
what's the truth value of p in
we know that this guy's not one step to prove itself
so what i'll do is output p not false here
and then i asked the question
what about this formula
is this true here
because this part is true
this pattern is false therefore falls
is this
an instance
of of implies five
yes it is
WR's to validate all instances of t
is an instance she doesn't validate
if you suppose that invalidates all instances of t
it's not possible
to be not reflexive
because if it's not reflexive you can put this perturbation
truth tables
he was
just list all the possible values and thing
i remember this is material in case which means that is
the antecedent is false and true
in this case a useful quite true
same thing
if is true we have to cheque of that is true but this is not
the case falls
for this column which is the value
and again you calculate the implications of this one one
and dissidents falls is also true
two of the falls
now you see that this is true
problems are exactly the same
two formulas in fact
but it people
and then there are the
ontology is like that is associated with
conjunction in
this means that
the way you put the parents around the conjunction and disjunction
that's why sometimes we write
a b
see for example
without the border between parents
that's right
and this is around city
this section
surgical treatment to put the prances around
this means that if you have a conjunction to form in just this
and then there is morgan's
which again highlights the duality logic
so there is duality between
conjunction disjunction
you can negate the conjunction
then you get the disjunction of the negation
and vice versa
negation cancel each other
have a double negation a
and all these laws
will be used to transform
propositional formula
to work with
see next slide
so as i said in the beginning of this concept of syntax semantics and
sounds question
what we have seen with this tautology that
all these operations changing
the ship form that's not preserved
this will be used in converting formula at the
certain form which is more manageable
normal forms
commonly used
automated reasoning
and the first one is called the negation normal form
and then you can jump disjunctive normal form conjunctive
for satisfiability checking
the standard
input is
you know what
so to simplify discussions
assume that we
the implications
right so
this is one of the topology says that i think is actually equivalent to disjunction
with with the antecedent is located
so what we can do is replace the implication form with
disjunction negation
and therefore we can work with former implication free
and also we assume we don't have nullary operators
also true
now what is in negation normal form
this is the form in which all the negation supposed to air on the left
so the only indication that ever appeared in form
right so far
so for example
a mean is not
the negation of obviously because
the negation appears
on the other hand
not x or y is
the negation normal form because it
the transform
formula into the negation
you supply
these three tautology
this is the moment of his or her
so the negation above conjunction can push
the conjunction but change the conjunction to
and vice versa the negation on top of this challenge was it down and it
can change that
when he hits another
so then you can help
so you can see that the recursive procedure
there you have the disjunction is
this is a pseudocode
written functions language
so you are familiar with
so you a is a literal literally means that it is fair
or the negation of their
then it is already in
negation normal form
so there is no need to normalize
and we just returned a
the interval of the second derivative of the function
and then the question is if you have the data and the data allow i
by the interval
between zero one if you bit like this
it turns out that you can actually do freeform
optimisation confined to find the best function
that optimizes thing here
respecting the function to be a certain
it turns out that the best possible function is piecewise cubic polynomials
might be a little bit surprising if you haven't seen before
of any kind of function you can think of
or i guess it has to be
it has to be differentiable
well actually the problem is that what this means
and the best possible and the idea here is that you want the function you
don't want the function to curve too much because then it's that is unwilling to
that might be nice to have
if so you want something that doesn't wiggle too much analyse the secondary to that
so how can we construct the gulf process that
the same solution as the variational problem
and in the construction look like this so
again we do something which is very similar to the example before going to function
was going to depend on a bunch of
promises promises going to have yeltsin distribution that's going to give us that the family
and look like this is going to be
one parameter alpha
the time axis is going to be linear
contribution here
the more interesting part is the part of here
i was going to be going some
and we're going to have infinitely many contributions again
the contributions are going to be some constant gamma i just like before
it's going to be
some of these little round function
the bracket with the parts of the end
i mean it has to the value x effect of the
and zero otherwise you have some of these little ramps
around the centre
everywhere within the interval
now we've got some together all these things
and then we have to
worry about normalizing this doesn't
the doesn't sum up to be a big and bigger function or what we normalize
the by one over the world
OK and then we have to put up with priors
on these parameters
we put
got priors on all these things
we put copyright the particular variant
these two guys and the different variants
this is the gamma promise
this now
defines a distribution over functions
because this was does in the limit where he has to look
so these
some of these people but some of the
negative some of the positive or something about the round
you think about what happens when you add together
o infinite many of these
so what do we do to analyse what happened well we can compute the mean
function and covariance function but
we're trying to get process
the same way as before
the covariance function here
it's going to be
take the
the limit as n goes to infinity again
and then
we get one or in some which and went into
an interval alpha from one
and then we compute this integral to the to the polynomial mean square
polynomial in u
piecewise the some
but problem with we we do that then we get something which is a constant
times something
which is
a cubic polynomial
are a piecewise cubic polynomial in x
now we know
when gonna to make predictions using this covariance function
then the predictions we'll have the form which is a linear combination of kernels
o grants functions evaluated
at the
training and test points
that function will be a piecewise
two people on because of a bunch of course the time these things to evaluate
x star and all of the
not going to be a piecewise
that was going to happen before
and then there a need to take you need to take the limit the variance
of the parameter controlling the
lena components
you have to take the limit where this main article
and that's a little bit unpleasant they have to be careful
to do that correctly
now why is that we understand why that is
well trivial to say because there is no penalty
on the function
the penalty will always be zero rolling up
that means that this actually correspond to the solution of the variational problem must somehow
include all kinds of you
it is therefore
they want to see the data then of course
we have to bring it back down to actually take account of the data that's
why you get this solid
the problem by the predictive distribution itself is fine
OK there's a bunch about here
it's going show you an example
here's an example of have a bunch of data points that ten data points
and i i again i think the
optimize the
the parameters of the
crisp function which the
which gamma in this case the noise level two problem
the airport again the mean function in this that black line again plus minus the
particular solution
what you can see here what you can see that but this but i can
tell you that this function here the piece wise uniform
so you should be able to see
thanks to the function does anything more than
a cubic polynomial do between two data points
piecewise polynomial in the end pieces go between each the
OK so
at NUS
any possible
o point on the
on the on the x axis right
so i had sort of injected anything into the system of the the covariance function
i specify the green's function but everything follows from that
so it's actually really is actually really interesting to try and do this on your
because it's it's a it's not very usual way to think about functions
so here's a picture of
doing this in two-dimensional case so here have
and input which is which is of two dimensions
and i have a
so drawn my axes are
the six hundred points along
this axis hundred points
along this axis
so my input space contains ten thousand points
that means that my
i covariance function
so i have an entry in the covariance function for each pair of points
i mean i covariance matrix
the ten thousand by ten thousand matrix
right i draw
o point from that
ten thousand dimensional gaussians is the ten thousand dimensional vector that can plot the values
as a function of those corresponding
and this is the function
but i'd rather so a random function from
so so
so the question is you know if i'm if i'm making inference about functions that
i don't know
and how can i know the
covariance so
up until now
i've only been trying to characterize
the notion of the gaussianprocess right so we haven't so this is all about random
so how actually told you about
you know how would you actually
usually you're not interested in random functions you're into the functions that
that are useful for predicting whatever it is you're interested right so we had gotten
that far yet
so but the but the but the distribution over functions specified there's a certain covariance
in this and the covariance depends in a certain way upon the
upon the inputs
and this somehow implies something about
the function functions phi and i'll tell you more about that is and how works
OK so the gas process defines a distribution over functions right
and this is one function
drawn from the distribution function
and i can only show you
a finite number of function values for so only ten thousand ideas here
when the limit the picture would look the same but because all the points that
would be in between would have also been between because
this particular gaussianprocess with this
with this covariance function
actually has the property that it that it's that generate smooth functions
so if i drew this
i even finer grained than you look things
so the function
is it is the function of x one and x two this is the function
value f over here
this is just illustrate that
in my simple example had of a function which was from a one-dimensional x to
f of x
but i'm not and need not be the case but you can also have the
axes can live in in
any space
that's right so the covariance structure
the command structure
tell you something about
how the
what the dependencies between cases right so if i say well conditioned on that i
had this point
that tells me something about what's going on elsewhere right now so force exactly
what we're trying to
to utilize we're trying to learn about function thing overtaking this observation
i could tell me something about
the function not just at that point but also at nearby points in some sense
right will have to get closer to exactly one is that sense and try to
so the the the ordering of axes this is completely irrelevant
OK this is that this is a random sample from bell-shaped curve
you have the bell-shaped curve in one dimension then if you draw a random sample
from that is the number
OK now i have a high dimensional one
so when i draw a sample from the distribution
i can show you a picture of the high dimensional gaussians but if if you
sample from it it's back to right
and i'm showing you
picture that
as somebody have already
i mentioned you know this was only about random functions right so how do we
actually how do we use this
to learn something about functions
so now i'm going to
i'm going to tell you how to do that in the
the three-step procedure
first i'm going to talk about
how to do maximum likelihood and what i call a parametric method parametric model
i'm going to
welcome this afternoon
so the
intention with this talk
to have somebody who would really give you information
from within three days
we'll deal between but from the outside side so here we have
somebody who
sees from the inside outside
probably the best person
we can get so one of the best people of this kind would be like
a few words about dialects so
but he was doing big data even before r
anybody mention this
the worked
the whole series of big companies
back in
early two thousands he was seen well
so he sold his you well streams of data not doing that
spam detection and detecting all this
shady business which happens on the internet and from the outside so lots of experience and that's it
then he moved to
microsoft's to life flaps so he was in this core group which
evolved so i guess into today's
hands two years ago at
two years ago i like move to
there was already around but not as popular as they
big announcements
smart person from markets are going to be like
now he works in this
that's research e side of it
you around much she
touches the data every day which would only wish to touch most of us
then set about the idea is basically to give us a little bit of a flavor what happens behind that
that's question not really what
i like this
thank you marko
thank you all for coming
so we begin by
referring to the previous keynote speaker and and the other see also sigma
last weekend's interesting conceal certain concept
spread around pretty fast
research network like
for those killed each sigmod which referred to
people as database experts
the scientists and data enthusiasts and so on
o thing that
the previous speaker correctly
classified this community is being go far very cool database experts which are
on my talk is more about machine learning and i think the machine learning perspective
this community from the community of of machine learning enthusiasts
she learning is now the key problem but there's a be quite useful
eleven applications
well i'm going to talk about this is something which is really discussed is
how they basically
build a fairly large machine learning system over what we call big data right now
and i'm going to talk about later whether or not we can call for a big data
but things got some
well they kind of processes and thought processes that we went through
in trying to make it scalable and try to make it useful forward
data experts or scientists who like and that zero
so let me ask
everybody how many people actually use
is a hand
so what
so i quite sure how much deft explain what you need is still some
some are called pictures
so this is an event which happened a few years ago and essentially so as they
mid-size earthquake
which think the whole the damage but managed to shook
six supermarket shelves you can see
so there's an interesting statistics
the second
what is holding radiation there are two different ways of thinking about it and i
will give you both arguments just to get some information about them
well here is first a simple handwaving arguments you're probably or more familiar with another
phenomenon called just creation and the creation of an electron positron prior spontaneously in an
electric field
and the way to compute these if you're just interested in order of magnitude calculations
is very quick and goes as follows the result of string data that comes from
the field theory calculation is that the rate of producing the plus and minus the
bear some electric field unit volume
goes like the exponential of minus the the mosque where the electron
divided by charge times electric field times age by
and there are some numerical factors both index form here
now the reason why this is
the correct expression goes as follows well we are computing really quantum tunnelling probability so
here is how you would computed here is apparent from the plus and minus it
is at first eventually abandoned that creates created out of fluctuations in the vacuum
but then there is an electric field that accelerates the particles and does well in
the two particles
so let's compute the work done by this external force field of the particles as
they move up the work is force times separation so it grows linearly
and then there is some critical separation which you see is the force over twice
the miners and that this could become separation we have actually done enough work
with the external field
two materialize the parent terms from virtual to real of particles with energy equal to
therefore you can definitely think of this process as it and link probability you want
to ban them from zero to q twenty
and the underlying operating quantum mechanics is
given by a very simple reformulates roughly speaking
the area
of these potential barrier
and if you compute the area of this potential buyer you get exactly the shrink
namely e to the minus m squared which we h barrett
h bodies there because that's the quantum
now think of doing a similar calculation but not
in terms of
production in an electric field now but
producing the bear in the horizon of a black hole
so the idea here is that i'm going to do the same thing and now
producing virtual there somewhere in the horizon of a black hole
one of the particle moves out the other moves in
they are accelerating
the force field of a black hole
no one will fall behind the horizon and we never see any more but the
other one may
it becomes very ill and come out at infinity and will be seen as hawking
radiation are infinite
what will be the difference from the previous calculation well roughly speaking the force field
which was charged times electric field before is be simply replaced by neutrons for namely
g note on the mass of the black hole
the mass of the probe particles really the article created over m squared and four
hours here i have put in the horizon news which is that it becomes
a region one of these will be happening
now remembered for his what's black hole are forced to
gn m
and therefore this
force field is of the order of little lamb over g
now there are two important things to note here first of all the force
is proportional to the mass
that's because we are talking about the gravitational force not an electromagnetic force
therefore one of the two
in swing disarray
he will be killed by the force field and there are a few will be
exponential miners must not months square
this sense it's a show of independence from us and it makes it look fair
right that's not like it what's factor e to the minus the temperature and mass
or energy
now what is the temperature what the temperature of the inverse temperature is precisely
your done
the big
much of the black hole over h bar
call this hawking temperature and i'll write it down in the next inspire more appropriately
so this is the naive arguments now let me give you the more precise argument
which is also very simple to explain but requires a little bit of quantum field
and the more precise argument is the following
if you look back at the expression
of the black hole that we have here this was the right most hole
a field theorists the one thing very irregularly they update time
each component
will be the response of one source acting alone
so if i could figure out
the effect of one source acting alone
OK and put that down here
and do the same thing for all the sources
that's what i get
so far the sources we have
the linear circuit so i know that the answer is going to be
in the in the final answer is going to be in power
this could be multiplied by some of land
OK i know that it's a linear circuit
so i know the answer show how would later in the year multiplied by some
constant moon simple i know
OK so i the same is true
four all this is the
and what i can do they can measure just distance affected by setting all the
other sources to this concept
all the other
and this is the no
all the sources except for this one
i can get that the answer
so similarly for everyone that source and we get or
OK so for every single that source n one n two n three and so
on and when get better
there were some up
and we get to
for i am
and i know that i inference
and no
it's going to be some constant b
multiplying i and
in this example of ours here
in this example
well this
and data
was this
this constant here
the some constant data from because out
and because of a whole bunch of sources
OK then we set the for each one of them
and each one of these to be and i n
will be
what is i would see here
if i said
all the other beings to zero
and i said all the other current sources except for that one is zero
what i'm saying is that
the response here what i'm missing anything here is that
they don't all the other ones
what i'm missing
i exactly so far the current source i then the effect of this current as
and so i don't i there too
OK it's going to be some constant multiplying by
OK and that constant
it's going to look like a resistor
right because
this circuit contains current sources what it's also resistors
if a short of like what the sources and opened on the current sources what's
left in here
the whole caboodle full of the old of art
OK look like what some some distance are
and that's what i did here
OK so this is what we used to look like
so far
so let's take a look at
these components
let's focus on these easy part first
what does this look like this component looks like an i
so the current
some resistance
what's the given by simply giving the network and this current source and as you
how do you measure
what you would do
it is open all the current sources short of the water sources
what they all mean and then measure the distance
OK so we understand the term
what about this term here
because the units of the term here
the big danger
it's the voltage is the voltage
i have the page
so this would be applicable pitch
OK and beautiful example of the tree
so what is that
as far as this current i is concerned
that's part of the skin and eyes concerned
the rest of the universe
as far as can socialize concerned the rest of the universe
looks like it is an unwanted source beginning in some manner
and let me just call it bth
for now and you know why second