mexico co-sponsored of and minus one
we immediately go on to the next statement
and now while we're executing the then minus one
we can also be executing
now this statement which itself will spawn something off
we continue and then we had to sink statements
i think says is
wait until
all children are done
OK so it says
once you get to this point
you gotta wait until everything here has completed
before you
x x plus y because otherwise you can try to execute the
the calculation x plus y without having computed yet
so that's the basic
structure what this described notice in here we've never said how many processors anything running
OK so this actually is just describing logical perils
not the actual parallels when we executed
so what we need is a scheduler
to determine
how many
this dynamically
on two
whatever processors you have available
so today actually willing to talk mostly about scheduling
OK and then next time we're going to talk about
it's about specific application algorithms
and how we analyse them
you can view the actual computation multi threaded computations
take a look
parallel instruction three
it's just a directed acyclic graph
so let me show you how
that work so normally when we have an instruction stream i look at each instruction
being executed from inner loop
i'm not looking at is loop and just looking at
this is the sequence of instructions that's actually execute
i can knew that just as the change before execute one instruction i after
execute the one before it before execute that got execute the one before
these that's the abstraction of course if you study processors you know that there are
a lot of tricks there
in figuring out
instruction level parallelism and how you can actually make that
serial instruction stream b
actually execute in parallel but what we're going to be mostly talking about is the
logical perils inherent what we can do with context
in this DAG vertices
or threads
which are
sequences of
o instructions
parallel control
i parallel control i just means born
and returned from this
let's just mark the
so the vertices of threads so let's just mark what the vertices are here
OK what the what the threads are here
when we enter
the function here
we basically execute up to the point where
basically here call that thread a or just doing the sequential execution up to either
returning or
four starting to do this born
people with n minus one
it's actually thread a which include the calculation of n minus one
right up to the point where you actually make the subroutine jump that's thread a
friend they would be the stuff
he would do
a from fiber farm
he would be he would be from the
right we go up to the sponsors we've done this before and i'm really looking
at this so be would be
up to this born of
so why
OK i want to give them money to compute y
and then we have essentially an empty threats all ignore that for now
and but really
then we have after the sink up and to the point that we get the
return of x plus y
so basically we're just looking at maximal
sequences of instructions that all serial
and every time i do a parallel instruction
OK i'm spawn saying
return from it that terminates
the current thread
OK so we can look at that as a bunch of
small threads
so those of you who are familiar with threads from r
from java threads or from a
PA six threads
OK so copy threads those are sort of heavy weights that express this is much
this is much lighter weight notion of thread
OK that we're using this model
so so those are the
the vertices and now
let me
that battle little bit how this works so we can see where the edges come
so let's imagine we're executing before
so we draw a
horizontal oval that's going to correspond to
the procedure execution
in this procedure there are essentially three
threats to start out with a those are initial red
is this guy here
and then when he executes spawn
OK you can execute respond we're going to create a new procedure
he's going to execute
a new a recursively within that procedure
at the same time
we're also going to be now allowed to go on and execute b
in the parents
parallelism here when i do was born
OK so there's an edge here
this is a judgement call based on swanage
OK and this is called the continuation which
because it's just simply continuing
the procedure execution
now this point
so i jump right back into it so i just have
the final remark on on what types of things you can do in
in the sort of link analysis that that we've been talking about
it's also possible to apply
what i talked about yesterday the probabilistic latent semantic analysis model
in the context of link analysis
in order to discover
instead of what we call concept yesterday to discover web communities let's
and the model works like that you assume that
the link structure on the web is a mixture
of a certain number of unknown latent communities e
the probability that a particular link has to do with that community the probability that
it is source node that community and the probability that t is the target node
in that community and that
gives you a model for the probability that as links to t
OK so
can think of it like that right now community is kind of bipartite graph you
have a couple of sources note a couple of target nodes they can actually be
identical but you know just conceptually might be easy to visualize and then they are
kind of relatively densely
interconnected right and you can use kind kind of model like that
try to find another way to look at this is what you could do with
something like pillars a model
in this context is
you can think of it that way if you you observe this very complicated graph
and what you can do it you pause pillars is actually
decompose that graph on the level of the links
probabilistically since you know you do probabilistically but but let's try to simplify the so
that you think of that graph is actually being a superposition of
a number of simple graphs that represent the community
so we think of you know what we observe is just the superposition
a lot of things that seems to be plausible right because there are all kinds
of people with all kinds of interest that work on this graph right and and
what we might want to do is to two
you know these different layers if we then superimpose them
the kind of get back the original graph and we want to do it in
the way that we really discover you know these kind of densely connected communities
i don't want to
get too much into details but you can you can do that with this PLSA
model you can also combine the link structure with the content information so basically relating
the idea that you extract extract topics with the idea that you use the link
structure and look for things that are look like web communities and then you can
do things like that this just a little
example here what you can do so here is similar to the HITS algorithm used
to query lists to generate a root set and then we ran this popular algorithm
on the link structure and also on the words and then these were the three
communities that we found and notice that you know this query was ambiguous so we
have a space probe ulysses
actually and you see the NASA and is that pages here as the most authoritative
pages and these are the words that characterize that topic and here you have this
is as ground who i didn't know that at the time when i ran that
i was actually thinking of james joyce but he was he was a general in
the civil war
and you see that you have whitehouse and other sites that relate to
that person and here you have a lot of things dealing with james joyce ulises
teacher so you know
education resources in some cases
so that's kind of nice right you can you can you can use
you know we're in hits it's always the question what is the dominant topic in
what do you do with this sub dominant topic and so on and so forth
in this framework you can really you know take some part of the web and
basically break it up into the relevant communities find the rather find the most important
sites all pages in that community and also have some description of what that community
is about
OK but
let me move on OK because otherwise i'll
i'll be in trouble later
so so i'd like to move on now into the part two of my of
my lectures dealing with supervised learning in IR
OK and so what i'd like to talk about this text categorisation is first maybe
i could
whom we can also skip that it depends on you know of people familiar with
naive bayes and support vector machine for text categorisation
should we just skip that
you know what we just skip that part
if we have time later we know we can always we can just swap and
i can i can go back and we talk about
so let me
so just as you know just
imagine i had talked about text categorisation and we moved on to the to the
next part and maybe come back to text categorisation
talking about recommender systems OK maybe that's a topic that so the the
my interesting OK
right so you know talking about the source of
information that we
we that's often available right
there there is usually data that comes with the
the content that we have the objects that we have right to type of
things that we store so these could be documents let's say in information retrieval but
very often we also have data available
about the users you know what people actually do we can collect data about user
behavior user preferences and so on and so forth
what we would like to do
also often is and that's the setting that we're looking at here in recommender systems
is that we would like to
do have the junction tree we should be able to find one
and the first step to finding the junction trees that we should make the clique
graph we should make a new graph in which the nodes the supernodes are cliques
of our triangulated graph
so that's the second step
so that's what i've done here this is my triangulated graph and so i have
walk to find all the cliques i see one two four
two three six and you can see also had some four cliques in the middle
i have two four
five eight clique
that's right there
and i have two five six eight on the right-hand side and then two three
cliques so this this is the clique graph
it's not a tree and i have to do something removes images to make a
so that's that's the third step this is the clique graph i got all my
now i have to figure out which edges i should remove to make make a
and it turns out you can't just remove any edges
but what you want to do is is actually
extracted junction tree by
let me i'm sorry let me back up here what you'd like to do is
what i've labeled these edges with is with how much overlap there is between these
here two four five eight two five six eight that has an overlap of three
they share three elements
this has an overlap of just one they share two
this has an overlap of two elements they share two and four
and it turns out if you want to make a junction tree what you want
to do is actually you want to include the way that the edges that have
the most weight that share the most neighbours
so what you want to do is certainly include three
and then in the end you would like to actually include the next highest edges
the ones with two
and these ones here and you actually want to drop
these two edges at the top and bottom
so that's the sort of third step the sort of technical details here about why
this is correct but i won't go into them to suffice to say that there
are very fast algorithms for finding which edges you should drop in this case i
drop the two lowest ones but for bigger graphs you can't just stare at you
have to run algorithm but the things like rascals algorithm will do this extremely quickly
for you
OK so that's that's basically it now this is your junction tree made you've got
it's annoying
you've got supernodes what i'm drawing here is is actually explicitly showing that what are
known to separator sets the intersections between these that's convention when you draw junction trees
but basically you're done now you can simply just run a tree algorithm on this
that's the tree
and you can run message passing like we discussed before and what this whole theory
guarantees you is is that
this algorithm with these four steps will be correct
at the end of the day the algorithm solitary it will converge and the key
is it will converge and compute the right things
at one level it looks like should be very happy looks like we to solve
the inference problem in general because you now have sort of a general purpose algorithm
that in principle works for any graph
this the sequence of steps all of which
in principle you can do and you'll get the exact answers to these summation or
more marginalization problems
so what's the catch here
there should be a catch or otherwise
many of us have been wasting our time would be much research to be done
so sort of catch here is
the catch really is
again really to this notion of when you eliminate
here we're not eliminating but we're triangulating but it's it's an analogous notion
when you triangulate start increasing the clique sizes
and the reason you should be worried about
is to think about what you have to store
by the binary variables on the original graph
the cliques are just sitting here you just have to store two by two matrices
so just most four numbers
for binary variables you to store k square numbers
four more higher state discrete variables
all of sudden things are getting bumped up by now have cliques over things of
size four even have to start storing tables
the multidimensional tables that are not just two by two to to be two by
two by two by two
so you can see there is again an exponential kind of explosion
it's not exponential in the whole graph but it is exponential in the creeks
so what i'm saying is that you can do this is all very fine
but you're going to pay a price that exponential and how big those cliques get
so you have be very wide from a practical perspective of how big those cliques
get when you do this whole triangulation in clique graph business
so this is sort of the key thing is the size of the largest clique
in the junction tree is actually minus one that's some quantity known as the treewidth
of the graph
in this case the tree with
it's not actually correct for this graph the tree which would be
for the largest clique minus one that is the graph of treewidth three
an ordinary tree just has cliques of size two
minus one that's a tree with one
right so trees are tree with one and there's a kind of hierarchy is you
go to tree with two tree with three to with with four years of getting
bigger and bigger cliques that are arranged in a tree like structure
so the reason this is such a key thing is that the complexity of the
tree algorithm scales exponentially in the treewidth
so it's a no matter what you do is going to pay a price that's
x in the general case is exponential in the treewidth
so the problem is that there are there are many graphs
we have
a lot of edgelets which means oriented segments
right now i see and there is a regular structure and faultlessly circle box with
respect to non
even in a very complicated situations like
what's up with to
if we try
and apply the
partition based approach like normalized
this problem
one by definition
because here we don't have two clusters we have a cluster and we have not
so the idea is that
partition based approaches like he means like normalized
many algorithms belonging to class
just one more this problem because they start from different perspectives can i get to
clustering and then the graph
so for example just show you this work in a very simple example
here we have
we generated a lot of points
random here to create some nice and then we have a dense cloud of points
so the idea is that here we want to extract
is dense cloud of points against the back
so if we apply for example
k means i mentioned before
since it tries to separate the best possible way
two pieces of the graph it will end up with something like this
and if we apply normalized cut get exactly the same problem because they insist on
the partition
question what if we apply dominant sets we naturally extract
four ground against the background
because the dominant set by definition
i want to partition the way they just extract the most are
i mean we also did some numerical experiments very nice
this is the precision
this is what we get rid of that this is what we use now normalized
this is clearly not this is not surprising because these systems
dividing the graph into homogeneous
so the idea is that
the dominant set framework is particularly useful
in all the cases where you want to separate foreground from background and by their
own definition normalized cut partition the approach one
now let's think about a computational problem because
computationally dominance intensive i mean finding dominant sets
i could be quite hard in the sense that can take to
remember we are considering
probably a large graph
maybe it that's right if we take a very large image
you may have millions of pixels
which means in bodies
and millions and millions of edges so it can be quite expensive from the competition
so in a way to speed up the process
another interesting thing is that there are situations where the datasets we want to cluster
it's not that
it involves
dynamically over time
so for example by adding
new image in the dataset of images
so if i add a new image dataset is it makes no sense to restart
the algorithm from the beginning
i can use the previous cluster structure and then they can just decide
the new image to the previous class
it makes no sense to
rear and the
class garden from scratch
so in these situations make
it is important to us to the following
suppose that i already partition the set of data into clusters
and i have a new point new object coming
so the question is
how to sign his new objects into one of the classes from for o canada
for example if we are working on
high resolution image
then we might we might want to perform assembly
of the pixels
a random sampling we perform the clustering of a small subset of pixels
and then the out of sample bits of decide according to some
so the question now is how can i sign
in a simple and efficient way
new query point to cluster structure that covered before
now it turns out the
the very notion of dominance set and that the very notion of
this way here
provides us with a very efficient and
principled way
to assign a new query point
the class
suppose that i already class to the set of points into a set of clusters
new point arrived
management development consultants are sitting having a conversation suffer plays and community treatment because
and have a conversation one of them says that guy
it is an extraordinary leader how does he get those results
he said it must be because he's a great presenter kind of
but that's not quite it
well is it because he likes people that that helps but that's not entirely it
is it because he's a good listener that helps but at the end of the
conversation decided now shoot
there are just leaders in this world
who have something
they're not all of us have
and it must be a gift from god
so they coined the phrase or they coined the word charisma
which in the ancient greek means gift
from god
we still today think of people who were regarded as charismatic as having some
set of behaviours are some set of abilities that must be born into the
they must be a gift from god to give some that ability to influence people
the way they do doing get engagement the way they used
the way data
we set out to specifically c could we find out
what charismatic leader share in common
if we can identify that
could we
for want of a better word bartlett
so that we could help our clients and their leaders to assimilate and get similar
if i go back to this gentleman
anybody recognizes gent
john kennedy
it's extremely hard
to find the people that i would be able to talk about that would be
recognizable on a global basis as having some charisma but
for an irish guy
this guy
it was the first
irish-american catholic president
when i was growing up
i was born in fifty nine
when i was growing up in every home in ireland over the fireplace
there were two four r two pictures
on the left-hand side would be
the sacred heart of jesus and that you have you seen that picture it's the
the heart is exposed as barbed wire around it and cross it's very very old
picture and on the other side was john f kennedy on the same level
that was the the way he captured the popular imagination he inspired a whole generation
of americans and we'll touch on that no
but in a business sense or lots and there is well
one of the ones i going to talk about this morning here is this gentleman
here steve jobs
founder of apple computers
against all odds
he should not
in business today
you don't want to take on microsoft bill gates
because that usually have die
OK but he should not be here today but the force of his personality his
charisma rallied the people who work from to the extent that they get extraordinary results
this lady here recognise her out of curiosity
it's not incredible she is recognizable worldwide now in ireland
we can after next we have obama visit a i newly settled summer
it's been in the news so much and now we have obama visit and you
know and you you think i'm joking i swear to god my mother's life we
have found the irish
routes for obama
have you have you seen that the news that we have traced the back and
we have found a relative of obama in ireland that's what we do
we've only three and a half million people
fifty five million in the united states claimed to have irish blood but that's what
we do we tend to search back in and find the roots of these people
and kind of claim them as their own
obama doesn't really look terribly irish
you know it has to be said but we found the roots we really tried
to find her right
because if you've seen the recent list of the world's most religious people
that lady
i could write a check tomorrow and solve everyone's problems
and we can't find a single reference
but again and again there's somebody who from an extraordinary humble background by the force
of her personality has engaged not just the nation but several nations around the world
and has captured the popular imagination and been extraordinarily successful because of now
when we started off to research says we weren't interested in this sort of charisma
that's all i don't johnny depp or angelina jolie has
now that egotistical
celebrity type a charisma
there is no value it's great fury go but for business it has little value
so the first thing we started doing was we so we have to redefine charisma
and business sense
but by the way
a little bit interesting thing for you to do
everybody when they start researching these days
we all have google
you want to research anything it google or yahoo or whatever
go into
google when you get back to your office about the word charisma in
and the search
and they go along the tabs
look for where you get the biggest number of hits
and it'll be on there
and you get about a quarter of a million hits
on the lady in a bikini
and her name is charisma carpenter
and she is
she plays a part in buffy the vampire slayer
she's apparently according to my daughter data source second-in-command vampire slayer and then in the
programme which is also a glamour model now we obviously with all of the confusion
around charisma
and the way people define and some people thinking charisma carpenter when you mention charisma
we obviously have to find it and say hey what do we mean about charisma
when we put it in a business setting
so we define the more as i say practical or commercial
we set
we want to find out what leader has
when they
create and maintain a work environment where people are emotionally and intellectually committed to the
goals of the organisation
when they build an energetic and positive attitude in others and inspire them to do
their best and perhaps the biggest measure of engagement
where they create a common sense of purpose where people are inclined to invest extra
time and energy and even some of their own time in the work
so we set out to find out
two leaders who managed to do that sharing common one is that they do
they get those results because
that on one hand is charisma in a very practical sense you don't care or
maybe do
we all have an eagle hiding somewhere
as commercial people really are biggest
interest in charisma is if it helps me achieves the numbers i need to achieve
is bound to the bound by Heisenberg uncertainty principle so we go to the single
blocks right this is number number number number we see that as somebody said here
that we had started anomalies these guys should this is something stupidity here's the order
of was which 1
you what this no this is the single strand is going up on just you
this is this is unfortunately this picture right and the left 1 and this is
this is much interested OK with you OK you get it you don't trust me
that if you have average
right is much in pursuit of analysis composite this that will cook so this is
the average
this is the average but again where does it come from comes from single trials
in single trials here we have this that would have this crosses that indicate the
centers of structures know which 1 to see how the structure looks like we click
the cross and we got this is low frequency
white time let's take another small blob that this more time this is very short
in time we see how it looks impressive this is stronger
yeah and so on and play with so many of them were selective reconstructions filters
etc. etc. so what is it it is
and this is 1 of the conditional that from the GP of this program ensuring
curious this up OK this is how to this and that is that the right
place and they should stop at the idea of how do we get to this
kind of picture after we get the data from some of and then we do
in matching pursuit decomposition general matching pursuit decomposition right that some of the
example there are programs the G . P that can be downloaded with complete source
code but this is not the only implementation that exists the planet definitely there was
this 1 in this particular 1 is compatible with the other tool which I was
showing this much interest review whereas we call it is the job of course you
can use it even in Windows and delivery with right so we download both those
things to do in general the composition of each single trial you put it in
the binary file where links partly because it takes time and the moment that computers
to foreign
and then you can
play was like this or any other matlab script that you like to to pretend
that you like to construct
to get the results that we're seeing in the previous slide so what's so good
about whether these are
the origin of his original way of showing
of show in a year and the year as this is 1 of the subject
shown this famous down my increases and we see here it's also almost like 2
100 2 100 per cent increase in gamma this frequency bands the signal was bond
passed through the squared and averaged talking the face relations because obviously going to have
to confess relation where this is the finger tapping right
so the accuracy of I would say that it's not only that it can be
activated at is inherently not in face but also the various uh the various experimental
maybe not exact enough to aligned properly
phase events of higher frequency right because this is just a prison about 1 and
here if therefore the occurs it would be
of the order of tens of the second to get it to data on the
average so
we choose the faces relations and get this averages above this frequency bands were taken
by trial and error of procedure why in this picture we see all the time
a microstructure us we called it in at 1 spot and can immediately see see
what amount you should state to get most of the gamma where exactly the alpha
rhies not between 10 and 12 but from here to there you don't have to
do it by trial and error such as part of this is not the only
frequency estimator will come back to comparison later on
again this is compatible with the proposed approach right because they're curves here
in a way they were estimating the same things
of this matrix like of of half of the smallest
and this gives you the embedding OK
maybe we can talk about detectors and exercises someone's interested
the point is now
this is actually very related to spectral clustering
because in spectral clustering we just said we take this matrix b
mapped to the rows of of this matrix b
now we do something which is very similar to OK we just have this matrix
c with coefficients in front
for spectral clustering we said we met tool
in this matrix the put the i can vectors which correspond to the smallest eigenvalues
now if you look here
we take the inverse of this matrix
and if you not look in but we take all i'd like to here
so what happens but but we scaled and somehow by their
by the i can so what happens is
the i values which are very small in the for the graph and on the
graph the first
brought them put them here so they will be very large so they will really
this expansion somehow buying which are
like the last one of the graph laplacian after putting them they become very small
so the more the spanish
so intuitively one could say
this commute time embedding
there's something which is very related to the to the spectral embedding
and and then
the this story goes OK
i mean the embedding we do expect clustering is essentially the embedding we would do
if we want
better answer to the
d dimensional space and use the commute time
and then we took a means so essentially the
the if you want to somewhere spectral clustering one
sense you could say is that it's the same like computing the commute distance and
then means to
OK i mean that's intuition and if you want to do it exactly it doesn't
work out because
well known spectral clustering we don't have those vectors here so it's
it's about hand-waving but many people find that it's a very nice intuition
two we to understand what special classrooms
OK so if you didn't understand the part that's not so important that to
OK skip the
OK now
OK now we seem intent like we've seen how the algorithm works in principle we've
seen several derivations of how we can derive
now what do we do if we really want to do it in practice
OK and the first thing one has to do in practice and i always get
about this this step so far as we have to
compute the similarity graph OK somehow get the similarity graph of data
now there are very many different ways you can do
so the
the simplest one is
so when i had in the example
i presented in the beginning summer
you just do something like
and compute the
the similarity matrix is something like the ghost in common as i j is
simon is extremely crowded sick muskrat and make sure that
this the similarity between points is only large like you choose sigma such that it
has a reasonable range somehow once it's very far apart have more similarities zero
so that's essentially says
using their completely connected graph
but the weights such that sense of the most of the edges have weight more
OK that's what many people do the disadvantages your matrix is not
it's not sparse i mean you still have those tiny entries in their own for
computational reasons that might not have very much
and there's the epsilon neighborhood graph which essentially says OK
given our data which was some parameter epsilon
and then we connect each point like it's two points which i have distance closer
than epsilon
and for an example here
i don't know whether it's really consider i was some along
and then we connect
points which like within this fall
that's what that many people do
in practice it has large problems because i mean you already see here in this
graph so the question is how to choose the
i mean i it is pretty small
i have OK then i don't have a connection between those two points which is
probably what i would like to guess to get but i here also don't have
a connection here and somehow
it tends to do to fall into very many disconnected components
of course a very bad thing to happen because
spectral clustering as i said in the beginning so
if this connected component
the angle is the angle this will always be the indicator vector of those components
so if you apply spectrograph testing to graph which is not connected
it's virtually every time the the connected components of this graph here this is not
what we want to get
so i discourage that
even though many people use it
the other thing was what many people use which i want to encourage this using
the k nearest neighbour graphs
so what you do there is
so you can do
there are two ways of doing that
i mean the essentially the idea is we want to can connect each point to
its k nearest neighbour so we have say
i can make good example
and i can start with the graph
the from the
so say you want to compute to nearest neighbour so what we do is we
start with this point
check which ones are the twin their nearest neighbour
and put the directed edge here
for this the same we the output directed edges and so on
and for so we do that for each point first of all
say this and
now the problem is if you start with that if ten it is directed graph
first of all
because it can very well be so we see here this data point is nearest
neighbour of this one
because it's just an old the closest one this happens to to be here
but it's not the other way around so if you look at the two nearest
neighbour of the
o find those twelve to nearest neighbour but it's not this one
so the first of august two something which is a directed graph
now there are two ways of making this graph undirected so either you
simply forget all the
that's what the what
absolutely completely robust
it just works period under all circumstances
really basically converges always
so if the problem in including ridiculous things where
after can take on the value plus infinity
they can be nondifferentiable in fact one will see a lot of interesting cases f
is an indicator function
meaning it's zero on some convex set in the plus infinity offered that that indicate
that set could even be thin
you could have it could be flat to could have non empty interior right
so these are not nice functions
from the analysts point of view and this works perfectly
so that's the good news
now rock-solid is robust the bad news is it
destroys splitting of the x update so you can't do
decomposition anymore so OK and that is the historical background brings us to ADMM
and the idea is that something like a method has good road good good robustness
the method of multipliers that's
and it's supposed to support decomposition
and so this is the way you should think of it and this was proposed
in nineteen seventy six although
it turned out later
in the mid eighties it was discovered that you could we derive this algorithm from
material from the fifties
maybe you know in the fifties problem but i don't know
they probably didn't explicitly knowing it but so the main point is this is this
this is not the right so that by the way neither stochastic gradient descent or
any any any of these other things so OK
all right
the form is this
actually it is the western form not the russian for that is the russian form
slightly different it turns out the kind of the same in so in the in
the western form you split the variable which we previously called x into two groups
and medical x and z
and i i we ask that the objective should be separable across x z
we haven't completely general equality constraint looking axons that's completely general constrained
that's it
OK i f and g are convex formal and augmented lagrangian and ADMM is extremely
simple it looks like all the other the other ants you've been looking out for
a while the dual vector y and it says this it actually it's a it's
one gauss seidel sweet
in in the method of multipliers so it says
optimize over x
then z
then you do dual variable update and notice it's identical to method of multipliers rights
got the row there everything is the same
OK so that's it now you can already see
the nice things can happen the first thing is you never
ever optimize over x zhi at the same time
right so basically this says if you have a method for handling minimisation over x
amount for handling minimisation of resi
this will combine them into something that can minimize
probably they can solve problems involve minimisation over both right and usually to be special
methods will see specific examples
and i already said this i mean if you were to minimize directed you jointly
get method of multipliers one thing it should be clear is you're welcome to minimize
over is many times you feel like before you updated to do variables right and
if you do a lot you basically have
you have a method of multipliers OK
and it will be examples and make the ability to split
so here you can say something similar to you why the update and you can
actually understand how
how how this works here what we split our primal variable into two variables x
and z and so there are there is this primal feasibility equality constraints have to
hold and then you have dual feasibility is really stacks so that the two equations
as x dual feasibility and why do feasibility
now when when you minimize the second step we minimize e over this thing
and you work out what it is and then you
i recognise all this and you say hey
plus wrote times this thing the residual is in fact that are up to dual
variables and what you see is this it says the following it says that in
there's three optimality conditions of primal and and to do all and it says that
the dual the second duel is free that when you simply do your dual update
here you get your second you get your second dual feasibility condition for free and
so simply waiting for this primal residual and the dual residual to converge to zero
so that's that's that's what it comes down to
now one thing i should like to point out it's kind of obvious but
it simplifies things it says if you have all you have the linear function into
that the quadratic in combine these into one is complete the square whether really want
to call it and you combine this into
a single quadratic and then cluster constant which dropped because it doesn't matter is minimizing
so so you'll see
in this case you is the scaled dual variables with what wrote times y k
says sometimes you get shorter formulas with this
sometimes this may be clear with this because you see
explicitly in this has a nicer story right that the vector prices somewhere you could
explain anybody what it means right you know when it converges to the optimal prices
this is zero and that the point of this term is a what's that the
cost for violating the consensus this is harder to to that
more complex formulas so we'll see but
OK so here's the convergence theory
you make the absolute minimum assumptions you could possibly make the we basically is this
the functions are convex closed proper
and the other thing is that the problem has a solution otherwise it's silly to
be talking about an algorithm for solving OK so literally that's it there's there are
no weaker assumptions you could possibly make no
and the theorem is this
again from
from the seventies but you can go to the fifties i you know it you
take your choice to win this was now the theorem is it works
and this is very carefully worded here so this is here here's what you can
but there have been no assumptions whatsoever on a and b for example is not
so what is asserted is this
the iterates it's the primal residual goes to zero
and the objective value goes to the optimal value
i think that's true always
here's what's not said there are many things not here because they false
but here they are and when you look this up another referee in other stuff
you'll find it's a lot more complicated than this
and the reason is you know your hypothesis will go on for half the page
and the big and the reason is this they will say things like this here's
what's not said here xk converges
that's false does not converge
do not converge
seeking convergence
there's a stronger statement xk converges to the optimal set that's false too
the k converges the optimal so that's false too
OK so
so what's being said here
four is another one xk in converge to x starring easy star which are optimal
that's also false
OK so very carefully saying don't but if you actually go back and think you
really sit back
and i think by the way a lot of those other statements become true but
you have to start making lots of assumptions
so any questions so far
well is not there
we'll start deriving the SVM primal and dual problems well maybe i can see a
few things about this
there's a curious small small interesting research problem here is how to set testing the
way how each of these species function like this this user is by testing a
in this three-dimensional space so so we do agree
his new point here we check the decision
that's the way how we jones is not being curve is you don't have any
explicit form of the one we have you know
being equation
so how to efficiently
identify these circuits
and show it is interesting to see that this is actually slightly related to how
to speed up testing
but the situation is not
using it in general you do testing you don't know knows
the relationship between those testing instances but you do not you know are a discrete
points in the industry that national cubic
you know that so the situation is slightly different so find ourselves spatial with
to speed speed up testing procedure
so now we need to tell you how to use the dual optimisation comes from
so we need to do some cancellation we can see this simple situation we don't
the selected variables
so in this formulation we have
we have a penalty term and we also have a select variable here to allow
training error
but this a couple of days the derivation of light field so we can see
that we now that
so this is primarily the problem
then the dual like these sort of different from the one we mentioned earlier is
that you don't have the qualities that i is less than or equal to c
you don't need to know about has no upper bound
and all other things are the same
so what i'm going to show you is hard
from these problems we can derive this one
so we're going to use something called fringe do
but this is a commonly used technique in nonlinear optimization more specific issues coming up
to date so we by something called lagrange function
we so that the intermediate region variables so we have the objective function here and
we also have inequalities are constants so we introduce something called lagrange multipliers of i
now we could by because it's really out of our dual problem
so we minus the summation of five times those qualities
so this is called the lagrangian by
lagrangian dual is defined to be like these
so these
so we maximised with respect
inside these processes we might we minimize with respect to w and b
so that's the definition of lagrangian do so it is that it is different optimisation
problem so far
so the four from the SVM primal optimisation problem so we define is not going
to do
so is different is different optimisation problem
so for these lagrangian dual
there is some good properties a spatially this this is the strong duality so strong
duality says that
the mean flow primal problem is the same as this that maximize the maximum of
dual lagrangian deal
so the objective optimal objective values
actually the same
that's the problem but you want to be careful about these people not for every
this property holds
will the later
so you have to be careful for every function such a problem
only for certain functions of of course for our function it will be OK
i think tomorrow in
martin's talk he's going to say something about more about duality is going to define
something called conjugate function
that's actually the general singing in convex optimization so this deal can those is actually
also derived from
that so called conjugate function but not going to do is
basically specifically for constrained optimization problem you so now we have to find what that
do is
and it was so hard
it looks like
so the next thing we are going to do is to simplify
this lagrangian do
try to change it to a simple form
increasing numbers of
that's a good question so essentially asking
was the idea behind primal do
one the big question you can explain the primal and dual front from some economics
series extreme
well i can give you some
very simple explanation here
so the
well let's assume that our final goal is four
some of object you
objective is to elicit this does
that's sort of going on
but is reasonable is not going to find out the different problem in this problem
must be related to the original one that it so is that we are going
to have nice
so that means some of these should be the same as the mean level of
crime in the UK please let me know about
the the objective function to this is the same as the objective function over the
and the right those qualities
the cards
so plainly visible that means
this is fine
in part of this is going to be called the full price
and this is this is a positive
it is nonnegative is nonnegative then
and the other is out is also not make it so
you have the
multiplication of two possible values
so in your mind is something y
so you the object minus something so this should be smaller should be smaller than
the original value right so this is not good is that this violates our goal
made making those two things to be together
so then we have no choice but to to maximize the hosting somehow try to
if it predicts that the features is true more often than it should be it's
which needs to go down and one of these lines from the features we reach
their optimum and we don't
so fairly simple
there's there's there's one big problem that
the big problem is that in order to compute these expected future counts
i need to do inference
and in terms of course is itself expensive
so i'm looking at the expense of inference at every step of the gradient descent
procedure or leave one which could not easily take hundreds of iterations so a lot
of the time this is going to be too slow
and you know people noticed this pretty much right away when they started doing markov
networks in the seventies
and the first thing that they came up with was very clever trick called the
and the idea of this trick is that he show objective function is too hard
to optimize let's optimiser different one one that's easier to optimize
not that it doesn't matter much
so the likelihood is just the product
for all the labels
the probability of each variable given its neighbors in the data
so just conditioning complicated so no inference needs to happen this is something that can
compute immediately given the data
so if i combine this with something like a fast second or the inference method
you actually get quite efficient weight learning
and this is widely used in areas like vision spatial statistics natural language processing and
so forth
the disadvantage of this of course is that optimizing the likelihood is not the same
as optimizing likelihood the problem is that
if she if at inference time you're going to have long chains of inference these
parameters could give poor results
because of its the likelihood is optimizing is the short range interactions between variables
it assumes that the vows of your neighbours are correct and so will tend to
it's also so i can be very fast for some problems it's just fine for
some problems it can actually pretty that so when it's that what can you do
well you can use discriminative learning
in fact is there's in machine learning people
pretty much everywhere tend to use descriptive learning of generative just because it tends to
get better results and it's also easy to see why give the results so the
idea in discriminative learning is that if you know the learning time which variables are
going to be clear variables and let's call those y and which are going to
be evidence
let's call those acts
then what you can do is instead of optimizing the joint likelihood of x and
we can just optimise the conditional likelihood of y given x
and the reason for this is if i'm going to no exit be time there's
no point in trying to model p of x
it's is going to be a waste of time at the best and the worst
it's actually going to you know producer westmont because i'm i'm you know mixing what
i'm trying to optimize with something else that doesn't really matter
so the discriminative learning often works quite well
in our case
what we're going to have this you know a we're going to be optimizing something
that has pretty much the same form
except now i have some lines that y x and i can ignore all the
cliques that only involve evidence variables
another thing that i can do now though is i have another way of dealing
with this hard inference problem
and the way the thing that we can do now
is we can approximate expected counts by counts in the most likely state of y
given x
and this is because
often these distributions have loads all over the place but once condition on on enough
my probability mass of lines being concentrated around just one solutions
it is the most likely region of y given the evidence that i have
so instead of trying to do that exponential sum just find the most likely state
of y and then do feature counts on those often i'll get pretty much the
same result
and of course to finding the most likely state of what does a lot faster
than trying to do the sum over all possible states
so this is the basic idea in a discriminative learning the
this emission is hard in the worst case
in practice what happens is that you can get a good approximation with MAP estimation
when trying to do you know the full
marshall competition would take too long
well i see
i see a lot because it's too it being agreed procedures very fast but will
the product
thank you
now what the issue is that you want you can
starting from this
whether the model
is totally provided
or you only want to make a few assumptions
but your model and you don't care about the whole construct
you could create a simulation approach that's reliance at by
your i from the prior
or from an alternative importance function
and then create regular importance weights
except that's
using empirical likelihood rather
he original likelihood
again whether you can compute on it
and we played
with this notion in in a fairly recent paper
to try to compare the two is a more standard maybe see
in both dynamical
models end
genetic population genetic
we found that this was providing much more stable
evaluation to the likelihood than the regular maybe see
i mean the state of art
eighty six
so why is it seems like it's well it's approximates just like
this picture that we don't really fit base and not
it's a bayesian
this we know it's from this is the picture you get in this paper
i've been because are
well you see me from the prior to more vision could be in debt
and its computational because you provide sample
that's tryst approximates
a certain target
as in this example where it where it works beautifully
i don't pretty picture employed doesn't work
right now
it really revision world
the only justification of local likelihood
like the whole collection of those econometric methods
i presented
it's validated by the sample size growing to infinity so is it really is meaningful for us
that's debatable
the second point for is more important is that
we have
giving an approximation to the truth
what truth is our means
the trouble is that this approximation is very hard to assess so image
these methods are good approximations
methods sometimes they are the only way to provide an approximation
but unless you an extensive simulation
magnitude that is higher
than the one you need to produce the approximation
you don't really all following are from the true and that's that's a big drawback
but again
in seeking realistic situations like the one
we face in popular in population genetics
this may be the only
right sorry implementation because otherwise we'll have to wait
weeks or years or we would have to use
alternative models that do not provide the same
amount of information
i okay
this is just an introduction so now can which
these baby say
so the jimenez maybe see
and i just
to us about the genetic background of the main reason i
don't want to make a more of a fool myself
about this thing about genetics so i
play safe and don't say anything
the second thing is that
some of the talks be
listening to and awake are
connected to his genetic so
there was no way to talk about
so i mean that we see
the gennady started
in practice
the population genetics about fifteen years ago
to deal with
genetics and i was reading populations to to a common ancestor where people
we're interested in
the parameters driving the divergence
between populations
and so there are a few parameters
when talking of of big data but seriously you could be
as small as two dimensional
one dimensional
can be smaller
this parameters were hard to
derived because the likelihood
very funny shape depending on
this population tree
towards the most common ancestor
that's was
huge and difficult to integrate
and this is this is a kind of example that's
they want to is
we are randomizing where you had several tribes
of of pygmies in
western africa
this equation
the badges were considering where it was about the origin of those
pygmy tribes namely whether weather-related together are ends issued from the branch
from the non pygmy population
earlier or are the split was
more complex and so there is this kind of scenarios
and you can just have to look at the colours
these events and i is they wanted to compare and trees
that a pretty good coverage structure was interesting but
the actual tree of going to the most common ancestor
it was not so this
difficult problem because the likelihood was not available so that's how it started
that's essentially who were in a kind of missing data
problem but there was so much missing data
that's this integration
it was not possible
it was only possible in the simplest of cases
and otherwise it would
have taken too long
to compute
going back to to the to the same problem namely that we have
the likelihood function
that's in many cases is completely
define you know it entirely
in other cases
as in empirical likelihood no few features but is you know it
you don't know what to do with it because it's competition is impossible and so forth
you can do and seems
you got importance sampling you can do any of the regular
trick that we are so used to
and so the question is whether we give up
any approach with potential u
you to change the model
it's not like in other methods is available all year after so four degree approximation
integration is how much approximation if it
and so
you have to do
maybe systems for almost these can standards
it's not based on most candidates on those based can
the magnetic field gradient between two entangled electrons
okay so you know this robin uses quantum information so you know why not us
okay well you know now let's ask you know so is could quantum mechanics be
relevant to the brain so you know there are three proposals that i've seen for
how it could conceivably be relevant it's important to keep them separate okay the first
proposal would be that the brain is literally a quantum computer that can run the
quantum adiabatic algorithm assures algorithm or whatever
okay the second would be you know there's all the idea that the collapse of
the wavefunction somehow has to do with consciousness
and the third proposal would be that there are quantum-mechanical limits on the physical predictability
of the brain okay so to cut to the chase i'm going to argue that's
based on our current understanding the first two these possibilities
it can be pretty strongly rejected
the third i have no idea
and in fact i think it's a wonder you know it opens up wonderful a possible avenues for research
okay so
could the brain by a quantum computer well we've already discussed this idea's physical implausibility
favor no know i wanna make a different point which is that you know even
you know if you forgot about the physics there are others severe problems with this
idea that i think are just as important as the first is that we now
know a lot has i told you about the sorts of things that a quantum
computer would be good for
okay factoring integers discrete logarithms
simulating quantum field theories you know
maybe some kind of small speedups for combatant modest speedups for combinatorial optimization problems available
you know is you know with the possible exception of the
the last not of these are things that you know had obvious survival value in the african savannah
it's not clear why we would evolve these these abilities right
you know maybe more to the point you know i don't see any evidence that
humans do solve problems like factoring integers are simulating quantum physics efficiently claiming yes humans
do seem amazingly good at certain types of problems but you know what the things
that are good at are just not at all a good fit for a you
know to the things that we've discovered that a quantum computer you know would would
be good at would give us the speed for
thirdly you know even supposing that the brain where quantum computer certify i wonder how
that would help it all sort of the mystery of consciousness that presumably motivated the
suggestion right i mean you know
you know like that we talk about the small any old mind body problem right
it's not clear to me how you are going to bridge the gap between mind
and body with a hardware upgrade okay
which is really what we're talking about here right and you know this is like
you know very common objection it's been made for example roger penrose is ideas right
even supposing it's right you know it still doesn't seem to explain consciousness
okay so could conscious you know could
consciousness be needed for the collapse of the wave function well if you wanted to
believe that's then here is what you would have to believe
okay you'd have to believe that you know the big bang the universe has some
quantum state can then first thirteen point seven billion years it evolves by a unitary
you know
no measurement anywhere inside and then you know the earth cools you know and then
finally you know human evolves and maybe it's a monkey or something right and they
and they look around and then they'd just suddenly
and then violently collapses the universe is quantum state okay this is
now if think an absurdity so you know my conclusion is that if collapse is
a physical phenomenon at all if you want to believe it is then u have
to also believe that something that can happen all over the place and the interiors
of stars are whatever triggered by some physical conditions that we don't know yet okay
even with no conscious observers for light years around you know otherwise i think we
get nonsense
but now what about quantum limits unpredictability this will be my last thing right well
let's consider faxing yourself to another planet like in star trek okay so you know
you go into the brain scanners scans your brain you know that's lake tahoe
that's mars
you know
u end up over there are okay
you know it sounds great you know i i can we have it okay well on
so if you're going to do this you know one think that it's important to
remember to you know have the original copy of yourself painlessly euthanised you know if
you leave it live radio knows which one you're going to wake up this
may be a wake-up is the original copy okay are you know maybe you want
keep a backup copy of yourself right but you know with ten backups if you're
running around you know how do you know which one u are how do even
make you know bayesian predictions in in
in social world okay so you know you start thinking about these puzzles which philosophers
about your strategy for solving the way problem reminder just twelve balls and you guarantee
that all exactly equal except for one that either heavier or lighter and you don't
know which and you've got to find and whether it is heavy or light in
a few users as possible
time to vote
and the options you get to vote for
i'm asking year question about your your strategy how many weighings do you need i
don't mean sometimes i can do it into i mean always can guarantee to do
in this many so my strategy will find and others have relied in at most
thirteen uses of the balance when you tell me how many you need to be
sure that you're going to be done first called that that means i have got
strategy hands up is that everyone else must vote for one of the other numbers
you can do it in thirteen but does need thirteen OK
in his twelve and eleven in ten
and lots of people
another important and what about three
let me ask you another question
so so we can understand what's going on
what do you do first do a
sixty six five five four four three
all other options
i think a please vote if your strategies for straying is i don't know i
made up pretend i had strategy but i haven't got one
for six again six is my first way OK for that
five five
four and five
quite a lot
three against three
four of the two against two
no i
one against one
right six against six down a few of you
please can you tell me
what was your answer to first question if you do six against six first can
you do it we in the five gang
during the full hands up
three gang
interesting OK so the sixty six gun
or in
maybe it's a good use of time since they are not claiming canada three to
ask about what the balkans for gangs are to so
and you have the majority after all
let's wait for again for
step one is a forward
one that reminds the first way
who has to skip over three and three gangs
is that about three or four
three industry three
two million for
OK i can use in three
in your
no OK so far against the young in the nest
obviously lots of these three
people say lots of these four people also in the following focus the majority
right so we're not done yet because
we sought to establish may be doing for against always a good idea
maybe we're not sure why
so we do this and let's say that this site comes and heavy and i'll
call these possibly heavy balls and can we possibly like balls and i'll say these
are definitely good
so someone from the foreign support community has already advocated the strategy what the hell
are you going to do now so someone to suggest what you do next
really the lights on the light side
they have you ever had
so only one of the lights
three goods in there
and what they really want table
OK i think i misunderstood i
three like OK three satellites are sitting on the ground for that suggestion number one
but you didn't all that show something else
let's be explicit you have to have these on the left
OK i want to know what you have on the left and we have on
the right you have left to have is and anything else
OK and what you have on the right
three good ones and one
like so you've put on two
the tabletop still
one good
one potentially life and we have is
right to get around the difference
another suggestion
i wish i there's lots of you and you also need it
what he did
someone who didn't do one of these things
OK so have heard
against good good good
thus putting all the lines
on the table
another option
he a lot like heavy thus leaving
all goods on the table and one of the light and what heavy
option five
like that
but right
two relax leaving on the table
two goods
and two possibly have
correct OK so one way of trying to solve this problem is to hunt around
through all of these options
maybe it's a good idea to have a principal so you can justify
pages rather than just searching random which is possible way of solving problems so that
can get in principle while
on the border moments ago we had principle all that said how much information you
get from around random variable think of the outcome of the weighing as a random
variable how much information you get is the log of one of the probability and
the expected information that you're going to gain is the entropy
shannon's right
his advice which is guaranteed but if is right then the possible strategy would be
to say let's push on in charge let's use the entropy to choose what wayne
we do
just make sure that we choose the way
such that the random variable which is the outcome which looks like this or this
or this
has got maximum entropy
that's why getting maximum possible information and
how about that for strategy
let's try that idea
with some
i wrote the structure of the world is very simple you have
ten or or
and each highway
is divided into so
you have
three lanes
going westbound
three lanes going eastbound
and there are some brands
some exhibits an inference
two the different
two to the highway
and these exhibits an inference we learn given the
cut the possibility for the
to change the highway
two to go to another highway
so the idea
is that there's a simulator
which generate
movements of the cold and the vehicles that are supposed to send their position
on this grid
every thirty seconds
in the rule applications application they may be problem
of delay
between the car and the central system so here there's is no
the problem of the labour unique clock
and we assume that all positions
all positions of the car
are transmitted instantaneously
two of the UH to the
monitoring centre
system is a random generator traffic
and another thing is that
the generator generates one accident
every twenty minutes generate the accident random
what's the problem
from this
these vehicles sending them
position every fifteen minutes
two kind of things
i have to be done
the first thing
to do
i have told
so the price to pay
to use the highway
depending on the traffic
the more traffic very
the most expensive is the top
so there are some rules
given here
we said that
each car
has to be
notified of twice
and actually the twice is associated to
segments of the highway is divided into seven segments
and the price depends on the segment and the traffic and the segment so when
the car enters the segments it's not if either
the price for this segment
and it gives the car two
the ability to change
at the next segment
in order to
two use segments we've low traffic and to have a low cost low
the told
so the system
has to compute
the total for each statement in real time
send it to the court
and then he and compute the
so you have here
we cite who was
used in this system
so the first
the problem is to compute in real time
the term for each segment and the total for the
the second
problem is that the the core
she was some queries
their account
they make a
in advances
can ask queries about the balance of their account
ask queries about the expense
over the last ten weeks
these are queries about the past
and also we can ask queries about the future
when they plan to do it three how much is going to
cost of vector
this is the pictures
application that i think it's interesting and it can be turned into a real applications
a in the next year so we get back to this example
and to see how it so
by one system
so what's the problem
there are several problems
when dealing with three
so here i just give some
more problems in order to illustrate
how the
can solve this problem
so we take one example which is
the computation of daily electric power consumption by customer
market segments
and we want to compute this
we have some should
that they are a very large number
customers having you need to and sending back consumption for instance every hour
solving this query we need to do
several things the first thing is that we need to
capture all the trees of the different
then we need to merge
then we need to make it john
between these extremes and the customer database because we want to
being the sum of electric power consumption by
customer market segment and the customer market segment is not present
in the
measurements were done at the customs house but on the information system
the customer data
so we have to join
these three
two are fixed stable
in the company in order
to compute
so with standard tools you can do
or the need to
all refs you put it in the database because the database or another one
you compute
the daily consumption
and you make an SQL query on the the database you have the answer
that's what you have to do
if then
you cannot store all
the consumption you have to be
the of the data
in order to make room in your database so with stream applications you want to
do this
on the fly
without story or data
i mean without storing or
electric power consumption
measurement measurements
from this
another example
which is more difficult is the
to find the
one hundred most africans
IP addresses sending IP address on the router
you will find this would double slit interference
you will find that i is for i zero
times the cosine squared
delta over two
and and for those of you have a good memory
remember that arises in class when you only have two vectors that you had
that light intensity
because with the cosine square of delta
now you also
i have this year
we also know that the maximum
this two slit you see four times more light
then if there were only one
you can do this of course
on their own by substituting
in this equation n equals
the the first thing that i want to do now is to make
a plot of that function
i will do that for any calls for
and then we will discuss all the consequences
also for cases that is much larger than before
i'm going to close this
for any equals for so we only have four
open and i always plot
the only sign theta
the reason why i like to call all these things in terms of science data
theta is the real geometrical angle
he is this screen with openings and there is an actual and the actual angle
thing something that i can immediately relate to this is ten degrees twenty degrees this
is seventy degrees delta is the phase angle
but it's not a real angle base
so i always like to plot
intensity in terms of sin theta
but you can also do it if you want in terms of delta
all right is science there is zero
there you get zero divided by zero
and you're going to get
the maximum
this sign theta is led that divided by deep
you're going to get the maximum
if i say
is land that divided by p you see the delta two pi
you get the maximum
you get the maximum here
sin theta is too
land that divided by p
you got the maximum
and of course on the other side minus land over the
you also get next
and according to the creation
if you really believe that equation for better
and all these big
we have the same
it would be sixteen i zero
in vicinity and square
and i will show you the first of all probably
but if there are
four split
in between
the prime maximum
there are n minus one locations whereby you have
completely destructive interference is zero light
and minus one in this case is three you will see shortly white is an
minus one
thirty three locations here
whereby by
there is zero light
i put to me and then i'll draw the curve
that's the zero and so i'm going to make an attempt now
the light intensity
prime xmlmime and zero divided by zero is and screened
here's another one zero divided by zero becomes and squared
and here's another one by by zero divisor becomes square
if you wanted to know what the delta is here
well the delta here is zero of course
the delta is two pi
and the delta here
forty five
the first one to show you or at least draw your attention to the fact
there's the wavelength dependent lab
what that means is
but if you take six hundred and fifty
nanometers which is red
red have the maximum here
the redwood have the maximum here the red will have the maximum the red which
have the maximum there
but is now you have
four hundred nanometers which is
violet light
it will have a maximum at different locations
he zero all always have the same location maximum
but the wavelength is
four blue for violence so you will be maximum
violet you would be the maximum for violence
and roughly here will be the maximum for violence
and roughly here
the reason why the red and blue there almost coincide i mentioned that also last
time for both the
is that
two thousand six hundred fifty is roughly three times four hundred
so they live a life of their own
that's now address the issue of the n minus one zero
i first want to calculate
what the location is here
where you have your first
complete zero
well you would have you for zero
when the upstairs is zero
and it comes out to
three point two percent
so think about that's kind of surprising result
here you had this test and it was supposedly reliable test
and you had a positive result
and somehow
the probability that you have the disease is still only a little more than three
probably OK
why is that
so about surprising result how can it be so low
the reason it can be so low obviously is the
probability to have the disease given up
positive test result is proportional
the prior probability to have the disease which was very low
that was only one in a thousand
so by getting the positive test result you're probability to have the disease has jumped
from ten to the minus three
up to
o point o three two
so it has definitely increased should be taken second test
but nevertheless because this prior probability is so low
what is called the posterior probability that is to say the probability in the light
of the outcome of the measurement
is also still quite low
now one thing is interesting about this example is that i haven't yet
i haven't even specified whether i'm talking about frequentist probability
or subjective probability degree of belief probability
and interestingly in this particular example either one could be relevant depending on
your point of view your viewpoint would be my degree of belief that i have
the disease is now three point two percent that's that's your subjective degree of belief
about the current situation
on the other hand your doctor may was statistic and think i five is a
large number of people like this will get the positive test result the fraction of
them who have the disease would be three point two percent so bayes theorem applies
regardless of whether we are interpreting probability as
the long-run frequency
or is the degree of belief
we will see other examples of this using actual particle physics examples as well
so as i mentioned there are these two sort of competing schools of statistical inference
the frequentist school and subjective or also called bayesian school and i just wanted to
spend at least one slide each outlining the general philosophy of these two directions
so in frequentist statistics
probabilities are only associated with the data that is to say with the outcomes of
a repeatable observations and very often or use some sort of shorthand like to use
the letter x or maybe the letter x with vector symbol
that's what i mean that data
outcomes of a repeatable observation
so the probability is only interpreted as a limiting
frequency and so we would never actually talk about same
the probability for the higgs boson to exist
or the probability that a certain constant of nature like the strong coupling constant
is between a certain fixed range like point one one seven to one two one
alpha is is either within that range
or it isn't
and no repetition of any the experiment will change that so the probability would either
be zero or one
but i don't know necessarily know which
so since the
frequentist statistics only tells you what kind of data you should expect given certain probabilities
it's not obvious how
such a method can be used to distinguish between good theories and that there is
roughly speaking the preferred theories that is to say the models that you choose to
favor are those models which give a high probability for data
which is similar to the data that you actually got
it seems like kind of a convoluted way of saying it but
but that's the way it works
it's the preferred models are those for which our observations would be considered usual in
some sense of usual they predict data which is similar in in some way to
the data that we actually obtained
and most of the
methods that will be discussing in the next three three and a half days
actually fall into that category
OK so then the competing schools
is what's called bayesian statistics
and the general philosophy here is the following
is the new for the data
you use basically the same interpretation of probability as in the figure to school you
would regard that as the limiting frequency if it makes sense to repeat the observation
but in addition
you use subjective probability for hypotheses so you could talk about something like the probability
that supersymmetry is correct the probability that the higgs boson exists
and what you would like to know
in a bayesian analysis is the probability for some hypothesis h
given the outcome of your measurement x
that somehow would be the ultimate goal
the analysis
and you would use bayes theorem in order to get that you relate the conditional
probability for the hypothesis given the data
to the probability for the data
given the hypothesis that's also what's called the likelihood
but in bayes theorem you also have to
right down what's called the prior probability the probability for the hypothesis
before you some data and here i write that with pi
but that simply is my notation for the prior probability
right so
so have a big discussion there about can we learn causality from from the real
world so can we can we discover whether smoking causes cancer by observing correlations between
the people who smoke also tend to have cancer because we can't directly infer a
causal relationship could be some common cause
the cause people to want to smoke and gives them cancer and the difference is
really interventions if you stop smoking or you less likely to get cancer or not
and if you make an intervention then you discover that causal relationship from correlation alone
you can't so the big field of research with discovering causality from statistical data
graphical directed graphs and one of the tools that are used in the field
thank you
twenty five years
for the
absolutely so
if you have three variables these variables might be physical processes in it might be
the x causes one x and y together cause z and to express your model
in terms of that graph feel quite right because markov equivalent graph we can reverse
the direction of one of those arrows novels and the properties and we completely equivalent
thank you very much
any other
any other questions or
point of clarification
OK let me give you an example then this is called the
manchester asthma and allergies study and the goal is to discover
fundamentally discover the environmental and genetic causes of childhood asthma which is you know an
amazing proportions
of children suffer from asthma it's huge major disease
in the western world
this study is the birth cohort study just over a thousand children monitored since they
were born
and we recently collected genetic information
four for each of the children in the study
alongside the genetic information we also have over the years we've collected all the study
has collected
very very detailed clean carefully collected environmental and physiological measurements for example skin test to
determine allergic sensitivity blood tests that measure
logic sensitivity notes on whether the child
was wheezing or not mexico only from the child reason a little bit of a
substance which induces an artificial asthma attack and you measure how much of this stuff
breathing before the show symptoms of asthma in children go through a lot to contribute
to this study and then measure their age is one three five and eight so
we have
data three times
and lots of other background information about with parents smoked and whether they have furry
pets and so on
so this is this is not directed graphical model yet this is sort of a
block diagram begins to capture some of the prior knowledge which the collisions have about
the nature of asthma and things which affected you may not be able to read
from the back the details are not important point the point is there are lots
of different factors here they connect to each other in very specific ways
so we have asthma
some here in the middle we don't actually observed that directly what we observed the
symptoms of things like wheezing and so on and the three major routes to causing
asthma inflammation of the airways
the force of strength of the airway system measured by the national total lung function
is called and the
bronchial hyper responsiveness how twitchy the system is how how rapidly the bronchial system response
to external stimuli such as allergies and over here this is the
part of the graph which describes allergic response here we have a box labelled genome
but of course the genetic the genetics points all sorts of aspects on this graph
this diagram itself is not even complete just the partial picture
so i'm going to do is take one little piece of this diagram and expanded
up and turn it into a directed graph
the point of this is to show that he's an example we we're not simply
looking for correlations between genetic variability in the binary disease label asthma not as much
the real world is much more complex as well as being many genes that affect
asthma there are many environmental factors
rather than just throw them into the big black box statistical model we're doing here
is catching all the
clinical prior knowledge that we have about the way the variables affect one the
so it's just a little piece of this
and turn this into a directed graph
so here the nodes on the graph here the arrows
is this is a binary variable which says whether or not the child has acquired
sensitize asian to particular allergen and h one
and similarly for age three five and eight
which is a binary variable
these boxes are called plates these just mean that what's inside the play gets replicated
a certain number of time so this is the place for the children down here
says children one thousand one hundred eighty six everything inside here
it is copied for every child every child has a copy of this variable
this plate is a plate for allergens of which there are eight mice cat dog
egg milk peanut and so on and so everything inside this place replicated a times
each child has eight variables to do the quite sensitize asian h one to each
of the eight elections
and this is
the to question this is an example of a directed graph showing
variables evolving through time so
we assume in this model the these are able form markov chain so the census
isation age five depends directly on the sensor isation h three is not directly on
the sensor asian and h one
these are all things we don't that we don't know do
we have yes
the way to accuracy
the support vector machine
it's bigger than
this actors you basically just regression
in order for me to figure out whether these images expressions converging whether it is
optimizing the wrong objective function
the diagnostic and when the user checked to see quality three
so let me explain
so in this one right on this just those two equations copied over
and it's one that say that
j of SVM is indeed greater than appeal
j of resumes passenger JFK pl
but we know that these images aggression
i was trying to maximize j theta
that's the definition of these images aggression
so this means that
the value theta of images aggression actually fails to maximize j
because the support vector machine actually return value of theta that that the
but the job maximizing j
and so this tells me that these images it regression didn't actually maximise
j correctly and so the problem is with the optimisation of optimisation hasn't
the other case
is as follows where on
g of theta as you is less equal to j of the to be or
in this case was only
this means that these images aggression
actually attains a higher value
for the optimisation objective j
then does the support vector machine
the support vector machine
which does whereas
on optimisation problem
actually does better
on the weights accuracy measure
so what this means is that something that does whereas on your optimisation objective
i j
you can actually do better
on the way to the accuracy
and this really means that maximising
j theta
it doesn't really correspond well to maximizing your weight accuracy criteria
and therefore this tells you that j f theta is wrong optimisation objective to maximize
just maximize ingested is just wasn't good objective to be choosing if you care about
the weight accuracy
so how this makes
so that tells us whether the problem is with the optimisation objective
or whether this with the objective function
and so going back to this slide the we had you know this is that
if you run gradient descent from more innovations
that fixes the optimisation of trying it is better
because the optimisation
whereas using different value for longer and longer times normal square in your data
fix this optimisation objective
changing to an SVM is also another we're trying to fix optimisation
and so on
once again you actually see this quite often
she didn't see very often people will have a problem with the optimisation objective
the following content is provided under creative commons license
your support will help MIT opencourseware continue to offer high quality educational resources for free
to make a donation or to view additional materials from hundreds of MIT courses
his MIT opencourseware OCW MIT that EDU
the that's a good one that's good
opera house
what oprah
i wasn't wagner
but it's good guess it's certainly very small style way over the top that was
maria callas
singing lemon water from
under addition you
which was written
in eighteen ninety five
and premiered in
the spring
i have eighteen ninety six
exactly at the time when the world was going nuts over
this mysterious form of radiation that could see inside
the human body
that there was a good
good match
things best best-in-class that's maria callas this is opera for those of you who don't
like opera
listen to this
this by the way some of you may recognise if you saw the movie philadelphia
this is the piece that is playing when the
tom hanks character visits the loft and the edges with denzel washington's character visits the
lost to tom hanks' character
this is playing
it's a fantastic piece
way over the top and this maria callas who was
the woman that restored
four opera
so going to listen to it
and there's birth rankin's hand
reminding us of
the fact that you always irradiate the one you love
so i have a few announcements
the next week a week from today
there will be no lecture instead celebration of learning
celebration number two
wednesday the twenty seventh
coverage through today's lecture
i will go through
the generation of x-rays but we won't touch anything to do with the use of
x-rays and indexing crystals brags like that stuff so
and anything we talk about today i think it's fair game
i'll go back to
in the early part so i think last time we set up into the until
the twenty second son to say
the twenty second is fair game we started talking about the properties of ionic compounds
electron transfer octet stability so we'll go through all of these
can refer to ground will and with x-ray spectra but not break the law
so the second thing i want to remind people that we've been getting i staff
meeting yesterday my recitation structures that some of your
part puzzled to learn that there's more than one book
the text is in fact three volumes and right now the x-ray
readings are coming from this volume here called the core supplement
so you need to be aware of that also some of the best materials in
the archive notes on the web
and also all of these images that i show
they get posted as well so some of you are feverishly taking notes and that's
but if you miss something you can go on
take it off the website as well
last point came out of the staff meeting last night
a number of people are becoming tati about
taking the weekly quizzes you're allowed to miss the weekly quizzes for
either health reasons or something
crisis in the family
but not because you just decided to sleep introduce i'd you like to take into
later times on giving the TA's discretion to deny you
the right to take a make-up unless it's proper i'm not asking that you come
in medical certificate or anything but
i will take you on your honor but i do expect you to take those
test when they are offered if you can't
taken on the day you can take a makeup up to one week
after that we want to close the books on and we're not going to allow
you as is the practice in other classes to throw away here
your bottom two or three scores
if you don't take it get zeros and that gets average your homework grade
know i want you to have the discipline of weekly
homework and weekly homework quizzes so
i know the two recitation structures are
announcing this but i want you to hear from me as well
it's only good it's good it's good for your mental health to take those tests
keep shoot shark
so our last day we talked about rankin and the discovery of x-rays
rankin was working in the laboratory
are studying gas discharge tubes in his special take was high voltage and low pressure
and under these circumstances he was generating
on the nodes to him until the night of november eighth eighteen ninety five photons
of wavelength approximately one angstrom
i looked at the
relevant physics
and concluded that
we could explain
the generation of x-rays by
this energy level diagram which is the energy level diagram of the target this is
the anode
the gas discharge
as a
which is charged negatively
and the electrons are made to
boil off the cathode accelerates from rest and they crash into the anode over here
and we think
when these electrons crash into the anode they cause the set of
o operations that ultimately result in the emission
of photons
in the next region of the spectrum so this is the energy levels of the
element here
in the target
and we reason that these incident electrons coming with kinetic energy imparted by
acceleration voltage is in the range of tens of thousands of volts have enough energy
to come in
and actually
this large come in and this large
inner shell electrons in the extreme even
n equals one k shell electrons and when that happens
there's vacancies that invited cascade
so we have a cascade of electrons in
and the target
from higher levels down to lower levels and as you know going back to the
early part of three nine when electrons move from high energy to low energy photons
are emitted and these photons are the source of the x-rays these are the x-rays
we saw that if we had a vacancy in the k shell we could get
electron moving from
l shell down the k shell
and such a full-time was termed the k alpha full-time k because the photon came
from an electron cascade into the k shell alpha because it came from one shell
you know what we deriving that will have
great right
is a pretty question
how you want to define or rewards from doing reinforcement learning is actually pretty tricky
let's say for simplicity that
i get reward one if i can eat snacks
and by the time steps get reward zero otherwise
may not be exactly what you want to do with it but it is something
and then
what i'm doing at the time step percent saying
that get a snack to get snack it's that to get snack
and the proportion of times to get a snack
the value
of of this
and then
i'm backing up in the short history
it's taken max over different actions are available and taking expectations
over executions obesity actions
we start from the
bottom of the tree
then you back
to try to figure out
how much reward to expect that i could get
if it takes some particular action
now right
so the computation so the process of creating the tree is top down
and the computation of which
of what the costs are said to be bottom-up
OK so it's the claim
this should be in a
the claim is that
if we use this backing up process
and we get some estimate the
we can achieve if we go in some particular direction system is accurate to within
this quantity
this is essentially
a more concrete version of the central limit theorem right so if only with six
bit then you know that if you drop things a whole lot then then
social credit counseling if you look at the expected value true
it in this particular case
so that you can
you can quantify
how much of the gaussians using the chernoff bound
actually the half timbers sharpened
this is what you get
the deviation with high probability the deviation between the cost you compute by this process
of backing things
and the actual
cost or reward
for taking some action is
and by this
so this tells you that
OK should kind of girl like
in every case where
so it's curious
so instead of approximate methods
finding the costs of different actions in our first state
and then we can
trying to learn some
predictor what to do in the first eight
and then we can use the same method
to get an approximate estimate of the costs in the second stage
you can learn there and so forth and basically all the guarantees that we had
before going to hold up to this kind of precision that
so this is that if you have a generative model
it's actually possible to solve reinforcement learning
one possible and it's possible that if you can
eat some sort of portal exponential
it's interesting
theoretically the interesting in practice because you can't actually
takes exponential
maybe it's worthwhile to think about
what can we do which is not going to involve these
severe exponentials
so we know that is possible given generative model
to succeed
if you can make some additional assumptions
we can we can
without the super exponential number of interactive the generative model
it turns out that it is in fact possible
if training time here that not policy
so i have alex to get me to the next
in the heavens generative model
then i can solve reinforcement learning by a continuous reinforcement cut costs cost sensitive classification
maybe assuming they have enough policy available training time is a little bit too strong
it turns out that you can even succeed with a weaker assumption the weak assumption
is that
you don't necessarily know
what are the policies you can have
you know where
policy will
well it
so i it's maybe you should think about thinking about that
the process sort of very well defined you know there are balls
you're going to come into some small region
and if you do act the ball hard right
so you you know
two the distribution of observations about policy
i will be making in deciding upon
and this is sufficient
this was the generative model
is sufficient to self-reinforcing
when you can reduce the cost of the classification
so all this is what is reduction statement
so first of all to