with a the k time
which is too divided by gunmen
i remember guidelines unit second minus one for this really has units time
so this one is going to be responsible
four that pain that we discussed earlier
what does this now
two power
j and n is obviously a frequency
this is
a striking example in the complex plane of a rotating
that story
and the angular frequency
it is and but we know is
and so this and the really is nothing but omega square and squared is really
omega squared
and so i can replace this and now
by whatever you have here
and so if i write is now
lines come over to
i can write down all j
only get a lot of
and i know exactly now what that omega is
that is the square root
of this number
and so therefore we get square
is omega zeros grant miners gone over four
so those of you the audience
four intuitively senses that the frequency would go down because of the friction there right
psi omega is lower
then omega zero
now of course if gamma is very low the two could be closed again
benson time that's always if you have a lot of friction then
omega lot lot less than omega zero here very little friction
well then they will be very closely
the same
and so we can now write down
in all its glory
the real part of this function
which then becomes x
equal some
amplitude a
times into the mine is gonna
over two times t
i'm in two minds j
times omega
lots of
look what i did
i have equation in the complex plane
it's perfectly OK
and then i went back to the real world going from the
the complex plane
but the real part of z
what i write down
this is fine
then i wrote down into the power miners j omega people all
first of all there should not be a minus sign in front of the j
that's not a major problem but i do not take it out of the
complex brain i believe in the complex plane spoke
clearly what i should have read the which is what i will do now
he calls eighty eight times e to the minus come over two times t
the cosine
of omega t plus of now
we are in the real world
you're going to see this equation
at least for the next five to ten minutes on the tape it is for
my site but there's nothing i can do about it you just have to live
with it
and think of it
as being this
and there are two adjustable
constance which depends entirely on the initial conditions
at time t equals zero
there are two things you can do to the object you can bring it to
a certain point away from equilibrium and you can do with the cake
recall the velocity
you are free to choose any way you want to do that
so it's clear that was those two choices that you have
that you final solution
you end up with two adjustable constant which
depend on the
initial condition
and so you see that this amplitude is going to die out
it was one of the decay time of to overcome
and that the
is lower
then the frequency
of the undamped system
i tried to make a
so here's t
and here is x
and to guide my
and i'm going to first
fourteen is exponential
and now i'm going to put in
term here
well by the frequency is uniquely determined omega is uniquely determined and the period p
is that omega
divided by two pi
could i
look what i wrote
i wrote team
because omega
divided by two pi
it was not my day
it should have been keep
now i think in general that we have about
where there is this specialization relations of things higher up
say more about the higher-ups in more they might be
so pedersen or they might be
it's about piece of that contain more events and more edges
things mall
that's a frequencies of size one recites who and what was so we have lot
of patterns and we would like to find
which things are frequent
one can
defined notions of the border of waste or or a quarter of the same
let's all concrete to think about
frequent sets
so the positive
it's a collection of subsets of the set of variables
the positive border of the set are all maximal elements of maximal with respect to
set inclusion
so all those that are frequent but none of whose supporters have been
so that's the positive border
the negative order is are the minimum sentence
which are not frequent so the sets which are not frequent but all of whose
proper subsets are
OK let's take an example
so we have from a to f and the frequency collection looks like
blah blah blah
the positive border are the maximal sets
all of the maximum so
by inspection one of means
and the same is the pace OK so clearly and maximum because it has the
largest cardinality
and when you look at
all right
everything here
it's actually a
subset of one of these
so this is a positive one
the negative border this the fact are the meaning of things which are not in
this collection
so well
do you
is not frequent it's not
so in the last and then get bored border e is not
it's in the minimum order
BCE is not frequent and b is not free those of the minimum
so possibly motor maximal frequent one's negative water more frequent ones
OK one can actually do the same thing trained general
ask what are the most the
maximal frequent substrings and negative
the border is then the
the frequent substring of let's not talk about that
now the algorithm i
you actually asked
this many questions
questions of five x frequency
for all frequencies lost the negative or the size of the negative water
and actually one can show that in
again in the model this is a
this is what you have to do
OK the sizes of the borders tend to be relatively large
but this thing i wanted to spend a few minutes on the relationship between the
positive and negative border
if i tell you
guys in the back row by using maximal frequent sex
and now specify all
so below the
is frequent and nothing else is
or if i tell you
the minimum frequency again i specified the frequency collections
you need
so given the positive border given
living in that border they both specify
the same collection of subsets
but the thing is that we got the water actually
the set of all minimal transversals of the complement of the set
in the
positive more
what does that mean
it's basically an extension of the upper edges can have more than two
but this is
so given a set u
eight is the hypergraph with it or a simple hypergraph
there is no element is empty and no
with which they enabled
your part to escape further pain
the information is legal in switzerland was then
andy indeed
it led us to believe that
i like this idea that one could control one so there
just as one could control so much in one's own life
he designed a monument for his father and obsessed over the choice of flowers
here he is with charlotte county on part of his
paris life
they designed furniture you know very well
endless stories sister who really deserves credit foreign
his cousin
peers generate work in the office on the corbusier himself
but we all know the furnitur which today is all over the world he did this fantastic that encourage
but this time family
had such an eye for design that to me
anyone who worked
in his office more than anything else would him by his sense rhythm his sense texture
this meant so much
this is a wonderful photograph i think mondrian standing on the roof of the car should on
with his hand on the spiral staircase
the sample of ten short or you know
every time one sees that one discover something else
but above all else
it has many
the same ideals
that we see in the exhibition
i got friend above
which is the point of architecture
is to worship nature
time and again
in his projects
one the problems he wanted to do
with given human nature at you looking
fields have you feel close to the sky
it is they worship nature it's simply the container
for looking at nature and by the way
not a machine from the that's another cliche
which has been blown out of all proportion and the court lucia
took task he wrote about how ridiculous it was
that's something is said to a friend on the street became turned into this hackneyed idea
the corbusier's buildings war machine from the
be emphasis was on
looking and everything else and he used the term with diary
in the late twenties he
got a commission to go to
south america
working on buildings they are he discovered early in the trip
josephine baker
he met her getting on to a both
i just want picture this corpus is swiss
he is
forty three years old
he meets a young
half-black half-white american jazz singer
it's known
photographs are known
and she
had a love affair
and it's always written and all
that's where they met in rio
getting on to a boat that was going to bordeaux
and for ten days they had a romance
with air i was plugging away reed his letters to his mother
i was pretty close to my own mother but i would not have written are
this one and
who represented
great human qualities who was in many ways his great love
he was already engaged to marry bond with whom he was living in paris
and in fact one discovers from the letters from
that he met
josephine two months prior to the crossing to border
when they got on the ship
it had been a carefully planned trip they decided to travel together and they've been spending a lot of
time together already her writing about him is magnificent
she said that the court lucia
you know gay it is there
what we can translate this into english today because it would have
and simple each of which has come to mean something very different i
then they did back then
but he was
the game is played in the sense that the words of
in nineteen twenty nine and a person
flirtatiousness heart hard-charging looking down there are in his white shoes looking at josephine has she glass
molecules that the wires from the eye to the brain and from the brain inside
one place
the other
recognise in order to form and
they on the right track
what are these molecules
so the
miles human genome project have transformed our approach to these questions it used to be
that it would take
maybe three to five years
a graduate student or postdoc fellow to hammer away
find the gene
and then
perhaps cloning
and now
in six months we could do well last and find out what are the genes
that are expressed in a piece of tissue
one of these techniques is to use DNA microarrays
we can little chips
that can be improved to six thousand genes or gene fragments literature like this
and we can extract the piece of brain
in this case from a new-born mouse
the visual cortex of the somatosensory cortex
an extract the irony from it
and then
play this on a on this chip and we can ask what the genes or
gene fragments in
the somatosensory cortex or in the visual cortex and then we can compare them ask
how this part of the brain differs from that at this stage
OK and this tells us
what are the molecules that are likely to be expressed in one part of the
brain which is another and these molecules must be critical for making the pathways that
differentiate the visual from the somatosensory cortex or the pattern of the sense of vision
from the sense of touch
specific pathways to and from cortical areas
likely associated with very specific molecules i haven't told you a bunch of other and
evidence gathering even as i speak on gamma function and loss function study that's how
you understand how to the gene
do what it does is venue move it
by knocking it out you in the extra copies of it or in order to
different players
you can ask does function go away when you remove it does function appears a
new and in different football when you somewhere else and there's the whole technology that
it is networks that process information and make something new
something or
or make a new output from a elementary in one
networks are
he was metaphor that i used earlier the engine of the brain
they are the cost of the brain
and networks exist all over
a model system that my laboratory and many other laboratories used to understand visual network
how to develop the work
in the visual system
in vision is something that we don't think about and for the most part but
least half of our brain devoted directly or indirectly television
vision is such an important modality for us and
we see the way we do
because there are networks in our head
that the visual inputs from the archive which is just the sort of pixels
and transform it into shapes and images
we don't see many things that we could because we do not have the networks
and we see some things that we shouldn't when networks can be fit and that's
we starts with the eyes
but i suggest the front end of vision
from the side information goes to the structure collapsed the already showed you in the
in the schematic
from here information was to the primary visual cortex and in people there are at
last count some part the visual areas
many more than whenever
imagine but due to functional brain imaging and physiology we now understand
some thirty area that make up or nearly half of the back part of the
that has to do with it
yet there is one kind of network
it has become the paradigmatic network for understanding how vision works and that of the
before generating orientation selectivity
two physiologist
given the nobel prize
for discovering orientation selectivity in v one
they were unfortunately at harvard
but they the simplest of experiments
this that an electrode into the primary visual cortex of the cat
and that's what makes these cells respond to
the humblest of questions but it has the deepest around
what makes the cell respond best individual caught in the primary visual cortex vocabulary monkey
and we now know even in humans
in a little edge of life
it's an edge of light that moves in a certain has a certain orientation and
move in a certain direction
OK it's not
light everywhere is not a pixel of light is an edge of life
one edge
that's a hard question because we can of course construct of i can tell you
that adaptation is tails but i
and that's because the world is made up of features or shapes are bounded by
line segments that constitute the edge of the ship
and so the first
elementary but critical step
in perceiving shape
is to is to detect an edge
and the primary visual cortex
and all higher mammals
therefore has this property
that generates the selectivity to the orientation of an edge
and this is created in the cortex because the new record from zero here
they don't have anything like this property they don't respond to this one little blobs
so my own lab we have demonstrated that not only are cells responsible edges but
they are organised in a specific interesting way
and we know that by using now
two the physiology
include not only recording the activity of single celled by loring wires very fine wires
into the brain and picking up the spikes that put out but also using techniques
such as optical imaging with a very similar in principle
the functional
magnetic resonance imaging
you can shine red light on the cortex
active neurons
need oxygen which is brought to them by the micro vasculature and when the oxygen
is given up
and the blood becomes blue
then it absorbs red light
so active neurons
sure the regions in which other active short lives
so here's a snapshot
of the picture
the 2nd thing would then Gilmore cause we the media citizen journalism which is why
you a AUS bloggers actually influence the world today significantly well it's a combination of
things they were self linking community that Google will float to the top and Google
and technologies that I started indexing them in real time and also now you can
get better news feeds than leads from their that you could by doing more cost
not better journalism so read the book with immediate about other things those it through
believe product reviews you by camera go look cruiser when noses but this is collective
knowledge every day we use it kind of course there's amateur academic Wikipedia right now
what about semantic Web visited there was well let's just as not get about is
is it is exactly but ontologies a rule whatever this is all by the technology
in general technology plot this thing and I think we'll find out how are technology
that's and this is what I think what technology can do for collected knowledge system
is a can be of memory can be a sensor actuator
nervous system distributing things we've sort got that nails named adult global telecommunications systems like
mixers and everything databases are basically free the capture happening for free digital sensors um
many-to-many communications happening What's new at was he was the unnamed bounded hard interesting problem
is how to extract value from all the stuff I think that's worsened technology can
play games so in fact I'm that talk about 2 ways that might happen to
be examples of how the intersection of social Web and the semantic Web can happen
for semantic kind of things connected to the first one is about tagging data everyone's
and this a great talent for talk about at dinner with Scientology people has on
the attacks whatever somewhat will talk about that and then the other 1 is blogging
data and how can we provide the 1st case the role of technology Chris got
slots attack tagging all over the place how do you compose many great do create
added value by composing integrate tagging data from other places a 2nd problem is highly
in fact create our knowledge repository where it has more value as a repository then
it were distributed so 1st case if there's a spell Clay Shaw he's a very
elegant writer at the University and he wrote this blog ontologies or irritable blob what
lots of stuff you know everyone knows Dewey decimal system is horrible and therefore semantic
Web is useless was a couple of missing pieces of the inference China by police
basically getting at is that yes of course particles into control taxonomic systems when used
as like Mike librarians used do justice system is not a great with categorize no
information on the Web I completely agree
he just the hate he also says that by the way tagging seems to were
just ridiculous because anyone can do it and everything works everything detector if that's OK
I mean he's not fool says that's OK that's point is making now our order
counter blogger whatever does appear from nowhere said about that but the thing was the
got me thinking that the the whole mistake here was that there equating ontology fact
the whole semantic Web 9 yards was thrown in there just because the failings of
taxonomies as a classification system for the or not as across the criticism is applying
these systems we give the wrong message sometimes like all taxonomy ontology whatever is all
about a library shelf has nothing to do with that it has to do with
an enabling technology my view for interoperability knowledge and if we think of it that
way ontologies are about putting the surface membrane an agent so they can interact with
with other nations is not about creating a single mom the database that everyone has
the lock lock into life and EKG take that view then we can actually take
this question of folk studied turned on its head so was folks where the limitations
of folks ontology can help so I want to the single Kaltag camp which was
upped this is the way the Web 2 . 0 crowd has conferences everybody but
sleeping bags and we slept on the floor of an office building and hacks for
24 hours and had talks and so on and it just amazing it was it
using a small number of features they really for
so random doesn't
surprise just randomly select features
it grows at the beginning of a little bit and then
almost remain constant
information gain i mentioned that uses feature occurrence and non occurrence of the feature
is not is not specially with here
so you can see a small peak around point
performance so by the performance is a combination of precision and recall
after all
and we want to maximize it
so mutual information cross entropy for text
peak at around the same point alteration is about
the same point here corresponds to about hundred features so using about hundred features
out of you know you so we go from about a thousand
i don't know what was thirty thousand features so using a hundred and getting good
performance is really good if you have thirty thousand features
and alterations this curve so it's kind of
dropping in the performance of bit slower
like cross entropy and mutual information
and that's on one of the data dataset
next i'll just show
a table with all the
naive bayesian classifier think this was using a bayesian classifier
for document categorisation and also these results using naive bayesian classifier so these are five
eight thousand categories how categories
the first column is the name of the feature scoring measures
so you can see
oddsratio term frequency
being up there
and these are all performances
when you think about fifty two hundred best features
which turns out to be
you know zero points two to two five percent of all the features
which i think is very nice if you can reduce the feature subset
and you can see that is really improved performance of naive bayes
if you compare it to the last
row in each set
random performance
so performance here
frank is basically
you know
if you have
of their eight thousand different categories
it's hierarchical classification the classifier here is induced in the way that for each category
there is a binary classifier
and then when you have new testing document you you ask each of those eight
thousand binary classifiers
what is the probability that a document belongs to this class
and and then you sort of the categories based on the predictive probability
and of course you can check for the rank of the really correct category
so that's the first revelation just saying on which position the correct one occurs
and for us it was impressive to see that
on the sixth position after eight thousand you get the correct category and that's of
course and rachel cross validation experiments
i have to measure
and then the precision and recall split into precision and recall
and the last column is showing something
connected to efficiency
you should start worrying when i said you know for each test example you should
ask eight thousand classifiers what they think about that
so the last column saying no you don't need to use a thousand classifiers
it's enough if you ask a hundred of them but of course not
you know quite smartly
selective hundred
and how is that achieved this very simple
naive bayes and
formula the model
he has
conditional probabilities of occurrence of some of the features
connected to the class and if you look into the best in document
it is very sparse
so only the models they have some
overlap between the features which are testing documents should be
because to try you don't you don't need to classify documents if there is none
of the words from the document is actually in the model
then you know you predict the prior probability of the class
so that's the idea behind
and what is the kind of contrition why information gain
it is not performing on this data so well
as maybe on some other data i should say that or some other experiments using
the nearest neighbour algorithm
four classifying documents will
on the data which is not so unbalanced in the class distribution it performs well
so i don't want to miss guided using information gain is is not good it's
not here
on this setting with unbalanced data set and naive bayes classifier
and why not it selects when you know if you look into the features
which are the features that information gain has selected
you know how they look
they are
you can see that most of them occur negative documents
and you can see that
it's also for some of the features is
the fact that they don't occur
the reason why they are selected by information gain
and that's how the
you know that's not the
the message you want to
give to your mother
it's because have so it's not one but two
which puts more emphasis on recall and the reason behind his
you know this is not a very good way because you treat all the unobserved
terms equal irrespective of the overall corpus frequency right so you get a very high
probability to
to turn say
you know
to terms that might just occur once in the whole corpus write things that are
very improbable that
you know it just doesn't seem to make sense so more
a useful approach here
it is to do smoothing by some form of interpolation where you actually
use the document collection to come up with a reference distribution
so when you look at the overall frequency of the word try to use some
or all documents in your collection
so that gives you the overall frequency
if we to take that as a reference distribution and now
and in the simplest case here right here just
the model now this as a as a as a convex combination so your estimate
now as a convex combination of the
frequency right the maximum likelihood estimate and this reference distribution and you might have you
know parameter lambda d for every document but in the simplest case
that will actually
you know you might just use it to be constant between zero and one
OK so
so basically so that's kind of the way of dealing with
query terms that do not occur in the document right so then you're not getting
zero probability but sort of you inherit you know the the
the probability that part here from the reference distribution
OK and then
you know there are various ways that you can actually
you know the parameters say using techniques like expectation maximisation algorithm
because this is basically a two component mixture model
there are other techniques
actually works fairly well in practice is called absolute discounting
where what you do is is first you subtract probability mass of delta
from every nonzero count
OK i see at most
well if delta is less than one
you can do OK and then you redistribute the probability mass
that you've subtracted
according to the reference distribution
OK so
it with the previously with the interpolation
you would that you wouldn't look at what's the number of distinct terms that that's
actually occurs in the document keywords here you know
depending on how many distinct terms you have
that's kind of
you know you use that to
generate some from set some probability mass aside and that gets distributed according to this
distribution case the nice thing about this
formula is actually that
the redistribution
will be proportional to the number of unique words
in the document so
by that i mean if you have a very long document compared to very short
then it's probably true financial documents that the length of the documents increases asymptotically faster
than the number of new words
in the document is a document of links thousand might have a hundred different words
by having you know of two thousand it might not have two hundred but it
might grow slower rates among others for asymptotic so that means then in terms of
the smoothing
the smoothing gets automatically adapted to do more smoothing for longer documents
and you do less moving four
the show you
so do less moving for long documents and you do more smoothing for the short
which seems to be reasonable heuristic to use here
right because you know very very long documents in the darkness a whole book about
a particular term does not occur in the book
well maybe it should be right but if i have a very short news article
you know
and a certain term does not occur well maybe
it's just because of the constraint that
all of the links constraint of the dark
so the the final
more that i want to talk about getting the
model for a little bit
better motivated in terms of statistical modeling
another popular approach is
to use the a hierarchical bayesian
if we denote this probability
that a certain term occurs in the document by theta d
and then
we've called
it was
this is a
know what
the station
yes or no
a s
what happened
you want
it's not nothing
i will
these four
so here
on the
here he
when we
what is
and that
how much pattern is there well that's roughly in over two bits of patterns
on the other extreme is if you have been in which you get by independent
art fair coin
with very high probability it will have zero bits of pattern
OK because the smallest program will be the same size
so this is
this is a a very simple domain in which you can
you can define a very general notion of pattern
the next question
i'd like to give you an example
of something that comes up in theoretical computer science it has no patterns
in my examples
is an elegant program
so these are these are strings of the form of nanoparticles
what an elegant program well i define elegant program
to be programme which is the most concise programming that computer programming language you fix
the computer programming language that produces the output that it does OK so this is
the best theory
if you view of computer programmers theory for its output and elegant program is the
oak cancer rates are the most concise the simplest theory for what it
for what it explains but to put it in computer science terms programming bell again
p is elegant
if you know
that's smaller
no program in the same language you understand you fix the language
programming language that smaller
produces the same output
OK so the first thing to notice is there's always an elegant programs
there may be several
but for any computational task
there are an infinity of programs and some of them had better be smaller and
more concise than the others i don't care about time
this is very theoretical
so also you can read my handwriting which makes it even more difficult but i
can really the actually
OK so
these turn out to be so to speak a practical example you know not very
of something that has no pattern according to the definition i've just given y y
y do well for the a lot of elegant programs are infinite infinity and their
bit strings y is an elegant program have to be
in the sense that i just
well the reason is as follows
a a
if the program has pattern
a more concise program that calculates the same output
the smallest program that calculates the the
original programmes
so instead of
taking the program and running it directly what i do
if i take the most concise program that calculates
the the the the program i'm interested in
and then i produce that program as a lot of the calculation and then i
run into rice running and then i produced the output of the original programmes
is a so
in other words if there is any structure in a computer program it cannot be
the most concise program because i can sort of run it through compression program
and and and then decompressor before running it and that gives me a smaller programs
you see you have a little bit to the size of the program you that
you have to add the decompression routine
if the complete the program is compressed substantially the decompression routine is going to be
fixed size if the program is so
so the compressed substantially
the compressed version of the program you want through LCD or something
plus the
the decompression algorithm which is fixed size is going to be smaller than the original
programme so what you do is you know decompress it and then you run and
you get the original output but you have a smaller programs you see so
so this means that an elegant program you know every bit of elegant program has
to be a complete complete surprise
if it's not a complete surprise each successive but
programme it means this is not the most concise programs
because there was of structure in the program and then you make a macro or
you do something to
get rid of that structure you see that redundancy
OK so
so so these these are examples of elegant programs are so the speaker an example
in the real world of something that has no pattern according to the definition i
gave which is
the idea that there
there is no program that's more concise that calculates that object that object being itself
computer program and elegant program
i'm going much too fast i think
it's not a problem
unless you stop me and ask questions
OK now i would like to go to another topic having given an example of
something that has no patterns
being intelligent program
i'd like to
i'm dealing with a very general notion of pattern it's an impractical notion of patterns
you see
my notion of pattern
there is no limit on the time
so for me the the pattern you see so
so this is a very
the theoretical notion of pattern
but because it's so theoretical in general you can prove as strong theorem about it
you know this the trade usually mathematics can be useful or can be beautiful
and usually one or the other you can do both i'm forgive me for this
this is enough to get you put in jail in some places to make mark
like this but i'm theoretician so this is the
OK so with this notion of pattern that i explained which is very very general
based on the size of the smallest program really
it turns out that we get these these surprising question if you're looking at the
amount of pattern in a finite stripping
if you're just looking at the amount of pattern individual
individual bit strings
if you just concerned with individual bit strings and you have the pattern isn't pattern
and i remember i can measure how much partners
you know
from zero bits to the full number of bits in the string that's the maximum
amount of
so what if you're looking at individual bit strings
you can another way to but it is you can always prove
lower bounds on the amount of power
if you're interested in the amount of pattern individual bitstream
you can prove or lower bounds
all you can prove or lower bounds on the amount of pattern in individual based
on their interests
however you can prove no upper bound on the amount of patterns
has something like
people were actually taken aback doesn't but
some of the others do
but for many of them they don't and so approximations and even the algorithm so
much slower for example for generalized linear models
there's no piecewise linearity
and so for logistic regression for example the path of piecewise smooth and you have
to do a lot of computations
so the company and so the algorithm seize up for large problems
so there is a need for efficient algorithms
four for larger problems
so this brings us to the topic of today coordinate descent
the idea is to solve the lasso problem
by coordinate descent
which means optimise each parameter separately holding the others fixed
now the
it doesn't seem like it's going to lead to fast algorithms
for solving systems of linear equations is the gauss seidel
in the context of lasso
it's something similar but you optimize in one corner to the times
so why is this
lead to an efficient algorithm
convince you of this today
and what do with it turns out that all the updates are trivial and that's
one of the reasons it's very efficient
and what we do is we do this on a grid of lambda values that's
the regularisation parameter
so we don't get the exact path but to get it on a finer grid
as we choose
starting from some lambda max down to lambda min
and and we use warm start
and it turns out that's very efficient
what's really attractive you can do this with a variety of loss functions
and and additive penalties
you get this same kind of efficiency
so coordinate descent
achieves dramatic speedups over all competitors by factors of ten sometimes a hundred and more
so the next few slides i'm and i'm going to show you know
i'm going to demonstrate some of these these speedup results
so use that same
coefficient profile for the for the little example i had
and we have a large profiles
all the lines and the
coordinate descent profile superimposed with dots and so you see there a hundred dots this
so we approximate in the path
as accurately as unity and we can even make the image fine for like
without much loss in
i'm going to show you some simulations and some and some performance results on real
and then i'll tell you about all the details after so the competitors are laws
algorithm is implemented in the r package
for squared error loss
eleven that's the package
that implements coordinate ascent
so that's the training base package
which is
the front end in or
and it does squared error and logistic regression
both for two and multiple class logistic regression
there's no reason competitor was l one logreg
that's the best two logistic regression package
my colleagues in as in electrical engineering at stanford steveboyington two of his students
cohen came
and that came out a year ago
using state-of-the-art interior point methods for convex optimisation and this is for two class logistic
and then
b b are in BMR are
that's a sense for bayesian binomial multinomial regression
this is the package biking can
lewis and madigan
now surprisingly they also use coordinate descent nodes bayesian actually go for the posterior mode
using the class prior that amounts to
lasso penalized logistic regression
and so they use coordinate descent as well
and this is an example where the devil's in the details because we have you'll
see we have a dramatic speedups over them as well
so let me show you the results
so yes
linear regression squared error loss
dense since features in other words and bigger than
forget in big p
we cannot distinguish between sparse features in dense features so
you see that if the
features of past such as the bag of words model the features are sparse in
and it sends back what is what the map
estimate would be under the prior and that's the only thing you have to do
right so it's quite i think it's kind of cool it's not not obvious
OK so now there are some examples of start with a little baby one
to see can see visually what it is and i am sure here i don't
have to go into all of this so i'll make it very very fast enough
you will be classification so
you know i have a bunch of a billion outcomes and feature vectors and i
form a margin my variables are WNV
omega lost you can make anything you like
any any the obvious options and you want to minimize an average
on average loss plus a regularisation term that could be able to squared l one
whatever you like
exponential anything like that
another then you the idea is is split data and use ADMM consensus to solve
will look at a really super small example just one that you don't expect you
don't even need to shouldn't be doing it but anyway people was look at it
there are two features and four hundred examples but so i can plot right
and i will split the four hundred examples into twenty groups but we do it
in a sick way each group of twenty has only seen either all positive or
all negative examples
right so so it's the most scuba so each box of twenty examples has seen
all spam all my right so that that's how it works so so they're going
have to collaborate to two i mean but probably the right way to do this
actually is to hash the data in which case each of them by the time
by themselves actually gets a pretty good estimate and the only thing to do by
collaborating is get statistical power
right so this is not that this is just for the fish to to show
the works
OK so let's see how this works
well these are all the private local estimates of course there are terrible because they've all been
they've all been given terrible ideas of what the data looks like is able only
seen all possible role negative things about the way the reason not all way off
in the middle of nowhere because the quadratic regularisation terms OK
the actually embarrassingly after one step which consists of averaging all of those you don't
get some is not so bad right so
if you then
i ADMM like five steps you get to something like this and you can can
you get the picture right so that's what happens after forty steps right hand but
the interesting thing here is just to this to visualize actually the data flow in
the communication here each box has seen like europe box
you've seen only positive examples you have absolutely no idea who else has an opinion
about about this problem will collaborating with to former class which you know nothing the
only thing you have is a protocol that implements map
that's it and what happens is they come back and they say well
the weight vector prior looks like this what would you do that and you say
well it's very strange is highly consistent with my data frankly but OK whatever and
returns w and then actually when these things come to convergence it means the use
of the global problem each box has absolutely no idea
how many others there are what they look like anything i mean so i don't
make too big a deal about it but it's worth thinking about what actually happens
let's look at another one
the distributed lasso example
and this is just made this is just for fun just to show that you
can do this so this is probably bigger than anyone would ever solved so it's
dense problem with four hundred thousand four four hundred thousand examples in a thousand regressors
or something like that
and it's about thirty to get back to that it really people like would we
routinely solve problems with this amount of data for sparse problems this one is not
sparse or dense so anyway i
probably somebody has solve problems like this are right
so just to do something real simple
you take this is split split the data into a eighty subsystems that's ten core
machines write something
really simple
not totally unoptimized extremely short
just the shortest think about possibly have and then they are just to give you
a rough idea of what this does it does something like this factorisation by the
way is a that's parallel
ridge regression statistically that's what you're doing you're doing a parallel ridge regression and it
takes about five minutes
subsequent iterations take about a second so again it's totally irrelevant how many steps you
take i mean i totally irrelevant but it's it's certainly it's not as interesting is
arguing about whether some takes twenty steps or a hundred total now that's that's kind
of irrelevant and the total allows all these things like five minutes by the way
this makes a very nice story right so there was a story
you could say about interior point methods that would go like this
the story would say so to say what are you doing so when solving convex
optimization problem and you you so great indeed profile code and find out that in
fact with they really doing is twenty
for twenty times their solving least squares system
you know that's what it is that that's that's one to point method does it
solves the KKT system like twenty times thirty times whenever something like that so solving
least squares
right so someone could say well why would you do this convex optimisation you say
well it's much more expressive
is the bipartite graph
we're on one side we have a bunch of products on the other we have
and we have the links
indicating whether
users prefer
some products and to what degree
OK so
if we consider them in matrix form you're a horizontally we consider users and vertically
consider items or products and readings here represents how much
a user prefers products
also the
we have many missing links and then the missing ratings here
are represented as
the question marks
OK so
algorithm y
we have initially you know in the history of
recommendation systems we have user base which is to consider similarity between users and to
group similar users together
and semantically we can use and base and more recently people adopt model based it
turns of model based methods are
formerly are in fact factorisation methods matrix factorisation methods
now so what i try to focus on here
is that in recommendation systems we often have the problem of data sparsity
OK which is why we don't have much readings to start with we want to
train the model
and applied to the test data
the performance
can be dramatically reduced if we have a very sparse matrix to start with
OK so cold start problem
data sparsity problem these terms all refer to this drop in performance and this is
exactly the the thing we try to
we try to address
we we addressed that from a transfer learning perspective is to consider this suppose we
have some new
product line fall selling books where
we want to recommend books people
but we don't have much data about books because maybe it's a new domain maybe
they are about new users
OK so
then where we can look at is some similar domains may be on different products
maybe on movies
and because of the similarity or inherent similarity between either the product or the users
is it possible for us to transfer some knowledge tool into the target domain to
alleviate the data sparsity problem OK that's the question OK is it possible
with this in mind we did a number of
experiments try to
there's ways in which the auxiliary domain can help
OK so this first work is codebook transfer and believe sitting there
a yellow shirt he's
so the first author here
now so let me let me give you a brief description of this
and being can answer questions thereafter
OK so
if you look at
if you look at the matrix representation of of the rating record
one of the domain we often consider it as
you know because the user group and and group are very large we can use
usually consider it as consisting of a group of users that have similar tastes and
a group of atoms that have similar
OK so if you can
group them together then we can compose a compressed version of the rating matrix which
can be more compactly used to represent the original matrix
OK which is inside each cell is a small version of the reader
and we can call that a cookbook
suppose we have a dense enough matrix then we can build a very good codebook
the question is can this codebook
so solve the the cold start problem for some other
it is it's OK so
if you have a matrix say in movies where we have many more ratings missing
as compared to a bookstore domain then perhaps
if he align their groups
you know the correct way OK that group and the other group then we can
because of their inherent similarity and the relatedness we can use the dense virgin to
help the sparse version his that's the intuition behind this work
part of the function which lies outside of minus over to the plus over to
OK so the next thing that we did then was to show that the truncated
in the sink weighted sinusoids
both in fact spend
l two
in other words any function
and l two
after you represented in terms of that series what you have left over has to
be orthogonal in other words if you take this entire set
truncated sinusoids
every nonzero function
is orthogonal to all of them
every nonzero function as l two equivalent sense
so so in fact the thing you get out of this
this is part of
looking at functions which we always ignored
OK there is another issue that we ignored when we're looking at functions
o which comes out of this
since sensitivity by assumption is in l two vector
in other words in l two function aside from this
l two equivalent staff
and face the band personnel two vector also
this inner product has to be finite
by the shorts and quality
OK how do we get around this we are dealing with fourier series anybody remember
of course you remember i hardly remember that
the way we got around it was by saying that the
that is orthonormal function which was a truncated sinusoid
he was was truncated to minus over two and cluster over two and the waveform
was just the
to the i two pi after
the magnitude of that function was always less than or equal to one
and because the magnitude was always less than or equal to one
you could just take the integral
of the of two
time space abandoned today and you can show directly to that in the world always
because this special property of the sinusoids
here what we're saying is you don't have to worry about that anymore
you can use arbitrary l two functions
as the confidence of an l two
orthonormal expansion
and it still works
so every one of these things has to be finite also
so in fact we're buying something out of this
at the end of the notes on lectures eight to ten
you will notice something that
and i'm certainly not going to hold you responsible for
it's something called the prolate spheroidin expansion
and it's just given their primarily as one more example of an orthonormal expansion
it's a very interesting orthonormal expansion because it has the property
that if you start out asking
how much energy can i concentrate within
a fixed time interval and affect spend with
OK which is one of the things which make this whole subject a little bit
fishy and the whole
and certainly very very messy if i start off with the time limit function
and go through the fourier series these truncated sinusoids
spiller energy
the band
in fact one of the problems at the end of lectures eight to ten
in fact carries you through the process of just how much energy
you can have outside banned by using these truncated sinusoid because truncated sinusoid when you
look at them in a in a fourier series have a lot of energy outside
of work where it is where it should be
so this
so this particular set of prolates parietal function gives you the answer to the following
i would like to find that function
which is limited to minor city over two plus three over two
which has the largest amount of energy larger fraction of its energy
within the band minus w to plus w
what is that function
well i found it happens to be the senior water prolates toroidal functions
okay so thank you for coming back
and we talked about
statistical learning theory yesterday
just some basic ideas
i think you're probably
understood so you should have understood
so what is it
the complexity of a function class
so when we do machine learning
we have some
the function class
we choose a function from based on empirical data and we want this function to
be such that has a small risk small risk means uh we have some loss
function we compute the expectation about loss function over
an unknown but fixed distribution which generates both training and test data
we want the expectation that
loss function to be small
so from all classes functions we want to choose a function such that this expectation is as small as possible
it turns out that
this is not trivial we cannot simply are
we can simply choose the function based on which one has the lowest training error and then
some other conditions are satisfied
and these conditions are related to the complexity of function classes
so it turns out that we have
below below
if we have a function class
also we see dimension
is finite then
within in the limit is always be able
uh be consistent so to get there
together risk which is as low as the lowest possible risk and of function class
it's a single number that characterizes starting from which number of observations
learning machine
no longer has full complexity of full capacity so up to
number of observations which possibly see dimension the learning machine
well the cluster functions is as complicated as it could be so you can realize
all possible separations between the data
end afterwards it can't be any more
and if we can explain all the time
we can explain the large set of data are
with the learning machine that has finite dimension
this dimension is
you can significantly smaller than the number of data points
and then
this cannot be chance or is is unlikely to be chance that we can explain the data well
because we're working with a learning machine
who's we dimension is such that it usually cannot explain arbitrary large datasets
so that's the basic idea
and in the end it comes down to find a good function class and if we want to
learn well
and dr
good means the complexity should be
ideally we should be able to
give some bones and complexity to understand what controls the complexity
how to logarithmically
minimize it
end of course
it's not just about having small complexity but at the same time the function class should be able to
explain real world that has such a big complex enough to
model the kind of tim dependencies that we want to model in the real world
so that's certainly a trade-off
i started introducing this kernel function classes
it's nice examples where we can give bounds on the capacity
say more about this later
even though
there are
and complex classes of functions
and because they correspond to the linear function classes in some other space and we
can do the theoretical analysis in the space
that was the pretty
and the
and i showed u
a few
give you an introduction to kernels and feature spaces so i was saying
we preprocess the data
and then we look at some examples
wearing the hat emissions space we compute dot products and we find out that they correspond to
simple functions in the low dimensional space
which we call kernels
so this was an example of a kernel this kernel equals the
the deed poll
of the
usually the product taken in input space
and it computes the
all possible products of these features of of decoding it's in the high dimensional space
so it computes all possible products of decoding it's in this uh constitutes a mapping into the high dimensional space
when we look at mentioned mercer's theorem
i mentioned
the class of positive definite kernels
so these are this symmetric functions
two variables
now we a bit of laser pointer
functions of two variables
and symmetric functions
such that if you compute the kernel matrix
which we get by only substituting the finite dataset in here and here
this matrix is positive definite
and this matrix is called the gram matrix or kernel matrix
we then
i think we also covered this space
give examples of kernels
and dimension that
kernels have this benefit that we can
construct nonlinear algorithms from linear ones
it maybe more importantly we can
apply linear methods to data that don't leave in a vector space to begin with
as long as we can construct a kernel on this data so we have some
data which is from some arbitrary domain
and maybe even just a set of a set of graphs so strings
as long as we able to construct a similarity measure okay are which satisfies these properties of positive definiteness
then we get a vector space representation of the state of a free
so i am
so i was going to do today
my plan is to show you the feature map uh
of a positive definite kernel is very hard to
meaning that it should work reasonably for most of the signals that contain oscillation least
because the model consensus selection so we have this reason label frequency estimates that quite
robust on the black box you don't have to turn the nob slight what time
window do you know what do you want to which way you want to use
which scales we want to compute just press about them and get the result and
not only did the time-frequency relevant remember that behind each of those blocks are exact
parameters of the Garber functions that were used to compute
and we shall explore this feature
no we get back to the pool craftsmen craftsmen the of encephalographic hostility between the
let's take the example of sleep analysis if you think about sleep recordings the in
the old days when it was on paper it was over how the kilometres long
with of paper and to make a non-GM that is used for the diagnosis the
doctor has to go through this House has work and this 1 has to work
at least 1 kilometer because he has to go through this uh this recording this
mortgage our recording and twice stone tool tools you get back into integration such etc.
so what what is he doing actually the encephalographic
encephalographic stated by provision my appears in the of art and and amount of science
in the game and the science is by definition that leaves us with is believed
that science is based upon repeatable
experiments if something is repeatable maybe crystals logarithmic and what we want to do is
to extract the algorithmic part of not to replace the encephalographic just to free them
from their repeatable model that can be taken over to combine a computer so we
take a look at the definitions of sleep stages and structures that for synthesis 1968
the standardization for standardization of since stage that was published so all anaphora quite a
few years we know for instance that they work and encephalographic consider sleep spindles is
actually very well defined structure and the definition is exactly in time frequency terms if
we assume that that if we are only able to translate cycles per 2nd into
credits because there is is more or less obvious similarly
more or less more or less that easy we can go with other structures like
like for instance slow waves
and we put together the automatic detection
all features if we need to find out that these structures which are fitted to
the signal in the general procedure
can correspond to for example sleep spindles slow-wave then it's just as easy as taking
these parameters right the future on top of the matching pursuit decomposition which is not
computed with a particular idea of making sleep analysis is a general parameterization and out
of these parameters without looking at the time frequency map and saying OK maybe there's
something here this is the planes very simple filter that has only few conditions mentally
get an automatic and I'd say quite reliable
detection and the parameterization of say sleep spindles and slow waves how it goes this
is example for example for example this example of how far away if there is
a blob
in frequency about 1200 right maybe it's not part of our that's probably sleep spindles
but there were probably and the parameters
underlying this block tell us exactly the kind which which is the out of which
more or less the help with all the Gaussian envelope in frequency and its amplitude
and all that we need to know here we have the instances of slow waves
that can be also parameters in the same way and for instance in the definition
the sleep stages 3 and 4 is based upon a percentage of time
occupied by slow wave activity if is between 20 and 50 % stage 3 even
more than half of that kind of 1 airport and the hit counted the 22nd
books the sculpted but I guess you all know what hit if there are no
questions right that's the case so if more than half of that kind of thing
that book
in most cases 2004 country is occupied by slow waves then it is supposed to
be or less stage 4 now before we had the basis this is basically the
1st signal processing method that depends exactly where things start and where it ends
and explicitly
from the parameters so can easily just out of the times occupied by these waves
that were classified as slow weights based upon other criteria as well and we know
well into the histogram automatic right not only that we can look and I think
when for example plotting this is an example of
a cold backward compatibility came because a before visually is considered only if it is
50 we can plot this %
over there a book
the book is 20 seconds and here are hours so in 1 hour would have
treebanks 60 of box right
and Bayerische airport we plot alliance that is proportional to the
the percentage of time occupied by slow waves within this at right so if you
threshold this at 20 and 50 per cent of the more-or-less stages 3 and 4
but you also see that it is a continuous process and is in line with
so what would be a good idea too
had the memory below that tries to approximate the state seems that that that should
he can connect two two filtering
and and state estimation
in the rest just going to show
that there is some mechanism that's what are they doing that
if i don't care about how this is done
particle filtering is is great that could be a really good
the solution for this
i just assumed that that we some whole has estimated the state
in particle i don't i'm not
at the beginning i wouldn't care about
resulting from state estimation just
make that we have the state information
if this effects that this
OK so what i'm doing here is that i'm simplifying the problem from its fortunate
in various ways
and and
i want to get to a place where i can really do something
so we see that even if we we do it is if we assume that
the state is measurable
the problem is going to be very tough and so you are going to study
the problem
in quite the details
and then maybe later if you have time you can come back to to this
even after program yes
OK so
yes OK so that's true but
so the the length of the observations of the length of the history is growing
this time so if you want to
somehow get to the visible the computational resources
then somehow you want to compress the he stays
so the problem is that it's pretty hard to generalize across history and
as the prime reason
it's a good question
you should get a cookie
so please ask more questions like that because it seems that i need some practice
or in this case
OK let's do i you
i don't know
five go see the
there are going to talk about this this is axillary asian
but luckily you have already finish or talk so
OK so
if we accept that we have state information then the next question is
how do you compute a good action
and that is the county there are two approaches
so one is called the model based control
and the other is more that the crown trauma
in the case of more than this control you somehow try to estimate the model
the dynamics
so trying to estimate the model so if you forget vault
the observation equation because we said that
that we also have the state
then what's left is just as
so if you knew then this would be just the planning problem
just the planning problem so talk about that
we have some guests
they should have special sensory
so why should be set up to you as i said previously
the problem is that
that different locations in different communities
and while
in control
typically denotes observation and
i tend to use the contrast here annotation but here in mdps left sometimes dino's
the next and so everything would become
unfortunately this state some of the survivors from all the changes that i made to
the slides
times so anyway so that these two different ways of
approaching the problem
so one approach is to estimate the model
this axiomatic scheme i'm saying that these
matches one of shapes
right matches the shape
you do the p norm
you decide
and uniformly you move the pain the p one over here but could boxes in
front of the box in front of their
so this one is independent again
this is an axiom
because it's an instance of that
now i do modus ponens what is modus ponens states is we the left hand
side alone
take this guy
check whether it's the same as this guy and if it is
then the sky down here
the rules are trying so you should be able to follow and now
put this whole thing because i haven't got placed on my page here
so that
this guy
is the same as these
and up here is the space where you put all of this stuff right so
this is the derivation
now i start here
p nor is
deducible from these guys because it's in there
this dissertation sick leave the left hand side alone just put a box in front
of it
and now apply modus ponens again
the the left hand side along
take this
see if it's the same as this if it is
in bring that one down there
prior to two derivations of the same thing
so what we have now
we have
characterisation or definition of what it means
for there to be introduction of five from gamma
just apply the rules see if you can feel the derivation
is the syntactically formulated logic so now i want to say
i'm going to take
these bits
and then we define a modal logic
using the syntax only
define it
this is the set of all formulae five which is deducible from the empty set
of assumptions
when you go on
you not allowed to have anything on the left-hand side and if you can still
do the production
five is deducible from the empty set
so will say that is theorem exactly when it deducible from the empty set
and this is the traditional way
modal logic is was defined
until kripke you came along
as a set of rules
syntactic rules
and then you talked about the theorems of the two
i want to show
the soundness completeness results
what's out timetables timetable is we supposed to stop it eleven have a right
quarter past OK good and do they have any coffee or anything at this point
nine OK alright
what i'm going to do is i'm going to try and do this and this
proof now
and let's leave the completeness proof for the next the next next lecture
because that almost catches mia so what i want to prove i want to prove
soundness that's this direction
just going let you read that from moment because
to prove by induction so some of you may be able to follow
so what am i trying to say
i'm trying to prove that
if there is the deduction of site from gamma
in size logical consequence of gamma
i'm going to do it by induction on the length of the derivation so if
i tell you that size is deducible from gamma you go back and look up
what does that mean
it means that
there is a tree with the root data and whatever right so
our assumption is
size is deducible from gamma so here we are
it's unfortunate that i've done this boards this way because the
OK so
here we are
site is deducible from gamma
and you know that these things are all instances of the idea rule
or the axiom rule
and then in here are the other rules modus ponens necessitation suppose there's modus ponens
and suppose this necessitation here right
modus ponens
and everything else is either modus ponens necessitation is going to do it by induction
on the length of this thing
OK what's the base case
the base case is when size in gamma
straight away
in other words
if size in gamma industry doesn't really exist because this guy is just an instance
of i
what's the shortest possible tree
the shortest possible derivation all size just in guam
what i have to show
that size the logical consequence of gamma
if size in gamma
and we have to show that whenever all of the things in gamma true everywhere
inside true everywhere
well the size in gamma
because it holds right
besides in gamma then our assumption is all the things in gamma true one of
them inside the you ask inside to everywhere of course
what's the other one the other one is that well it could also be an
instance of an axiom
right so again this thing doesn't exist it's just that you use AOL
look at this formula here is actually one of the shapes
it's one of its instance of one of shapes
and then you have to go here and say
get rid of
it is
the rest
it's not for
one of the word
original model
but i don't know
it is reasonable
all right
one of the
that's not
all right
world war
this was
last year
these are
he was
first of all
robert c
the only we
much more
so all
one of problems
the role
on the one part
there are
so you're
two more
or are
and but you
one she
five of
four days
well that's all
very simple model
o lord of the
o were
these organisms have
these there
from one of the problem
o thing
you are
from the
one two
one of the
not of world
this shows you know who
a lot
there are
and we know that order of all documents is always the same
we can simply recreate
previous estimations of plagiarized from sound file
and that's it sold
what we're are doing
we get
string number i mean from from all
from owl
my medics presentation
the read one probability sort of pagerank
and there
because we now know
number of things that
can here so it's
we can simply
get previous radio and and do this all this calculation
now we are getting now we are producing so it's like in this formula
what what what what what we get
we are getting our results not for one page as in previous on previous slide
but that we are putting them into into this array
adding them into different lots of this different cell
so we still need one error
that has all elements
so the size of this is equal to the size of our collection
cannot handle the situation can really
reduce the size of the story
actually can
in this case what what we're going to do
we can
simply divide this area
for example
by two we can
use only half of this right
in this case
for every iteration for every calculation
we are going to run through all matrix twice
so where
go through all this metric
the first time
and we are adding only four
the first half of elements
we are doing that so into to some temporary file
and then to replace this array is second half of my of
a way to force the pagerank for the second half of collection
and again run through through the whole
metrics presentation
and and in every case we simply ignore
things in our ports links post lists that are
in our output
in this case
managed to avoid
output array
but what we want to go on what want to be lost actually in real
one reading of the whole matrix presentation for every iteration
so now
every iteration
we need to or read
this matrix presentation so many times
as the number of
there is that we have for output
it's not that i should not use using this approach we can fit the collation
of which around four
any size of
four in memory they have only this story so it fixed number
and they always can
you can create can take some smaller a and only in this case we need
more iterations
so on every computer can calculate pagerank for
every size of the
of our metrics for every forever size of the collection
the only
the main difference is that it will be slower and slower because you need more
and more iterations you and wrote to presentation of adjacency matrix
actually managed to do that
so we can calculate pagerank
every computer
very very on the very small compared the problem be that if you take a
very long time
and how we can
increased speed of all
first of all we are doing iteration
the first approach that can help
to increase gate
it's so my last iteration
there are and this is the part of
science and there are a lot of articles how to
creating this
optimize pagerank calculation
the engineers about thinking about practical approach
and in my opinion the most simple and practical approach
it is to use
as initial where
this course and that we have
in this formula
well it from our previous calculations
the intuition behind this is that we don't have a lot of changes all in
and we have a theoretical example the theoretical result that usually pagerank is pretty stable
so based on this weekend
i believe that if we have
have to run both the observational and interventional resumes to check it but the belief
that actually there is enough information here
but if you condition on those variables you're going to get the the a is
model here which you can transform and this and even if you don't observe you
and that's the common case
then this is indeed
it is if you like
it's just it if i didn't have you in there would be an arrow from
fifty to one
but this is a special case that is not completely general
so we have to and so we have to argue that this would be appropriate
one of the or or
but it
it's not all around the variable it is the variable which tells you what regime
you're talking about so
if i can i can only condition on it
it always conditioned on
that means i said i tell you what this value is and and so i
consider if you like consider the joint distribution of these three variables conditioned on f
t and there's that's really three different distributions because there are three that fifty
all represented in one picture
you can think of
agents sometimes exploring sometimes intervening taking your random coin toss is not quite the same
deciding ahead of time what to do and you actually even think there's even a
bit of argument y randomisation works because it's not obvious that it works
randomisation is an observation regime is just that you know more about this probability structure
it's not an international regime
o so one point to point out is that it's often the case you can
say i would value knew more about the the patients
health economic status and all sorts of other things that will be enough knowledge that
i know
how we respond to treatment and it doesn't matter how we got here
if these are all if i do everything the doctor talk into account when you
decided how to assign the treatment then that will be adjusting for that will make
it OK
but that's fine i would but i would have to know is if i don't
observe you understood in trouble for don't deserve you then i would still get an
arrow from fifty to one and i could just take the body channel
despite the what the distribution of y given t only without putting you in the
problem i couldn't just transform at from one
to another
OK let's suppose then that you convincingly tell that story you believe it
and new is the variable set of variables which you you you know what you're
talking about and you can observe
one thing you can do
it is
you can compute what you might call the average causal effect conditional on somebody's got
characteristics you
which is what it says so
it's the expected you just change the treatment from one to zero for somebody with
those characteristics and notice
i haven't put an indicator of the treatment regime here
and that's because i don't need to
because the distribution of y given you and is the same in all three regimes
so that's why some meaningful thing and i could calculate it i can computed by
modeling the observation regime and it will be relevant
causally meaningful in the interventional regimes
and i can use that as the formula here
to estimate the the overall average causal effect so here's the story
the average causal effect what is the is is expectation why when i intervenes set
this set the treatment week one minus the same thing
when i said it is zero so let's consider each of those terms looks like
this so this is just the standard probability calculus rule of extending the conversation to
bring in additional variable in this case you
now i realize that when
well i'm intervening articles t
automatically the value of t will be little t because that's part of my story
that's what i mean by intervening so redundant information
but once i could added additional condition here
i no longer need
to put in f too coarse too because the expectation of y
given c and u
and information about fifty actually doesn't matter what if fifty years by this assumption so
i without leaving out means think about the observation regime
so when i don't mention it is the observation regime
so that's the same as this
and now
having left it out
the only random variable left in this quantity is the variable u
and the variable u is independent of st t
and therefore this out the expectation doesn't make any difference
i can remove it and i just get the in thing and and if i
just take the value fatigue was one subtracts value from google zero i discover
the average causal effect is the overall expectations all the observational regime of the
of the the average causal effect for the sub population of people with a particular
value of and i just average over all possible values of you would kind of
the distribution this for reasons which may or may not become clear
it's turned the back door formula
and not just the expectation but this this calculation goes to the whole distribution and
looks like this in terms of the whole distribution where everything on the right can
be got from observational data so i can estimate the whole interventional distribution by this
formula ford or formula from purely observational data so long as i can believe the
story i told
that's important and so long as i can observe you because that's one of the
so i can do this modelling in the observation regime
that story then allows me to transfer that information to the intervention regime and here's
the way of doing quite a simple story but not too trivial
and a very useful one
you could also
use a similar story to so what how what i justify
my original story my original story
it was that i
i don't i don't have to worry at all about the this completely ignorable treatment