people who have the same evaluation function but choose from the latter gives distribution from
a distribution that more frequently doesn't make the best move but only the second best
third-placed or i guess in our case even further down
that's what we could do if we had this distribution now let's see how we
model this distribution and i'm back to the one about the
detailed scores given the colouring of the board here
and so
one suggestion is
and that's the basic model i'm talking about here is to model this
as again pretty much gives distribution with an energy here
and it's the interesting thing what this energy looks like and
so there's some here
indicates all the vertices on the board that are neighbours so on the board just
connected by lines right
and the idea is that this energy
has a linear terms
in this course and the quadratic term in this course so
this term is essentially indicates if i have the blackstone somewhere
does that make it more likely that this we look at the end of white
and black control at the end of the white control
that's guided by this parameter here now we also have coupling
and that's correct characterised by these coupling parameters w which just take for any pair
of neighbors
just look at the colours
of the two that determines the value of this parameter and then multiply that by
the product of the two
so this guides the correlations between territory and this is where we can feed a
lot of information into the system because if you look at the final position in
go it's not that territory is scattered all around there's no such thing as a
single point of territory of black surrounded by white territory but there are certain smoothness
constraints on this on the outcome of the game and and that's captured by this
by this these parameters here
so here's a factor graph about and actually when i look at it i don't
think that it may not be as insightful hoped it would be you can imagine
that the c one c two c three this is essentially the go board
and now for every one of these
you have these is and that's essentially the final score
right there are kind of on top layer on top of that
and then you have these factors
that on the one side connect these neighboring points
but also get input from the two colours
of of the points that we're looking at
and so this is the corresponding factor graph for the model and i'm just putting
this in here to show that the relative primitive primitive model and that one could
also say put factor in the middle here and connect all four
positions to it so there's a lot of more complex models that one could explore
this is an interesting aspect here that we need to cover and that's symmetry of
course in going you have a certain colour reversal symmetry rights if they exchange black
that doesn't really make a big difference
you also have
the symmetry between edges
we see that it doesn't matter if this is black and is right or vice
versa as long as they change the the colouring as well as the score
and if you use the symmetry what you find is that this simple model just
boils down to to five parameters that we need to determine all that we can
and that's
we have the coupling for chains so that the coupling between two
the scores of two black stones or two white stones we have an entire chain
couplings surface white stone and the blackstone then then that tells us how holders find
scores will be coupled we have a chain empty which could be the empty white
or empty black
and we have the conductivity of empty space so to speak the coupling between two
empty points which determines how likely it is that two empty neighbouring empty points are
either both black both white or one is black and the other things like
and we have only one parameter that determines
and what influences of stone actually has is on a single point on these external
fields because we would assume that the black stone is just as good for black
is the white stone is for white
that's just represented by
this being the opposite of that and obviously we think that there is no bias
for empty stones by the way this doesn't hold true the the stronger player out
against the weaker player right because then a priority we would think that the stronger
player has a higher likelihood of getting a point for him than the weaker player
there's also an extension of this model
which takes into account liberty is not the only features in this model that i've
been talking about been the colouring of support but if few as you see in
in your play
it's vital quantity to know how many liberty's chain has because that determines how stable
it is tactically for example if it has fewer liberties then you lost right so
you see is an important quantity and we have to have an additional model that
actually deals with this and also takes that into account and of course you could
take any number of features of the position if you deem them reason reasonably useful
for predicting territorial values
now in order to
to use this model we need to do inference
and in particular what we need to do is we need to find the pointwise
and pairwise marginals the point wise models we need in order to sum them up
to find out what the score in the pairwise models as well as the point
wise we need for learning because if you remember if you want to learn such
a markov random field or similar to a boltzmann machine really use the learning rule
involves these pointwise and pairwise marginals and we explored different ways of doing this here
are two sampling methods the simplest thing you would always try to use gibbs sampling
but sampling has the problem that if there's a strong coupling between your variables then
it makes it very slowly so you have difficulties getting a whole bunch of of
points that are neighbors in strongly coupled to fly to the other colour
and one way of dealing with that is this one wang sampling which
which avoids that problem by flipping entire clusters
and this is just a comparison that this really mixes faster than that but i
don't want to go into that
you can also do exact inference
but that's computationally very hard because it the nineteen by nineteen board needs to click
size of twenty
if you want to do inference and so the computational complexity is ordered two to
the twenty which is painful that's kind of you know it takes several minutes to
hours to do that and so another alternative of course is to use sleep EP
loopy belief propagation which is quite efficient but leads to overconfidence in the results and
show you what that looks like
we learn some parameter values of course and
i told you there are effectively only five parameters this is the maximum likelihood solution
using a few hundred games for training
and maybe the most interesting well plausible thing i should say is that this value
for w chains is very high this reflects the common fate property
that means that if two points are
in the same chain
this is the 1st
legal that's the tangent plane
to a subspace of that given by the equation that complex ways see at a
given point can be found
by looking for its normal vector and we know that the normal vector is actually
what 1 normal vector is given by the gradient of a function because we know
that the gradient is actually pointing to that manipulative level sets towards higher values of
a function gives us the direction of fastest increase a
OK any questions about these topics at a
thank you
OK so let me add actually occurred from note to what we've seen so far
about 4 directives and how to use them which is maybe something it should have
mentioned above weeks ago
so why do we like to cover directives when 1 of the reasons is we
can do all all these things that have another reason is that fairly unique possibilities
to do physics and to do if you to understand much of the world you
because of a lot of things actually are governed by what's called partial differential equations
OK so that's what you want
control remark about whether this is good for
so the partial differential equation is an equation that involves the possibilities of a function
so you have some function but unknown that depends on a bunch of variables and
and partial difference in equation is some relations between its buffer derivatives so that is
our equations involving the partial derivatives of an unknown function
so let me give you an example to see to see how that works so
for example the heat equation
is 1 example of apart from different equation it's the equation when it divides to
fight for you the space of some of
equation fossil evidence from t equals some constant times the sum of the 2nd half
shows with respect to x y and z so this is an equation well with
trying to sort of
for function and that depends actually on unfold valuables
x y z and and so what did you think of you know what what
you have in mind when this equation governance temperature so if if you think that
f of x y z t will be the temperature
at that point in space at position x y z and that point C then
this tells you how temperature changes over time
it tells you that at any given point the rate of change of temperature over
time is given by this so complicated expressions in the buffer derivatives in terms of
the space coordinates x ways
so if you know for example the initial distribution of temperature and this form and
if you assume that no think is generating heat updating heat away so if you
have any understanding heating going on than it would tell you how the temperature will
change over time and eventually stabalize to some final value
yes but you
why do we take the directive twice well that's a question that and state which
forces exports and attitude and going to node in a few weeks will actually see
a derivation of where this equation comes from and try to justify it but really
that's something you will see in Physics class
reason for that is basically
physics of how heat is transported between you know particles in a fluid volatility in
any medium but
this this constant K actually called the heat conductivity tells you how well the heat
flows for the material looking
so anyway and and giving it to you just to show you an example of
life problems where in fact you have to sort of 1 of these things
it's not hard to sort of partial differential equations is not a topic for this
class it's not pixel 1803 which is called difference equations without powerful uh which means
that you will tools to study and some of these equations but when there's only
1 variable involved
and you'll see is what the White House
so and if you want often later on we have many find classes about buffer
different equations but you know 1 thing at a time
so just wanted to point out to you that value of functions that you see
in real life satisfy many nice relations between the partial derivatives
OK so that was you know in case you were wondering why on the syllabus
a buffer difference equations now we've officially called on the
that's basically what we need to know about it again
but will get back to that a bit later
OK if there's no further questions let me continue and go back to my list
of topics to
0 so it should have written down that this equation is solved by temperature at
the point where Atlantic
and there are actually many of them are interesting but the difference equations you will
maybe something known about the wave equation that governs how waves propagating space and about
the diffusion equation which tells you how you know when you have to be a
mixture of 2 fluids how this somehow makes a lot of time and so on
basically to every problem you might want to consider apart from different equation to solve
OK anyway so it back to my list of topics
for the x component
the other firms out there
and if i substitute my solution
but i know deep in my belly has to be correct
if i substituted in this rate equation
and what you find of course it is no surprise that only gets credit
equals case creates
times sees created
and so that is going to be
OK wise gradient
plus cases great
times square
my KY in my case the quantized
because they are now
only allowed for certain values
so i can right now
omega square
this density squared
i get by
over b
was nancy five
over c square
was me
these for bidirectional and sees useful to see direction
what is the problem
only one person
there interaction is cx there actually is a in the wider actions b
the reason why direction o
so we have the boundary condition in the y direction and upon conviction
the direction
or to communities and just make the change
what i missed something
i leave it see i cannot change that
because if i change that then it becomes a terrible chain reaction
that c
well i'm very sorry that i call that c
thank you very much
so we find can i get my talk back by the way
so we agree it with no mistake on the blackboard but there is confusion about
my apologies
yes if i called the dean there is another problem dx three y and then
you have another
i have followed this convention this was the seen
this is the you see the same see here
that is that same c
so is the cause c has nothing to do with the speed of light
it's one of those things
that happens and stands for mary and and stands for nancy doesn't stand for normal
this time it stands for nancy
my apologies
all right can we go on
the you have permission
OK thank you for trying because in the could have been a mistake but it
wasn't that way
so now we know what you see there now
is that you have the whole family
of frequencies
right so we need all the conditions for the x direction
and the whole family then you can give
mary nancy your as a
subscripts has omega one one omega one two and omega two one omega two two
and so on
i tried to some
what actually
this system is doing
it's awfully difficult
but i think i can make an attempt
suppose we look at the system in this direction
so we're looking at the y z plane
so here is the same direction which has this lengthy sorry i will repeat it
once more
to avoid confusion this is been so this is the y direction and this is
the same direction
and so x is coming straight out of the blackboard
so we're looking out from the side like this
that means that the components of the vector in the x direction must be zero
it must be zero here because this is the play
and there cannot be any tangential component in that play but this is also plain
and there cannot be any tangential component in that play
this is also a plane and i cannot be any conventional component here
so everywhere here must be
the vector x direction must
and so what does it mean that
one one moment it means that the whole thing think of it as a member
that the whole member on comes to use e vectors is like this goes away
from you effect is like this goes towards you and goes away from that's what
can you hear me
OK thank you for inviting me glad to be here so i'm going to talk
about subjectivity and sentiment analysis and i'll tell you what subjectivity is at the moment
i prepared slides with the of conference web swapnodes summer center and were members of
our group at the university of pittsburgh
i just want to start by acknowledging my colleagues and students in this area
i work with claire cardinality riloff on extracting and summarizing events and opinions in text
and with random house the word sentence subjectivity
learning multilingual subjective language we've recently had many graduate student co-authors and so this seems
like a good area for graduate students to work
OK what is said to activity
that term from literary theory and if the linguistic expression of somebody's opinion sentiment emotions
evaluations belief speculations and so on so the and so on the general term we
use is private state which is from the comprehensive grammar of the english language by
cricket at all and a private state the state that is not open to objective
observation verification what does that mean i can think that you look happy i can
guess that you're happy but i can't directly observe that you're happy
are verifiable and the reason that we use private stated the general covering term that
includes everything that we want to talk about
OK so
why would you want to do it in our research group are applications are question
answering information extraction so consider what's recently been called the thing in question answering where
the question is asking for
an opinion are feeling and emotion
so what is the international reaction to the re-election of robert mugabe as president of
so here's the relevant
sentence for that question african observers generally approved of his victory while western governments strongly
we did a couple studies and we found first of all the code opinion question
answering and gives me is more complex in fact question answering we found that for
a given question on average there's more answers
the answers are longer
and there's more partial answers that would have to be aggregated
and we also
using automatic sensitivity analysis to improve question answering and the second paper was at this
conference last year
for information extraction this is where the system is trying to extract for example terrorist
incidents from tax
and we observe that sensitivity asking causes false hits for information extraction so the parliament
exploded into theory against the government when word leaked out that's not a bombing offense
and so in this work we explored subjectivity filtering strategies to improve information extraction
a recent study that we just finished its pilot study that we're going to build
from is we look for several kinds of subjectivity improvement data
these are health tax
and these are important for syndromic surveillance
and are the goal would be
not necessarily still two things out for IE but to augment the output of an
information extraction system with information about how certain things were whether there was a lot
of fear
what people know and what they did not
so as i'm sure you all know there's many many groups and companies working on
applications involving subjectivity in sentiment analysis opinion mining the slightly different terms in this area
and here's a few more
and what we have in mind here is
you're basing this on what people are saying well what's being written about so we're
talking about what information can you get from text
so the classic is product review mining what features of the thinkpad t forty three
do customers like which they not like is a review positive or negative toward the
this track sentiments toward topics over time
for example is anger ratcheting up or cooling down a continuous area is prediction based
on what people are talking about what they're saying let's predict whether
what the outcome of an election will be
well the market trend go up and down and et cetera as many other applications
people have proposed
OK this is growing area kind of hot area i guess
i want to point out where making available as part of this tutorial
a bibliography right now it's got about two hundred twenty five papers on it but
it's not complete we're putting together are
our internal bibliographies and will make it more extensive
and these are just the papers in computer science not other related areas and mostly
since two thousand
so there's a lot of stuff here i'm just it maintains great bibliography and also
want to point out that there's a sentiment AI yahoo groups for discussion of this
i also wanted to put this up here to point out how much stuff is
going on in this area and in two hours i can't hope to cover
the field
and i actually opted not to make it too broad may just mentioning topics i
decided to go into detail about about a couple of things
because it's only two hours on a little bit longer than normal lecture
so what i'm going to focus on the first of all i'm going to talk
about fine grained classification rather than document level classification has a lot of people that
work on classifying an entire documents
i'm going to focus on the lower level
the perspective is going to be on linguistic ambiguity syntactic language is very
it's ambiguous
they are baby they work against all the other existing algorithms as turns it more
into a science so you get a new feature terms of features and their different
if you have objects or you're doing visual dormitories but if you have a new
feature that you can test it against how the performance of all the other features
and actually show that you doing better and you know what vision papers they're doing
this because it's very complex to do this this comparisons but now it's going to
be easy you get a database point opened be and you get these charts out
so hopefully they'll reject all papers that don't fit test against everything else should be
done in machine learning Isaiah shows some of the use of this on a robots
that I thought I'd digital it here but I'm running at a time so just
move but it was started Bahai to stop any of this is this is visual
dormitories so it's the robot tracking itself and forming a trajectory by watching these points
that the detected points and that's the tracking of and this is using and something
called a star detector along along with the current descriptor calendar descriptive call any of
the dolphins fully reconstructed exact trajectory using stereo points okay so we're changing the whole
interface that that for object recognition to pack it again in this modular so that
was just detectors descriptors here's here's object recognition in general being worked on right now
by myself and in terms of a some recent work where you will see here's
the robust I might have to skip a bunch of this and there's a lot
of detectors basically we can get out spots that my stereo or we projected texture
if you see here to get dance steps and then using that we can do
a lot of stuff so I think I'll skip a bunch of this so ably
did it we did 8 a milestone to which was finding outlets and doors that
open it so the so this robot but had the wrong 26 miles of Samarra
along without bumping into people just running through the building day and nite and then
had find within an hour at a 2nd test had finding the founder clicked on
10 rooms 10 outlets about the finding the open the door if it could some
doors we locked on it and it would have to detect that it couldn't achieve
the goal and go on and I think that maybe I'll show a little bit
of that it's sped up and maybe it'll run this was the plugging the sped
up so I won't show nearly all of it but also the robot at that
time so that's opening the door and this is the real time and then moving
into fast time it what I did was it could find that outlet and plug-in
exactly in 1 shot 70 per cent of time buttered bonuses depended on the doing
this and so we had a tap we actually intend it and we we actually
wanted even even when it could tell plug-in we we miss a game that just
did this plugging pattern to make sure it to get it to a hundred percent
but but now that I know of the robot was itself we use a form
Cameron and it's a Web interface you can just go to the Web site put
yourself in the middle just do it exactly Sosa gave us that are witnessed so
this is the founder of Google he was falling this thing around a day so
that newer techniques of these grading periods here I it's like Kinkel through all this
recognizing transparent objects that's knew that by just simple combinations of gradients that they're done
branch and bound technique by pouring in ending so it's very fast adjustable Warren or
an enzyme Acadia in asking us if suggests home think of set myself up F
hair had and this is the class I thought but at using this algorithm they
they were able to within just a month get the robot to move move to
table which wasn't shown here but the identify objects pick them up and put and
into the recycling bins be politically correct and make a show here so so that's
recognizing the objects that you can do there's a fair amount of clutter as we
also use the point clouds to clear things about this is the point cloud and
it's so it's a better find that and segmenting it's and then grabbing this bunch
of clout circuit so I get 0 minutes left will just go on for the
last thing this is some new work an object recognition that we did not using
point clouds getting good results very new work that's going to be a C C
and and notes and finally a again with just 1 more thing and that's so
with open-source with the Haskell it's partly funds this but they have a challenged and
then and everybody's playing with these recognition chances they get 60 cent 1 year and
then they get 62 % but everybody knows what happened last year so that training
on the test set that I want to that I want to contest the drive
looking at where you know you really get us all probably get a process and
that way to put a stake in the sand saying what's the what's sold isn't
evolving to do this with Ross so that the total be there you can have
any license you want but that when someone says that is picking up objects on
a table solve ego yes in that code the repository it solve anything that will
drive progress and maybe machine learning configured similar things to do so give people everybody
standard problem and then you must you must complete that problem 100 % at this'll
established increasing states the Sam Watters vision solve solves all these things so that how
you also have to plow proposed questions so much from his calls itself a reference
yes so it's just a writer as or and that they're making managing managing it
in general is like children their miserable at that happens of miserable that that the
and small are
and overlap
so the these
orthogonality wasn't at all easy to identify g
i found a way to deal with the problem and now we
describe what it led to in the following years
OK where are we
i want to say more about
these applications it's probably
of greatest interest
i went to enhance the signal to noise out of it
suppose you're using free transforms
so we have a signal that's gone
no it's a gas in noise is white noise in
how would we
approach the problem of the noisy
we would take fourier transforms
and we probably throw high frequency
i would say those high frequencies
four or in some way we will diminish because they were
that's where the noise would be
question we would be losing some signal
that's right so we wouldn't be so
comment was that would look great we recently
by throwing away is high frequencies
so it certainly look smoother
it is really the signal
that single no
no because we we throw away part of the same one through it and we
kept some of the noise
because of course
we can help because we don't know what the noise is
we we are filtering gives the best
if you assume
r time invariance
so that can move into the frequency domain and calculate the competition becomes very nice
we would say i will move frequency domain which just throw away
four or reduce the high high-frequency
well how would use when
so that's the competition
i want to use way
so one
the signal to noise well
the same thing
take the wavelet transform
look at the coefficients the the
not part i would absolutely keep
that's the schools
average part
most of the most of the signal
i probably would keep a lot of w not
but i began to throw away some w one
i remember my picture of matlab toolbox
i would keep the main signal nokia
keep a couple of levels
i would just threshold i would say OK
coefficient larger than such and such
coefficient smaller throw away
actually orthogonality is nice property that if you do it like that
because you know what why is it is orthogonality there are
so sort of you know the energy right
i orthogonality the price of always know you reduce the energy
but if this if you don't have an orthogonal basis
not so sure
throw away a little bit
it wasn't
and the rest so
he might have gone up by throwing away
all right
it's it's
here and in the right way
by i
o thing
and of course everybody realises that
there's parameters to choose either to decide
what's began with small what's the threshold
how much we like you know
how many bits to i want to keep
that's a big issue
if i'm doing
the actual site high-definition TV
well i'm sending out signals in real time
sending a certain number of
CBS it's second
i can make more than k o o
four by
so if you're compressing real time you know
it's for second you know the compression rate you're shooting for and you
i have to reset the threshold
so it's quite exciting
so i would say probably
with wavelets in the in the wavelet versus
fifty competition
in the
mostly fifty
because we know how to do that as we know what we're doing
and the hardware is all built every
o chips are
but in images still images
still hardware to be but a lot of
we probably these lectures are compressed before they go on the web
my guess is it would be for
system that would compressed
and you can see that you plans areas you get a zero if you climb
one you get ones and almost all of them look like the right class
so if user back outside this guy
but it's a very good generative model
of course what's happening is when i class
when i one of those high level units two two
in the two thousand going connections and the weights and those connections lower the energy
of the two reveal and raise the energy all the other beings enough i wonder
in the state space then settle into the true reinstate
and it's good recognition so these examples of cases that it wasn't sure about that
actually got right
so can recognise all sorts of different things
these results from a few years ago
the support vector machine gets about one point four percent
this model
after a bit of tuning
but it's not just going to fine-tune gets one point two five
as will see later we just going to find you can do quite a bit
back probably can't do better than one point six
we you might be able to one point five nine but
basically counted about one point six k nearest neighbors about that so you have some
idea of how tough it is
and there's lots more results in the kind some which are much well below one
but those ones that use prior knowledge about pixels about convolutional neural nets know about
the pixels being near one another about translation invariance these locally
this is pure machine learning approach where you don't know anything about pixels you just
give a big vector and say these vectors have these labels how well you do
so called permutation invariant question list because these rules be just the same to the
data set and for me to the order all the pixels and then fed into
the program
was anything with the prior about
spatial locality will get screwed up
in a sense you might think this is doing something that sort of this is
doing about musical features
but yes you could
but if you take the most pure machine learning approaches like support vector machines
and just feed into this you get results like this
so if you take jan's nets
convolutional neural nets
trained by mark williams ranzato
using backpropagation the best results yes about point four nine percent if he does unsupervised
layer by layer pre training followed by backprop you can do that
and this is the record for a single method you can do better by averaging
methods for single method i think this is the best
i'm now going to give you a different view of why this led by let
one learning works
the depends on the equivalence between different kinds of networks i think this is if
you want to understand what's going on when you stack up these balls machines
i think this is by far the best way to think about it
so here is
a directed
basically graph a directed belief that or directed sigma that
this kind of funny properties
between every pair of layers in the same way it's
we already had is given the same weight
so this image is the transpose of
and these tools can be different sizes
but this is the same size is that this list is that this is the
same size this list does
i call this v one i call this the two
that's sort of joke
because of the visual systems like
but really what i mean is is the hidden units
the hunt of the same size as these
and now i'm going to convince you that this infinitely deep
sigmoid belief network
is actually the same thing is restricted boltzmann machine
they are the same just different ways writing
so first of all let's try generating data from this
to generate data from this you start a long way up here
and you compute p of the given age
p of h can be
of given hp which can be PV give lectures on
whether p of the given ages just
given the size of a new energy input to visibles put it through the
logistics sample
SPV image
if i keep doing that that's exactly the markov chain was running to the the
restricted boltzmann machines sample from this equilibrium distribution
and therefore the distributional get here if i generate that way is exactly the same
as the distribution i get if i run this alternating gibbs sampling
this is also give something
so they define the same distribution
now the next thing is
how to do inference in this model
OK so i've got his start to believe that remember with belief nets you get
explaining away
so when i try for the states of these given these
i'm going explaining away the can and this gone and to correlate things and surely
inference is going to be complicated
solar generation is easy
except the stuff of the way up
inference is going to be complicated
well actually none
this is a very special kind of directed belief net in which inferences just as
simple as generation in fact is actually the same processes generation
so to do inference
well we can to do is we're going to take the vector here
we can multiply by the transpose those weights
and we can put it just a function sample assuming all these are independent
that's just what we did with a restricted boltzmann machine
and that's going to work in this net
and that's what's exciting is that you can do exact inference in the deep directed
belief nett
well if you think about it
find these weights
the same is these weights means that if i have to say you know here
with big positive connections coming from these two minutes
then the equivalent unit up here
but a big positive reactions going to those two units
if you think about the earthquake and track example
the reason explaining away because if i observe the that's all
then probably
the spaces at the beginning passive for observers on then one of those needs to
be able to make it
so they become anti correlated only one of these to be able to make
they become anti correlated
so in the likelihood term come from the data these anti correlated
but now
because these weighs the same as those words
in the prior to coming from here
these are positively correlated
because if that turned on make but these
so this sort of positive correlation come from there
and this anti correlation coming from here
and we really really lucky
they would exactly cancel
to make these independent
it turns out we are lucky
whatever they do put there
as long as these things in an exponential family
then when you do this
infinite directed belief nett
all this stuff upstairs all of these weights up here
will have constructed the prior such that
if o to generate enter to there
i guess some correlation here
and that exactly cancels the anti correlation they get to
so these really are independent
so now we've seen a way of making inference simple in a directed belief nett
the people had really thought of before
which is
don't try to do the difficult inference using monte carlo
don't just assume independence
stick in
weights appears such that
these really are independent
and i can do that simply by having infinite with these weights tied to those
one thing gets a bit more complicated which is remember i told you that if
i can get so i need to sample from the posterior really easily
i take this state
i'm not by the transpose of those ways to produce sigmoid i sample but i
can sample from the posterior
i do the same with sample posterior here
so i can just run the chain in this direction
getting sample from the posterior less
and to learn the weights from s j zero to a size zero
what i do is i take
price lnp divided by p
the game but quite
but this is
the basis of the natural law
so i can write it like it
so this is the bound
i get
on the number of mistakes for the separable case of course i can also look
like this in over here
but i'm concentrating on this one because it was right
and then
which depends on the number of acts
and on the
and log of the number of the main
more precisely it should be but that is going to depend on you want it
to be chosen adaptively
as a as you see it in the stream
this is what you mean because in principle you don't know anything about the stream
going to predict the outcome
people that
you might try to analyse which p
if everything about this is the way of doing it
this the way OK i mean there's enough about this just being made up about
and it's the best thing is the nearest thing i can come up with
maybe the
there are many other
a better way of doing it
not about this is that
this dependency here
this dependency is something that you all
ready find in in the back
analysis of l one regularisation
indeed what happened here
so let's look at it closed now what how does the bound we can the
next thing i was right
if a right
if they choose p the told you want to go on
then what is my q
like you i can compute
like you know is going to be one class
one of the
and i will be
a little bit of then a little bit more than one
i can upper bound to the
q wrong of you
which is a little bit more than one with the one norm of u
with this
maybe there's a minus one
you do the computation the reciprocal so these two are thousand one and that's all
if i make this substitution in my bound what they get is that
i can upper bound to their one class epsilon norm of q with the one
norm of u
and then i get the
and then i get the max
infinity square
so i got my
drawing on now
one infinity
and in our log independence on the
this is again an upper bound on the number of states
of the p norm perceptron for p
got a bit
this is the kind of about that you get when you apply
multiplicative updates like in the we know
or the exponentiated gradient that
this one is by the on this one by a if you given in the
mouth about what
so the the average corresponds to using an exponential potential function
but then we get back with these things and by applying the analysis for exponential
potential function you get about the same for with slightly different costs
so is that that
polynomial at approx in this in this analysis the polynomial is sufficient approximation of explanation
for the purpose of this analysis whenever p is the largest who will and
or exactly one
so now you can go back and compare this with the perceptron
for the two norm perceptive about the perceptron
which is that
two knows where the now and i'm enhancing
stressing the fact that that the norm
OK so let's compress so this is the p norm
for p equals who lnd
and this is the wrong
the perceptron and i noticed that whenever
you know a good deal
it is sparse
next day state
OK if xt is then
this thing is going to be or or the order of the
and this thing is going to be we don't get
this thing is going to be of the order of
and this thing is passed is going to be again the order of one
if it's part in
is really about
this bound is of the order of lnd
and this bound is of the order of the
for the situation in which you have about a target
and then
is the fifth
we can construct the end up a situation in which the this but it's still
a big but i shall i get it into the other way around
this was was analysis elucidated by giving in the world
i realize that these are going to be complimentary complementary properties
good this so this is what i wanted to say
for the pin-up receptor was originally produced by
legal fall in
the club the lender authorized independently
by a
in another paper for
whatever was about immigration because the paper about occasionally the trauma and grow
there you have any questions about this because i'm going to finish up with this
and the last twenty minutes
wonderful about what i ate there is generally the next thing
sum of squares or something like that the residual sum of squares
so let's look at that for the examples that we've done
let's see so before we actually going compute the p value is one thing that
you can say right away
and that's the following
how big you think the case where it should be
well if you look at the sky square you have some over n data points
and is the distance between the measured value
and somehow the expected the predictive value from the theory and it's divided by the
standard deviation
of the measured value and the whole thing is where
well in general here you would expect the distance between y i lambda
to be roughly equal to sigma pi i
and then you summing and terms
so just naively you would expect to minimize value of the class were to be
equal to the number of data points
well in fact you're then adjusting some parameters in this function so that's not quite
you will recall that the expectation value of the case distribution is in fact equal
to the number of degrees of freedom
so what you expect
if the hypothesis is correct
is that you would expect to minimize value of the case would to be equal
to the number of data points minus the number of fitted parameters
so very often you say well i had ten data points in the consequent of
nine point seven
so therefore they were up roughly equal and if it was good
or if i had ten data points and i got consequent of thirty seven
well then you know something's wrong
but now more specifically what you can do is you can find the p value
you can find the probability
under the assumption of the hypothesis in question of finding a case is high is
you've got
or higher
so that would be
this integral here where that distribution is the case for distribution for and seventy
degrees of freedom
so if you do that with the with the previous example with the
the first order polynomial so that's the line that has a nonzero slope
then you wind up with the case would mean of three point nine nine
there were five degrees five data points and to fitted parameters so therefore three degrees
of freedom
so you can do this in general then in row from three point nine nine
to infinity
of the case pdf
with three degrees of freedom and you get o point two six three
so what does that mean
that means that if that hypothesis is correct
you would expect to get a case where
as high as you got or higher
twenty six percent of the time
and that's reasonable that means you want to horrifically unlucky in generating your data or
in in observing your data
on the other hand for the zeroth order polynomial so that's the horizontal line
that given gave case great mean of forty five point five
there were five
data points one fitted parameters so therefore four degrees of freedom
and that would correspond to a p value of three point one times ten to
the minus nine
so let's come back to the question is the hypothesis of the horizontal line right
or wrong
i don't answer that question directly what i can say is that if the hypothesis
were correct
then you would expect the high spirits high is this one or higher
only three times out of a billion
therefore what will therefore it was probably wrong right but that that that's the final
step goes beyond the p value the p value is simply the probability
assuming the hypothesis to get customers high you've got or higher
so i got just a few minutes so fine
finish up with final topic
let's go back to this this is a very important example of observing some number
of events and where you have some number for background some number potentially from from
i don't know whether or not the signal processing exists or not
and i only measure the sum i don't distinguish between signal and background when i
make this this measurement
again let me assume that the expected number of background events b is known
and i'm searching for this this is very simple process
let me assume now that b is four point six
and i observe five events
so i think in the previous our what i said i said suppose b was
o point five
and i observed five events
so then i was thinking well i probably discovered something new
but now let me suppose the expected number of background events is four point six
and you observe five events
what this kind of intuitively
you're not going to get very far by claiming that there's some new signal processing
there if if the
background alone had mean four point six then that's really quite compatible with five
also can we say anything about the signal process we can certainly try to exclude
the hypothesis that the single process was very large
i suppose the expected number of signal events were
so the expected total will be twenty four point six but only observed five
that's not very compatible
so i can certainly try to exclude higher values of s
because i have to do with properties of structures registered as an example of combinatorial
principles and any other reason for doing it
and penelope maddy
has taken
two was quite a long way
i was thinking because
i consulted with the people who work in axiomatic set theory and very large cardinals
that she has a good general discussions about
the foundations of
set theory
and so on
he comes to the conclusion that there is
a long unification taking place that even though the competing assumptions
so i had to skip over this
i recommend reading books
on realism and naturalism
mathematics for these
the problem is that with structuralism
in many interesting structures
necessarily thing rather than stewardship was saying
numbers can be understood because if you think of the structure
the is the first and the second and the third and so forth the concept
of number corresponds to the ideas of water in a certain
but the
structures that we use
when the
the film can be singled out
but the structure can be singled out
so the argument about the existence of subject
because it required construct some the an important factionalism that's developed in mathematics called category
theory because
it says
pillars is that you have
combinations of structures
then put together and according to a
and you have relationships between different structures and the social relationships that you're standing there
the question is will have to try to understand
why certain things are inescapable in mathematics
that gives this objectivity
two and many questions about the underlying logic goes along with that it
one of the questions about what is the difference between classical logic
it was just coming originally from one
and questions about constructivism
many simply
project intuitionism there
because of the common idea
that if you do not have a lot of excluded middle
behind that
you have to prove everything so
she was the manager for the class of food
i think she most compelling point there
i hope you have a couple of weeks
and ask
about this
the past from classical logic two
intuitionistic logic
as the passage of generalization
and even though didn't think of it that way because he was much concerned with
real numbers
the policy
function theory
but in one
you may have the possibility of structure
there are many interesting cases
possible intuitionistic logic
that's impossible in classical logic
again we have really completely come to the place where we can show mathematicians are
expanding horizons and thinking in terms of more general logic new structures you then
i had high hopes for the area called synthetic differential geometry and the case from
people in category theory the
originally proposed things in them
number of people carried out
the process of doing it turns out that this
by using
differential manifolds
you can put
two articles setting a kind
set theory
and you can describe infinitesimal
quite differently from the way it's done in nonstandard analysis you can discuss different kinds
and how they affect the differential structure there and conceptual ways
you anything about the film number
in principle
so this is why you was hinting yesterday at small and this continuity
you need some assumption that list that you move from one to the other because
in fact what is the difference
the difference
is about one fourth of the radius of a hydrogen atom
so it's absolutely sense to say that you're mishearing as a bit odd length of
flower up in
this email places
if this is not the same as well it is it is that they make
no sense because it depends on where the atoms themselves and moving one provided that
the model of data that we have is correct which is far from clear
so the real numbers
never actually there
but they are so useful with the in
well let's be because they were in most cases they will work that has b
understanding that this is not the real thing
topics that will come
conditional probabilities bayes theorem independent case here
one of these
it has been mentioned before
let me
specify here this
famous property
linearity of expectation
so this position of linear combination is a linear combination of expectations
at some point in time if everything goes well i will be using this
and i will be resorting to the six point
over and over do we
have the probability distribution and where
which is the probability that this
four when
review of the thermodynamics people there is always a month the probability that something was
what does it mean non-zero probability in the real world
we are just using this as mental artifacts that are accessed alone and get useful
one the way the probability of something happening
the best approximation is that count
so if i have this potential option of somebody earning a lot of money in
a sense this database
and i want to have an idea for probability distribution i can count how many
people some of the official community police below
this is not going to be the real problem will be an empirical approximation but
it is about the best
as a kernel
provided that we accept that there is such thing as
actual probability
god will be coming back to this
way of thinking of another
conditional probability we take in many cases form of tell implications
you will see that i will be
taking you into logical point of view because it
i i like that you see some of the largest principia in propositional logic everybody
now to the feature of implication is that whenever a always me
and this is the definition
well said
i don't think any observations of humans
and ask them whatever you think of is the most interesting
yes maybe for having had the mother
anything else
you will find
one percent acceptance
some used for anything you can think of
so what is really the opposite way
i don't mean that they somebody that does everything the opposite way
because the quantification
although this may be too and i am not sure
but for a huge from the point defiance then you will agree with me that
anything you can think of
when somebody is taking your question
and we have to accept that
them having implications
in data mining
well you can do that
and they have they do appear but when you look at them
and you don't want that
i will be coming to this late so we will be measuring two things out
implications of so the implication of the implications
events i will look at the number of observations so will call it the support
which is the same thing as the probability of the empirical probability but in a
different scale
and i will
the research centre of the notion of confidence which is
the conditional probability just
as coming from today
so the number of times both events come up with a divided by the number
of times
and dissident appear
now this is a quite natural mysteries and located user whenever you want to measure
intensity of implication and then you will have to to explain it to a medical
doctor he knows about conditional probabilities you would expect you to use this
but unfortunately you have two hundred with utmost care
get a sense of
are the diffusion of heat on the manifold he so called heat kernel the class
in and i can fix i can functions of the laplacian of the heat kernel
gives rise to what is called the heat operator the diffusion operator
and the diffusion distance
between two points is defined like this
if you imagine
and initial distribution of heat on the manifold which is
at x so it's delta function at x
and if you imagine initial distribution of heat which is the delta function and y
then you can ask if heat
the floor happened on the manifold of there was diffusion along the manifold and i
started with initial distribution concentrated on x i would get distribution of heat and that
distribution of heat is given by
the heat operator the diffusion operator applied to the attacks
and if instead i took
delta y and applied to heat operator to it i would get HD applied to
delta y which is the distribution of heat
from an initial condition which was appointed moss
at y
so basically on this manifold i would like to define a distance
i take a point x
i start with an initial pulse of heat at that point x and allow heat
to dissipate over the manifold so the heat flows along the manifold and then that
i following the geometry of the manifold of the kingston bottlenecks in the manifold slow
down there
in some directions where which are very small the enough flat to speed up the
so the heat is flowing along the manifold
and you end up with the distribution of heat after time t
from an initial location x
you end up with the distribution of heat after time t t from an initial
location y and take the euclidean distance between those two
OK that's what is called the diffusion distance
we will see
is that this is essentially
very closely related to to the lab class in
diffusion of heat and the manifold is governed by the heat equation on the manifold
in the heat equation on the manifold
he is actually given by le plus f is the partial derivative with respect to
the way the diffusion
as opposed to the plus and i can maps works
is that it looks
at the i can functions of the glacier and it embeds every point into a
low dimensional space using this particular
so it looks a last matrix looks so that i can values and i can
vectors of the last matrix
dikin values are the lambda one lambda two lambda three and so on and i
can vectors f one f two f three and so on and given a point
x u map it like this
and that gives you
an embedding
for every point x
it can be related to taking a random walk on this graph
another two notions of randomness going on so we have to keep our hits
clear about that
you're taking a random walk on the graph
but the graph itself is a random graph
so you have manifold
you randomly sampled this manifold and get this random graph by connecting nearby points to
each other
and now you do a random walk on this
random graph
the essential question
which now is resolved is whether
walk on this
random graph is close
the actual flow of
on the underlying manifold
and the answer is more or less yes
so this so let me give you let me give you a justification for the
laplacian i can maps and from first
remember the high-level intuition from where this comes and this is very simple
justification high-level intrusion from where this comes as i have a bunch of point sitting
on the manifold
and i would like to embed it into a low dimensional space
so i have a collection of points x one to xn
and i will map it to a lower dimensional space and you end up with
a bunch of points y one through y and
and in this case we're taking an extreme form of the sphere embedding of the
entire set of points onto the line
the lowest dimensional space that we can think of
OK the one-dimensional space so we met them to y one through y and
and what little as united maps is trying to do is is trying to preserve
to co-occur together and if you actually apply this on models like latent Dirichlet
allocation as they've applied Tom Griffiths et al have done then you find that
the topics are kind of look quite nice so this is a topic and is basically
a genetics type of topics or maybe is actually more a population genetics type of topic this is another topic
which is kind of like genetics except that it has talks more about genetics and
evolution and natural selection and so forth so it's somewhat different topic
this is I guess this are topics analyzed from data set of articles scientific
articles that is kind of dominated by biological articles that's what you get this
lots of topics that are more biological in nature okay so here's another topic where has to
do with the infectious diseases and so forth and finally here we have a
computer science type of topic so the nice thing with this topic models is that you could kind of
use these topics to kind of summarize a very large a collection of documents
to have an idea of what the documents are about you using this topics
you can do things like you know measure similarity between documents or maybe use it
to to browse the documents because it tells you how one document's related to
another by a share set of topics so latent Dirichlet allocation is this kind of
very standard model for topic modeling and it basically models each document as a mixture
model and each mixture component is basically gonna be a topic which is gonna
be interpreted now as a distribution over words that tend to co-occur together so
the model is as follows so for every document J we're gonna have a distribution
over topics and that distribution over topics is gonna be given a Dirichlet prior
and it's a distribution over topics in the sense that it tells you how much
of the document is gonna come from topic one how much of the document is gonna come from
topic two topic three an and so forth so if the cross bonding entry of
phi J is small for a particular topic that just says that that topic won't be exhibited
in that document much and then for every topic indexed by K we're gonna have
a parameter that describes the distribution over words for that topic and again we're gonna
give a Dirichlet prior over this this parameter it's symmetric Dirichlet where beta is another
half a parameter of the model and W here is the total number of words in
the total number of distinct words in the document corpus and now the generative
process basically goes as follows for word I in document J we're gonna first determine in
which topic that word belongs to by sampling from a discrete distribution with parameters phi
J and then we can decide which word this the Ith word is by sampling from
the distribution given by the corresponding topic and the graphical model for LD basically looks
like this so we have plate over topics so that says that that part is replicated
K times for the K different topics one's for every topic we have a kind of nest
that set of plates here where the outer plate corresponds to documents and for every
document we have a distribution of our topics and then we have a set of words and
we assume that all the word are IID in there and for every word we sample the topic
and then we sample the world itself so that's the graphical model so one of the questions that
you might have will be you know how many topics can we find in the
corpus okay can we somehow infer this number of topics automatically from a data set
given that we've learned all about Dirichlet processes now and we can take I mean we
can derive a Dirichlet process as the infinite limit of finite mixture models we can
imagine that maybe we can just take this model and take K to go to
infinity and see whether that model works turns out it doesn't work the reason is because are
the following so if we take K goes to infinity you end up
basically because every document is a mixture model right as K goes to infinity we
are gonna end up with one Dirichlet process for every document and that Dirichlet process's
gonna describe both the distribution over topics as well as the topics exhibit as well as the
parameters of the topics in that documents or for that documents and the base distribution here
H is gonna be the prior distribution over the parameters which is this Dirichlet distribution
which is kind of a smooth distribution and what happens is that if you use
if you take K to to go to infinity then the model that you get
is gonna be like this where basically we have one Dirichlet process mixture model
for one document and a second one for the second document third one for the third
document and so forth and you notice that there are no arrows that goes from one document
to the other and that's kind of a problem because if you don't have arrows
linking from one document to the other than there's no dependence between the documents so
that's kind of no sharing of information between the documents and given that topics are basically you know things
which are shared across all documents that kind of says that this model won't really
produced topics for you another way in which you could look at this is because
is the following so we know that our base distribution is smooth because our Dirichlet
is prior this Dirichlet prior here is has a density so this is
smooth distribution so we have a smooth bayes distribution if we sample G one from a
DP with that bayes distribution and G two from independently from the same DP then
we will get two sets of atoms right where the locations of the atoms are
drawn IID from the bayes distribution now if the bayes distribution's smooth then this this
set of atoms will not overlap with that set of atoms at all so given
then as we see infinitely many data points
we can't we can't put a maximum dimension on on the size of the parameter
and so we have to use an infinite dimensional space
so a nonparametric model and this is not only true in in bayesian modeling pretty much in general
one way to define a nonparametric models say that a statistical model
which has an infinite dimensional parameter space
so here's an example
simple density estimation example
and this is not bayesian example is just standard parametric and nonparametric statistics
so in both cases we're going to be estimated
using a gas in distribution but we're going to use the girls in distribution in two different ways
so here we have a bunch of data points
doing making parametric assumptions and say okay the data is generated by about two dimensional girls in distribution
so we fit in the gaussians and say with maximum likelihood
we get this
we get this picture here and
you see if if if there's more data coming in that may change that may
change our estimate of the parameter but it doesn't change the dimensionality of the parameter
right it's just
two dimensional location parameter and
two by two covariance matrix
it here this is the winnow passing window type estimator
so what we're doing here each time we see data point
six calcium with a fixed could be taken down with a fixed covariance matrix
put the scales and at the location
of the data point and so we're setting the mean parameter of the girls into
the location of the data points
and we do that for every data point
and then we
we normalize we add up these densities and normalize
okay so basically what we're doing is we're using
you can think of this smoothing
we're doing a convolution with a gaussian kernel and that way we smooth the data
the data is is a bunch of spikes
sharp spikes and we smooth with a gas can
and the density estimator get that way
it's called a parzen window estimator
all right so you can see that in this case
we get
one additional location parameter for each data point that we see the number of data points increases
as the number of data points increases the dimension of the parameter space increase
so to accommodate this unbounded number of parameters unbounded number of primitive dimensions we dimensions
right now if you want to be bayesian about it
if we want to put a prior distribution on the
what we have to do is we have to put a prior distribution on infinite
dimensional space and that's a nonparametric bayesian model yeah so the definition
that we're going to use your nonparametric bayesian model is a nonparametric bayesian model is
a bayesian model on infinite dimensional parameter space
thank you so far
and the interpretation
the interpretation here is that
the parameter space
one useful way i think to interpret this is the parameter space is the set of possible patterns
that we
that we assume can explain the data
and so in these density estimation example that we just saw
the set of possible patterns would be
a set of probability distributions right are set of density
precisely because we're doing density estimation
for doing regression so that the example on the first slide
then the pattern would be
a smooth function
and if we do clustering
which we're going to talk about
most the time today
then this pattern here that explains the data is is a partition
partition of the data into separate clusters
the solution we are looking far
is not in individual pattern
but the distribution over these patterns namely the posterior distribution so we start with a
prior guess how his parents are distributed we add in what the data look it
looks like
and then we compute the conditional distribution of the parameters given the data of this pattern
given the data and say okay this pair is more probable and this one is less probable
that's that's a solution that would ideally like to
and i have to say a few words about exchangeability i'm going to to get back to this tomorrow but
we will already be it will already come up several times today
and so that
the question we ask is
we made this we are making this assumption that the data
in some sense ten plus noise
and this is really crucial to what we doing forty fought
different several different reasons one reason is
that if
this this noise market this is correlated
then it's really hard to do inference it's really hard to estimate what the parents
but there's another like and a bit more
fundamental reason basically which is
what we really want to do is we want say there is something that the
data have the data points have in common
and then there's something that's just randomness and we would like to extract the common
part because it is useful information
right and then we would like to throw away the rest
that's exactly this assumption this is what the data points here
and this is the rest that we would like to throw away
so what we have to ask is in in which case is this assumption here justifiable
it turns out that there's a very sharp characterisation and precise sharp characterization of when we can justify this assumption
based theorem which you've seen
incidents intellectually
this is this is encoded in the bayes equation in this
factorial here
and so this is the basic equation here's a prior distribution
the parameter
up here the of exchange given theta
is the likelihood of the data point number jay given the parameter
this see evidence term and then we have the posterior distribution of the parameters given the data
and you can see that here they are
the likelihood over all data points as a product
and this product says
a product over distributions always expresses independence
right so
these data points are independent of each other
but given
the parameter values
and this is called conditional independence
so conditional independence in general probability simply means we have a bunch of random variables
in this case the random variables x
and they are conditionally independent given theta if
they are independent
provided that we know the value of theta
and the intuition behind that is
these these random variables contain information about each other
but all that information is summarized in figure so if we know theta then
knowing some of the random variables one tell us anything about the
that conditional independence
so this here is the conditional independence assumption
and that's exactly what what we have here we basically so we can rephrase this question and ask
under what conditions can be make such a conditional independence assumption for forty
and if we look back at the
at the picture on the first slide with and then we also see this conditional independence assumption in there
which is in this case
the red line is the feeder right
and then the data points scattered around that independently so if we know
the location of the red line
we will see how this is done
o if we don't want to
provide the label
we can also try to induce
regression trees
out of the data here again that would be nematic
attributes involved and here we would have a prediction which will be the average value
for subset of customers which are described with certain attributes values
so far more realistic case
let's say regression tree for brief predicting algal biomass which was done in one of
our application applications so
then you would have a prediction of a certain value of
the biomass and you would have the deviation plus-minus this deviation around this
average fat
OK so this will be regression trees
but to in this course we really
mostly interested in the
classification decision trees
and we will see how this is done
so in your course materials you have
chapter on
decision tree induction
who have you can read more about it
so let's look at a certain
example again we have
we have fourteen training examples described again by
one two three four
attributes now the classification task is to classify
people in two guys who would go and play tennis depending on the weather conditions
and those who will decide not to go
to play tennis if for instance the wind is strong give high those high humidity
if there is hot temperature so this guy didn't go to to play tennis whereas
with the weak wind and overcast
whether the person decided to go to play tennis so based on the data we
have fourteen examples we will try to induce the decision tree which will predict whether
we should go and play tennis or not so here we have is a different
situation we here again have the most informative activity but based on the three possible
values of the attributes the
set of all the
tennis players is divided into three subsets
and here again
all the players decided to go play tennis if the weather was overcast
and if we
become acquainted with the terminology which is used in decision tree learning
we call these
internal nodes
and these are the attributes names
each branch corresponds to an attribute value
like a wind sock week
each class is a conjunction of attribute twelve years that this is the
his rain wind is strong that this one pass in the decision tree
the terminal nodes and they
assign a classification
if all took is sunny and humidity is high then you know tens today
and we can describe this also in the form of it's the disjunction of conjunctions
this whole model so if focus on and humidity is normal
of course any and humidity normally
then this leads us to the class yes
outlook is overcast leads us to the last yes
if alpha Q's rainy
and the wind is we yes so for each class we could have such a
disjunctive description consisting of a conjunction of attribute values
so this is that the
equivalent representation for class yes and then four class no we could also
transform the decision tree into an equivalent representation
what next to it
this is the situation here
he was and messages
i mean actually query then the next with
his stories are that is what
so the key insight even the naive approach with the query from scratch needs to
compute in messages from one one part for per all n variables there only two
n possible messages
every time i run the procedure after as the message from this so that any
so i mean naively wanted to
for every night
i would have to do in queries
each one people entities
the query messages
but if you think about it
the only two thousand messages there's only
no no
this way or the other
i can compute all possible messages that could ever create history in only twice the
amount of work which was over
so that's the idea
i seem to be forgetting to query i compute all two n possible messages so
messages go this one is
instantaneous we want to know
where i just think about it
route ninety all messages to look into the black hole
even though they are in this area were doing that
only two possible graph can be all those
it only twice network routing
an interesting properties wrote messages
so this approach is used
condition whatever happens experience
you compute all messages
and this is what
and then you really all the queries
what one is going that we're not pretending that he was group
product all the messages coming that
the reason for this usually better
any questions
if you have seen before
and you say i then
and john
so if you haven't seen this before
experiences in february and say these things
so how many of you have
OK so this is the key insight here if i need to query a bunch
nodes in the the tree
i don't have to do that would be to reduce query over
so the only thing we need here is coming from here
all messages efficiently and still get the right
so what i want to compute the messages here i assume that we're working from
the leaves to root
but now we're trying to use the route so
can you make sure you get all this is correct and he is that
it was found the following message passing protocol
you always complete to messages can
messages to nature
only when it is you that is always the first
so this
protocol guarantees about the
messages will be
correct he but
take the product of all incoming messages
in with your potential function is you
some these tasks
so what you see
this is from all neighbours
it may be passed on to so
this is because otherwise you just to make one arbitrarily group and collect messages inward
on the back
this is not a strong
this schedule
by which she decides to compute all the messages in the tree
has nothing to do with
the decision which will eventually make query language
i can have message
on the street where designed for the purpose of computing messages
this is be true
and i'm going to compute messages by passing towards the through the first and then
passing messages always
in the world such general p can be written in this way
let's call this submanifold as rule rule find
he the
this feature is the natural parameters speak of that function then we can construct
the conjugate point that these functions
where all away with this
at the
calculated in this way
it just so these that i said nothing more than just cut the expectation parameters
this is a formal generalization of the embedding really just it reduces to the
rank the diffusion of embedding when whirlwind tall
i take this embedding functions as shown earlier
now these for the simplest case of course we just
he wrote to
so in this case of the log linear model the exponential family
expect change from from this just simply just the usual formula c
now with this
find family rule finds manifold we can show
is that
the following
this function the fee
which is the integral of this
of this rule
and the people
this is
the potential function this is the generating function
partition function
strictly convex can shown to be strictly convex
there is a strictly convex function
the rule is
strictly monotone functions strictly monotone functions of these absolute value strictly convex
and we can also show that
we can construct this
feature killed and then see stars
which is the
two conjugate function
and this is called the generalized entropy function
just entropy function is constructed by first constructing the poor representation of this
and then
the prediction is remembered that involves the projection of the
the original function into a subspace which is given by this the basis functions
so in this case
it is immediately
evidence that this rule find some manifold is the for patients it has to manifold
so we have constructed
prima try subspace
of the
space function such that it has this nice offer hashing property
so any role find some manifold is of operation
as applications for this framework let's look at say the embeddings now
so really to this is we have to all we have to
generalized divergence functions
originally divergence function b
which has both an f
and a rule right so if we chose f rho two beta off embedding
we have a two parameter family two problem with respect to so both five
OK so have a two parameter family hit rate is really the embedding function in
the parameters it was traditionally called off but in this case
when we want to differentiate between
that and the fact that we use in the convex set in convex analysis that
we call it they saw
now we define a two parameter family of divergence functions
and this is
in this it's
extension of this is proper
that was given in the the classical literature involving challenge
it works out
in the following way when i saw the problem is the from the effects the
reference twenty three when you have two months after is exchange of the reference point
was they represents a conjugate dwightcollins country twenty
you faculty to minus one
then these tools from the family of the function
it's exactly the the divergence where you used to be the minds but i promise
as it
what is called the divergence
and the same is true of other good plus one
it used to beat parameter as its so called for prompt into other which is
not the same is true if
you used to be if you like to be able to
years many different you let me to go to war it also has this so
it reduces to for the full problem but when be able to negative ones
it is the
jensen differences
so this image breaks
so when you got to know what this talk part of the family coaster to
the chance difference
to just different
in the remaining say
five minute also with the top very quickly on this image on jonathan space so
we have constructed a very general
divergence functional on the space and we can use the same trick in which she
used to construct
among in metric and to find connection to have connection on these this entire offer
family of functions and all the condition is a bit lengthy and involved some interesting
trips because you have working with no functions in dimensional space and the tangent vectors
diffuse and you will need to be very carefully thought out and forth but eventually
you to finish the derivation you have this is the general form of the fisher
information in information space with the using these are the tangent vector fields
the other functions as well
the functions as well
the functions of
the sample space i mean the function of it's the associating a function of sample
space with each point with each density functions on the manifold
so that that's what is
this change takes this also so it by you the this is what's required of
a metric space in you in but you have to change
she is defined is given by
if the second derivative of f in the world and so so for that you
have this
five connection which is given by this b b is defined by this bunch of
stuff now we can write it out very in symmetric form which then become like
nice when you look at this one
so it turns out that she is just tall
prime n real problem
and is basically this derivative of this
OK so it immediately becomes very tool is symmetric symmetric
to check out that this actually exactly reduces to the classic form of
contrary connections and we have to win all so if we let this
minimizing linear function called convex
non linear function of x subject to convex inequality constraints and
linear equality constraint
so convexity means that the function f here and i satisfy this inequality
if you apply if i two and convex combination of two vectors x y linear
combination of weights negative traits add up to one
then you always get the function value that's less than the same weight it
some of the two function the point
so if f satisfies the inequality for convex functions
and equality constraints to be linear
and linear programming these creatures are actually special cases
so if you go back to the same properties that we can say again there's
no analytical solution the case for linear programming
but it can be solved reliably and efficiently find the global optimum
software is not as well developed as for linear programming but there's a lot of
development currently and this
several software packages matlab and c and python
and also more and more free software for solving complex optimization problems
and the computation time is again polynomial
the more complicated expressions of the cost is exactly because it also depends on the
validating the function values
and derivatives
but you get a similar bound for linear programming
and again if you try to apply a convex optimisation problem so we propose practical
problem we're interested in
posing practical problem is a convex optimisation problem
then one thing we noticed immediately is that there are very there are more difficult
to recognise and linear programming or disperse problems
people have many more possible transformations techniques to
formerly minutes
he formerly problems into context or
but also once you start looking into applying convex optimisation practice you find many more
problems than you would think first sight
so that's what we call modelling formulating a practical problem as a convex optimization problem
some short history so the history of apply numerical computations are then forwarded to the
development of the simplex method for
linear programming formulation of linear programming
in around and the simplex method forty seven
i started to extend linear programming but at very efficient method for solving linear programming
problems in the simplex method
then the first and most obvious point that started to generalize the programming of the
constraint on the cost function with place linear function with the product function
he kept the linear inequality constraints
it's called quadratic programming
then you would have expected more than people have continued like this if he could
make the linear constraint functions quadratic and look at other extensions
but they didn't really happen in that they so there is another
extension of linear programming is called genetic programming
around the end of the nineteen sixties and we'll discuss it a little bit in
the second lecture
first from the next include linear programming as a special case but is actually more
nonlinear convex problems
and then nothing happened until the beginning of the nineties
and at at the beginning of the nineties we saw got a big explosion of
in this area
formerly many different more general classes of convex optimization problems that know semidefinite programming second-order
cone programming
what i think you pratically constrained quadratic programming this problem and also the constraints
but other sanctions robust optimisation and many other topics
so that's one thing you notice if you look at the history that this really
started the nineteen nineties
one development picked up around nineteen ninety
four years ago
at the research which is
and i want to have this
specific part has
i don't have to
most of the time
one of the material for
apart from likely to develop with our customers i want to
what we have covered
so this whole thing is all that kind of
so much
so basically it can be done in one
it has to be done at the interface the
what the past
one the
and another example of home page
we invented
recall that for most
one five
and then for that also has got professional competences
which is one of the reasons why it's so difficult to work
as a better world
and for any of these properties
because right but the power of the input
what find the very expensive for so we had to put
and and
the same ship
because we also have an incredibly good attention
however all
of the rest of her life because it's all about
the market
and so on
the best of all firefighters
it's the best
but if i have time to check so
the developers are already market i could
the story is that somebody said you know what to do
so why
this is a problem
four miles from
whole host of conflict was the sort of evolution hold
so tried to
and we're trying to do this requires that were like also
one of the places
the first one
this is the kind of software this is because the whole point
one of the reasons one
distortions distorted like this invariances with the great decay very fast
so here is something else maybe lv maybe someone
and let's say that
this is the
number of clusters
i'm trying
lower numbers in the lower the cost will be categories
there are two different situations when i have too few clusters then
suppose that the true clusters three class
if i use two clusters that i'm going to have a cluster of large variance
in one small in the and then when i jumped from two to three
suddenly the is jump from
this value
to this
so i'm going to have large jumps
down to the true to the two cases so
thank you go
like this
on the twenty four clusters then typically have two centers you
and if i put five maybe i have something like this so know what i'm
doing is i suppose
filling the space in the basement the dalai with more and more sensors
this is called quantization when actually just putting the somewhere to be
so it's very different regime and then
there is actually some or predicting how
this cost degrees asymptotically if i add more and more points
but it's not in there is no large because i'm just taking a few points
from the centre and then in another
and so the the k will be
much slower
and so one intuitive we're looking for the true number of clusters is to look
the need the for
but of course i have a lot of firms with a lot of nice
if there is a lot of variation so you can see when you here
but what exactly the is is very hard to describe by a bicycle for so
that you can put into in a computer program
in many cases
this is one of these people do this by
looking at the german so
a lot of time means that
i'm approaching the talk
the prime here in this site
and this is not going to look for the decision but
they found that this jumps larger and this jump the jump stroke progressively decrease and
look for the largest shown that is to the next
this quite better motivated despite is less less lamont
OK i will stop for course four minutes for questions here
just to let me just the moral don't think every algorithm that competes at face
value yes i think what you could use what's useful and could be useful algorithm
what you could change and improve because sometimes you can make it
that's what another reason i presented
OK let's see if there questions
i look at another set of methods for choosing k
which are completely different
and that justified intuitively and in
but they
also people have tried and they seem to
to work well in experiments they're called stability that
so what is the idea
the idea is that if are going to find structure in data
if you change if you only a few points then you should still be able
to find the same structure so the high-level nothing should change
and so everything that's not every algorithm not stable to small perturbations of the data
should be suspected mean
it can be used for the problem or it results can be interpreted
because they are too sensitive to changes in the
and so
well this is a very alike is incontestable two i think
these methods use the converse which may not be true which is you find something
stable it needed a flat structure in the
so what they do the following
you have a data set
you better
you the clustering on the other clustering on the first day that says and then
you compare the two
and sorry
i think the micro is
OK so the question was whether the
really changes because it's
a stream of data like the industry
stream of news or for dynamic system
and the question is a bit of very simple answer is that they assume that