and these direct direct sum of four
one dimensional algebras
and this
you can obtain by violating the ball in every polynomial belongs here
in two
roots of that is in the elements of the spectrum
OK so this is a well-defined is an isomorphism
and in the set of in the case of x minus on this is exactly
the discrete fourier transform
that is the matrix representation
in general i mean for
arbitrary polynomial with discrete
but with distinct
it's a vandermonde
which is exactly fifty
of and for our example
but this implies that we can afford to computed using order looks square and algorithms
and this is a very good news for
for computation
OK so
all this means is that finding transforms
that approach the two time for a transform
as n goes to infinity reduces to polynomial find polynomial families was set of fruits
approach the unit circle
our goal now becomes to find such families of polynomials
and we have first define what is done
a set of rules for family point so if you have a fine opening hours
with degrees
with increasing biggest for the of the degree and
and then some
complex number is a limit of zeros for this family if there is a sequence
of complex elements so that
they are the roots of
polynomial in this family
and their limit
is exactly easy
so how should we do this
i'll just state our main result
namely if we define
the family of polynomials
it looks like this
we can characterize exactly
all the limits of zeros for this family one units and namely
they are all the points on the unit circle
and they are all the points inside the unit circle that our roots
of the
free term here
and all the points outside the unit circle the roots of the
it's quite efficient of the dominant term here is some
so what does
all of these polynomials actually look like
and we could just to see them
in the order of the
our ex
and we can see that we can cluster
the equations corresponding to the nonzero coefficients corresponding to these
polynomial is here
we only imposed a condition that the first cluster and the last cluster is nonzero
the others could be zero but the
the all lie on these equally spaced locations
we can even go further and make a polynomial family that
was degrees
increases by one every time as opposed to viki we're here
i'm not going to be those what essentially it's the trivial application here
and how do we actually get to prove this result how do we
you get to prove that
a limit of zeros for this family
is exactly what they say it is will use the alcohol advice here
OK this is the result
from the seventies
and before stating that
here we need a few preliminary so for family of polynomials satisfy this
linear recurrence where these
coefficients are constant
its characteristic equation
like this
of course
each value of x
this equation will have some fruits lambda one
lambda n
the roots are distinct for some values then obviously we can write
we can write the general term of the sequence
like this using some
polynomials that depend on x and the roots
and part of course if they are some rules that are equal you could do
the same tricks that you do four
linear recurrences with numbers not only
and we can find
we can find these polynomials of
in the usual way by letting
and going from zero to
and minus one and this uniquely
produces these these quotations
the degeneracy conditions that
sweep under the rug here but we actually don't need them
but the theorem does
are that m is the smallest degree
over any linear recurrence that this family satisfies
we've seen them it how that influences our results
and we don't want to have the situation that
two of these
routes to these functions only differ by multiplicative constant for all values of x so
we don't want to fight
OK other than that
with all the conditions stated above that is the limit of zero for
the one norm your family
if and only if
there exist an ordering of the characteristic roots
such that one of these two
mutually exclusive conditions that it satisfies namely
one of the roots is strictly larger than all of the others
the is the root of the polynomial
the coefficients corresponding to this route
there exist at least
two routes that are equal in absolute value
and maximum in a value
and these are all the
this is a lecture six linear algebra
we're at the start of this new chapter
chapter three in the text
which is really getting to the
centre of linear algebra
i had time to make
first started on the at the end of lecture five
but now i would like to say
r is officially the lecture on vector spaces and subspaces
and then especially
there are two
back to some place that were especially interested in
one is the column space of a matrix
the other is the null space of the matrix
i got to tell you what those are
first to remember from lecture five
what is the vector space
it's a bunch of actors
where i'm allowed where i can and i can add any two two vectors
in this space
and the answer is there is in this space
or i can multiply any vector in the space by any constant
and the result stays in this space
so that in fact if i combine those two into one
you can see that if i could have and i can multiply by by numbers
that really means that i can take a linear combination
so the quick way to say it is that all
linear combinations the
any multiple of the
any multiple of w stay in this space
so can i give you examples that are vector spaces
and also some examples that are not
to make that point clear
so suppose i'm in
three dimensions
then one way to get this one
one is the whole three-dimensional space
so the whole space are three
three-dimensional space
it would be an vector space because if i have a couple of actors i
can add them and i'm certainly OK and they follow all the rules
so are free is easy
i'm interested also in
some space
there the words some space
that's space that some vectors inside
the given space inside or three
still make up the vector space of their of their own the vector space inside
the vector space
and the simplest example was applied soap
can i just get there
there is a plane
it's got to go through the origin
and of course it goes infinitely far
that that's the subspace now
you see that if i have
two vectors on the plane
and i have done the results they
in the play
if i take an vector in the plane and i multiplied by minus two
i'm still in the plane
so that claim is the subspace
so let me just make that point
through zero
prove that their own zero zero
in of
and also
another subspace would be aligned
o line through zero zeros of the line have to go through the origin all
subspaces of god contain the origin contains zero zero
so this line
in the summer
why is a sum
really if i
i want really correctly i should say
a subspace of
are three
i that of our three was like understood
now so let me call this plane p
let me call this line l
let me ask you
other set other sets of vectors
suppose i took
so here's the first question suppose i take two subspaces
like pnl
and i just put them together
take their union
take all the vectors
so now i
you've got pnl in mind here
i have
two subspaces
and for example
a plane ally
i want to ask you about
the union of all
the union bound
this is all vector
or but
is that a subspace
is this the substrate
or not
because when i just want to be sure
and i've got
central idea
suppose i take the vectors in the plane
the vectors on line
put them together
so i've got a bunch of actors is the subspace can you give me like
so the camera can hear it or maybe
the tape
can you say yes or no
do i have a subspace if i put
if i take
all right
you on the plane y for all and all the ones on the line
and the
so join them together but i'm not taking this guy
actually i'm not taking most of them because most vectors are
not on the line or a plane their of tomorrow
do i have a subspace
right thank you know
because why not because i can because if i
that that requirement isn't satisfied
w is independent of fx the dispersion of w doesn't depend on how ai intervene
whether intervene so this is a constant
i do better
because can
OK so so it's nice linear regression
and b and b it is the coefficient of x and it's causal regression coefficient
in the sense that these models
how the expected value y
varies with an applied
the value of models learning x arise around the user going in setting it and
that's an interesting thing to know about
and it will be lovely to learn about it
it's cause it it has causal meaning if i could believe this story and the
linear regression
problem is that can actually are estimated from observational data just like that and you
can see why because
if i take in the observation regime if i do this then i get the
expected this term becomes explaination that if w given x little x in the observation
regime and that correlated in the observation regime so it probably depends on x and
therefore i can't extricated from this to
so i'm in trouble if all of observing x y and observation regime not suppose
i'm not just going to be able to observe w but there's something else i
can say so let's add to the story there is another variable z
that has the properties first of all
it's sort of something which is closely associated with x which is why the cause
i care about and it doesn't depend it's supposed to be
out there it doesn't depend on which freedom regime and talking about those of pre
treatment variable if you like a cup example shortly and
and let's suppose that i can believe is independent of all these things which are
getting in my way so something sort from outside which is quite independently only
influence it has israel association works
and also other missing arrows this matter here says it doesn't affect even if i
tell you z is this ritual y given everything else is still that modular components
linear regression if you like so
is still why only depends on w and x so is it is an instrument
and if you could intervene in z which may or may not be the case
you could actually maybe try and which affect the value x
possibly in a heavy-handed way you could is not the same as going infecting itself
influencing is stochastically
and if you work through the analysis with all those additional assumptions find defined this
so i go through the details but you've
here's somebody could estimate from data you can observe what so we observing z although
not yet so they been observed the expectation y given
the observed values that do that so this is something estimate
and here is the same thing with x and say this is something estimable from
these in the observation regime
you might build linear models for both these responses and then that's nice and easy
you could more generally an important point to notice is that here is an equation
relating possible quality quantities these two functions of z
and they had this linear relationship
and there's this constant beta which comes in there and if only these things are
trivial enough
you can estimate beta particularly in the case where these have linear regressions then beta
is just the ratio of the two regression coefficients which is the standard econometrics instrumental
variable form
so that's made by the columns of what i want but i observe something else
and getting in trouble
get beta
rather heavily on the linear regression assumption that you got problems without it so the
binary case for example you can't actually estimate the causal effect exactly
what you can typically do is get bounds upper and lower bounds on the average
that had a 1 in the free variables or 0 1 and 0 and the
free variables and then we filled in define the others
I forgot what they were but maybe it was that
that was a special solution and then there was another special solutions that had that
free variables 0 and this free variable equal 1
and I have to fill those in
that's c can I remember how those filling and maybe this was a minus 2
and this was that 2 possibly
I think probably that's right
I'm not yet
2 room
the criteria
I would have to remember what are my equations
that's a tonight rather than go way back to that board that we remember the
1st equation was to X 3 + 2 x 4
equaling 0 now
because I'm looking for the guys in the null space
so I said x 4 to be 1
and the 2nd equation that I didn't propaganda minus 2 for the 1st and then
yeah so I think that's right
minus 4
and to give 0
OK those with the special solution
what we do to get the complete solution
how do I get the complete solution now I multiply this by anything
the ones say
and I multiply this by anything I take any combination
you remember that's how we describe the null space
the null space consists of all combinations
of so this is x
all combinations of the special solution
there were 2
special solutions because there were 2 free variables
and we want to make that count is complete
that carefully now
but just while I'm up here so there's that's what that that's the kind of
answer I'm looking for is a a constant multiplying this guy
is 0 free constant that multiplies expert taking
no way
right x particular solves
a x 3 will be I'm not allowed to multiply that by 3
but a x and I'm allowed to multiply xn by 3
or add to another
because I keep getting 0 on the right
OK so
so again XP is 1 particular x and a whole subspace
right is 1 guy + + anything from a subspace
let me draw
but because try
I want to draw
I monograph all this graph that I want I want to plot all solutions
X so what dimension
this is an unfortunate point
how many components is X for the for unknown so I have to draw up
a four-dimensional
picture on this cheap blackboard OK so
here we go X 1
Einstein could do it but the
is is that those
representing 4 dimensional space
where are my solutions
do my solution form subspace
don't do does the set of solutions to a x will be former subspace no
what is it actually look like the subspaces in this picture
this part of the subspace right
that something like 2 dimensional because I get to parameters so it's I'm thinking of
this null space as to low-dimensional subspaces inside our 4
now I have to tell you and will tell you put next time what does
it mean to say subspace what's the dimension of a subspace but you see what
it's gonna be
it's the number of
independent constant so we can choose
so somehow there be a 2 dimensional subspace
not aligned and not a three-dimensional
playing but only to a low-dimensional guide but it doesn't go through the origin
because it goes through this point so there's x particular X particularly somewhere here x
particularly so it's somehow as subspace and I try to draw that way
it's a two-dimensional subspaces that goes through x particulars
and then onwards by so there that particular and I added on X and and
OK let me skip the the OEM part for parametric distributional clustering and just show
you on that image that you have already seen before
how how you you will find solutions at different temperatures at very high temperature you
basically get this sort of these these salt and pepper type image you have six
different colors in here and you see it's basically a random choice which of these
colours you select you lower the temperature a little bit and the most dominant structure
according to your cost function start to appear
so here you get sort of for condensation of grey values in that area and
in that area and these if you remember these are the black parents in the
in the in the landsat the image and the black parts are coming from from
the is not in the lede sentences into the aperture radar image and he comes
from the radar shadow
you go down and all of a sudden small structures appear
you still have a mixture between yellow and blue here and between two
blue and you go further down
and at the end
at the end you basically get this type of of picture we have now much
better solutions than that but i only have to meet you in this in this
presentation format here from from that image
you have the same form only on what is plotted here for different temperatures it's
the kullback leibler divergence to the mean histogram so if i if i do the
same thing in histogram space i have to somehow characterize my different solutions and it's
it's it's i do that by plotting by plotting the
the the the the prototypical histogram for one of the segments by basically plugging the
distance of support to histogram to the mean histogram
and you get this abrupt changes in solution space which basically give you these these
these these splits
let me not going to that because i was too much time you can use
a multiscale approach for it
i guess have five minutes
yeah because we start a little bit late but i don't want to go in
the negotiation phase after one and a half hours it's usually
we have already
OK the third part i think is is inherently connected to the generalization issue basically
how many clusters do i have up to now i used his magic number k
as an input somebody told me how many clusters i have to use ideally i
would say well maybe i know an upper bound on the number of clusters but
please if if if it happened to be
an image where two of my envisioned clusters cannot be separated on the basis of
the data are you know the algorithm should figure out by itself that rather than
ten which is the maximum number of clusters in applica occasion i should only use
and then discard in some way on all of the the the the of the
other segments so that's the cluster validation problem and there are a couple of approaches
to it
the most prominent ones are by his son and insurance this is the minimum description
and think of the subspace as being the circulation subspace
o of the corresponding graph
then this problem becomes
find the circulation within the graph that minimizes the sum of our course
it's a classical problem
then we have a block separable problems
with linear constraints
special case of linear programming quadratic programming just about any separable problem with convex cost
in linear constraints maps into this
let me also mention that even though we have a subspace constrained here
i can easily change that too
a late general linear constraints simply by translation argument so
this is not any any loss in generality ballistic the constraints to be a subspace
the next special case is the french duality framework
now here there are only two terms
and the subspace has this form here
this the coupling between the axis they have to be
the second component has to be a linear transformation of the of the first
and then the of the experiment of programming problem
reduces to this one which is the classical form of french about perhaps you have
seen it with you it was to be identity here it's just a small extension
spencer duality has become very popular these days because of a special case in conic
semidefinite programming second order programming all of these
are special cases of fenchel duality where one of these functions is the indicator function
of the car
is the
the the
right to the the
indicator function course
OK the case of some of functions which i mentioned in connection with machine learning
one of the components correspond to batches of data
notice that this is different than this because here i have a dependence
on the vector x before vector x in here i have a dependence on the
other components
however by introducing a subspace of this form were all the components are equal
then this problem
with this subspace becomes this
so some of functions are special cases in there may be some additional constraints here
note also that fact extended real valued
they may embody constraints themselves
now the dual problem to this it turns out to be
very semantically identical just the FZI placed by the conjugate into the subspaces replaced by
so far in the derivation of this i don't want to go into details but
it's very simple
what we do is we convert the problem into an equivalent problem by introducing some
o valuables z
zeid which we make equal to x y
now this defines
linear constraints to which we can assign the lagrange multipliers
four milligrams in
and then minimize over x and z
and then after you do that
you obtain
this dual function
of y of the lagrange multipliers
but now you exploit separability here
so the macs the minimisation
breaks down into components and then
what comes out of the conjugate
of the of ice
and and also there's a subspace constraint coming from the inner product here the unconstrained
optimisation with respect to the
so that's the dual problem
there's also a sign change for the optimal value of this is minus the optimal
value of the people there
an impressive sight
so these are the two problems and
now let me mention
duality conditions i mentioned earlier the rockefellers condition are very powerful for the case of
component is one-dimensional
nine components multidimensional
the optimality conditions are not quite as strong but still there are fairly strong
and is a certain vector some conditions which is in my paper which involves something
called the epsilon subdifferential
of this
function here
air flows and causes things to change
and then there's another thing which is
the sciences and and engineering which i'm going to talk about under the heading of
so let me
let me explain this
i don't want to belabor it because i just in doing this in order to
introduce you to the ideas on your problems that which is the first
OK so this so on problem set one
you have an example which is based on a simplified model of gps
sort the flat earth model
in that situation wealthy flats just horizontal line like this
and then you have a satellite
which is over here
preferably above
the earth
there there
the satellite is x knows exactly where the system
he knows exactly where the point directly below the satellite is so this point is
treated as known
i'm sitting here
with my little GPS device
i want to know where i am
and the way i locate where i and is i communicate with the satellites
by radio signals and i can measure the distance here which is called h
and then the system will compute this horizontal distance
which is
which is l
so in other words what is measured
so h measured
radio waves and rocks
various clocks
and then
l is deduced
from h
and what's critical in all of these systems is that you don't know age exactly
there's an error
in h
which will denote delta h there is some degree of uncertainty
the main uncertainty in GPS is
from the ionosphere
there are lots of corrections are made
of all kinds
and also if you're inside building it's a problem to measure but it's it's an
extremely important issue
there's all explained in a second
so the idea is we we then get
two the get delta l
is estimated
considering this ratio delta alpha delta h which is going to be approximately the same
the derivatives of l with respect to h
this is the thing that's easy because of course it's calculus
OK this is the easy part and that allows us to do something about the
real world
that's close by
over here
so the the reason why you should care about this quite a bit is that
it's it's used all the time to land airplanes
so you really do care that they actually know
two within a few feet or even closer
we're playing is and how high up it is and so forth
all right
so that that's it for the general introduction to what the derivative is i'm sure
you'll be getting used to this a lot of different contexts throughout the course
and now we have to get back down to
to some some
rigorous details
so everybody happy with what we've got so far
good question the question was how did i get this equation for height
i just
i made it up because it's the formula from physics
that you will learn when you take
in one
and it has to do with the fact that the in fact it has to
do with the fact that if you this is speed if you differentiate another time
yet acceleration and this is the acceleration due to gravity is ten meters per second
which happens to be the second derivative this but anyway i just pulled out of
the hat from your physics class
so you can just say
see know one
all right
other questions
right so let's let's go on now
now i have to be a little bit more systematic about limits
so let's see
let's do that now
so now i like to talk about is limit
and the continuity
this is a warm-up for deriving all the rest of the formulas
all the rest of the formulas and i'm going to need
to differentiate
every function you know remember that's our goal and we only have about a week
left so we better
let's start
so first of all
there's what i will call easy limit
so what's an easy limit
an easy limit is something like the limit
as x goes to o four
of x plus three over x squared plus one
with this kind of elements all have to do to evaluate it is to plug
so you can do this one at the time
no matter how the more these joint distributions are
you can take the
relative entropy but now the relative entropy condition
and that's my conditioning
it is so important when you
deal with any of these information measures so you take one
conditioned on all the others that you have already taken
OK so now let me go back to
and that intriguing
saying that the could glider divergence
the relative entropy generalizes shannon's definition of information
and winners information now let me just point out
now that i read these shannon's definition of information actually shadow
i mention that work in his paper in fact he did mention information theory
in in one place in his people but he never says anything about
this being a measure of information or never
even defines mutual information in his paper for one matter for of
for that matter
OK so
what both defined we know in china
who we have here in this picture
shall define the discrete entropy
and also these
what we call now differential entropy although he also calling entropy
winner also define these differential entropy about the same time also in nineteen forty eight
in the book
they became a big bestseller called cybernetics
and essentially winner the only the only reason he gave for defining it that way
was that OK for nine months
the told him that that thing was a good thing to look at
now this is from a from the next from a paper he wrote later
the shannon winner definition of quantity of information for it belongs to the two of
us equally
sharon was a little bit more circumspect circumspect about this definition
and then the mathematician that actually realise the first mathematician who realized that
what china had done was really revolutionary was andrey kolmogorov in the soviet union
and he he got it right and has no physical interpretation so
the first thing that one makes wine
or in you introduce this quantity is to take the logarithm of a probability density
and that's a big no-no
all right so when we took longer than up to now we always took longer
in terms of quantities that don't have
units so to speak
OK they were ratio of probabilities ratios of pts
or rather than weakening that even is in the most general case so you you
always have to think of the
of probability density functions as
being one over
meters or seconds or whatever your
you're underlying euclidean space means
so i
this is the kind of integral that should be
declared illegal
and the one that gives links to a lot of trouble
too many people that tend to use it
thinking that it satisfies the same properties as entropy
but then they run into trouble
why has this been so important in information theory
if you you could take the leading textbook in information theory
my comment almost to devote whole chapter to this well
essentially because
relative entropy
to come along time to get into information theory
even though
it was defined by collecting liebler only three years after short
it's been extremely slow
in in getting into the toolbox of information theorist so
that avoid essentially was taken by these
differential entropy
right and the main reason is this formula
the entropy
actually if you take the
relative entropy of
a given distribution with given mean and variance and due take the relative entropy with
respect to the gaussians distribution we use the same mean and the same variants that
of course is going to give you
number that will gatehouse
no model that distribution is
is you can write it as a constant
minus the differential entropy of px
right so this this is really one the reason why
these differential entropy now
important because this is important
and of course
it also says that this is what the winner
show the same time as shown
that among all distributions that have the same
the gaussians is the one that has the largest differential entropy
and that also
explains the rationale for the maximum entropy principle that again is quite
quite common in applications where OK we don't have enough information to say what
i distribution is
so we have some
information may be about the
the second moment of distribution
from observations and then we would like to actually from the bootstrap distribution so
a typical thing to do is you we say well
right and you can actually move these things that
and then look at
effects of
what that strategy does
now notice what's happening in the business user
we one of these programs moving around the dashboard
that result in an of operational strategy for
so it might say one
the very
i want to offer them nothing let him go
that would be in the room
because just like
it's not even more so the
now but could be also very
high value customers but the point is
you're moving along axes that was acquired in one right it's personal
just like i just left
this is just like
imagine things like engineering students have a very low value today they have very high
value euro two
by the probability of challenges again predict that this is a great example
embedded data mining
he doesn't even know what's happening in the background that is happening the background it's
working directly to solve this problem
you can do the same for banks you know we extend this to make it
the banks and so forth
going to city
the domain knowledge we all know data mining algorithms
pretty stupid
so much about
so how do you make them smaller
at the time trying to make more
is any i complete problems so you can engage in a project for ten twenty
years and that's all
or you can solve it very very well
that is the way
is by solving a very narrow problem where actually there is no more about the
then the human being with
here's an example of use
it's the case study from the mining DMX group
is process of selling right recommendation systems
so let's say this is actually what we do not
some of these people are
and they're on your site
and trying to evaluate different is aspects
if you follow statistics statistics value
and know much about this customers predicting
so something common access like about
what i don't know
is that first of all i was trying to decide
but i think the show is that
sounds very simple to
but not
because the
statistics say that there is probably more than the it's
they sure
they could be an upset be down depending on the strategies business because they want
to be
just spitting image that they want they don't sound just expensive stuff
that's a customer was
what's the best of the best
what is the statistics statistically based algorithm
statistics for i know this customer it's all about us
so much more
that's the worst thing you can do
because if you just
selected pants show another start asking yourself what was wrong with my choice is the
the wrong color maybe sort model them we think about the next thing you know
you're the best continually
but i think show the things that go along
so you get surfaces statistics
it's just another set of statistics that condition something different
even though the numbers
there are also sorts some contractual things you have to worry about here so
actually if you can show
shirts from different from competitor there's all sorts of things that you never think about
the phenomenon
and of course that when the checkout that's when you do that your statistics you're
imposed by
let me see if i can just pop the basket something
now what is different here
there's two things more mining and i challenge you to
one is the knowledge of these products for all these products are related to each
and two
business constraints
those more important and so is all the statistics you can go about this is
pragmatic grand for managing and maintaining models
channel five minutes here
this is a big deal
we spend a lot of energy trying to come up with new data mining models
what happens when you produce
what happens when six months old
what happens when you actually visit data generated is no longer there
how do you updated
i do maintain
i think data
dropping behind when you do the secession
i come back to you later tried to reverse engineer what
israeli israel palestinians obviously but i mean the stuff
the despondency about russian zyuganov are
what's the what's up this was still the war in yugoslavia and pedal hostage
crisis in peru if you remember from ninety five so this was the small cluster
it is one way how to present this high-level structure of such a collection then
if you would do mean then
so would get a little bit finer structure
this is about seems so it just seems instance
OK so this is one
quite classical way of
visualizing text
this team is also home
this picture in particular is very popular because it appears most of the books for
this is
probably it was most one many made the time
so this is analysis of castro speeches from nineteen sixty
two nineteen sixty one and so
so he had serious speeches and in different species he was using different vocabulary different
words and i think that this was then manually categorise and visualize how the frequency
of certain certain words is changing and then this was kind of
indicator that
certain thoughts were going on his hat and some of the things he was known
that he was not able to to be silent this is kind of musician how
to reverse engineer such information from some this species
types of physicians so this is critical dot com which some of you might know
so this is a visualisation of search results
so i a
around this i this
good work
so let's see if you type in
data mining
basically it performs just clustering or the result set
probably the using some
on the back end
we visualize the results that can connect to the most relevant clusters so
one of these methods which
mentioned before just nicely visualized flesh
and this will be also some kind of categorization topics
so this is one possible way
the other visualisation of
of search results is this site which
developed by
our guys which i shall now
which is also
see into sink so it's
this is temporary sites but so it appears likeable guy but actually it's not just
our proximity now
but if you type in the query so
and search
and we would get normal will results plus something here on the right
and what it happens so
again this our proxy takes all the
it performs clustering identifies
the main keywords so opera web services and object and now
and this is the region of all
well this rank
now if we move this
red dot
sorry let's say opera
ranking will change and it would be more like close to this concept of operations
of the soap opera of here would get all the hits which are related to
soap opera well let's see if you would move this two
something else this
happened is i think the general character of the slam problem as a graph estimation
problem is now very well understood i mean it now seems kind of so obvious
that you wonder why we didn't quite realize this
fifteen years ago but we did with resistor problem we applied the camel filter to
but of course the kalman filter is just one example of an algorithm of
solving you know the general
graph of the variables that you're interested in this learning problem so in this particular graph
yes the problems that the variables you want estimates are
the historical
positions of the camera or robot that moves through the world these are the axis here
hand the positions of these landmarks were able to observe in the world these otherwise
we can't directly observe is what we can observe these image measurements
so each of these image measurements is for instance the image position
of one image feature that we match an image
it depends on one position of the camera
and one landmark
so these are the things we want we have to
basically do inference on the on the grafters to solve for the x
otherwise so once you understand the more you know the general character of this problem
you realize this other algorithms that can filter
that you can
use and some of them have figured
big advantages
some something
useful ways when in two thousand seven climb produced a system called a
peter which basically cells exactly the same problem
has monitor land but does it much better than particularly
doesn't better because they were able to uh
build massive
i have thousands of features rather than
a few dozens or hundreds which is so we were able to do
and they are able to do that's by basically solving
this graph problem in in a slightly different way basically bringing in
what was previously an offline technique bundle adjustment
which is basically the
you know the global
the least squares solution to to these kind of
they did what they were doing is taking an ever growing network like this and
always solving it from scratch on every frame it had to be clever and now
they were leach choosing which in the past data to keep
which in the past data throw away
but by some careful management and then of course
more computer power that led to run
bundle adjustment in real time on the second thread
then they were able to get really good
results in this peter system
we really took back on board
first all we
did a piece work to figure out why
he time which really
better than that of the kalman filtering
methods that we were previously using
hand we were able to prove it to ourselves it with with this kind of analysis so
this was an
experiment that we actually did in simulation so
imagine you've got a camera
which is just moving
for half a second
so during that time captures fifteen frames
in front and there is a scene where you can potentially measure
a lot of features so potentially this four hundred
features that can make
measurements of one on the wall in front so if you want to estimate the
motion between here and here the best possible way to do is to take holidays
take all of the feature measurements in all the frames all the correspondences
bundle adjust the whole lot of offline expensive but gives you a good
a good solution
so the question was what happens to a good solution
if we start
kind of taking away the data so festival we can remove
the number of intermediate frames
that we use
andy other thing we can do is reduce the number of points
thatwe use
so this is a graph basically showing
accuracy so high
is good here
so this maximum point of using all of the frames so up to fifteen frames here
and using all of the points
we get really good
as we start to degrade the number of frames
and the number of points you accuracy
reduces but the interesting thing is
when you degrade the number of intermediate frames that use it it doesn't degrade very much at all
and you can do statistical studies done statistical studies show that this is the same
i really HAK i
all you
each day i
people to
and each one of k
what i times each two
he two hash functions
two hash functions h
one of k and h two with k
as you compute the two hash functions
and what you do is you start by just using each one of k
the zero progress here i then
will be zero
and for the
the first for the
probe number one
just at each
the problem true just add that hash function amount again
just keep adding each to OK three success passion
six f approach me
so it's very easy to compute two hash functions of france
there you can delay the second one case
basically computer and then you just keep adding the second one is started the location
the first one batting second one
what am
to determine your
so this is an excellent method
there's a fine job and usually pick
the power to here
basically you're using a
usually people use this with the multiplication method for example
and part two
h two of a forced to be odd
so you use and even values there because otherwise you
for any particular use skipping over
once again we have the problem that everything could be even or everything could be
you're going through
to make it two k lot enemies
power two
they're guaranteed that every slot
OK so let's analyse this this turns out to be pretty interesting and analyse
so once again the worst case
you know
caching is lousy
over-analyze average
this we need a little bit stronger assumptions
chaining and we call consumption
uniform hashing
which says that HP
equally likely
you have
as its probe sequence
of other keys
and there were approved
is the expected number of probes
is most
one myself
if alpha is less
number keys on the table is less than the number of slots
thanks for and shows the number of probes is one of one myself
alpha load factor
for open addressing we want to load factor
to be less than one
as we have more keys than slots open addressing simply doesn't work
because you're going to find a place for every t in the table
look at unsuccessful search
the first thing is that one protein is always necessary
so i have
and over
sorry if i have in
items stored in slots
what's the probability that one idea is that probo again collision with something that's already
in the table
what's the probability that i get the collision
n or m right so probability
and over and
my tables got things in their and hashing random talk one of them
what i'd like something and overran
and then the second probe is necessary
so that
i do second proto
with probability
on the second from do i get the collision
to make the assumption of uniform hashing each
is equally likely to any one of the n factorial
permutations of the probe sequence
what is the probability that on the second proto
i get equation
this the permutation you're not right
something like that
song we've seen that before i call that the distance from the sun to the
is about one hundred fifty million kilometres
forgive me for
mixing up meters
this kilometres but you have to convert that of course two meters
and when you calculate
how long it takes earth to go around the sun
no surprise
you'll find three hundred and sixty
five and a half days
simply substitution
of these two quantities
the equation that i have here
and i have here
the velocity of the earth
you know if it is about thirty
kilometres per second
substantial speed by the way to do this is going around the
some thirty kilometres per second way higher than the speed
that the shuttle
is it around the orbit around the earth which is only eight kilometres
the second
jupiter is five
times further away than the earth
so the time for me to go around goes was
five to the power one and a half
that's about
twelve so take stupid about twelve years ago
the sun
notice that this
is independent
of the mass of the little satellite
and that was
very unfortunate
forty americans when
on october
before nineteen fifty seven sputnik was launched
they could find the radius very easily because they knew
the period
that it took sputnik to go around the earth that what about ninety six minutes
they could calculate the velocity they could calculate the radius but they had no clue
about the map
that was a piece of degree
the americans wanted to because if the mass was very large of sputnik that would
indicate of course that the russians had very powerful rockets
you cannot tell
the mass
from the
orbital parameters independent of mass you have a very light object or very heavy satellite
they have the same velocity in orbit if they have the same distance and they
have the same
i mentioned earlier notice that the orbital
period and escape
very by the square root of two if you're at a particular position
for instance
you have a particular
position around the earth
you the satellite
if you want to escape
from this
you will need a speech which is the square root of two times larger than
that orbital velocity
and so if you wanted to
from the earth
then you need your eleven point two kilometres
we have there
if you and the earth in orbit u eight kilometres per second and eight times
the square root of two is exactly
eleven point two you see the connection is always through this square root
of two
there's something remarkable about these numbers
total mechanical energy
and i will write once more here
which is one half
the square at a given
radius minus little
capital and
of are where m is
the mass of the sun or the earth is of no concern to me now
this is the kinetic energy for something in orbit at this rate is and this
is the potential energy
now notice
i can substitute now
forty three squared
i can substitute the square of this
this is the that is the orbital
speed and then i get
g over are
and so this one
was one half
and and j
and now compared to
almost look like carbon copies of each other
except that there is a minus sign which is crucial
and there's a half half-year year which is missing here
and so the total energy e
which i called the mechanical energy
always for a circular orbit is one half you
and the same
as minors
the kinetic energy
a remarkable
coincidence you would think it is not as much a coincidence as you think of
the difference if something is in orbit is the orbital speeds
the radius r
and always is its total energy
is half
potential energy is always negative
OK later in the course we will cover elliptical orbits i will not do that
today and so i will march on to a completely different topic
and that is the topic of
power so i will abandon for now
orbit entirely
what is power
is work
that is
so the amount of time
the the WDTFW is the
the work
is the instantaneous power
at time t
we also know power in terms of political power
that's very different
political power
you can do no work at all in a lot of time
you have a lot of power
here in physics
life is not that easy
units of power
are units of work which is due for second
but which we often write w
which is named after physicist what's don't confuse this w for work
with the w for what
which is one ju
per second
the work
that i do that the force is doing
is the dot product
between the fourth and certain displacement of that
force we have
dealt with that before
that is
a little bit
of work that i'm doing
i have force which is constant during this short small displacement
so i can substitute then in there
and so i get the power
is the derivative of this was time
and that is if i keep the force constant for that short amount of time
is the dot product
times the velocity because the dt
is simply the velocity of that object
so power is also force
but it with the
velocity if the force were perpendicular
at all times
to the
velocity vector
the power is zero
let's take an example
i am on a bicycle
here's my bicycle
and i'm sitting on a bicycle here
and i'm trying to
and i have a certain
and i keep that velocity
that's the way most people
i would write their bikes
there an drag which is unavoidable
we discuss that
more on that but the basic idea is that you get full control of machine
and it all links server is not a web service
when their Web service story here is that we use Web services as an administrative
interface to control the servers so that you're able to start and stop servers and
to make certain that are still running
so you can basically people use these with bottom and use this Web servers interface
with automation to control server products not talk more about that there are more and
there's no I once again there's no up-front Costa anything so
In the case of 30 due to that server recharged by 10 cents US per
hour to run and there's enough momentum or anything plus the same band bandwidth charges
that we charge for an entire history
so it's
really I changed the the price equation for computing versus the way that I like
to explain how this works with automation
so nearly whether to project a start of we start with some sort of a
prediction in or nearly the way we make predictions something like this hopefully you're prediction
more like this than just a straight line but pointed to start production and then
typically what we do is we go wild
and by servers to stay above that that
predicted projection because that's the idea with the prediction the start need nominee searched about
what the problem with this approach is that this is really nasty thing it's called
In reality never looks like the best line notebooks looks
some other random and that has to be very real costs the 1st task is
an opportunity this is sort of like an airline seat that simply you paid for
it but you didn't village in so you lost that and there is a real
cost of course in the 2nd thoughts that most of us worry about witches you
didn't have enough capacity in the user had a bad experience in if you're com
they went away and never come back in a bid to project you'll hear about
so neither of those so what's happening is by using Web services and monitoring the
server to to find out you track whatever you want see CPU utilization requests for
2nd on the network our we want to go
you track attract servers tuna fleet of servers as you go
In so doing you have what amounts to just-in-time capacity
and I think it looks like an infant pooled servers out there from your point
of view of course it's not but it's also big might as well be from
any individual organizations point to and its civil division just-in-time capacity
so we have if you think about how virtual server works there is at the
end of the day
a virtual server is always a file
he was represented by a file so there's
3 different kinds of Amazon machine images which reduce file representations that I want to
spend just a 2nd talking about 1st of all
there's a public mine which if I can get things working here
I'll show you in the doubles and publicly inquiry basically an I that's out there
on our site there that we've made available 1 of the hundreds that our community
is made available in the contains you know some distribution of Linux with some of
its offer was installed on top of that you're able to run
where a lot of people don't really need a private and my with yourself around
you can do you can create that either
customizing public in mind sitting at a starting with an image on your machine and
uploading it to to our service and that's stored in your own history account Amazon
history accounts
he and
only you have access to it that's what probably most people would run
but there's a certain pattern that I want to talk about because I think that
this is a real business opportunities for almost in a year and it's kind of
a new business opportunities it's sort of software as a service
I like the cult's offers and nobody another reason I'm going to and what up
in my is all about ideas for example in the case of easy to but
say that you add some software to win imaging you wanna resellers
a CRM package that you installed on top of the support on top of the
image or something like that which you can do it you set your own price
for a new make it available on Amazon . com
purchase for argument sake let's say that we added at 20 cents and costly church
and so what happens is people
visit the Amazon . com website variable signed up for the public or the stadium
it was going to do
going to
it's going to be again approach in which we must realise over the sources too
classes and properties over the ontology
OK so that's what we're going to do OK
but we not that because we have to deal also with the fact that they
can the sources is now the population
we have only by its own auction OK while
in the ontology as we know
we have both objects by in particular the eastern system the classes
OK so we need to solve the so-called impedance mismatch problem
so let's look at this problem a little bit
so the problem is the in relational database we have by
in ontologies we have both object and by OK and in fact i just played
the main villain
OK survives only use
a few letters for objects active told that the property OK
so the point is there
we have to take out of top also values we have to create
OK we took it out so the point is that we have
we need to have constant dollars create objects
from the couple of months
in the actually
there is a very nice thing however that you should have been the ontology
after this so we don't really care
what is the shape
it's a fact which are going to do in this is the part of the
part of the formal solution is that we can consider this
simply skolem function with that's colin functions these functions that are not interpreted
OK so what i do i take it up
i consider is an argument over skolem function and i don't need to give an
interpretation to this kind of functions the infection said to the new generated in this
way is really
meaningful enough
to be
the object identifier
all of a the instance of the class over the property that i'm interested in
OK so this is how we do it mathematically i think i'll skip this
and this is now
the mapping is generated so essentially we have
this part of the here
these are
and i think it's quite clearly over the sources OK
in this returns some
OK these are the values in this five is now use
in the real
OK over the a of the ontology and how use the weight on the one
in use that i can on getting uses argument skolem function to generate
object to generate abstract objects
and let me tell you that this over here
OK it's not clear why this
this is the first of that we this is a conjunction with you but we
don't distinguish viable and actually this means that we have be in
they got thinking and not in the last eighteen because we are the simplest kind
of conjunctive queries
OK so let me go
at this point i would like to show
that some
a mapping from we also
now what we do is we take essentially the
the ontology they have been used so far in this tutorial
we follow a b a box
and instead of using a a synthetic data from this but going to try
to connected to real database in particular this is a database that is using your
relational database OK
if you if your data for instance is is larger than fits in memory
in your computer then you're in trouble
so what i'll talk about today
is the trick to speed this up
and the trick is simply
instead of waiting for all the data before we start the optimisation
what we do is we just look at some of the data
and that some
of the data that could be like a single data point or it could be
five data points or it could be a thousand data points that's that's the parameter
that i can choose
but i only look at some sort of sense of current observations a look at
the current batch of observations then performing optimisation step on that then i grab some
new observations optimise on that and i keep going like that this is called stochastic
and what was so what we approximating is this function
and we approximating it stochastically by stochastic is and this sub sampling of the data
because when you try to model
i analytically what's going on there the the assumption that you make is that your
data is sort of i i d it's it's identically independently distributed and you're picking
random data
in practice of course that's not what you do you pick the data that you
have at the moment so typically say if you have an online learning system where
data comes in all the time and you try to adapt to that
you don't have the
the choice of picking your samples i i d
because you just have to take what's there
none the less sort of the label that's been attached to this
these techniques
on why is it an approximation
well if my parameters theta would be constant
then actually it would be exact right i could just take subsamples
and if i then go and add up all the subsamples or of the gradients
of the subsamples i would
the original function of the original gradient back
but that's not what i'm doing i'm taking a subsample
and then i'm doing my optimisations
and the optimizer changes the parameter vector because
i'm searching in parameter space
so now what adding up over time is actually slightly inconsistent because it's all these
gradient measurements
done on different data and slightly different parameter values
and i'm going to pretend that overall that corresponds to some sort of gradient of
the entire objective function
people have done analysis on that and derive conditions under which that works
so they
nothing to do is is too strong but you are very right in pointing out
that the problem that's exactly the problem
the upshot of all of that is that you don't want to do too much
on this little sample of data
because yes it's poor information you only have some of the data not all of
it and so you don't want to expend huge effort for instance and do like
you know gauss newton are living but mark warner whatever optimisation step
because the minimum that you find in that step actually has very little to do
with whether true minimum it's that's true
and that's why i'm interested in these kinds of methods because these are cheaper and
less efficient optimisation methods
and it turns out that if on this small data sample you just do a
little step in the right direction
and you keep doing that for fresh samples over time if you set this up
in the right way it will actually converge to the right answer
so yes you can't be too over-aggressive in optimizing on this small subsamples that's part
of the
part of the the game here
there's various scenarios so
one scenario would call online learning
where the better just keeps coming in
so you never see the same data twice because it's just i don't know you
have a video feed you know you're trying to learn from that as it goes
but there's always fresh images coming
so you never recycle that data that's online learning
in that scenario you actually have to use a stochastic approximation because you cannot wait
for the end of the training data
before the end of this this loop because there's no and
however it turns out stochastic approximation algorithms can be very efficient optimizers so people use
them even when the training set is finite
and what you would typically do
is you say you have your training set
let's say each of these vectors is one
and they keep coming
and this year set right
becomes more important
so two things about it in our vascular systems the flow rates are generally low
enough that you have to worry about that
and are are
are vessels are all
very similar in terms of their of their
microscopic geometry and that all of the blood vessels are are covered with a monolayer
of cells called endothelial cells
the basically former blanket over the entire surface of the inside of the circulatory system
so there is very little
frictional resistance to flow
there better
it's really the point
the questions
so this this equation sort of makes sense right well if you if you go
on to study biomedical engineering you learn exactly where this equation comes from and you'd
be able to derive it yourself but but for now just accepted
and if it is true for almost all the vessels in our body almost under
all the circumstances of human physiology and it tells us that resistance varies with viscosity
link and radius and if there is in in in in kind of the
the way that you would expect as discussed fluid goes up resistance goes up
as the length of the two goes up resistance goes up
right harder to pull through long strada through a short stroll
and as the radius goes up
resistance goes down
right because the radius is in the
it is in the
denominator here so radius goes up the resistance goes down and remarkably
the resistance goes with the fourth power of the radius
what does that mean
that means the fold increase in radius leads to a sixteen fold reduction
sixteen is two to the fourth round
sixteen fold reduction in
so resistances of all the parameters resistance is most sensitive to radius
when you have
so what's the unit was let's think about what unit would you
would you measure pressure and
what's the unit of pressure
that scales is one
newtons per meter square millimetres square to force per area
is pressure
this is what some more commonly those are those are
those are the those are great units sorry
pounds per square inch is another unit PSI
what's the pressure in the room here
one atmosphere atmosphere is another pressures on their relative to atmospheric pressure
if you have
many many others
millimetres of mercury it turns out that all of those are are are proper units
four pressure and you can convert between one or the other as long as you
knew what the conversion factor was between the
we usually use atmospheres to describe atmospheric pressure physiologist usually use millimetres of mercury to
describe the pressure in the circulatory system
millimetres of mercury so one atmosphere is seven hundred sixty millimetres of mercury
one of the blood pressures that are relevant in your circulatory system
how many millimetres of mercury to think
anybody know their blood pressure is
a hundred twenty over eighty one
they'll tell you that a hundred twenty millimetres of mercury over eighty millimetres of mercury
we're going to talk about where those numbers are we're those pressures actually exist in
a few minutes but that's that's that's the range of pressures in your circulatory system
from zero millimetres of mercury up to
one hundred twenty millimetres of mercury
roughly and we'll see you go outside that range sometimes now
these are pressures that are inside or circulatory system so they must be
but there are only a fraction of an atmosphere how can that be
right and atmosphere is seven hundred sixty millimetres of mercury that's the pressure in this
room if your blood pressure is one twenty over eighty
what does that mean
well pressure is a we only care about differences in pressure
its relative pressure that matters not the absolute
pressure so when you say that your your blood pressure is one hundred twenty over
a that means one hundred twenty millimetres of mercury above atmospheric
eighty millimetres mercury above atmosphere
otherwise our blood vessels would collapse
because we're surrounded by air that's that's seven hundred sixty millimetres of mercury
to inflate those vessels you have to be at pressures above that
but since all we care about our pressure differences in the pressure that you measure
when you measure blood pressure is pressure above atmospheric
to make sense
so so delta p is in millimeters of mercury
q is in
o litres per minute
so are is in
units of
millimetres of mercury per litre
per minute
four millimetres
it's in
units of
if we describe this out
millimetres of mercury
people are and this is litres per minute
are most units of
some detail about particular techniques the basic idea of defensive programming
is to assume that a if you're getting inputs from the user
they won't necessarily give you the input you've asked for
so if you ask for positive numbers don't count giving you one right
and b
if you're using a piece of program written by
a programmer who is not perfect
perhaps yourself
there could be mistakes in that program and so you write your program under the
not only might the user make a mistake
other parts of your program might make a mistake
and you just put in lots of different tests
under the assumption that you'd rather catch that something has gone wrong
then you have a go wrong and not knowing
and we'll talk later in the term about dozens of different tricks
but the main thing to keep in mind is the general principle
people are down
and we all make mistakes and therefore you write your program so that
catastrophes don't occur
when those mistakes are made
john severin to come back to it but that's what basically the goal here and
you only put my hands up when is it stupid programmer i certainly written code
has this problem tried to use my own code that has this problem and good
to is very good
hygiene i'm going to use that word again you're getting into the habit of writing
defensive code up front part of the collection of things that you want to do
is a great thing to do
i stress in particular because i know you're all going to get into the stage
gotta problems that do
a couple of hours
you still writing the code you don't want to waste time and then use quotes
always time doing those extra things to do the defensive programming is one to get
the darn thing done
it's a bad habit to get into his when you come back to it in
a hot you later on down the road to really get into the notion of
trying to be defensive is you program
the other thing i want to say here is that this file
the programme which is run
it's actually very common one
i'm going to give it a nice little name
after referred to as exhaustive enumeration
one i mean he says i'm literally walking through
all possible
some parameters some element of the computation
testing everything until i find the right answer
so it's you know you can even write that down essentially saying try
all reasonable values
until you
find the solution
and you might say well what i mean is not going to be really expensive
and the answer is yes i guess if you want to search all the pages
on google one by one yes probably take while
but then lot computation for which is the right way to do it is one
o exhaustively go through things and just to give you a sense of that
we show you an example going to change this
it nice big number
you computers are fast these days i can make this even bigger is going to
do it fairly quickly so it really is quick to do this it doesn't mean
that exhaustive enumeration is a bad idea is often the right idea to use
so we've seen one example of this is idea of walking through all the images
look for the square
let's look at some other examples
in order to try and see other ways in which we could do it
the particular school over to here let me show you a second example
let me comment that out
here's another problem
but i like to solve
what i want to find all the divisors
i have some integer
can figure out all the divisor evenly into it
again the same kind of reasoning says given some value x happened because small wonder
what an easy way to do this
well let's just start at one
that's my variable i'm going to change and check doesn't divide evenly into
x if it does printed move on to the next one printed out
so again i can do the same kind of thing here you can see that
in fact
the list is run to make sure does the right thing
in fact if we go back to the co what i decided to do here
so starting
within initialisation by there's my first step is equal to one
i'm going to walk through a little loop or i check
so first of all as long as i less than x so there's my and
test i'm going to do something in this case the something is i'm going to
look to see
i divide sexy evenly so remind you that have sort the percent sign that says
divided by i have zero remainder because this because we back the remainder that's equal
to zero
prince something out
and there's my nice increment
simple little piece notice again exactly the same form
take the thing i wanted to very
initialize it outside the loop
i have test to see when i'm done
and i got a set of instructions on doing every time inside the loop in
there's an equal sign you you you should not be sleeping
you're not supposed to sleep
this is an equal sign
a minus b
x got
equals minus b we and business now
so i'm going to
this would also you all sleeping
while he was sleeping my goodness
the next the minus pxl miners MG KX well and the miners in the mines
becomes plus
i try not to sleep
x the double dot
now we get plus
times x dot
now we get plus omega zero squared
times because the valleys omega zero square times ax
by dividing them out
now i get equals
omega zero squared
times at zero
times cosine
omega t
i'll move this al but in a little bit
and i'm going to look now at the equation at the bottom
and i am now
because of this one
looks almost like a carbon copy
the one that i had here
we have zero cosine we get
now instead of an of zero divided by n
cosine omega t
i know this
so this takes the place of my earlier have zero
divided by n
zero divided by amazon acceleration by the way
better be an acceleration because this is an acceleration apples have to be apples so
this is an acceleration this is an acceleration and this
is also an acceleration multiplied only scrapped by distance you get distance divided by time
so you see how the the connection between the two go
well recently i got an have zero over and
times cosine omega t
now because of waterloo in motion i'm going to get an omega zero squared
at time zero
so you see now how
this motion of my hand indeed
translates into
a force on the object
well i have the solution
i don't have to do anything
all i have to do is change this by omega zero crowd
times at the zero and i'm done
the difference in equation is identical
i don't even have to change the tangent of delta
nothing changes this is the only thing that changes
so we done
we can make some predictions
the prediction is that if i'm going to shake this pendulum
and i'm going to do it very slowly
taking one hour to go to the left and took taking one hour to the
right and if my amplitude is at zero
what do you think that the
amplitude a
the solution of my differential equation will be
in other words i'm going to show a very slowly
what do you think it will be without looking at the difference in equation
i just go with my hand like this
amplitude only at the zero
amplitude at the zero and i do it very slow
what will be the amplitude of a
at the zero
so you expect that this goes to add to zero
well if you don't believe it go to this equation
substituting easier zero in easier you get omega zero created this only because it was
quite easy at this year
exactly what that
equation predicts
but your common sense says the same thing
now what do you think there is if i'm going to move this pendulum very
slowly to the left and to the right
of course
of course the objective of all and we will be ridiculous if i take one
week to go from here to read the object will be their rights of the
object is always here so you also predict that delta is here
so now
we can make
prediction that at resonance
must be one half a
the square can be in the time it takes to go from a to b
and so t
it would be
the square root
of two l
what's really would have been
the speed b
would be
early on to one
and so
that would become
we multiply this by a square root
of two
a l
and if you want to see that in all glories details
and of course you have to take that h
and you have to multiply that by two out and take the square root
so we get too
i'm sign
o thing minus u of k
i cosine of data
and the whole thing
the power
one half that speed
at would b
i however
what not to do it that way
i don't find it very elegant
i would say
why don't apply
the work energy theorem
why not say that the work done
when that object moves from a to b
must be the kinetic energy
at point b
why is the kinetic energy at point eight
now i know that i really think zero speed so this is zero
and so
the kinetic energy of the
it's clearly and one half
the square so it comes down
two applying work energy theorems and calculating how much work was done by all the
forces at stake
conservative and non-conservative makes no difference
and that would equal to one of them
first of all
when it goes from point a to b
is doing
positive work
it's going down
and the amount of work the gravity is doing is plus and
g h
but h
divided by l
is the sign of fatah
so this is also ngl
times the sign
that's positive work
by gravity
so we have g
times the site of data
that's the positive contributions
by gravity
and now we get negative contribution
by friction
because the frictional force is uphill
but the motion is down
one hundred eighty degrees opposite so i don't have to worry about the dot product
the cosine of the angle
minus one
and so i can ignore
the dot and simply take that force
the frictional force multiplied by that
distance al but i have to to the minus sign
because the cosine
of that angle
equals minus one
and so i get
i'm the frictional force
o fado
that's the negative we're done
and this equals one half
the squared
and i lose and
and if you look very carefully
if you're willing to do that in your head
during the two to the left
you get two GLI
and then you get
the g sin theta UK
cosine theta problem you get exactly the same result i find this somehow more pleasing
we use the
work energy theorem
the friction does negative work
converted into
but that's no problem for the work energy theorem
we know in life that friction
takes kinetic energy out whenever something is moving
it will come to a halt
if you spin the talk
but we know
at the top
i will not last very long
of friction
and i have here the top
i hope you can see it shortly there it is
teeny-weeny the top very cute i play with him to my office
i'm rotating it
and you see that friction
sticking out kinetic energy
and it's converting it to eat
please stay on the desk will you please not fall on the floor
it does was great
so you see
that's what friction does kinetic energy has been removed
and now
it has been converted to heat
this service is a little smaller than the desk