for instance joint models in it in a way that is provably private there may
be some opportunities in analyzing in the and the fact that we can analyse only
small chunks of the data and still get globally relevant results and my hope is
that that's going to provide some capabilities that if we could analyse as we do
now small clusters of individuals to come up with a universally
valid conclusions are at least conclusions that we feel comfortable generalizing the not to be
possible to do analysis like that much in the same way that snow said we
need to look at a few geographic districts to figure out whether whether drinking contaminated
causes color i don't look at everyone in london
we sometimes questions so just briefly some conclusions first i don't want to leave without
telling you what happened in the end with john snow
snow's analysis did not immediately convince the london board of health the miasma theory was
flawed but within about a decade it was the predominant theory and snow's work was
was represented and understood to be really quite groundbreaking
it did fortunately at the time to convince people in his own neighborhood that they
should remove the handle
from pop which was the primary water supply for the neighborhood it's so well known
in epidemiology circles and what
not generally known
that's not generally known is that first of all the cholera epidemic was winding down
so many people have said oh well the prompted didn't really matter
but also
subsequent investigation
identified a single household that had started the epidemic that had a sewer system that
communicated directly with the water supply that part
the day that the pump handle was removed another person in that household became ill
with cholera and died several days later and so it's very likely if the panel
had been removed the cholera epidemic would started all over again
also just to conclude with the overall topic of the talk computational social science gives
us some amazing opportunities to address important questions
but also some really interesting i think research challenges moving from networks to analyzing whole
social systems moving from looking at conditional patterns to joint models to take into account
a wide variety of relational spatial and temporal information and moving from merely finding associations
the fighting finding causal dependencies
o also going to have to seriously engage with social scientists if we're going to
do this kind of work and we're also going to have to take a more
systematic approach trying to understand how to do this work in a way that preserves
here's some people that i want to make sure i i acknowledge and some funding
agencies provided generous support for this work and i would be happy to take questions
thank you
so you don't need for
talk now for questions
people ask questions if you could disrupt the microphone
OK we be
repeat the question
he called
and so i can hear you
and the most promising
special temporal reality and the difference is certainly in in time for all you know
in the temple case was actually runs only one direction or
at least in the physics we tend to think of you know at the at
the macro level in last that physics works very differently than we think than than
temporal information actually provides additional constraints on the possible causal models what is remarkable is
that the work that has been done so far and causal discovery does not use
temporal information it's amazing that we've been able to get as far as we have
as well as a broad field by not explaining that kind of information because when
social scientists go look causality that is absolutely one of the constraints that they they
stable or unstable
a little bit more unstable you this one also a little bit more unstable these
ones are kind of in between
so in a typical experiment we might show people
but sixty different examples of these stacks ten blocks and the judge on a scale
of one the seven how stable they are and then we build a model of
what's going on in their head that looks just like what i showed you before
r it i mean you could think about is one of these fancy kinds each
man's but really what we've got is we've got some we are modelling that are
saying they have some representation of the
a be unable to not directly observable world state which is something like a cat
description of these objects
which they inferred with some kind of approximate bayesian inference from the image by inverting
kind graphics simple graphics rendering model
and then once you have actually description you can
you can judge stability by just propagating forward something like a kind of a physics
engine so so here using the way we actually build this
this model people's mental models we use like simple game physics engines as there are
no has probably pretty much everyone here knows fast and ready approximations to classical newtonian
and so in this case you have these objects and you can say well now
we turn on physics what happens well little fall in some pattern
and because it's probabilistic
this is just only one of
a number of possible guesses right we can't where you the probabilities coming in various
places but one place they come is that
you can't exactly invert this
this graphics model you can't from a single image guess exactly the
it's certainly people can't
exactly the precise data those three objects just from a quick glance to make some
gas so here's another hypothesis of what underlying state could be and then you can
run newtonian physics and then you get a different answer
so in the particular models that we build
uncertainty comes into these policies programs in just two places just keep it simple
one is a state uncertainty that's the single parameter so how you know how much
basically saying how precisely can you localize the objects the blocks from
the image that you see
and then there's some latent force uncertainty it's you know we put in certain basic
forces into a physics engine like gravity and friction but we allow for the fact
that could be other forces that you maybe you didn't know about like for example
somebody could walk by not the table little better wind could blow
in this first experiment that's not a big deal i'm rather we didn't tell anybody
about forces so about parameter won't do anything but that's one of the things we
can manipulate later on
so here's an example of actually
getting some predictive power of the small
hand again i'm not going to go through the details experience but i'm gonna show
you a bunch of scatterplots data because i want to emphasise how this is enabling
us to make precise quantitative reverse engineering models these aspects of common sense which traditionally
have not been
the manifold quantitative analysis
so in this plot here each
each dot is one of these sixty towers and the model predictions are shown on
the x-axis and people started from the axis
and again what we're asking people the judges on a scale of one the seven
how stable is this one is very unstable this one is judges very stable so
those are two ends this
and are basically ask are model same thing how does it work it just runs
a few of these conditional simulations forming estimate the block posterior r but position because
steering and propagating physics forward and then just inspects the output of the simulations to
see just what fraction of the tower fell that's what gives us a quantitative measure
and you can see that we do a pretty good job of capturing the the
range a variation in people's inferences the correlation here is that is in the midpoint
is about point five nonlinear correlation now there's parameters that we have to today but
there's really only one parameter that has to be fit here which is that's state
uncertainty because we have a model in detail how the visual system works
and that's so that's in the parameter corresponds to you know a relatively small fraction
of one as a small side of the block
it's it turns out that that's actually very important fore modeling this if if you
if you assume that people were able to localize the objects perfectly then it wouldn't
fit nearly as well
it certainly has some both by researchers and psychologists whenever we consider a very complex
model like we're going to do probabilistic inference over a physics simulation
we may also want to consider alternatives which a simpler approach is certainly in psychology
many people would find it a little bit impossible this idea that you have something
like a game physics engine in your head so we can consider many different simple
heuristics that you could compute just on the images themselves are on some kind of
geometric description without going to the dynamics like the height of the tower that something
about the top heaviness various schemes i won't go into the details but i'll say
that for a whole bunch of different judgments
there are
heuristics we can come up with which can do almost as well as these physics models
but the key thing that shows you that you've really got some kind of intuitive
theory or some kind of ability to run a rich physics simulation in your head
is all the different kinds of things you can do with this model
it's it's a kind overturning test if you like again it's kind of a core
theme from today is lecture a kind of many train test
here a bunch of questions that we that we got experiments i showed you one
where the judgement is just you know will the tower fall but think about all
the other questions you can ask about just this kind of stimulus so which way
will the tower fall if it falls are how far will the blocks fall they
go all the way over the table are just
with this kind of crumble or suppose you bump the table so suppose you add another force now
and you have blocks the different colours when you have more red or yellow blocks
what if you bump this side the side or what if the blocks are different
shapes and sizes or what about kind counterfactual reasoning adding the block of the thing
fall off or what if we add other kinds of physical parameters like suppose the
red blocks ten times heavier than yellow blocks what's gonna happen what turns out that
we can
we can do all these things here so for example we can
we can get people to judge this is this is the actual snapshot of subject playing this little game
where he simultaneously judging
which way the blocks will fall and how far he didn't really get the direction
very well but there was really a good answer
consider this try this task in your head along with strider imagine which way the blocks are falling
there's a little bit better trackers one more try before you see it
so this logical expressions
again we can have if then rules as we have discussed before
and then no such a decision tree can be used for classification we we have
a new weather situation like folksonomy temperature hard humidity high wing stock
so what do we do we use the decision tree for classification
if after his son we go here
and then we look at humidity communities high
we go here so the prediction will be that will not go to play tennis
so decision tree learning
we did
this decision trees we want to classify new instances for which we don't know the
into one of the discrete sets of possible categories and this is useful in medical
diagnoses classifying low applicants and whatever other
possible classification problem
so how does the algorithm work and there are the data is
has been developed in early
in nineteen seventy nine that was the well known i these three algorithm developed by
ross quinlan
at the same time nearly there were statistically stations who have developed in nearly the
same algorithm for decision tree learning but i'm who has developed
britain cart
and then these developments would further into the algorithm c four point five c five
and they are also implemented in the wake of toolbox for data mining
what do we do first we first create the route
of the decision tree
and then if all examples would be of the same class we wouldn't
construct the c decision tree then we have stopped
usually the
examples are of different classes
if not
all the examples belong to the same class we select the most informative attributes we
note with the club with the attribute names
and then we split
the set of examples into subsets according to the values of the attribute
like that we have this this divide this training set into subsets and for each
of these subsets we recursively build decision tree again
at each step we again look whether all examples belong to the same class
then we stop and label the the
the node with the class labels and that becomes the leaf of the decision tree
if not we split again
so it is the so-called divide and conquer process in which we construct the decision
logically logistic regression i think logistic regression doesn't have to deal with the class which
is numeric attribute
it is a binary
OK so and the doesn't build the decision tree
we get a ratio
you know
but then with the regression you typically have let's say values and then you have
some coefficients and you do
regression type of prediction
so this would be the that the the main difference is here that you kind
of split the set of all the instances into subsets
until you have got
clean subsets of instances so in terms of what you can use
forty four
it's the same
so you can use it for prediction but the description you get from the two
approaches is different
it is to get the same
the same result
you can use it for the same purpose so the question is whether you will
be able get the same classification refused the one or other
so here the approach is that you would get this the
i want to to have a look at
particular application of logic
and we're going to apply
first order logic two
reasoning about dynamic to make so what i mean by dynamic domains and domains in
which we can have
we have actions that at disposal
and those actions change the environment in some way
and we're gonna use
first order logic for
and furthermore i mean you
you might have seen some other ways do so for instance you could use dynamic
today is
it is a whole lot of other different logics to do this
some of this i'm guessing you probably have flavor from uses lecture
i guess there is one
at least one moral and i want to draw from
this lecture
i'm not going to give it away just yet have little might come as a
bit of a surprise but
the idea is that there's some moral to be taken here when you're going to
use first order logic something in this case we can use it to
reason about this dynamic system
OK so it's like the point
again i still a couple of slides from
from the
prec milbrooks textbook
so one way to do this is the sort of strips way i think you
see what covered street yesterday right
so the basic idea is that when you perform an action you just have a
knowledge base of facts
if x ten you what true right now
and the idea would be that you delete things that are no longer true and
you add new things which things become true when you perform action
so if i flicked the switch
you know this which might have been in the down position it becomes no longer
true so i deleted
this which is now in the opposition so that becomes true and that to my
and that's essentially the approach that strips takes two play
but suppose we don't want to just talk about the current sort of state but
we want to talk about states either in the past
we visited previously
all states in the future that we want to go to
how can i do that
so that's what we're going to have a look
OK so
let's try and actually
let me go back to
so then she by looking at the slides but
as i suppose you've got this system that you want to describe and the thing
is so we want to do is reason about the environment and what changes when
when you do actions if pick up the cash
i want to be able to describe you know what the environment looked like before
it cup what looks like up become
we need to write all this down in logic surprising i want to do this
in first order logic
so what what things we can write down
i mean like specifically what things but what
in general
what sort of what sort of knowledge do we need to write down to do
this task what i need to describe
right stand
right what's that's good as i don't want to necessarily get into the nitty gritty
like positions of objects but positions of objects tell us something about one
the environment state
so we need to describe the state
so that's first thing we need to do
OK what else do we need to do
every possible but in general like i'm going
describe one state can describe we can describe all
you could do that go i guess the goal to describe what god is perfect
usually the goal i can say
goals school
what else we need to scrap
actions right
now he said something nice said like possible actions
so when it comes actions what we need to say about actions
you need to say when possible right
we need to say
so actions are a bit more complicated things because we need to sort of describing
it when you cannot perform the action so for instance if
if i include the cup to the table
i go pick it up you know that that action is not possible because the
what else do i need to know about actions
what they do not just one
anything else
looks good to me
OK initially what's to initial good
you've done this before
anything else
OK this is what i put on
said the state of the world
actions that changes to the world and what changes they fit so what they do
and you will see i didn't quite so there but we'll see them when they
what when the possible
in some cases you might want to describe constraints on legal scenarios so
types of constraints might be for instance if i put my two cups together
if i move this one then the other one comes along with so that might
be constrained
we're not going to talk to much about those constraints
now he is the
the question is what leads to the
you know the the point that i want to make it in the lecture system
got quite give you the answer to hopefully you see the light
hands up
if you think that this is
sufficient this looks good
OK if it doesn't look good why doesn't look good
when he worried about
that's a really good question but i guess at the moment i just want to
reason about what's possible without reasoning about how might achieve something if i have a
which is more what planning is about
we can treat goals but we're not so worried about goals as saying well if
i did this what would the world look like next
so i don't really need to consider goals i just wanted to figure out
and i personally think that's a good list
and to me i would say that if i could
describe all of these things in logic
my job will be done i could
say well if you told me that you execute executed this section followed by the
section followed by the section i could
OK in this study this would change this would change as we change in the
i could tell you exactly what state
looks like that you would end up
that sort of my objective
so i think this looks great
and this looks good
OK now what we're going to look at is this thing called the situation calculus
in the situation calculus is just a particular
one was on
o one one o
one one
the one
this year
it would be
o thing
i like
in the world
very good
in water
being one of
now you're you're you're
all of them
which leads me
to cluster the data points and that we use k means is just for convenience
we could use anything else but we just know came into that's what we do
OK so i don't have a slide on this i guess somewhere now so one
one big problem with k means is
first of all it looks for classes which are on things right so if the
the data set looks like this
k means would probably put them in here but i mean you cut like this
it doesn't work so spectral clustering does not make
any assumptions
like it doesn't make a strong modelling assumptions like asking is so in principle it
in so spectral clustering the work very nicely on examples like that
the second thing which is an advantage is that
spectral clustering just also linear problem because this often i can the problem so there's
nothing like
we have a non convex optimisation problem we restart five hundred times and stop solution
and one of the two thousand things to make sure we end up in local
optimum which is or something close to the one we are interested
but of course
that's the because we i mean we just made the relaxation such that we end
up with a linear problem so in principle we start with a very difficult problem
and then relax so far that we just don't know what the the problem is
just as one solution so they might get rid of it but it just turns
out works
this one
one that i have
so i mean it's actually OK
so i don't want to say that spectral clustering is the only algorithm which can
solve problems also
i don't know if i don't say it's the best one it it's one of
the islands and depending on what you want to do there might be many tests
and we will see that i mean there's a huge variety of clustering algorithms
i think they're just a few of them which model is working
if you just need to apply them to the dataset they in many cases give
reasonable results and k means and spectral clustering is one of the few communities might
be another one
so i don't i by no means i want to say that spectral clustering is
better than anything else it's one of them but i mean i like it because
but it's i mathematicians i'm mostly not working with real data it just like that
it's very elegant writer and so on but i mean many people in practice also
like it
and this
OK so i get so the question was whether it can happen that actually the
data contains very clear clusters but after mapping in the
in the spectral representation sort of messes up
yes that can happen
mainly it happens to choose from parameters and we'll talk about which parameters and so
on to translate on
it doesn't happen so easily so if you if you have a reasonable set of
it usually doesn't happen but so i think spectral clustering is and i
the data that's content clusters will usually find them but any other groups or to
find the source of
i mean that's usually not the pointer algorithms to further cases which are ambiguous and
some of you might have just different models of what to do in those cases
OK i really want to mention the second explanation
but now i fear that not nearly nobody knows whether around market so i just
want to give intuitions
so we have to get more data
so it looks like this
so the random walk
is a stochastic process which is which
OK it's actually something which is very intuitive so you
random walk is something to start with one vertex and then you randomly jump to
another vertex
and the way to see other vertex so you're allowed to jump to any other
vertex which is connected to you
original text the probability with which to jump from one vertex to the next depends
on the weight so if we have like
if the weights are normalized to have something like one-third here one
and that's bad
just make one for everyone on board so we started the vertex and then with
probability one quarter jump to one of the neighboring vertices and we do that again
and again so we start with one down to the next one then randomly jump
to another one in this whole process is called random walk
on the graph
and random walks on the graph are so previously said that matrix is often can
be a nice thing to explore
or i can make this or whatever spectral graph theory to explore properties of graph
invented often
tools which can be very handy if you want to explore different properties of graphs
so for example in clustering
you could say
OK i run random organising cellular to run very very long time
and then you can't also has been any vertex
or you can count how often the jump between two vertices
something like that
and so the intuition for random walks is often
we want to find a cut through the graph
that is that the random walk on one side of the cut it tends to
stay on the side
so that the random walk here and in most of the cases in runs around
the cluster then OK occasionally it will jump to customer but then runs around in
this class and doesn't jump back until i found itself later maybe terms but
so we can use the random walk to
you can you can sort of formalized clustering in terms of a random walk by
saying i want that the
clusters are objects such that the random walk stays inside them instead of hopping between
and that's actually what has been observed for normalized spectral clustering
so actually
i don't want to go into the math but someone should get across what i
mean so so
by p a given b i mean the probability
during group in group b
and now you are and what makes one step
then i want to compute the probability that after the step is it is in
a way so i'm hearing be
so what is the likelihood that after one step i am in
now if somewhat average this the whole groups because i just don't look at individual
points but the total
and then you can show that
the normalized cut like this creature and we wanted to optimise is exactly the same
we look at the probability of a given b plus the probability of b given
we we are in a
and that only one to many that's the thing we want to minimize right so
what this means is that
instead of saying we want to minimize has been cut in the graph
we could say
we want to minimize
this random walk expression may be just what i just as said we don't want
to sound too often between the two
and that's an intuition
what it's all about intrusion so that's an intuition which helps me and other people
probably don't get anything out
OK so that's one more interpretation
the other interpretation of has to do with random walks
in terms of the commute distance saw
the commute distance the first is a very elegant things so often you have the
you given your data in form of a graph
what you want to do is you want to
a bit complicated that's actually very difficult to work out its it several pages of
boring mathematics and you get an expression for the this mu four MU two are
defined by this expression here this is the what's called the k th central moments
of the distribution and this is the fourth and second central moment but anyway OK
there so you have expressions for the bias and variance
now for these two examples for the
i mean and variance of a random variable it's relatively easy and obvious to just
write down some function of the sample
they can be used to estimate those parameters but we can do that in general
sometimes the parameters that appear in in
PDF might have some obscure interpretation and it will be at all obvious how to
you know what function of the data can be used to estimate the values so
we need to work
general prescription procedure
and in order to
lead us to that i need to introduce a very important function called the likelihood
suppose that we have done some measurements some some collection of individual measurements x one
through x and of course that my my experiment right one experiment consists of observing
that set of numbers
and i can be model
that outcome that set of outcomes has been described from a certain
joint pdf f of x one through x n but suppose that this
contains certain unknown parameters theta
the idea is now to simply evaluate that function
with the data that i obtained in my measurements and regard those measured values now
as fixed
and then this look at this function not as a function of x but as
a function of the parameters and that's what i call it like the likelihood function
it is essentially the same function as the joint pdf
of the measurement
but i do not regard it as a function of x i regarded as a
function of the parameters
so that's the likelihood function is an important special case which is the usual case
in this type of problem that is that i have some pdf
f of x for each value of x and i simply sample x number of
times i have independent observations of x and each x is sampled from this pdf
f x now we call what we said
about independent random variables i think the first day a
is that independence means that the joint pdf for all of the x values factorizes
into the product of individual probabilities and so in that case the likelihood function would
simply be given by the product
over all elements of the data sample and here what i have the PDF four
x each time evaluated with eye
observed x value
right so that's relatively simple to compute in a computer program obviously
so now we have the likelihood function we can use that to two
define a prescription
four constructing estimators in the following way
the idea is the following is that this is the parameter that i'm considering
is is close to the true value
then i expect that to give a high
probability to to get data similar to the data that i actually found
and i tried to illustrate here this here on the left hand plot
but that's what i've done is i've generated some data points with a monte carlo
according to accounts in distribution
and take marks there on the x axis those represent the
x values and
for the true values of the parameters when i evaluate the likelihood function so the
the function from the previous overhead i get a certain value typically by the way
we don't report the likelihood function itself but rather the long it's more convenient to
work with the logarithm of the likelihood function so you i happen to get log
forty one
that is actually very close to the if i try to adjust the value of
the parameter so as to maximize the likelihood function is only a little bit higher
OK so the point i want to make here is that the
parameter which is true to the true parameter which is close to the true parameter
values gives very high value for the likelihood
one is it by the parameter far away from the true values of i try
to shift the distribution over four if i try to make some distribution much broader
than the true value then you get correspondingly lower values for the likelihood you can
kind of see how that works from the formula because what you do is you
you take each data point you evaluate the PDF
and you take the product
so here i evaluating higher number than i am saying
so that's just motivation really what i don't want to say is the following definition
we define
the maximum likelihood estimators to be those values of the parameter or parameters
for which the likelihood function is the maximum
that seems like a very simple elegant statement and so you might be able to
think that surely you can derive that's
to be
the correct estimator but it's not
right there's is no there's no such thing as the correct estimator or the incorrect
estimator i these maximum likelihood estimators are not guaranteed to have any
optimal properties in fact in in practice they
it very good properties in practice they are almost as optimal as you can get
but that somehow nevertheless has to be taken as the definition
you can make additional
you can actually if you start the company
micro computer
the fact that you invest now
four building it's another idea and so on open source you the option to actually
do a second generation computer
and that will open new scenario
and so on
scenarios have a probability
which is significant of failing with zero
again just cost but the fact that these are non-zero probability
i can give actually gain that would be discounted back
that's the real option
opening opening
was value and of course you can see that
you can dream and these people were dreaming about the excessive riches
that would come
about due to the the evolution of the internet and could basically justify any prize
that was actually the russian edition we have very good animals to rationalize things that
we and to reconstruct stories after the fact
especially story example that's a very nice example of of rationalization of which are now
to be
my own belief that it's all these arguments are correct it's simply a part time
scale we know
we know now that it takes time to actually exploded we can
there's been
but as for example in eighteen forty with the UK railway
in the eighteen seventy with us railway system
investors lost everything
eventually actually
let two extraordinary
advantage in the country but it took some decades to actually get to fruition
so i be continuing the discussion of the specific problem based on the fact that
i want to stress here which is very interesting the fact that
four inverse to
that's interesting for an investor on the that's my
the play a big role in all of that was studied and also the other
historians of the study
they come
in a kind of second wave after the started see of
good economy
economic positions
the come
rather rather in form of herding investors
i'm showing this quantitatively by showing you the net net
capital flow influence in the US
stock market
going from four outside the country
the forms of time
now look at
OK this is your baseline
look at the acceleration of the inflow
was of the order of you know of billions
tens of billions
two close to four hundred billion a year
think of the
the story of the importance of foreign investment
it has been demonstrated very clearly in the asian crisis
the above all in nineteen ninety four nineteen ninety seven
is the story also behind the bubble community in nineteen twenty nine they showed you
at the time the foreigners were europe and so on doing a lot of money
in this new economy is the emerging market
now if you go on and look at
many bubbles and crashes this is one subset
so we knew that we are dealing indeed with the
repetitive phenomenon you just put together in different colors too
i have some nice slide
a different
price trajectories that as i have translated in time so that they are all coincident
on this graph in terms of the time of the crash which is not really
all of these
financial time series crashed this time and the time spent about a year and a
and i just changed the order in a squeeze
by some of the transformation the
alternate which is of course always visible adjustment that i'm changing
the monetary unit
and i show here that these indeed
some commonality at least visually between
some of the crash is already discussed the others i did not discuss yet
for example the crash in germany and the US
associated with the
russian before the devaluation of the ruble that we see not as an extension that's
really linked with the global
also this picture work for currency this is
the above or if you like on the dalai lama community
i mean
maybe you would if you look at them you so i use that function
but apparently not very many other people do because
at this point somebody would have said hey we need that one
all right
now some people say oh why i do need that function
i we get you messages to mailing list people complain all i can do my
work because you don't you have provided for me this function
OK well maybe you can write it and
in a way that i was surprised to find that the overlap is very large
but we're still missing you know some now
i think that that's what happens is people do write the functions they need
they care about the there and then
i'm not surprised too much by the five hundred number and i'm not too worried
about it i think that
the idea that some group of people with
decide what we have to go and knock out all of those functions and get
them working so that people take us seriously and use our user software is kind
of crazy
so i'm not worried about it but i thought you should know that
overlap is pretty big eight hundred functions is all functions i mean you do you
can do some significant work with that
but it's not for everyone
there's octave forge in the package system we have so many other packages doing all
kinds of things
it's nice to have a tax system now because you can download it
file and install it and it's all taken care of you don't have to decide
or do i put these functions
how do i install not just past what do i do
the idea was also that octave forge which would become this huge sprawling
collection of functions can be broken up into smaller pieces and distributed
more i isolated
could be
you it's back
OK well
could be
broken up into small pieces and
maybe they could release
individual packages on a different schedule than
the entire
collection of octave forge packages which was becoming hard to do
parts of it would be ready for release but other parts were in and it
was never never seem to be a time when all was ready to be released
unfortunately it's really hasn't quite happened
and and i'm hoping that it will
if release management is what you like to do
instead of documentation
there's another job
you can work on
the next major release i i expect to see well but most of these things
are actually done
were released and then we'll find out what bugs are in
so smart object oriented features i was another thing missing some people like to try
to use that
part of my life
better looking
open GL graphics they are open based graphics renderer is in the works but i
don't think that's really going be ready for use by this time but it may
be a sort of preview of what's coming in the future we plan is still
the back-end for rendering graphs but it's not really
it's not really built for doing what we're trying to use it for which is
but the graph window on the screen
you know the pretty pictures instead
it's really you know it's a command line tool and so on and converting the
handle graphics hierarchy
in two
calls to new plot is not
particularly easy
it doesn't work very well
there's no single precision datatype if you want to save a little bit of memory
improved array indexing this has always been that i implemented the original original re indexing
stuff and i didn't do very good job so it was always slow and
complicated and slow
now you know it's his name is up here four times right
he just showed up last
february here january february
this guy is another one i think he sleeps either OK and he
these amazing is a lot of great work herself so
he he he made it you know if you use malabar data types they don't
actually lighter add subtract sixty four bit integer
his his going to do that now which is good he he optimise expressions like
a transpose a story transposed times b so that you
you don't have to actually form the transpose of a in or before the multiplication
he's doing that opposition he just recently added something on permutation matrix optimization so when
not when you do something like diag of the vector not storing a bunch of
zeros along with which is what i think about this
and then i always there are additional improvements incompatibility because people always come and say
OK i tried to my program and it didn't work
many aspects
but there's a lot left to do
a lot of people seem to want to have an an interactive development environment they
they want to be able to
i have active when they started pop up
graphical user interface and
i don't understand why
and you're out but they they wanted
i mean these are people who are writing these are people who are either getting
phd have phd
you other smart people and they apparently are afraid of the problem
i would ask them to type
i'm not trying to do this my users but you know this this doesn't make
a lot of sense to me but
i can understand the
it is convenient in way to have an interface that allows you to view the
command history separate from having the typist
but these are not to me
major features means that really is i can put it over the top ring and
take over the world because we have pain on the screen it has command history
over here
and the list of you know sometimes i think that if you if you just
put up the window that said
the that had
file edit
about are helper whatever you know that those three
people say are going great now i can do now i can do i work
things are more important to me are the graphics
the profiler people always want to know
which part of my code is spending the most time
so that's really important to me
some of really great to have a just-in-time compiler so we could improve the speed
loops for loops are always bad
you know very slow
but this is the gigantic project so
if you're a just-in-time compiler
that's another job for you
you know you don't like writing documentation are doing really smart and
then you can do that would be great
and but it if you're not of these things if you nice things interesting maybe
you can tell a lot of people here too
machine learning
things like that so domain specific packages there's thing that you can do you can
write some domain specific packages and make them available so
so that improve active in that way active community in that way
and you're so engaged with something that's going on your head you're on the way
and your so wrapped up in some issues going on work you drive onto the
from the path of your house is said
get here
you know that experience where time just goes by like that you're so engaged with
the problem well when you create an environment like that people get into what they
call flow it's like a resonance
when they don't
no this time go by
where they actually enjoy their work where they engaged with the work and to engage
with the leaders
leaders who create that environment
create an environment in which creativity thrives relationships are enhanced people work in flow productivity
how do you do that in several ways
if you're going to inspire people you better be able to communicate with them use
the interesting thing
the communication is not this sort of communication is not the i have been to
the top of the mountain communication it's the quieter
one on one
interpersonal communication
and i say that because you probably won't statistic are you would statistic
this research done that says that the majority of people fear speaking in front of
the group
more than they fear death
seen that they do the research every so often to give a list of things
they ask people to rank in order of which they fear and always comes lower
than speaking in front of a group of people
and the implication of course is next time around the funeral
this thing the guide up there making the eulogy would probably statistically prefer to be
in the box
rather than making the speech and i say this i say this point is important
the sort of communication
that is seen as being charismatic
is really the one-on-one required communication what we remember well of course remember martin luther
king's and john f kennedy is great speech makers we're really
as they say in the states where the rubber meets the road we're really happens
is one one
i was in istanbul two or three weeks ago
and i met a fascinating character in the the coffee break
and his job was he was a freelance union negotiators
OK so what but haney who was there with me called hired gun you know
like a gunslinger and if you had a tough union negotiation you bring this guy
and is very cynical really isn't
you bring this guy and he does negotiation for you and he was that
a guy with a legal background and humorist very interesting combination backgrounds very unassuming you
didn't look at them say i can see where he would intimidate me in negotiation
he didn't look like a heart as
he he looks alright now said
tell me about your job tell me about what you do
and i give you the long after short version of his twenty minute version is
that there are two phases in every negotiation to
phase one they tell us what they're going to give my client
extra productivity more hours more time whatever this
phase two
i tell them what my client is going to give them
synthase two is the most important the most important thing the first thing i set
out to do
when i start phase two before anything else i want to get those negotiator so
so crazy so angry and upset with me that they get up and kick the
chair away and leave the room
i want that to happen as soon as possible
as early as possible i am one of them lower red in the face with
as you know
what's that i see are horrified faces i'm not subscribing to this i'm just reporting
OK this is reported che can i see you know what what's the thinking is
that they're going to come in and they're going to say i give you that
and they're going to try and painted like it's size
and i'm going to offer them that
and he said all right let's suppose that you define as the measure of separation
the difference between the two mean values
divided by the sum of the two corresponding variances
that's one possible definition of what you mean by having a large separation between two
if you do that what the corresponding classifiers what's called the fisher discriminant and it
this is this is widely used i'm sure you run into this in
the analysis that you look at
that leads to a linear
decision boundary obviously i was going to give you a is going to the decision
boundary will correspond to a hyperplane in this in dimensional space
and there are few important cases where this decision boundary is in fact equivalent to
the optimal decision boundary that you would obtain using the likelihood ratio
the one that we would get from the neyman pearson lemma
it is equivalent to the neyman pearson statistic if the signal and background pdfs happen
to be a multivariate gaussians
with equal covariance matrices
so that's not
it's not often going to be the case
but it could be however that you might be able to a first transform your
variables in such way
that that criterion is at least approximately
so it's not it's not that these things actually are quite useful you might be
able to actually first transformed the variables in such way that it leads to the
transformed variables they look like multivariate gaussians
for which a linear decision boundary would work with work quite well
in general however the optimal decision boundary will have to be some sort of the
nonlinear things
and this is this is the big industry and we don't have time to talk
about this in these lectures much i gave a series of four lectures a few
years ago
on multivariate methods and i think the overheads are still on the web
and it is if you look in those lectures you'll see a list of other
references that you can find out more about
these various strategies for constructing non-linear decision boundary
you've probably heard of the number of the methods neural networks
support vector machines kernel density density estimation methods things like boosted decision trees
so these are all about
with the exception of neural networks these are relatively modern innovations and
and only in in the last few years have found wide application in particle physics
in particular boosted decision trees for some reason have become extremely popular
one of the reasons i think that these new methods have become popular is because
there's new software available for particle physicists there's this program called TMVA to package
it comes as part of route
so t
every package it has to start with the letter t right some rule
and NVA stands for multivariate analysis and
if you look at the problem sheet
number seven that i mentioned on the the web page just at the beginning of
the lecture that shows you a number of simple programs to show you how to
set up TMVA
and how to train a fisher discriminant or various other types of classifiers and so
if you want to have a play with these multivariate methods and then that's the
tool to use
there's another also by the way this right up the describes the package is
is good in two ways one it tells you how to run the program but
in addition it describes the mathematics behind these different methods really in very readable way
so i highly recommend this note that you can find in the archives
there's another program called statpatternrecognition which is also very good and in many ways complementary
to TMVA
but i think the support for that piece of software is
is is no longer is no longer being supported
it might regain some support sure
for many years amongst those those multivariate methods for many years the only sort of
modern one that was in vogue in
particle physics was the neural network so let me at least give show you an
example of the neural network
if you consider one of the things that we looked at the philip two program
in the nineteen nineties
was the reaction epoxy minus goes to w plus w minus
and one of the cases is that each of the w bosons can decay into
cork anticor
if that happens you get four jets
of hadrons coming out
so we want to select events of that sort
and then use them for further study we wanted to study the properties of the
w boson and measure its mass and invariance properties
now unfortunately that's not the only way you can get four jet events in epoxy
minus collisions you can have the policy minus goes to cork county cork
and then two more gluons get radiated and if that happens you also get four
but on average the gluon jets tend to have sort of a smaller angle with
respect to one of the core jets just the sort of distribution of energy and
angles of the jets is different depending on which hypothesis i'm talking about
so what we did is we cooked up a number of different variables that somehow
allowed one to discriminate between
the two hypotheses and they all have funny names like sri city and planarity in
thrust and so forth
and and here's what the distributions would look like for WWE events
and the open histograms the the white histogram is what you get for the QQ
gg events the other hypothesis and you can see that for any one of these
variables if you had to make cuts
you not get a very clean separation between the different classes of events
so what we did is we used these as the input to a neural net
and that works better that somehow give you a better separation
so in any event to find out more about the mathematics of neural networks
and all these other techniques i have to refer you to
if the lectures i mentioned earlier or this right up here
i think we'll have time to go into those
OK let me go on to another aspect of statistical tests
that is the following
so a statistical test as i defined up to now
it was simply a partition in the data space and depending on which
side of that partition
the data is observed you either accept or reject
a given hypothesis
but now suppose i simply say look i have a hypothesis
it predicts a certain distribution for the data
for some set of observations and now i make my observation i observe a single
this processes which we call to station
giving the excess energy into the lattice in the form of heat so we lose
this energy
photon energy into electricity
and when we have a photon that has an energy less than the band gap
then of course the
let's excited electron cannot reach
the allowed energy states so it falls down
and this photo is not absorbed
so we have two processes one is non absorption
photons that has lower energy
the band gap of the semiconductor and internalisation so actually losing the excess energy of
the photon
which is larger than the band gap
and these two
process is already accounted for about fifty five percent loss in conversion efficiency
and we call these spectral mismatch
between the band gap of the semiconductor
and the spectral distribution of the radiant source that i was discussing at the beginning
of this lecture
so just due to the spectral
we are losing
a lot of energy
now the transport i already mentioned that we have two mechanisms one is three
and one is
so you see
this is schematically using the band diagram
visualize the drift
and again
one important thing
when you look at the ben diagrams
up till now
these lines were straight
now you see that they have a certain slope
whenever you see have been diagram
let's say the
of the conduction band the minimum energy level of the conduction band and the maximum
of the valence band not straight lines but
there is some slope or shift
that means that you have electrical field in that area of
semiconductor or device
so when we talk about grief
it means
that's the motion of these particles in electric field
and you can see it by
looking at the
of these energy levels
it was then there is a slope there is electric field in this area of
the material or the device
very simple once you look at band diagram
and you do not see straight line you know in that part of the device
i have electric field
and then the carriers have to move by drift
and of course we can calculate so-called drift current which depends on the concentration mobility
and the
think of the electric field times
the unit of charge mobilities very important parameter i mentioned already
and the mobility depends on the phonon scattering so actually the vibrations of the lattice
then of course you can understand that when reading introduces impurities like doping items the
ionized them so they become
and of course this charge influences the movement of the particles when it is positively
charged it will somehow
attract electrons that move around and is negatively charged will somehow attract holes so then
we have a scattering these ionized impurities
you know the diffusion is the process
whereby particles tend to spread out from regions of high particle concentration into regions of
low particle concentrations
this process takes place
we understand
why when i say here we have ten to twenty
and here ten ten to ten
after some time we have ten to fifteen everywhere
OK but
that that's that
that's of course the force but
what is the mechanism behind it
so why they tend to go
that direction and all the other direction
but now
imagine we have a neutral particles so even though we have electric field the neutral
do not feel the electric field but still
they can diffuse
what is the motion
why today
not stay there fixed or fixed without motion
again we have this term emotions
as i was discussing was the vibrations of the lattice
not only
say the eight times
vibrate due to terminal
motion but also
these particles
there is still some kind of cultic
the movement
and of course this goes in all directions
but the ones i have
larger concentration than larger part due to the scouting movement will move in one direction
here then from this
small concentration here
so finally
two these celtic term motion
i will get
the uniform distribution
one of my
interior or device
so the term emotion is behind
transport and actually how quickly it goes
classification of legal documents and we found that
if you simply get
class of
document not based on the text but simply copy class of documents from other documents
that are linked with this document
you get the highest precision
so you can classify documents simply analyzing graph structured documents
not not that don't use any text features at all
links and hypertext graph is very useful when analyzing internet data
and we discussed in the first lecture that
our presentation of this type of data is some metrics as instance
matrix of links
well one is moving from one document to another
and this part
all the children born to discuss
how we can use this presentation
how we can prove present this metrics in men in our system
first of all
i want to remind you
that on the first lecture i said that
these metrics
once be the
it's obvious from this picture we have a lot of zero here or in the
but you can see that it's my example that i
draws include of the top of my head and in the real life maybe have
we're emailing graph of the internet
but it's not too true because
you know
that usually have
pretty small number of things from every page
and we have
power law distribution of number of links so there are some number of
pages that are extremely popular is a big number of incoming links
and we have a big number of pages that
i have a small number of things or don't have things at all
this is usually there is a lot of
the philosophy behind this
you can say that y
all this metrics of
so far
you can
talk about
physiology of human brain
that the always use this narrow that are connected with limited number of narrative that
looks like
the same model therefore are trying to build the same
the same type of graphs in the universe and we are trying always to repeat
the same words but really so we are trying to minimise actually number wrote that
we are using in real life so we're trying to repeating words but if you
use very small number of words
in this case it's hard to draw
distinguish them
therefore using such strange distribution of work the same situation is here
so we are trying to lean
as as less as possible at the same time trying to link to the same
important sites with the the same important page
and you can you can do a a lot of experiments try downloading part of
the web or using real document collections and you can see that this is always
just semantics is always very sparse
and you know how to present
sparse matrix
we can use the same inverted file with all this
started believe
compression methods
in this particular example
we create an inverted file
we're in dictionary actually it's ideas of our
and four in in posting lists for every for every
document we have documents
link to these are actually in this in this thread sorry i'm wrong in this
round documents that are linked from this document
and it's much more easier to be this inverted file this way because you
parsing documents
you get
for example HTML code of this document
extract all links
you are listening is key in some structure that returns ID's
so you
create current all the set of things to set of ideas
and for them into posting lists
and you can do
all ordinary compression that we discuss
because you can always start
this idea is
in increasing order it's against sequence of integers
that can be compressed extremely well
there is this open source project
and they
use this approach is is that called it's very onto their scores
very very close to make the call that we discussed
and they come kamprad
i just the semantics of a big part of the web using only about three
these apparently
so it
well compress information it can compress so
bridges small amount of
data multiply
so we have this
good presentation
so we have
we have the whole matrix of web
well compress files
and we can access from a document to all lanes that are going from this
because remember inverted file that going from g
posting lists only by every document can easily get all links from this document
i mean it
an example an example of such a link
graph analysis algorithm
and i wasn't there is i i decided to
take the most famous one because of good market one company
the most popular one is plagiarized
you can look into the this formula from different points of view
you can think of as the probability that some random walker who is visiting pages
on internet
the probability that
stop doing this
probability that a random walker
comes to some particular the internet
so you can things that if this page if this guy coming going from one
place to another
come to this page this page is more important there are much more
or or in our internet that comes to this page
or you can think about you can you can
think about this at the same time
using as as a markov process
is markov process because we're looking on into the previous patient going to the next
and in this case if you have a very good man to the ground to
consider all i see i can vector of our edges and symmetric on the internet
OK so
it's a very simple formula that
usually bar
a set of possibilities or some set
they can be thought of as an integration
that means you can just
kind of saint integral
so in some sense you can think about choosing
the set as
and the
probabilistic threshold p
together right and maybe even uniformly randomly
and there an or maybe going to greater whatever
but the point is that
this this principle
it all
the little information and a lot of places
it's better than
a lot of information in a few places
places in p
are places in as
it holds
and when use that to compute this
the number of runs of individual learning our
exit it turns out to be quite similar to the number of runs for if
you want some probably
somebody particularly getting an extreme version of this algorithm where
you take
a subset pick only one p subset
we learn
the different subsets
but the canopy
we learn
learn one
individual problem for p
in all these predictions school come together at the end
and compute that in
multiclass classification
now we have one last won the gold discusses the classification
this is the
penultimate one in a lot of ways because
because it's the classification can encode
since we
i think this kind of all in this way
because classification is defined by some measure
on tax cut
the vector of costs
there are some friends family discussed
but the it we evaluate
carlos is different
the station
a lot of stuff
we do that
this is vision
in this way
for this
these cells
it's all about
a two
well this is
it is
they have
lost in the first place
in the last section i
you can
and these two
and in one the
that is
only one
and each other the
optimizing the problem
we will all labels
what to do do
i think the whole
or in this case study
it is
was this
to make something like labels labels
how do
if you
the columns which i thing want to concentrate on the
relationship between the parameters
sorry that anybody slides
i'm i'm surprised as well
no this is and this is the lengthy mathematical proof which as i said
well yes but this is not is not to do with representing the space is
this to do with
how much bigger you need to make your network in order to achieve the same
level of reduction in some squares error
i'm not a hundred percent convinced by this
OK i many use to illustrate the
typically you will get away with much smaller
structures and you will infuse polynomial basis
the series RLC mean series
you might
it depends on how complex the function underlying function is of course is what to
do with how complex relationship is the
accurately representing the features in
and the date
but i i
i find this quite hard to to stomach exactly
it conveys the message
well yes so the
i i call it a malign relationship because the parameters
and now non linearly related to the output
hence the error
hence any function of error
rather more complicated than the nice bowl shaped function that we had
four hours
linear in the parameters model
the optimisation becomes much more difficult
this is not to do with neural networks it's to do with nonlinear optimization
in particular there are many possible solutions
that are mathematically
downward turning point
so yes so even with a linear output unit
the effect of the hidden weights in the output
is not linear
we're in trouble
his analysis this my peers to resist all aspects of
is the physical example
the nice linear in the parameters case k
one dimension we've got tonight quadratic error surface
if we rollerball down nice quadratic error surface
i was standing there when the accelerations and when the end
it rolls down it goes back to the for the but it gives up its
energy because the friction or whatever it comes to hold the only possible place come
so what does it sets off in the negative gradient direction
in reality
does a bit of this and then
at the point where
the gradient of j with respect to w is a good is there
we can mimic that everybody i hope those of gradient descent algorithm can resist
doing another one of these
OK we make the rate of change of the weights
with respect to time
proportional to the negative gradient directions so go downhill
and we step downhill
OK so we discretize the whole problem and
instead of rolling up the other side of it all this is just keep stepping
downhill until such time as it is unable to move
without going uphill and you stop there
we get a minimum point any real difficulty so even in the case when we
can't do
closed form solution we can still find these
quite easily with some iterative algorithm
given by something that looks like that
as soon as we have a non linear relationship between the weights and the
output then
everything changes and we wind up with cost surfaces that can look like this
very simple looking cost for the service here
i should say local minimum cut paste going
it is a local minima
OK here we have two downward facing turning points but actually there could be
any number of them
it could be any number of them all achieve global minimum as well as
a little bit tricky
so in this case
if we can only move downhill
wind up to at that point which is a local minimum not a global minimum
we start there
we wind up where we would like to be
if we start there we wind up we would like to be
and if we start there
we want what we don't want to be
the problem is
once again is being blind to all this
we have no idea where to start
this is a fundamental problem
nonconvex optimization are books and books departments devoted to people in the entire
research lines to the problem
it's fundamentally difficult
it's like trying to find your way down of the scottish highlands in the mist
without that
if you had the map
you know where the best answer was anyway and we can all go home you
wouldn't have to do any kind of optimization
we don't have the map
all of these
neural network all these multilayer perceptron things are
suffer from a slight problem that is you don't know whether you got the best
is the same thing in two dimensions i can make an animation that is the
same basic idea it looks a bit more like a mountain range now
when you start determines where you finish
a big problem
so i will assume that we're looking at minimisation
we assume that is analytically intractable problem which is for almost everything except for the
linear in the parameters sum of squares case
we step parameters downhill
that's the best we can do
basically a new set of weights is it which are also the weights plus a
step in the right direction
all of the techniques for doing this kind of optimisation error
matter of choosing a better step
the back propagation algorithm
one just takes steps that says what's what's the steepest direction to go in and
he was
discuss long before
the word wavelet ever got sort of
and nobody has paid any special attention or even probably noticed functions of one of
refinement equation with
nice numbers
but now
because we do notice
this with fixed a this line is
the solution to this
ways in with this with this very special or lowpass filter
so there's another example so all the
so the family of examples in other words
quadratic swine
q x y
we can do exactly
that's about the limit of
exact solutions i know less
well i just went by and said that what will work
what i'm after
have to
i would love to reason makes based system
to do that the idea think that an exercises professors
privilege right so i suppose i have
one lowpass filter
and the function field corresponds and just make a simple
keep the same coefficients
same function as well as
what about the coefficients come from convolution of this
my claim is that
the result was
from the convolution
was itself
so i
i'm not answer your questions
asking that you
there can no symmetry is built into this at all
although it's built into these examples
but do not make any assumptions about symmetry here
that's right
that's right and maybe i give away you might check prove first you could i
i pretty sure you to prove it directly
in the time domain
but probably
the convolution
better off get in the other domain right
in in frequency domain the multiplication
so let's see how i would get in the frequency domain good thing
all right so i could finish this formula
which would be the formula in the frequency domain
OK so let me finish
this is the product well who needs information from but
that's what it is
i mean the frequency domain so you will not be surprised to see the function
we called capital h
i make appear
remember when capitalize it was
it was the function
and all of them
which had
she says it's
capitalism and then you remember was
the size some of the coefficients
times either the minus j
using gene today j omega
finite series
this is a polynomial because soon thinking here if fire filters
remember a troublemaker
show me
the thing is
when i could take when i go into the frequency domain
OK to frequency scales
if have chance
for a transfer this skin
feeding on a free transfer this will involve the out of what
anybody know
it will be two omega
because somehow it flips the other way around it will be
feel out of over two
we can
we can easily do that and of course the book does
and so may or two and
and then
OK let me say it in words without
write it down but i'm willing to read
so the fourier transform of all right yes you're right with the fourier transform
that equation
the fourier transform of this equation is fantastic
put it in yellow
i like
so i'm taking the fourier transforms like the head my
on the left
speak to people you need on your personal scale of tend to do them just
the the the pay and the respect of just being as well turned out as
you possibly can just look the part
the second one is
i'm gonna touch and the moment a little bit more detail a little bit of
energy enthusiasm and here today to talk to you about christmas it's subject to really
gets me excited
and i've been excited by charisma for so long as i can remember god almighty
danny was saying to me in the break he said one of the most engaging
things when you meet a sales person who really believes in their product and around
the two thousand presentation you buy from almost just because of their belief
because of that enthusiasm because of that energy and where you walk on you better
like it's not the two thousand time you've done it even if you have you
have to give up some energy i've already touched on smiling just warming up again
keep it open if in doubt keep your hands out
so if you if you don't know what else to do with your hands just
keep them away
by the way
did anybody notice me breaking one of my rules during the break
one of the problems when you talk about body language is then people start watching
to see you actually practice what you preach
and what we are trying to get speakers sorted out over there was over here
and i found myself standing here way with my hands covering my genitals and i
looked around to see if anybody look
so i went back to a comfortable because one i'm in a room full of
people i've met many of you for the first time today
secondly i didn't know the technology was going to work and i was a little
bit nervous that the speakers wouldn't work
it even when you're aware of this stuff you can slip factor all too easily
so in the presentation if in doubt just keep your hands away from your body
is people have a clear view of the year solar plexus use eyes
just make eye contact with people make eye contact with the the the hardest person
to make eye contact with in the room
so find the person doesn't want to make eye contact and when you crack then
everybody else is easy
it feels easier honestly you get people just to give you this and i don't
care how long you look at me i'm not going to smile and they do
so given a little bit of what use positive language
i know it sounds terrible but you pick up a newspaper you switch on the
radio switch on the television in ireland there's as much negativity as you need to
last you a lifetime
you go to a presentation the last thing in the world you want is that
sort of negative language now
we live in a world where we have to deal with negative situations
use positive language to deal with it
get rid of the week native language speaking stories you've been spared so far i've
love stories about my father who was a little bit of
poor man's philosopher
and i like to use his stories to illustrate things people love points made in
stories love the made in quotations love the maiden similar the love the made indirectly
i think it may be appealed to the inner child or some such
how many people have
vision statement hanging in in the hall of the
the organisation they work for
it's not a trick question
OK a few
one of the things that i mean every organisation
it doesn't matter how small you are
it doesn't matter if you're one person organisation have some kind of vision statement says
that here's why i'm in this business here's what the long-term impact i want to
have on the world on myself here's why we exist
this is why we are here
and it's important because it helps you to define
well the organisation going to help you make decisions in terms of your mission and
how to make decisions in terms of goals but you should never delude yourself
that that vision statement motivate any more than the four or five people who put
those are the only people who in general are motivated by the guys walking to
work in the morning don't walk in signature after a and o
we will be the world's leading i feel much better now i'm ready to go
they don't care we don't care we don't care
until we know
what's in it
for us that's i said earlier when you
i want to share your vision of your department
the schools that you have for the year
what you expect from people and their contribution to it you better at the same
time as you tell them what you're looking to achieve the saying and here's what's
in it for you
and i talked about how you do that little bit more but let me just
go back
i think it's time that they were living at that particular time very everybody was
tremendously demoralized and when they come up with something is not only is that i
think about nineteen sixty two when he said in this decade
before the end of the sixties we put a man on the moon
now as it happens
the space program completely revitalized american industry and indeed the technological innovation had echoes for
thirty years after it i mean it just changed everything out of sight two things
he did their most important one is
he created something which was so big
so inspirational that it distracted people from the reality is around them at the time
henry ford said that obstacles are those terrible things you see
when you look down from your goals
and in the current climate people are looking down on all they see is obstacles
one rosalita first rule leaders one to create that picture
that very personal picture of a here's where it's going to be like
this problem here is where we're going to here's what we can achieve together but
then the second part is and what's in it for you
now in order to tailor your vision
for the people work for you you have to know that in some ways better
than they know themselves
you obviously have to know what the strengths
because you can not
talk to somebody about becoming all the people are becoming unless you know what the
people becoming you need to know what the development areas are
you need to know where they need to be buoyed up because if you know
that derek has a weakness in this by working with you in the service of
this particular goal that you're gonna races capabilities raises value raise his is general self-esteem
in general works well then he will engage what causes he had from self
is the bottom line
you need to know
every one of the people who work for you inside out because they don't care
about your vision
realistically they don't care about the vision of the organization b be on its capability
excel is already extremely complicated
let's just have a look at it
reversing the reductionist metaphore just to remind you that the main metaphor of the selfish
from his book in nineteen seventy six now they
j genes of course was in huge colonies safe inside gigantic lumbering robots that's you
and me
communicating with it by
tortuous indirect route sealed off from the outside world that the that is of course
the central dogma applied to the system as a whole
as actually show that's incorrect
they are in you and me that's the only empirical statement there and it's correct
they created us body and mind that the quote i used earlier on and their
preservation is the ultimate rationale for our existence and in case you didn't understand what
he wrote in his book the extended phenotype
just two or three years later he wrote the reader should imbibe the fundamental truth
that an organism is a tool of DNA
and not the other way round line going to carry out experiments on your
so very simple experiment except for the one statement that is an empirical state where
i'm going to turn those statements or upside down
and state opposite the experiment is this
this a challenge to you all
can you sing
of any biological experiment one could do any empirical test that would tell the difference
between these two statements services the alternative i call the alternative genes as prisoners now
they are trapped in huge colonies locked inside highly intelligent beings and then as you
and me
moulded by the outside world i reversed the central dogma
communicating with it by complex processes through which blindly as if by magic you don't
have to have that phrase in if you don't like it function emerges they are
in you and me as the only statements unchanged we are the system that allows
their code to be read the genome starts off in the next is the proteins
in the egg
initially coming across from the mother to initiate reading of the gene and their preservation
is totally dependent on the joy we experience in reproducing ourselves and incidentally is our
joy not theirs we
the ultimate rationale for their existence
and you can also reverse the statement in the extended phenotype fundamental truth is that
an organism is the only tool by which DNA can express functionality by which the
book of life if you like a particular metaphore can give DNA alone is in
fact dead
my point here
it's not
to convince you this metaphore is the better one
the selfish gene is that both matter falls
this is not biological science
there's nothing in biological sciences that justifies the centre selfish gene concept nothing in biological
science that justifies all the production is nonsense that we've heard
since that was published so let's have look at the question of unravelling complexity
i would suggest that we need to work in an integrative way
at all levels there is the original
reductionist this part
the bottom-up approach and what we've got to take into account causes the feed downs
as well as up between all these levels because systems levels control cell signaling
all levels control gene expression site reverse this arrow
it's the system that reads the you know
not the other way round
it's protein machinery of course that does that and very very important we're beginning to
understand the extent to which this as yet another dimension of complexity biological systems
and there is a genetic marking by all levels
so let's take an example
as the chairman said earlier on i've been involved in computing cardiac activity for many
many years
and what thing to do is take one of our models
of pacemaker is
and a cardiac cells is actually based on experiments done in rapid sign is now
and what we succeeded in doing is to reconstruct the electrical grid shown by
the pacemaker cells in the science of the rabbit
starting with equations representing some of the proteins involved potassium channel here which is also
lighting up and down in synchrony with the cell voltage the calcium channel was also
non-selective channels there are many others but shown three
for the sake of simplicity and being able to make the diagram comprehensive at all
it would look too complicated
when i showed this
a number of years ago to meetings of science
newspaper journalist in london in one of them for the following question to me and
said professor nevertheless beautiful reconstructions and indeed if you superimpose an experimental recording on
this theoretical reconstructions you can't put to tell the difference between them so you can
now tell us which is the gene
the pacemaker activity in the heart
so you
john too deep into the reductions agenda there's no such team
so we're it
the genes that code for each of these proteins
they also late in synchrony with the cell voltage
surely one or other of these or
a particular combination is driving the system
so you must be able all to
so now identified
the gene for pacemaker is in still haven't understood i'm going to carry out an
experiment to demonstrate why that way of thinking is wrong and can repeat the same
experiment performed for him
so let's start
before i start to talk to you about graphical models
we should first be aware there is material out there that very nice and covers
very well subject
so many good books for example i highly recommend chris bishop's book
it covers machine learning journal has a lot of the model
sold for introductory five for machine learning generally come in this book in particular that
the mothers as well
duty at scales book
it's a classic work in the field probably the first time the
that the
graphical models have been systematized in very
very nice work
also highly recommended
and the more theoretical book that covers the basics of the theory of graphical models
is defined more accessible
if it's free
the graphical model the graphical models chapter of this book is available
from chris bishop website
the charge OK
so but only the graphical model
chapter which for the purposes of these lectures of difficulty
so you can check
so there's also published material that people have been using a lot unfortunately is about
material not available in the one
have access to it
which is mike jordan's book called
book which i think has changed my life it's as well
and also there is plenty of useful if you can find videolectures
in particular recommends
some revised we do all sorts of being among the very nicely
you can check that
you know that don't
lots of good places to
to learn about
i did
an experiment just tried to
checked how many
pages that come up in google scholar search for
a bunch of different names
actually related to graph like come to EMI with hidden markov models
bayesian networks markov to form
it's quite a lot i mean this is
bit of data
because of this
it is like
not very recent so
so the numbers have probably was substantial
first question was not
heard any of these
any absolutely any of these
so we have one person who is and who hasn't heard of what what is
basically means is that
it's very
even though we have
and the thirty audience is is in general not familiar to
many many people have at least heard of
this one of these
although it's
good sign because actually all these things are very much for the the related
in fact many of these are examples of graphical models
so we'll just
in this course
all these
all these methods from a unique perspective from a unified perspective
no in fact
many of these are really
instantiations of modern examples of article it is
common field
hidden markov models bayesian networks markov random fields
and particle filters mixture models conditional random fields some of them like sampling
any other questions
please feel free to interrupt a time
so now why graph model so basically
it's amazing
the number of fields where this has been applied to k
image processing speech processing natural language processing
document process
but convinced by from computed in many fields outside of computer science
like economics physics social sciences
it seems to be quite general
mythological framework to actually analyse
in different
and i in different types
of the
before we actually start talking about graphical model is just show you pictures
of applications of graphical models what is this
so this this is this is an example in physics
it turns out that you can model how
materials behave using graphical models for example
here we have what they call a ferryman
in the left hand side is an example of the ising model
the ising model is essentially a model that
the fact that the joint
particles that are close
to each other they tend to have the same speed in particular type of material
it's been is basically orientation of the magnetic field
what's white not black here is essentially
atoms that have been one or money so that's basically saying
referring to be magnetized in one direction you action
what you can see on the left hand side essentially simulation
of the magnetisation of one of these materials
by using ising model
so what the ising model see essentially we have here in the bottom right-hand side
we for the representation of the magnetisation of every out which can be either up
or down
if you have a ferrimagnetic material which is
the example on the left it means that
this material will
three for
that neighboring
after all have the same
organization sort of words or or don't
that's why you can see this is what
in this image
this image is generated some kind of
let chance of leg
and contiguous chunks of white wine
because if one particular atoms wide
that the system will refer to the neighbor is also white
so that's why you have small
there's other the type material called ferrimagnetic material which is exactly the opposite
it's such material prefers
the neighbouring atoms have opposite spins
which is this case
so again please
these temperature
that's basically is
it's some models we are modelling basically how
we're using a graphical model
but we'll see later detail but essentially what you're doing is using a graphical model
to model the behavior of how
this means seen these materials they change according to the temperature if the temperature is
very very high
it doesn't matter which
what you have here
so any material inside the sun just evaporate right
so basically the more you become these are actually the more
objects in the images
and we get the size from the features section
is a using this example already these on the left here
this is recognised instances
of the object
OK found in these images
he is the same of model applied to the background sets OK so when we
apply the this motorbike model to the background we should find anything of high likelihood
and for the most part that's true
but there is one incorrect one somewhere here here's an interesting one
this as far as the models this configuration of detected regions look like a motorbike
in terms of spatial and appearance the other ones were
classified correctly
as background images
his face model
this is what i learnt across the faces in c
it learns are
some overlap
between the various parts here there's nothing to exploit that
aeroplanes you see this spatial model pulls out the fuse large type shape of the
aeroplane very nicely
red party it tends to correspond to the tail of the plane
now in the case of the spotted cats what's all-important is texture
if you see from the size of these ellipses the
aspect of the model is relevant larger structure part is irrelevant what's so important to
the texture
we in this example is an ordering constraint that's why on the in the extraction
that's why he's all aligned like this
and because we have a generative probabilistic model we can sample from
from models this is showing the same test motorbikes
some samples which
for the training images which were assigned to
each of these parts and sample of their various positions
some comparison with previous work so well
this is what his equal error rate
the various classes equal rate means we find many false positives false negatives so in
the case of faces
six percent of the background images
which had no faces in the set to have faces in the
and six percent of the foreground images which have faces
the faces were found again six percent means
and comparing this to around one thousand yes we do better
but that's just because we can deal with scale
you'd expect this was done a year later the would expect to be better
in some improvement over time on these algorithms
but in our case we using the same method recognised many different classes all the
same parameters
i want to give some idea of whether we benefit from having
the structure model which is explicit as well as the part model
experiences so these what is rather showing are where we learn
structure and the
so we learn
everything but then when we come to the recognition we switch off various terms
so in the case of the motorbikes if we
use the full model which has both the appearance of the parts and their spatial
distribution we get the best results
but most of the meat
into the recognition mister the bite comes from
the parents if we have the appearance only but no shape that's this blue curve
shape only
this integration so good we still do OK
contrast that with faces where if we don't have the appearance the result is just
pretty much the same as chance of the appearance is very important in the face
the i six
likewise in the left business spotted cats the position is is largely irrelevant we had
in additional information actually makes matters worse in this case because of this sort restraint
i mentioned
so we get some idea of the relative contribution of these parts
and the parent sorry in the confederations cup
because sort of half-hearted assessment and you've look you've learned
i know i mean the proper thing would be
which we haven't done yes we'll do is to both in the in the learning
just use parts and not the configuration and then in the recognition just use parts
of information really which we have to do that
probably the learning and recognition but what's going on here is well
we're just not taking when we fit the model when not taking any
account of say the
the appearance garcia that's what this means here
just giving some feel for
the contribution of the two parts of the model
obviously it's an interesting question how much the gain by having
the structure and this much has this tighter structure model which is what you can
talk about soft it
my understanding and this is what i focus and he
it is and that's what's done that you
you get the assignment of the parts to save so we just can use integration
as we assign the best part but we don't take into account the problem you
know it doesn't matter as if it when signed partners probability of how close it
is to the cluster centre we're not using that's happened on the assignment we just
use the configuration
we don't have accounts for
OK quickly going to talk about a couple of
all of this model
one is to loosen up the structure so so far we talked about it structure
which is a guassian jointly in the position of all parts
there's no reason why we can't have a slightly looser structure which is a star
where we only record the positions relative to some anchor point in this case x
now that there is no explicit
now model of the
gas gas
position between six one x five is already said this anchor point