think there is clear relation
but i think that
so i i don't know
well what we do know is that the training procedure is of course more complicated
something one single as you do this you
he said that
why i
so just it is the your creation
yes it is also possible that he was still
and how to design a kernel
this is also still a research issue
so i mean by saying that that we should you design quite a few kernels
but we want to be very careful is what we have you write function you
make sure this is a very nice products of two many functions
four so the function is even
if you think b
they should be evaluated kernels but they are not
it is also difficult to give you an example
forty two strings strings as well as so there's something called a distance to this
is the thing
so that we can define could be like these
explanation by
it is in this sense of this one and this is in this case the
reason for that is for the probability that the outcome is the same as is
he said that he distance with gradient descent
is this something
true but is not
so this is a
so you want to be careful
you're using
let's function looks like to one but sometimes it is not
so it is
so that they do you have a question about how to shape with
function is very well or not
if you importance you mention is a condition called mercer's condition so they
it tried tries to address the issues of kind of chaotic represented for that so
the conditions is for function k is can be represented as using the product then
there's no conditions say that fall function g four g such that this integration is
finite then if you could escape into this integration should critical to zero
this is actually a condition to develop an interesting nineteenth century has like one hundred
years ago
the problem is it is also easy to cheque this condition so
four four
the kernels this is used to show you
is very powerful some others then you have to use other techniques to those
OK so so so so this point and finished discussing parameter
the kernel selection and quite a few practical issues
so questions so far
raise your
it has around
well yes and no
if you the computational
you can try to agree to search so that's the way it was simultaneously check
everything and you give you good parameters set
you don't have
you don't have so many resources so
i mean if you don't have many parameters you have only one parameters
you need to try several points
that will give you a good parameter estimation
so in that sense he is that sort
when you a simple program they use the discretisation of parameter
you check cross validation accuracy so that's the program to automatically select parameters for you
but you have more parameters than it is more difficult
that's why is
is it
well little OK
there are some studies about that stands but the problem is a series of it
is there's ever seen that it's usually the number of support vectors is being increased
as well as the number of training data is increased
so so that since then
there is no direct relationship with number of support vectors and the performance is the
number of support vectors is related to the number of training data
but maybe
some kind
so for example the first person to really think percentages
well that's several hints for example you if you all all training data had to
be support vectors usually
this is the situation where we're thinking and
so you don't that
that means it is
it is OK i thirty percent training data support vectors and the sort of performance
good that we i don't know
necessary so we can see is usually if you tried to set the parameters you
it's just just came up with the fourth edition
and so on
that book was a bestseller
i think it's all over half a million copies
i'm not sure where it is now but it has done very well it's been
a perennial classic
and it's really it's it emphasizes the long-run performance of the stock market but it's
really a
treatise on financial markets
and i i get a very good reaction from this
students for this but this one is
very readable
it's not so intense as proposed
jeremy siegel has the unique distinction
business week asked poll asking
NBA's who was their favorite professor
this is about ten years ago
and they rank
business school professors
according to their popularity came out number one in the united states
as business school professor
and so i think you will like this work with the next work is my
own called irrational exuberance
this is the last book
that's the phrase
that was coined by
alan greenspan
in nineteen ninety six
and refers to the stock market boom
of the
two thousand
one of the nineteen nineties and the the boom-and-bust but i think it's related to
the bus that came out later after two thousand
i wrote this book in two thousand
right at the peak of fortunately right at the peak of the stock market
but what i'm saying to you is the second edition which came out in two
thousand five
pretty much at the peak of the housing market
and so we're going to talk about
both the housing market and the stock market
in these different books
these books are all on sale labyrinth books
which is an independent bookstore
here in new haven i put it there because
well i think
the major chain bookstores
fulfil an important function but i'd like also to support
independent bookstores
and if you know the story labyrinth books
is independence not change
and independent bookstores trying to struggling to survive this is financed in the book business
there's something
about maintaining an independent operations of the labyrinth was at columbia university
and you
for some reason they shut down or columbia bookstore but they've opened up now
in principle
there was this famous bookstore conference on nassau street called the commas
which is wonderful book store in there
number of times
but they just went out of business so labyrinth has moved in to take their
anyway that's where the books all the books are and
and a i checked there are available now them
we're going to have
these lectures on monday wednesday we're going to have t actions
the second part of the week
we're going to ask you to look at your schedule
sometime before next lectures and think about when you can come to the teaching assistant
but they will be wednesday thursday and friday we have six problems that the six
problem sets are due
and generally on mondays
so will go over the problem in the teaching
a couple days several days after you turn the man
this is one of the biggest classes yale but i think
we've got
i think we've got it so it would be good and satisfying experience with you
we have
very qualified
i'm very impressed her teaching assistants the important thing is for you to
stay with them
and get to know them
and i urge you to attend the interior sections
the course is going to be graded we have
two midterms and one final in class mid-terms
the grateful beasts roughly ten percent problem sets
twenty percent first midterm
thirty percent second term forty percent final
but nonetheless we also use judgement and i'm going to appeal to the TA's
to help me and judging
i also asked the teaching assistants to give me little capsule descriptions of u
so that ten years or twenty years from now
and i get a call from a reporter
asking about this illustrious person who was once my students i can have some in
the primary
so that's why i hope you'll stay with what you need to find teaching assistant
will stay with that person
i want to say something about
one particular interest of mine
because is part of this course
this one is
extension on the right
the rule gn
is introducing existential on the left
the is are on the right again
and here
this existential on the right
together with contracting two occurrences of the same formula to one which is just set
combinatory properties of sets
how do i get the FAI just threw it into free
if you like that comes from the
be by throwing in junk on both sides
all right
it's not obvious but it's a it's all legitimate you know within the meaning of
the act is proof
and you can do it from the axioms the health system if you really want
which i really don't
that's the theorem of the logic
the not fact about logic
that i want to observe
and that's
something called the rule
of choice
absolutely nothing to do with the axiom of choice
i was ages ago there was no office ten
this is the rule of choice
route choice is used a lot in mathematics
in mathematics you get to a point where you have proved the existence of something
you say let's call it
and you go deduced deduced its nutritional properties of whatever
and then you say
so that force
as long as what you called it didn't matter
you can choose an a
that's that's the logical principle suppose that from somewhere or other you're deducing you get
an existential
you've proved from whatever you start with such things exist
is a let's choose one
let's call it
well introduce a constant
just as erotic a function similar
a school it's a
and from that you get some conclusion
you can conclude
the b halls
this is no funny business
OK it provided see doesn't occur in the conclusion
provided that neither b
nor any other side assumptions that use made any assumptions about c
claimed to so
the idea is that this deduction doesn't
in the way depend
on what name chose
maybe secret gamma i don't have any way i mean
let's TV something that's completely foreign to the context maybe it doesn't even occur in
i if you like the and you can always choose the constant completely outside the
so if you if you join the existence of something from wherever you going you
can always pick one give it a name
get a conclusion as long as that the depend on what name chose
so is see doesn't care anywhere
then that shows this falls
and if you need any side assumptions here will they stay as well
this rule of choice it's plausible that holds i'm not going to establish that it
but it does
right i mean you can you can work
all right that's a little bit of useful
back in the logic
probably the on
was like to do with completeness
while nothing yet
we're going to to
we've got a consistent set
we could work linden baum's lemma again
and we could blow it up to a maximal consistent set
but that's sort of wouldn't help a lot
because in first order
logic maximal consistent sets
don't always have the nice properties
well don't have all the nice properties that we
like to get completeness theorem
they behave like they do in propositional logic with respect to the connectives they treat
negation probability they treat implication of the tree
conjunction disjunction in just the truth table way that's fine
but they don't
i have strong enough properties to handle the quantifiers correctly
right what we would like it is
that we would like
when we
got a big delta
the something like for all x a
is in delta
if and only if
eighty four x is in delta
for all
for all t such that
good things
quality we like
so that's a is going to
if and only if
for some
appropriate t
some instance of it is in delta
how big set would not only true the connectives in the truth functional way that
we would like it will also treat quantifiers in the way that we'd like to
be able to cook up
an interpretation is going to do all the tricks
but that doesn't happen it
this is
you see this one one one one one one one six six
so we got this one or not is professor
stanford was already been published but
first of all you can see the
similarity was presented by the united states
this is why
but you say i follow pass
he was this one
he also go through the page
article operators will be able to be
this is a visit each to go to the same set of conferences
this was far from the
most similar ones that
i really want to be in the past before the
conference of these we publish the same set
they systems
sigma here's a nice properties so there was a really hard to come by a
lot of work to be we should also similarity that's why because of those cells
this is very similar to the one on a
then at the origin nature of those guys
what's called parents
you can see this
alternative is a key here is
you would found find a reason
the reason is
OK well before i went on frequent pattern for this is of
there's a lot of work is so
we share the same scene conference brochure
since we know what this
it can be
the other
so you can see that
one on
some of them
so you can see the very subtle differences
doesn't seem to be so you get into these you used
try to find out what was about
this very interesting because the same
in a essentially
you want to
she was here
she got this paper
she tried to rediscover the
i was young stars fear
this is what is most
then he to his own surprise surprise she
by child child nodes also this problem
he actually also guessing he
the best of
maybe that's the key
in this region
o hours
you got
five years
this the system to mission
OK you you can see the first phd policy they wasting money more or you
it's probably the most one two
stanford one
mission was the very reason
this is the flying to our surprise
you can find this
what was the matter because of the same set of conferences using you know something
that's that's not problem
she actually went back to school
this flow
she was playing flickr
the network
that user group
this is a star network schema
the schema
she took flowers lotus flower
so this flux in which features most
to this block
she used two different as well as the ones he i i i g
our expense with this one
i mean is
this shows
he's tag if they share same similar partial is i'm only one or two
find pictures
the picture is not that you mean by by saying this flower flower as follows
OK that looks like
lotus flower anyway
just because they have to act something that some of the five
but if you go to school i actually here is one of the things you
go down here you go down here
this one and this one
you take the rule also clustering
four users sign
he said well i mean this was one
many users
many had received right away
but like me probably more people had this one flower
the handle
the full analogy
an allophone really is a predictable phone phonetic variants of a phoneme
phonological rules
applied to phoneme strings to produce actual pronunciations of words and sentences
so there are a number of phonological rules that that are typically applied assimilation for
the spreading of phonetic features across phonemes the sequence of words this wish
for example
i might spread
so that might become this wish
in it is i would pronounce it i've actually assimilated a phonetic feature into the
last one of the first word
this table at the bottom here represents exactly an example of flapping
the word city here in a funny make representation i might transcribed that the dictionary
using a t
but the flapping rule tells me that any
inter vocalic t or d might be pronounced as d
and so that that would appear as phonemic representation the city
the vowel reduction rule here i would change a of OWL two
a reduced vowel in an unstressed syllable so in example here for the word for
knowledge e
i would pronounce satisfy analogy i might say phonology so this is an example of
applying sort of vol reduction is as a phonological rule
rushing through the archive of
there we go that was your introduction
two distinctive features and
for anybody any questions
that having raced to that so quickly any questions on that
the big problem dictionaries i think professor why will actually alluded to the issue of
of dealing with canonical baseform dictionaries
and this this little figure here
gives an illustration of the problem we have
and using in trying to
use canonical dictionary is in speech recognition
and i refer to canonical dictionary is basically being those baseform dictionaries that we we
pose as a set of rules before we start before we
we we build our system and the surface form variants are those that we might
consider to be
one allophonic very variants or
as they would actually occur in the acoustics when we were of the work
i could think of of having
some here expanded in terms of its canonical phonetic baseform just sequence of n phonemes
so for any particular phoneme k
there may be some pronunciation variants of that running
that let's suppose i have
dozens of examples of utterances of this work
i have my linguists go through and label
are label those utterances according to
the actual pronunciation that is perhaps i in i had an utterance of the word
city and i didn't actually other that we didn't actually say city
i said city
and so
linguists with label that or perhaps i was speaking particularly fast i might have deleted
a phoneme altogether and so we can actually label that the another is according to
its pronunciation variants
having done that perhaps i could then
produced separate acoustic models
with whatever my favourite modelling form formalism is
that will describe these various acoustic variants so you would think is great
now i can represent
this word in terms of how it actually appears in in real utterances and i'll
build a better speech recognition system the problem is is
i don't know how
in in
how to predict those pronunciation variants during recognition
given this lexical base form
well i might have a phoneme k is one of the
one of the phonemes in this space form expansion i don't know how to pick
the proper
the proper the model associated with the acoustic variables that might actually occur
another illustration of the problems with dictionaries let's suppose i have this sequence of words
purpose and respect
and i had the basis for
pronunciation that i would have pulled out of my dictionary
and i would also help let's say the surface form
pronunciation that my linguist would have labelled from the actual occurrence
of these the surface form phonemes are the surface form
phones in the
actual utterances and so what we see whether the
sources the difference between the two well i can see here for the word and
i've deleted in this particular is ever deleted the d
i might have also
so strictly is simply had a pronunciation variants here i'm instead of pronouncing i might
have said and i could also have various other surface acoustic information that might not
even be represented in my baseform dictionary for example
the linguist might label a for each
constant the
closure and the release
whereas typically in my
lexicon i would just have a phoneme there representing that stuff
there's all sorts of things that are going to appear in my surface form representation
that might not appear in the base form
and you say well
great let's just make a bigger dictionary
and know if i got if i've got this different pronunciation of and let's slap
it into the dictionary is just thrown in there but what i've already got
the were and you
that's got the same
if i phi slapichyn
this additional potentiation
four and was going to get this ambiguity
same thing if i if i have the word had and i try to throw
in a a pronunciation variants for that well that's going to overlap with the the
canonical pronunciation for heads
so as i simply try and add in these pronunciation variants in my
i'll increase the coverage but i think going to introduce the this ambiguity among my
dictionary entries so you see the problem
and so you have to be clever about doing that and
waiting your pronunciations and so on our our our
one of many ways to
to try and deal with that problem
well any NEC gets even tougher
OK here's a member of the results here that that make it even more grim
for dealing with these problems with dictionaries if i talk faster if i increase my
speaking rate well increase the number of words per second but the number of phones
per second might stay roughly the same so i'm going to be deleting all these
so velocity they are easy as long as they are along the line of sight
if you're transverse velocity in cosmology those
so let's come back to our wobbles look
the reality is called below but we should
that in reality he was best the sleeve that the working with table in the
same cemetery between nineteen twelve and nineteen twenties found that most galaxies in the light
of most galaxies were shifted at that time there were not called galaxy they were
called memory and people didn't really know what they were they they know if there
were something close by that you had to avoid when he wanted to study comments
or whether they where all the island universes
well there no big objects like our own universe which by that time was our
and so
that was the first state all look all this never seems to have the light
mostly shift rather than blue shifted
and and why is that
if i interpret it as if he was the velocity then it would have to
write this kind of equation and it
it turns out that the velocity there
so these are the kind of images not exactly the same historical images but the
kind of in
images they could have got to
first of and and edwin hubble
in order to see it actually that's all you just have a galaxy you put
to sleep through the galaxy the light to get started and so this is the
image of these kind of galaxy and then you see the assumption lines
the PS and then get move with respect to
rest the position what it would be interesting this different galaxies
right and this is the spectrum and is the same feature
gets moved
and so we came up with a velocity well OK i'm going to make this
connection between
and this is the galaxy the farther away they
the fact that the the fast and this seems to be going away from me
and so say the well she
i interpreted like velocity and i put constant here
and a connected to the distance because when i plot my points it looks to
me more or less straight line
and this is actually what are born
the is there are no about in this blog
in cosmology has been like that for many years and the enormously before yesterday
right you get your
wind in the arab world that's too hard
so this is
actually hubble original number and he came up with a value for this hubble constant
of the order of five hundred now today
the latest that tell you that is of the order of seventy four which you
know a few percent error bars
and so basically today the plot to look more something like that but he was
right there is basically a linear correlation between velocity
the recession velocity and distance so thank you to edwin hubble we can measure distances
relative ease in cosmology
once we measure
well calibrated
they what is called the cosmic distance ladder
measuring the value for the hubble parameter
so let me take a very brief as i mentioned something about the great debate
in the twenty you can find more at this link so the debate was between
sharply in court
that they were arguing whether those who never really where
never that you have to avoid in order for you to be able to study
comments and they were you know like
clouds in our own universe or whether those nepalese where
so far away but the small enough to you but they were really big and
they were basically like our own universe our own galaxy and they were called island
universes and oblong in nineteen twenty four closes this debate by saying you know
galaxy doesn't mean universe
the universe is much bigger than one and galaxies all those nebulae or the island
universes of the galaxies and i actually can classify them
and he had to sons theory on how galaxies were born evolve which
the double classification still holds today
so you see how many things you need to do in order to get the
telescope named after the
they have always very useful because it allows you to determine distances
with some caveats however because you are you are interpreting the recession velocity as these
stands but you know the universe there is gravity acting their own galaxies are not
isolated we've seen they live in groups and clusters and so
if i'm an galaxy right
that i think i should follow the hubble law but there is another massive galaxy
nearby me there
then you know
and they follow a little bit into the other galaxy because of gravitational attraction and
so you expect to see some scattered around the table and you may expect to
see some galaxies to be blue shifted rather than shift that you know if there
is a big master that the men this happen to offset
what is the background hubble functional look
but the next key point is well
if you're not a special place in the universe
then it means that the if i would like to sit in a different galaxy
and repeat the operation of esther and and and harbor
i should still find that all the galaxies are not flying away
so basically
the conclusion is well maybe just this will happen if the universe is expanding
and imagine you are making a cake
and making you know you put in the
the k can be of any put some raising it when when when the k
crisis will happen to the raising they all fly away from each other
so imagine that there is that galaxies and the the cake is the universe is
expanding then this is what you would see
but this will bring us into our conclusion that the universe is expanding so it's
not static
help us to coding
help us get rid of all the noise
and the output noise in quotes here
so i see a happens to be a method that can be used but rather
for the methods that can be
placed like and you see another others
i will not go into
this part in detail
so when when you saw
we need doing
the brain pong game
i was using one particular
which is pulling the strings
there's lots of other possibilities
so our subjects they typically think about squeezing the ball
kicking a ball some
you know resilience of subjects would always kick aboard
they feel touch feel since feel heat whatever
so this is something some kind of imagery that you would be using
if you
look at this slide
god has pointed out that there's some desynchronisation
if you say if you close your eyes and i
i'm doing here this is
the picture is that the
again not gave me
so then this some of activity
if you
open your eyes again this idea rhythm is suppressed
and this suppression
over them
this is something that we
we'll be using
most of what what comes in in this talk
so now
but we not be using the ideal rhythm suppression because we have all eyes open
now i mean we are
actually using
the ideal rhythm
that we have when when we have some motor
actually or
all motor imagery
so because
for places on the dressed there's neither rhythm over the
of the motor cortex which is naturalized if i move it to its attenuated and
the same thing is actually happening
if i'm just imagining this
here's one
view of
the problem with variance
we we see many single trials
i think
fall of it's clear what the difference between single trial and averaging as
i mean if you if it's not clear to you then you can look at
the slide
the solid lines are the averages
not so solid lines
the single trials
if you look at this from the math perspective
and to you
i had an explanation from god will
you can actually see so you
if you imagine
lieutenant then there should be some activity on the right hemisphere
if you look at this on several different try as you can see that there
is some considerable variation in this
this is one subject imagining across different single trial
this is right and left imagination so it's it's
why did
bit of the challenge
and this is
some more
subjects but now
on average
over many trials
you know all these two plots on one subject and you can see that no
subjects are like and they all imagining left versus right
i mean of course the conclusion from that is you have to deal with the
variability and you have to to use machine learning for that
because its primary tool that we have in our hands
and just
to just spell out what what we do
first of all we have to tell the machine learning algorithm what what the brain
is doing
if you
we do
right here
and we
these are
the rule
or maybe that is not that there are
well i
all right
o he
OK a
thank you very much
they are
or at
you know
so the
all that
so far
we've seen a new representation called markov logic
it's very nice because a it's very simple
markov logic is just first-order logic with what's on the formulas there's almost nothing to
learn it in the first order logic
and it's also very powerful because a as first order logic is a special case
as we just saw
it also has most of the graphical models that people use a special cases so
it's both very simple and very general and that's nice
but without efficient and effective inference and learning algorithms this you know is only of
theoretical interest so let's start by looking at the inference problem
and again here what i'm going to do is i'm going to start with logic
the kinds of you know things that techniques that used for inference in logic and
and see how we can extend to do probabilistic inference
and in logic because as i mentioned people to tell you one as entailment queries
there's this clearly follow from this knowledge base
and this is usually done using theorem proving
the improving is one of the most intensively studied problems on earth but most theorem
provers follow the following scheme
so i'm given a query in a knowledge based on what i do is i
negate the query and i added to the knowledge base
and then i converted that to CNF
and then i check whether the resulting CNF is satisfiable
satisfiable means that there is at least one world one assignment of truth values to
the atoms that makes
all the formulas in the knowledge base true
if there is no such a satisfying assignment that means that the negation of the
query is incompatible with the knowledge base and therefore the query does fall from the
knowledge base
so this is what is called proof by refutation
and you know most theorem provers work in this way
notice that all the hard work is being done by by this call you to
say that
so that is the function that i give it CNF and it tells me where
there is satisfiable or not
and of course that is that when you know the quite essential NP complete problem
so there's no guarantee there is no way to solve it efficiently guarantees but there's
a lot of very sophisticated technology for solving SAT
and the most widely used technique for solving SAT is what's called the DPLL algorithm
which there are many variations DPLL is is short for the
names of the authors davis putnam large man and loveland
here's how it works
and this is important to note because this is what we're going to be building
so the the bare bones of DPLL is as follows
you give me a CNF
and if CNF is empty i just return true because there are no conditions so
any state satisfies the CNN
on the other hand if CNF contains the empty clause
then i return false
because it means that there is no way to satisfy the class so there's going
to be one unsatisfied clause
so these are the basic cases of the recursion
now here's the recursion
the recursion is choose an atom a
and there's very plus various possible heuristics which is in the attic and then what
i need to do is i'm going to set the atom to true
in the CNS
simplify the CMFA
and also
with the simplified formula
and if that returns true then i know that there a satisfying solution and a
return true
if that fails then i said it to false
simplify the CNF and calls again
and again if that is true then i know that this is true if both
of them false then i know that this CNF is unsatisfiable
so this is the basic algorithm that we use for satisfiability testing
now what we saw is just the propositional case but in general we want to
do inference in first order logic
so how can we do that
well there's two basic ways the first and most obvious one is propositionalisation
as long as we have a finite domain
i can just form on the ground atoms by you know putting all the classes
into all the predicates arguments have large propositional problem and i just apply propositional theorem
prover you know i use DPLL or something like that
so it in the integral from minus infinity to plus infinity video
multiply by
he was powell minus omega
in the world
joseph the following
at the same point in time so he sought to more hope it will be
to be so
so that's
what will happen with this
when you when you look at the atelier of
at all
toilet twenty that so let's take something which which is the building which is invaluable
so there's something which receive light you some electrical signals from it
and the motivation of this they are
it's just
account for each time you receive like you will have account been there is
as the capacitance
what you want to get to know to get votes about
as an output so that you can manage things that
a very simple thing to do is to is to use the US
you want to voltage converters neural systems so let's say you put stuff
molecule with still to it
and then you can
we can wonder what is
what is the speed at which the interior
it is
none of the formulas are going out
and you will find that
the output of that in the frequency domain is is the function of the
i supplied by the by the capacitor is supplied by the capacitor is called the
fall of the function
so then we have to
two were but which is that we take the magnitude of this this
concept function and reproduction in the log
and then you will see that in fundamental frequency what will be the way would
polls for function which is just silly
below the so-called we have defined as a product of
but still lives in the first round
you've got the one molecule and after that
he starts to decrease so about not just an asymptotic representation of it which is
just quite line
just assume that to support your local public goods
and you have got a three DVD films between the maximum blood on the the
real thing which is that when you are just before
so the first thing that is in some ways with frequency and when you are
the the phase of the existing nodes is moving by minus forty five degrees
if you put to sleep on this particular frequency input
what we have chosen this frequency is is about a hundred and sixty kilometers so
you put fifty input
you put a hundred and eighty two that time you see that you start to
lose some of the should because because you start to be
on this
in this region
and if you go higher
which is a five hundred kilowatt you've got almost nothing because you used to be
a little
law and in this
so the best response in if you
i replied to fill that gap
one of the system which is what is the time response of the system you
just have to make the
four you from
this this is a new we define an exponential
since you put been in the input of the cell c and this is what
you get
it goes up and then it goes on this
ossie osborn time which is one of possible
and then if you put those
so in fact but so you have at the input something which is way
the instead of the following day is input it would be
it would be
slaughter on the same for going down so that comes from the idea but this
is the that is about two point two
the bank and in this case it to point to make poster
and of course
with this kind of things we can only go ontology dlb festivals when the PIN
diode was given to be able to get to get involved so it means that
we are far away from what we want
it means that a signal still is not good
the you don't have to
after the second i know even if you want something working properly then if you
stand on the on the optical links on a succession of ore one of the
and you will see something like that
and this is called an eye under the good a good quantities of quality of
a competition like this
is given by the opening of this
so feedback
that's the bottom some formal education because the next step would be to to amplify
so here is it since been you've got an input and each time you
some about
so from two weeks you've got
thanks to what you want to go to the petition as well and then
if i just your
no it's not a course title
good you point here which is just
the multiplication
the public goods input with all this he felt about
it did
we we close it then it means that we get from the output a function
of the output on the input and we make found so the equation because lies
at this point six is of course the edition of the input but that that
but also with us if you remove a fraction of the output and then if
you compute everything you find something like that which is
this is the feedback
what what does the feedback is that the electronics for this new is just an
to be done
is the feedback loop
of these three signals and one signal is sitting here one zero zero one is
sitting in zero one zero one is sitting in zero zero one
even i can calculate the mean of those three it's one thirty one thirty one
so you calculate the energy in one thirty one thirty one third and three times
one nine four one third
which is exactly what this a free energy differences between orthogonal and simplex
is one minus one over in other words that the factor
and energy that you lose by using orthogonal codes instead of simplex code
why do people every is orthogonal codes
if it's just pure loss in energy in doing so
one reason is when n gets up to be six to eight
it doesn't amount to a whole lot
and the other reason is
if you look at
if you look in modulating these things and assign weights and things like that
you you suddenly say
the one you're using this
it becomes easier to keep frequency locking phase lock
and it does when you use this
we have to think about that argument a little bit to make sense out of
it but that in fact is what people often use orthogonal signals
because in fact they can recover other things from it
well because they're are actually sending the mean also
and the mean is the thing that lets them recover all these other neat things
so that sort of
sometimes rules out this and sometimes rules that
OK orthogonal by orthogonal codes have the same energy
well look at them
these cues signal points each have the same energy and
these two have the same energy is these two
so the average energy
is the same as the energy of each point so this and this have the
same energy
what happens to the probability of error
we can evaluate it exactly
except here's the case we're just looking at the end of two case gives you
the right answer
i mean here to make an error you have to go
across that boundary there
here to make an error after either go cross that boundary we're go across that
their probability essentially goes up by a factor of two
same thing happens here
you just get twice as many ways to make errors carriages you had before
and all of these ways to make errors are equally probable
all the points are equally distant from each other so you essentially just double the
number of likely ways you can make errors and their probability essentially goes up by
because up a little
well because the you think about goes up a little more a little less than
it's it's almost
OK so i want to actually find the probability of error now
if you're sending an orthogonal
namely we take an orthogonal codes where we pick as many codewords we want to
and might be sixty four might be a hundred and twenty eight whatever
we want to
try to figure out
how to evaluate
the probability of error for this kind of code after you face the fact
that in fact
these lines are not orthogonal to each other
OK well where you do this
as you say OK
even though
even though this is a slightly messy problem
clear from symmetry
but you get the same error probability no matter which signal point you said
namely every single point is exactly the same as every other signal point which you
call the first signal
it depends only on which you happen to call
the first author normal direction whether it's this or this or this
i can i can change it in any way i want to win the problem
is still exactly the same
OK so what i'm going to do is try to find their probability when i
say this signal here
well over twice and one zero zero
actually understand the square root of a zero zero because i want to talk about
the energy here why my torturing you with this
well fifty years ago fifty five years ago shannon came out with this
smartalice paper
which said there's something called channel capacity
and what he said channel capacity was was the minimum rate
he was the maximum radius which you could transmit on channel
and still get zero error probability
sort of the simplest and most famous case of that
is where you have
white cassino ways to deal with your trying to transmit through this way cassie always
and you can use as much bandwidth as you want
namely you can spread the signals out as much as you want to you can
sort of see from starting to look at this picture
but you're going to be a little better off
for example
if you want to send one bit
in these two dimensions here with orthogonal signals
if you can think of what happens down here for m equals four
you would wind up with four orthogonal signals
and if you want that was for orthogonal signals
you're sending two bits
so you can use twice as much energy for each of them so you can
scale each of these up
to be
two zero zero zero
two zero zero and so forth are sending twice as much energy
you're filling out more bandwith because you need more degrees of freedom to send the
but who cares because we have all been what we want to get more complicated
but the question is what happens if we go to a very large set of
orthogonal signals
and what we're going to find is that when we go to a very large
set of orthogonal signals
we can get the error probability which goes to zero
as the number of orthogonal signals gets bigger
it goes to zero very fast we sent more bits with each signal
and the place where it goes to zero is exactly channel capacity
now in your homework you're going to work out a simpler version of all this
in the simpler version is something called the union bound
and in the union venue just
the probability of error when you send this
in fact those are exactly the ones you throw away
they are just written out in more general expression for this your if you're interested
in the function of only some of your variables
you can
rewrite this in a way i don't think OK three because i don't think will
be productive you end up averaging
something that you can analytically some over
on the samples of
most of your variables are the ones are interested in train
the row blackwell theorem would tell us that there is always a good thing to
do if it applied which doesn't but empirically it works incredibly well it's often a
good idea
so far
i've said you've got this fixed distribution you're interested in you might
debate which variables you want to keep control when constructing estimated that
it's fairly straightforward what we do is going to write down a joint probability
evaluated up to a constant and is one of the standard algorithms might might be
a bit messy to apply them but there are these recommendations in the papers of
how to check that giving sensible results
this is where a lot of money colour courses well and and you get the
idea that
advanced monte carlo methods are just going to be about finding good q say
you want to make a monte carlo estimate better you just need to make better
proposal for around the space better and that's sure
and i don't want to disparage that line of research is very important so if
you're interested in a particular application
you can have all sorts of domain knowledge about the application so you can go
and work out good ways of moving around your state space in your problem i
think is into metropolis hastings
in it for the rest of the lectures talk about more generic tricks that don't
involve specific applications and they're going to solve the
move away from this very standard
setting up one fixed distribution with one set of variables
so the first the first chunk of this is all going to be about what's
called auxiliary variable methods
this is kind of counterintuitive so
why are we doing and seems well to some of the things that we're finding
it difficult to some and maybe if you could sum over some of those variables
analytically you should do that first reduce noise
o thirty variable say
well why don't we just make a problem because sentence something over just the variables
x let's introducing new variables v and some over days from over joint distribution of
the variables are interested in and more variables
this here is an identity and it looks as well
we can sort out the these analytically because we can push the integral of to
be through and get rid of them to get back to his that's what we
should do but in fact
sometimes it's a good idea too
deliberately introduce more often not some that analytically but sample
your variables and some extra variables to before you start estimator
to me that seem like a very strange thing today until you see the algorithms
and sort of see what they achieve and then it certainly seems more appealing to
the first of these algorithms
it was called when someone edits an algorithm for spin system so called using models
of sometimes boltzmann machines or or logistic models these models have a lot of names
a way of updating expensive to say
here the data has been system has two colours red and blue and they could
be binary variables one zero
and the model so that adjacent colours like to be the same so under drawn
from the distribution you get regions tend to be
the same colour
so this is often
embedded somewhere in some some sort of model one continuity in space
very very heavily research and statistical physics
let's imagine doing gibbs sampling on
a system like this is a gibbs sampling would go through each of the spins
tendency for this one then i'm going to look at my neighbours and see how
many of them blue and how many of the red and then i'm going to
decide whether to people who already and if i more blue neighbours i'm going to
tend to be people
i get something sweet would involve going to every one of these variables in turn
and doing flat
and if the coupling strength between adjacent sites is very strong then it's very hard
to give something to make a big change the updating any of the variables in
it doesn't want to change from being played because that would be very probable so
it's only really able to change the the variables from the edge with some of
the labels the blue and some of them are so if you do we get
something sweet through this
just the boundaries are going to shift by about one
and this picture would just like ever so slightly different it would just
the band drift slowly by random walk backwards and forwards
this went along algorithm which are not going to drive here
as light of extra variables which are
depicted by the black
grid it as a binary variable linking site
on on the graph so for every edge in the graph as an extra variable
to add more variables and you actually had to start with
and the reason it does this is the
once you've got this big system of colours and the edges it's possible to derive
a markov chain update where you can move around the whole state space very rapidly
it puts in the edges
which links
together some of the knights you can imagine that there are clusters of nodes where
you can walk around the edges to get all of the nodes within a cluster
and you can't get all the nodes because there are no edges linking to
then it has an update where you can read clusters once it got set of
bonds it's able to move to a new state so this is one iteration is
when someone
and the coloring at the end it's completely different to the colouring beginning whereas give
something would have taken many many many sweets through the system in order to do
this diffusion
you haven't explained really how this works but this is
the first famous example
of an auxiliary variable method and you something you should know that in the back
of your head that sometimes people are able to introduce variables in a way that
will move around quickly
it's not that generally applicable it is in theory but in practice it's really only
successful and it's been systems
then to tell you about a simpler system which came later
which is very generally applicable
and it's only going to introduce one
extra variable
it turns out that you can derive it in exactly the same way as the
previous socks
one of the earliest slide said
the way you sample from a distribution is to draw samples from underneath the car
the drastic avenue just sample uniformly from under area pointed out that can be difficult
to do because it means you've got to compute integrals about
slice sampling says why don't we run the markov chain
that runs around underneath the earth the curve instead
so now we're not going to be something independently or like we did in rejection
sampling we still gonna be running around and because it's going to be a walk
the walks around under the curve
as samples will be dependent
this fly something to produce one extra variables we did we did have at position
x and i think space and now we've got to hide underneath the curve to
else to be around other applications this is not so
this is just to show you sort of visually the effect
so this says one regular sation this is out regular sation as we
vary the strength of the regulation parameter
of course in the end everything goes to zero the weights go to zero
but as you can see one regular sation certainly just go to zero
and stays zero okay and you can consider that the more important
variables are the ones that are lost the longer ok
whereas now to everything kind of goes to zero roughly the same
time and so it's harder to determine which of these things actually
has to be thrown ok so now what's the dacian view of this the
patient view is that in both of these cases we really what we're
dealing with is a prior distribution over hypotheses
ok and when the data comes in compute the posterior distribution
and the difference between al to and one is what kind of distribution
do we assume as prior ok so in the output case
we have circular gaussian that's the prior
and so when we compute the posterior we also obtain a gaussian
distribution ok and so for that reason it's actually very easy to
work with delta regular sation in many cases
and least all kinds of interesting algorithms gaussian processes
and so in the one case what we uses double-exponential prior
ok that corresponds to this kind of diamond shape the sort of
goes out much much quicker than gaussian
and so as a result you sort of put in a little bit different kind
of prior knowledge and to you're going to get a slightly different
hypotheses when you do your search this is something that is
under your control and the choices really guided by to criteria
one is the ease of the optimization because working with
for example with conjugate priors really makes things easy from
the point of view of solving the optimization problem
or sometimes choosing a sort of smoothness and the prior smoothness
and the error function makes a gradient based optimization easier
to deal with and then the other sort of important consideration is
what do we actually know about the problem
and so here it's sort of it's easy problems regression problems
but often on we deal with structured data
the prior actually reflects something that we know about the
hypothesis space ok for example for trying to infer gene networks
maybe we know that certain genes cannot be connected and so
we can build that into the prior
so this is just to give you a cartoon picture of this asian view
of regular sation ok and what we're going to do here is start
with a prior over the weight space this ok this is the picture
here with the red circle is a gaussian prior over the weight space
and it's sort of centered at zero okay
so in the axis of any data we can use this to draw weight vectors
ok and each weight vector is going to be a hypothesis
ok so here is red lines represent differ hypotheses that
we've drawn from the prior ok you consider all over the place
always say is we like the weights to be roughly small
ok but there's no rhyme or reason until you actually see
some data ok now to other hard to even over here on the right hand
side the second row we have a data point so little blue circle
ok and so on now what we do when we do the regular zation essentially
as we compute the posterior over the weight-space over the parameter
space and that is here says we would like to fit the data
ok so all the lines are encouraged to go through this point
to fit the point ok so compared to here where the lines were all
over the place here we have one there's all over the place but they
do fit the new point that we've just a lot
ok now what does that mean from the point of view
of the weights ok what it means is that
this gaussian it used to be round ok is no longer around because
we've taken the around prior when we combined it with the likelihood
of the data likelihood is here ok this sort of redlining
likelihood says all weights are good so long as they fit this point
ok so when we do that we get a gaussian that's more squished
ok so on one side we have to go through those the data point that
we have on the other decide which so still have a lot of freedom
so there's some lot of variance ok in the weight vector
but we restricted the sum ok so now the second point comes in
ok here's a second point and now you can see that we want actually
to fit both of these things ok so what happens
is we take this sort of this zero probability over the weight
vector we combining with the new likelihood from the new point
and then we have something that's very sort of concentrated
in one spot ok and now if you look at the last that result
they all all roughly through the two points there is some variability
ok because we have a distribution ok but they're all pretty
well aligned together and as we get more data what happens is the
spot that tells me what's the best the weight vector kind of squishes
in the variance reuses and the lines get more and more aligned together
okay so how does this relate to bias-variance well with put and some
bias here through the choice of prior ok
and then the data comes in ok and the data
is helping to decide how to sort of shrink this
in order to actually fit the observations that we have
ok and the more data we have the more we're going to shrink this
ok and the limit of infinite amount of data maybe we're going
to know fit this exactly correct so that was there's always
skewed by the data
so why is this interesting well it's interesting because it gives
us more then just estimates of the values of the output it actually
also gives us some kind of uncertainty estimates
in in where our hypothesis is confident on its output
and where it is not ok so this is a sort of another picture of the
same problem basically you have these circles here which are the
data points that are observed the true function as the green function
here and we have these red lines that are drawn from the sear
distribution over the weight vector ok
so what you see here is that when we have a data point the blue
point here around that data point we have
a little uncertain because we know we have to fit it
ok not exactly because were allowed some noise but
more last whereas when you are away from the data
there's a lot of uncertainty ok because you don't really know there
you can really tell what's a good hypothesis
and you can see in these lines all kind of go through a loop point
but they're all over the place as we get more points ok
these lines focus in order to capture these points
outside of where we have data we still have a lot of uncertainty
ok so the moral of the story is that you can always generalize well
around where data actually is if you're working with the
beijing method you can actually get analytical estimates sometimes
or empirical estimates of this uncertainty
ok and you can work with multiple hypothesis at the same time
right and was less zero then you misclassified it
so by setting some of the sea ice to be larger than one
on i can actually has some examples with a large and negative and therefore on
the line my album to misclassifies on the examples the training set
however i encourage you have not to do that by adding to the optimisation objective
this sort penalty term penalizes serving ice belong
and so this is an optimisation problem with the parameters on the w
and all the seas all the sea ice
and this is also a convex optimisation problem
it turns out that
similar to how we want to do all of the support vector machine
you can also work on the dole for this optimisation problem so i want actually
do it just to show you the steps right we should use you construct the
general isaac dungeon
now if you are not going to use alpha oxygen to denote the french multipliers
now corresponding to
the set of constraints and we have to use c and this new set of
constraints on the sea ice been zero this gives us a new so french multipliers
and so the the grandeur of the optimisation objective minus some from
for you
very minor
so that's all
the dungeon
discovered optimisation objective
you know or i guess what plus alpha a times each of these constraints which
can be zero
and so we can
so what we divide entire two again this is really you know the same as
on and when you divide to do all this optimisation problem we simplify
we find that on you get the following
you have to maximize of
that the about for which is actually the same as before
and so it turns out when you when you derive the dual
and simplify
it turns out that the only way to do it changes compared to the previous
one is that rather than the constraint the alpha creating real zero
we now have a constraint to the alpha of is zero c
so this derivation is very hard because just go home and try to do yourself
this is really essential to the same as
and when you simplify it turns out you can simplify the hours you to our
approach multiplies the way
you end up with with just these constraints in the office
see how hundred the time
just as an aside i want i won't bother i want
i want to write easy there it turns out that on
remember i wrote down the KKT conditions rain last lecture the karush kuhn tucker conditions
forms of
the necessary conditions for something to be optimal solution to constrained optimisation problem
so if you think the conditions on it turns out we can actually derive convergence
conditions so we want to solve the after this optimisation problem
so when we know the alpha ceph converge to the global optimum
it turns out we can use the following
it turns out that on
and then i don't see a lot about these
so there's also the KKT conditions you can derive
these said convergence conditions for an album that you might choose to use
to try to solve the optimisation problem in terms of the office
that's the one norm soft margin SVM and this is the
change the album handle non linearly separable datasets as was also the a single lies
there may still be linearly separable but you may choose not to separate lineages
he call
questions about this
seventeen important check questions
a few questions
because the pretty hand this to make sense
it's great
the last thing i want to do is on
talk about our love for actually solving this optimisation problem on so right we
o down this to optimisation problem with convergence criteria
so let's come up with an efficient algorithm to actually solve this optimisation problem
i want to do this part needs to
mean excuse to one another called coordination centre is useful to see you
so what actually want to do is is tell you about on
now album called coordinate ascent which is useful to know about and turned out that
they want apply
you know in the simplest form to this problem will then be modified slightly in
an innovative us very efficient algorithm for solving this some optimization problems
on that was the reason that i had to derive the dual not only so
they use kernels but also so can point out like like like like the out
so what
with posterior probabilities that adapt the data
as much as thinking about
at each time there are various possibilities that might happen so again with the same example
we can imagine
nowadays it's in the traditional way of modeling analyzes use something like a mixture of
the two component has mixture where one component allows for their lives
so there's two possible models but that's two possible models
at each time point
and if we look at the change points in this data
we might adapt is adopt a very similar strategy for modeling change points
and it may be selected
it may be that there are various components of the state vector that we make
expect anticipate a subject
i subject to abrupt changes
and then we'll be thinking about the same kind of mixture strategy there
for possibly several some parameters
so this is mixtures again for switching mechanisms for outliers
for automatic intervention
in a dynamical model context which again is all part of the historical panoply of methodology
so sequential learning
just to sort of complete the picture before we come to some some more examples
this is another textbook example
where we're looking forward in time
we've got a model that comprises it's composed of several components
there's a trend
there's a dynamic regression
there's a seasonal pattern its commercial sales data and
particular context
and what we're doing here is tracking the data and at this time point here we've seen
ten data points for forecasting had this is some notional forecast intervals
am because we know the data reported them on on the part is blue
and here we are tracking the eco-efficient ov thee predictor variable
and as we come through time when learning about this this parameter it's changing
the posterior intervals one degenerate
because is changing through time
we open to intervention so as we go ahead a few time points
as we see departures from the model
we may have a mixture structure we may be using other forms of informed intervention
at were allowed to step in and change posterior distributions in order to reflect an attempt to
forecast errors
at each timepoint forecasting ahead
asking questions about what might happen we do that by simulation across these days and a great deal
in simple linear systems it's it's analytic
and then as we go through time
after the end point we are interested in time series analysis
so will
distinguished at term from
the forward sequential updating learning analysis the adaptive learning
where we are more interested in looking at what is happening locally and how things
are changing anticipating change because the forecasting goals
to the looking back the retrospection thee analysis so what we've learned and how we planted
and how what we've learned will help us understand how we might modify the model for the future
so having tracked all the way through time we can then retrospectively update all these
relevant posterior distributions for the historical trajectory
the coefficient
that has changed over time subtly
and also in this case the variance be residual error which is this
a couple of points underwent some shops that increases that
as we saw
focus areas that warrant unexpectedly large
model composition has
a reciprocal model decomposition
so we build models out of components
and by the same token
when the building when we built a model
i'm not sure you a couple of examples
very often we're interested in components
we're interested in taking a model
the state space model with the multidimensional state
and decomposing
the signal in the model
into potentially interpretable
and actionable components
and this is a circuit second key aspect of this idea are breaking things apart
so let's take a particular subclass
of dynamic linear new models
the particular subclass hear
we've got some data that's the signal x error
the particular subclass hear has these matrices
the regression
matrix if you like this is the regression parameter which follows the state space model
and the markovian transition matrix effigy here are time-invariant they don't have a subscript e
we sometimes call these time series models
and the reason we call time series models is that all linear time series models
or linear gaseous in time series models
there is a view that all the time series know about autoregressive moving average processes
this special cases
there are other special cases
so in a very real sense all
traditional linear time series analysis sits inside the state space models and bayesian been doing
traditional time series analysis without knowing it for many years as a result
on these foundational concept a decomposition then
the key here is that in any such model
one can take the signal
this is just a theory and theory of
differential equations or difference equations
and break it down into a series of components such that they sum to give us the signal
and these components correspond to the eigen structure in this matrix j
that defines the model
sorry skip this slide again
can take one of three different forms of several forms
depending on the i can structure this matrix j if are unit igon values or replicate i can values
i mentioned before r
the feeders are not actually observed right we we
assume that what happens is we draw the random measure from the dirichlet process
then we put it in two hour make some mixture
and then we sample from the mixture and what we see is the data
the data from this mixture and i would like to get back at what this mixing distribution has look like
and the way we do that is with an algorithm with the gibbs sampling algorithm that i think is
is the easiest way to understand this organism is
to think of it as a kind of because that's really what it's kind of
a sampling version of you end up with an infinite number of components in the
the way it works is the following
we compute
assignment matrix of assignment probabilities was the data points in with that we've seen so
we've seen data points one three and
the rose correspond to data points
and the columns here correspond to the clusters
to our current estimate of what the number of clusters is
so this is not necessarily the true number of clusters is the estimate that
our algorithm currently things
is a is the number of clusters
and those these rules rosier
and then we have an additional roll over here
and that corresponds to the probability of creating a new class
so basically we take
these probabilities here correspond to be keane terms in this sum
and this probability these probabilities over here correspond to this integral and so we get this from evaluating this term
we get this you from evaluating this term
and we write them all into a matrix and then
because they should be assigned probabilities we have to normalize them by rules
and so each rule adds up to one
and this is exactly like the thee
the matrix of assignment probabilities that you compute in the e step of margaret
except for this additional role for this edition colony
india my reason we don't have it
you know we don't have a device for creating new clusters in a finite mixture
model so we don't get this probability here
basically if we would would just cut this out
take this
partial matrix you end we normalize each rotor one
then would have exactly the assignment probability matrix and you
okay now how do we do get something with this well
we use this matrix here
sample assignment variables
these variables which
the value of this variable is a clustering index so for each observation xt exchange
we have a variable phi jay
and the value takes is
the index of a cluster
so one through
are could take value zero and that means create a new cluster four this point
and how do we get this variable well be we take the corresponding role
the role corresponding to exchange
and we sample multinomial from
yeah so basically what we're saying is we assume that these terms are currently are
mixture weights are our current estimate of these weights we something like nominate
okay we do that for each point sequentially sequentially because it's a give center
and then
we get for each point we get
we get a cluster assignment and why is it important that we do that sequentially because
because if we at some point
if we draw
if we draw an assignment to this term then we have to create a new cluster
the number of clusters become larger
and then we have to we compute this matrix and the next term could be assigned to the class
so what happens at some point
as we go through this matrix
what happens at some point in this iteration
can influence further points and that's the characteristic of the gibbs sampler
so that's the assignment step we sample this
this variability multinomial e and then we have
another this and this
really corresponds to the east and yemen algorithm and then we have another step which is
corresponding to the am step you i very very simple parameter and what we do here is
we take all the data points that are currently assigned to a given cluster
the following content is provided under creative commons license
your support will help MIT opencourseware continue to offer high quality educational resources for free
to make a donation or to view additional materials from hundreds of MIT courses
visit MIT opencourseware OCW that MIT that EDU
i really
stated everything
about discrete coding is clearly as i could notes
i stated again as clearly as i could class
i stated again as clearly as i could
and making up problems that would illustrate the ideas
and if i talked about it again it will just be totally repetitive so
so at this point if you want to
understand things better
you got to come up with specific questions and i will be delighted to
to deal with the some
so we want to go on
there's one other thing i want to talk about
we're not having a new problem set out today
i don't think most of you will concentrate on it very well
but we will are
tell you what the problems are
which will be do in
october fourteenth
pass it out later
but it's
problems one through seven
lectures eight to ten
and one other one all the way at the end the problem twenty six
one two three four five six seven
and twenty six
so you can get started on them whenever you choose
in past other
problem set form the next time
last time we started to talk about
the difference between three months and the bike integration
most people tell me this is further
into mathematics and i should go
if you if you agree with them
after we spend a week or two one this please let me know
and i will torture future students with it
my senses
in the things we're going to be dealing with for most of the rest of
the term
knowing a little bit extra
about mathematics is going to say you awful lot of
time worrying about trivial little things you you should be worrying about
in other words the great mathematicians of the nineteenth century who developed
this is really the
the nineteenth century were part the twentieth century
these mathematicians were really engineers at heart
the twentieth century in the twenty first century
mathematics is very much because
very separated from
from physics
and applications
but in the nineteenth century and early twenties twentieth century
and physicists were were almost the same animals
you could scratch one and you find another one there
they were very much interested in dealing with real things
they were like the very best mathematicians everywhere
and the very best of engineers everywhere
they really wanted to make life simpler
instead of making life more complicated
one way that many people express it is that mathematicians are lazy
and because they're lazy they don't want to go through a lot of work and
therefore they feel driven to simplify things
there's not a lot of truth in that
and what we're going to learn here
i think will in fact simplify
what you know
about fourier series and fourier integrals a great deal
engineers typically don't worry about those things
an awful lot of engineers and unfortunately even those who write books
often state theorems
and leave out the last clause of the theorem
and the last clause of most of those theorems
the only way to make them true
just add claws or not as the case may be
at the end
which makes what they state absolutely meaningless because anything you can add were not as
the case may be
and it becomes true at that point in the whole question becomes one of those
cases under which is true
that's what we're going to deal with a little bit
we're going to say just enough
so you start to understand
these major things that cause problems
and i hope you'll get to the point where you don't have to worry about
them after that
OK well the first thing we started talking about the last time we were talking
about the difference between remind integration
and the big integration remind was great mathematician
but he came before
all of these mathematicians
we're following the bag
and who started to deal with all of the problems with this
classical integration which started to fall apart
throughout most of the nineteenth century now what raymond said well
split up
the axis into equal intervals
then approximate the function within each interval
add up all of those
all of those approximate values
and then let this
but this quantization over the time axis becomes finer and finer and finer
and if you're lucky you'll you'll come to limit
and you can sort of see when you get to limiting when you don't get
to limit of function is smooth enough
and you break it up finely enough you're going to get a very good approximation
and if you break it up more and more finally the approximation gets better and
if the function is very wild if it jumps around wildly
well look at examples of that later
then this doesn't work
you will see what i in fact this approach does work banks that now
instead of quantizing along this axis
on this axis
so he said OK let's
so far was zero
quantized quantizing epsilon two epsilon three at and so forth
and you know everybody when they talk about slander thinking about something small
and there are also thinking about making it smaller and smaller and smaller and hoping
that something like this happens
so so then what he says and q quantized this axis
start to look at how much of the function
it lies in each one of those little windows
my drawing that out here mu two is the amount of the function that lies
between two epsilon and three eps along now the function lies between two epsilon three
at ceylon
starting at this point which i label t one
going up to this point label t two
all over here it's not in this interval until we get back to t three
if is in gamma here well it was in gamma here
if it's to be here well into some form this
and so on
every rule has the property that for the whole proof has that property
well that property means is that every formula that occurs in the proof
is already a subformula of the conclusion that you're trying to prove
so you do not need to consider the rest of the language you can restrict
attention to subformulae the thing in trying to prove
and that's really
really important
o thing to be able to do it means you get some control
on what this person might look like
now all of that's lovely
but what about quantifiers here
the cry
can we fit them into the picture
of course
we can
but there are some
there are some wrinkles on
we get rules of course four
introduction of quantifiers left and right for the universal quantifier
we want to k so we want to show
for example that
so delta
that for all x a entails something
how do we prove that
we show it
by i
deriving whatever it was here
from some instance
and then generalize
subject to the usual
restriction no funny business
for x in a
and that's
o k
what about universal quantifier on the right
we want to show that
everything is a
you know unless one of the side conditions cells
how do we show that
we show
he follows
i would say
we can derive a with this site
he is
provable so therefore everything's provable
that's not ordinarily
but in certain conditions it is
we had exercise this morning is the last thing i did
under some conditions that's OK it's OK effects
does not occur free
in gamma
or dealt
OK then there's no special pleading for exit could be anything
what's true alexia is true while true of anything else because in the rest of
this thing there's no special pleading for x doesn't matter what it's called
bassist x is true everything
this is this is the common sort of reasoning you know you are familiar with
this from high school
you want to show that every triangle
as an acute angles service for
so let a b c b a triangle and then you go to do is
to do is to use of what you show is that ABC is because in
acute angles of
you say well there forever trying
so it is this inference and you don't
because nothing turns on what you call you called it a b c et al
x y z
you could call it anything you didn't make any special assumptions about a and b
and c didn't assume that line a straight line they
you he didn't make any any
site assumptions about
we get rules for the universal quantifier and exactly the dual roles for the existential
one like this
something follows from then it follows from the existence of something or other satisfying a
the variable here
know there's no special pleading for it
and a similar thing
on the dual thing to
so this
but on the right
gamma entails the reason i
unless delta
if it's if it gives you a particular instance of it
there is no funny business
so OK we can get rules the quantifiers
and that gives us proof system that we can work with arbitrary sequence a sequence
system for first-order logic
but now the
subformula property has become a little bit more complicated
because here
for instance
and here
here there is a formula
that doesn't actually occurred
below the line
OK because got this term t in it
that we just pull out of the air somewhere we don't know what what to
do that might be
so there's a weaker version of the subformula property you know up to substitution of
terms for variables
everything here because you
so we still sort of have some
kind of control of which fragments of the language you might be wanting to look
but what we can't control
is what terms might get introduced as we go
and it's important that we can't control that
because errol martin is going to come in here and persuaded the first order logic
is not decidable
and if we could keep control of this
we have an algorithm for deciding which we
can't have unless the allows councils to
it's not quite as
trivial is in the propositional case for that reason
there's another reason why it's not
as trivial as in the propositional case as well
and that is to do with
the this thing
is a consequence relation
the first night they learned to play to
pi one and it's so simple it just print hello world and starts to fly
and he's like outcome you're flying in as you i just typed important anti-gravity
and i also drank everything in the medicine cabinet but i think it's the right
so this
it was such a popular
little cartoon
then they jump into the interactive interlude now here that in python three which is
the long-awaited third generation
they added the integrand gravity module to the core language
so i'm running python three because all these third-party libraries don't run python three but
i've installed the sort of the
test here so i don't have a long history of for example of this module
is kind of fun that to tim peters wrote
so it's basically a little
o point let's composition of pi found beautiful is better than ugly
explicit is better than implicit symbols than complex in sort of gives you is and
you should be programming
so in that vein they also wrote the anti-gravity modules so
in order to actually check
OK so i'm going to go into the
keeping time we flash me every once also no kind of where i am
when the start of briefly to show some of the features of item that i
think you really need
and then i'm going to focus on on the mat on the pilot features hopefully
show you some things you haven't seen if you have a python programmer
so this is the python shows just enhanced python shell and i started with this
moti which basically says important matplotlib important be giving in matlab like
the environment social straight out of the gates
you can start doing things
make a histogram of one thousand random numbers normally distributed with a hundred bands
michigan graph
looks like a normal distribution so like matlab you can fairly easily too easy things
but not really to emulate matlab so i want to show you some of the
interesting things the python can do
beyond those capabilities to start out with so
people talk about python has been that early batteries included some input the URL URL
this is a module for searching data of
on websites and
again this is something you can develop the little bit harder so since in the
financial services industry financial example from yahoo finance does anybody famous stock that has lost
a lot of money in the last
you academics no no no takers no favor stocks to analyse
this one has lost me a lot of money my daughter's love these crocs and
that's not been good from my portfolio so
we have a finite set of historical prices you can download the CSV file spreadsheets
so i'm going to just
right click and copy the link location
so this is a link to grab the CSV file from yahoo finance and
and i'm going to say that link here in the shell
just pasted into that this variable URL
and i'm going to grab the of
the web using the URL library
the URL little
that you insist or in the trooper
the temporary file for us
and so it has the URL
and as stated in this temporary file called their something something this csv file system
going court the CSV file we have this
this nice CSV importer which is
really we work you for a lot in the financial industry sources my life
well let's see what the file looks like real quick
so it looks like a standard csv file
i can show is nice
let you type unix commands are arbitrary shell commands you can kind just i just
to last
so we basically have these headers and these different types now this is the date
string some price stayed in some volume data which is an integer so already we
we're not a whole world floats is that laughter in
what i've done with this are this or record
which is very nice to structure from
sqa seven hundred seventeen rows in it
and opened the first one
it has a daytime object is the first row it's eleven twelve that's yesterday
some price data
some integer data
so essentially what we've done here is created an array of these trucks
it's why i always xis the latent wise data because mapping for me go from
x to y
if i have a functional mapping from x to y
that's it specifies how my data is generated so i can do that for this
i can say what position annexes which is
the one dimensional space and that's time
and then i can is assigned cosine function to generate the not
this is also generated by looking at some
two dimensional space and saying well in one direction is the spiral and the other
is just linear
so all these things are generated by functions
so what happens if we
try to model the functions directly one thing to show
here's an idea
from seven humbling but it's sort of inspired by
by some of my work i believe
is to show that you can use this idea for model selection so
if i have a function regression function that models from f
from x to y
with some noise
and i'm going to say that this regression function is a guassian process i'm not
going to go through that
i have a regression function
and i look at the quality that regression function
one thing i might claim is it that's good smooth regression function from the latent
in the data space then i got a good representation of the manifold
now casting processes
allow us to school
regression function
so look at these data points here
this is the regression is input and this is an output is one dimensional regression
because we're going to go from one d to multiple dimensions or to data to
multi dimensions
now this is the parameters of the regression function will change
i do belong here so i'm changing and that of the regression function see here
is really weekly regression function here is to smooth the regression function
OK now here it looks like a really good regression through these points
these error bars either side
in fact not even better according to school so this is the log likelihood score
OK now starting to draw
it's only snow
now what's nice magasin processes is i can find what the best regression function is
parameterized it and give log likelihood score
so the question is can you use this
some of these visualizations some of these embedded these reconstructions
in this case here is the data and here is some reconstructions with isomap MVU
maximum variance unfolding platini collapsed and only
so i haven't talked about these three methods
here is the likelihood for these different reconstructions
so once high
so it's a guassian process regression i'm short on tyneside in real time so that
i would like to talk about model the guassian process regression so
it's the best type of regression you can possibly do
the easiest way to think about the next generation
check out processes before you do anything
nonlinear regression
so in this case is need to be nonlinear
but if these different approaches isomap MVU
i LLE
and by the lasso and you can see it scoring use the best now by
i would say looks pretty good
i that looks OK as well and the platini like that look OK to something
wrong look at low score LLE
so this regression scoring is telling you you've got a good and bad
his something with a hole in it
the data
these guys all struggle with that we hold in this case
only and you really recovers and that's reflected in the likelihood score
now of course in truth you don't have
the ground truth so these scores are reflecting
the ground truth is called you don't need the ground truth
to see this you have to know the ground truth
look by these girls attending the the quality of embedding without ground truth so gasoline
processes provide away
to look at the quality of different embedding so in this case and he must
have done something weird like jump across the with the connectivity structure i don't know
why have useful but they've also failed item at doing the best here
and again you isomap coming out of the top ranked so here is this what
this is basically saying is that you can use downstream processes
two school structure and give probabilistic model