and the reason why that's the first problem that people
look that an extension is that the simplex method for linear programming exploits pull here
the structure of the constraints
and that's very so that's related to the fact that the linear inequalities
if you replace the linear inequalities by non linear or quadratic inequalities
the simplex method becomes it's difficult to generalize the simplex method
in the nineteen sixties there were some another extension it's
smaller but also fits in this development known as genetic programming that i'll introduce
and then for while not much happened in this
area of a convex optimisation but at the beginning of the nineteen nineties also burst
of activity that people looked at several extensions
similar to linear and quadratic programming known as semidefinite and second order cone programming
also quadratically constrained quadratic programming so this problem if you also replace constraints with quadratic
and so on
and now we see what happened around nineteen ninety to trigger this activity
we see same and applications so many new applications were discovered since the nineteen nineties
so in control theory a semidefinite programming
was used extensively starting around nineteen ninety
genetic programming found new applications in circuit design
then in machine learning i think everyone knows about support vector machines and quadratic programming
also l one norm optimisation which is a form of
convex optimisation is now widely used for sparse signal reconstruction and for
solving very difficult
optimisation problems
and the list goes on their applications in computer vision and finance and so on
so get most of this happened after nineteen ninety
and the reason why people became more interested in convex optimisation around nineteen ninety
was the development of interior point methods for convex optimisation
and these were not new methods over
used for linear programming
since come across famous algorithm for linear programming in nineteen eighty four
but then later on nineteen ninety
an astronomer of ski
extended the approach interior point methods for linear programming
two general nonlinear convex optimisation
and that also
some made these problems more easy to solve
they also
motivated people to look at convex optimisation as an extension of linear programming
because the methods that were used isn't implemented these are very similar to a linear
programming methods so then also motivated people to look
four applications
and to try to use convex optimization for modeling different applications as an extension of
linear programming
so in most of the research in the nineteen nineties focused on interior point method
since the last five or ten years there's also increased interest in convex optimisation what
people call first order methods
so basically
methods are similar to the basic gradient descent method the most elementary
green for optimisation
but people have formulated new types of gradient methods with better convergence properties
and all this custom at the end of the next lecture
so the useful in very large scale applications because there
much easier to explain much easier to implement and much
less expensive than interior point methods
so that's introduction so in these two lectures
try to cover
some basic theory about convex sets and functions some basic definitions
we look at these problem classes classes new problem classes that were developed since the
nineteen nineties
and then also look at some
developments in algorithms at least since nineteen ninety
so i'll discuss interior point methods and then these fast
gradient methods
so today we probably get two
second order cone
programming problems and for the tomorrow
any questions
so sorry very quick introduction to
the theory of convex optimization
so we sort of it's convex sets
so set is convex if
o line segments defined by points in the set is are included in the set
but this is a convex set
this is not convex because there is a line segment that is not included in
the set
this is also not convex because the line
defined by two corner points of the square are also
not entirely including
so that's the definition and that's the mathematical description of the line segment between two
points x one x two
so these are some common examples that will encounter so the solution set of a
set of linear equations is always convex it's actually
of structure that we've looked at before really really complicated and it turns out that
just looking at structure in inferring function from it is kind of like trying to
reverse engineer your computer by looking at the motherboard insane
what does this do is very no orderly structure
we must be able to look at it to know what it does
what numbers on things
the brain has ten to the power of love a hundred billion
if i'm not mistaken neurons
and each neuron is connected on average two thousand others
so now
quite some structure there
so it seems like well
i start with why do we need so many neuroscientists seems like we don't need
any neuroscientists because we actually don't stand a chance and we should just give up
but that's what computational neuroscience comes in with the idea
relatively new idea that all the brain is a computing device right so if you
wanted to
reverse engineering or computer the first thing you'd ask was well what can i do
with my computer my computer computes things seem think about the brain the brain is
a computing device
so what we can ask is
can we use computational models
to understand the functions of the brain rather than going from structure we can go
what does it need to compute what what it need in order to compute these
things and then search for those functions in the brain
and this will contain something very abstract and formal abstract theory
it's not concrete it's not like structure but the abstract theory can miraculously help us
organize and interpret all the concrete data that we have and we don't know how
to put together
that's that's in general
how i see how how i see the contribution of computational neuroscience understanding the brain
and there's
a framework that was suggested by david marks think in the seventies
he was a researcher who studied vision computer one of the first computational neuroscientist so
this framework really helps us do computational neuroscience and the kind of
i understand what what we're doing
and what level of analysis we're looking at the framework basically says that when you
do computational neuroscience and we try to understand what is the computational function of the
brain and how that is
how that is realized in the brain
you should always remember that there are three levels of analysis one level is what
is the problem is called the computational level what problem is the brain trying to
and this that at this level it doesn't have to be the brain the same
problem could be solved by computer by an algorithm by
i read about
it's also hopefully solved by the brain for studying the brain
then you can ask yourself well what's the strategy or whatever
different strategies
a different algorithms that can solve this computational problems still were staying in the very
abstract in the census
that until here
everything could still apply to robot
and finally the third level is how it's actually done by networks of neurons in
the brain this is called implementational level
david marr suggested these three
o levels and what we're going to talk about today is
mostly well we're going to talk about all of them because i think reinforcement learning
helps us define the problem defined set of strategies and then understand how these are
realized in the brain
what's the hardest problem face in your life
every day
i don't wanna know OK
my name is one of the problems
OK thank you very much thank you for the for the invitation
to speak to you and for organizing the the summer school
i'm delighted to be here in taipei
so today
and tomorrow i'm going to give some lectures on
pattern classification theoretical results in pattern classification
so let me start
they giving you the overview
the two days lectures
i want to begin with in this lecture
the formalisation of the pattern classification problem
can everybody this
i agree with the formalisation of the pattern classification problem
and some examples of
the types of classes of functions that we're dealing with which
i will be reviewing you know some of the things that you've seen i want
to make sure we don't fix the the notation
and then i look at
general way of obtaining risk wristbands so so performance guarantees the pattern classification methods
using something called rademacher averages
so to be in in this lecture in the next lecture will look at
aspects of the
vc theory vapnik chervonenkis theory
and we get on two the convergence of who are going to properties of large
margin classifiers tomorrow
OK so
let me start by looking at the
the pattern classification problem
and defining the problem
so here i'm considering
we will assume always that we have already done so we have an x probability
distribution p
and his ex-wife here is distributed according to p
it's a distribution on the the product space x here is some domain this is
the space of possible patterns that we can see why is the space of labels
i'm assuming that the cardinality y is fine
we wanted to classify
elements of x into
one of this many classes
and for most of what all talk about
over the next two days
the cardinality y is going to be just two i would be looking at the
two class case
so we assume that we see
in x y pairs
right that have
the same distribution there independent and there's
that that's the same distribution is that of XY
and the aim is the aim here is to use this training data these in
x y pairs
to choose
a decision rule
that is the function
that maps from x
so that the the risk of that function is small the risk
here is the expectation of the loss
so we define some loss function l
which tells us how bad it is
to make the prediction f of x
when the true outcome is why
this is
loss function l
measures how bad it is
to make prediction f of x when the true outcome is why
right so where we're interested in the expectation
the loss expectation under this random choice of the x y here is distributed according
to p
OK call this the risk
and for instance the case the where typically concerned with here in the
binary classification case in particular
this loss function
would be the discrete loss zero one loss
i be we incur loss of one when a prediction y had is different from
the true outcome one
OK so some examples
the space of patterns x
might be
a mass spectrogram
the class
represents different disease states and we wanting to use
you know this this mass spec data from from somebody's blood serum to decide whether
they've got
prostate cancer
so you know i'm i'm thinking quite abstractly
the the
the main here is is
not necessarily
you know euclidean space
although many of these examples
for many of examples we define some set of features on the space and then
and then look at the euclidean
representation in euclidean space
another example character recognition so this
the main x might be features of some handwritten character and and the space of
labels y is how we want to
classify these
these characters
the set of of
possible characters or x might be some
properties of a three d structure the candidate drug mode molecule and y represents
properties of some property of interest right so whether that that molecule has some acceptable
pharmacological probably like receptor binding affinity or something
OK so
the key issues in in pattern classifications of problems of this kind
parishes of approximation estimation computation so
the perspective here is with thinking of f is being chosen from some fixed class
capital s
six class of functions
and then having made that restriction
right we
have an approximation
the question of how well can functions in the class f
solve this
pattern classification problem that is what's the smallest value
overall functions in f
of the the risk the expectation of the loss incurred when we predict for this
and the outcome f of x and the outcome is one
i might have modified
flip the arguments from my earlier
definition here
all right so the approximation this is the property of that class of functions in
the problem the underlying probability distribution px x y y
estimation is the statistical issue that we only get to choose our full let's call
this matter if had
by using a finite sample
OK and so the
the expectation of the loss
might be rather far from the best that we can do in that class right
because the only information we have comes from a finite sample
and of course the computation issue we where
we're concerned that we can use the the training data to choose a suitable f
so these are the three things that they were going to be concerned with
so in these talks are not going to focus at all on on the approximation
i'm going to be looking
mainly the estimation question and to some extent the computation
all right so
let me say a little bit about the classes of functions f and the pattern
i in nineteen seventy five in november and so some somebody disagreed phrase some i
wish i'd said originally i don't know is that someone said that language
it is a dialect with a powerful army
and that's that that's true france the time the french revolution
half the people in france new french
there was bilingualism you could know that allow you could you could all over now
part within the south of france where a lot of people or people still speak
about what the that's mostly dying out how does it come that identity
a sense of allegiance to
a state or country not everybody but how does it come to nineteen fourteen when
people marching off to get killed thinking the as as
french national anthem in in pretty good french how does that happen
how does the state
increase its range
how does the modern world housing created we call this is is a clumsy world
word but state making
how does this form another side of this is how do i get this change
you know the sixteenth century seventeenth century as somebody who we were who are
and they say well you know i so so i'm of the family protestant if
was the sixteenth century or late sixteenth century late sixteenth century when any time after
fifteen twenty fifteen thirty parts of germany i'm protestant i'm jewish are in much of
the balkans i'm muslim are in most of europe i am catholic and in eastern
europe i'm you know russian orthodox i live in the village near my are in
russia how does it happen by the end of the nineteenth century people have given
rushes to star in the starting in in the famine the whole story the great
writer called the world's attention to
you know they lot of died in in fields thinking only the are only new
we were starving and his ministers were treating this bad how angry he would be
well they didn't get the they didn't know that these are going to given one
damp but but the
the regions two
others are the sense of being rush hour or being dominated by the russians are
something had to be constructed as the way to the state constructs its ability to
extract taxes extract body is for national armies also provide resources but identities are transformed
and so i give this is example of state making is is one of the
themes that ties everything together and you know this course in nineteen forty five but
look at the problems in the post-communist world of of state making was going on
in georgia which is more complicated than than the newspapers are present in very many
ways to relate with the horror show of the balkans in the nineteen nineties so
a lot of issues religious hatred that we only work would be limited to northern
ireland you know that's another thing that's very important to the whole thing and other
courses economic change
obviously this is that of course in economic history but the rise of capitalism and
that's what it's called capitalism or large-scale industrialization
it changes in ways that will suggesting the reading and i'll talk about a little
bit the way people live in very fundamental ways there's lots of continuity is but
there's lots of big changes everybody is an end up in the assembly lines right
and there are other ways of of
rule production women's work remains terribly terribly important
and i spent some time doing a very dear friend of mine my mentor and
teacher until just died a couple months ago my great sadness once said
that's very it's bitter hard
it's better hard
to right
of remainders
so lots of people were left out
of all of us do one lecture when i talk talk about popular protest
and i think three examples
of people rebelling
and i i i stand back and said what does this mean what's going on
i think the example
from from the pyrenees mountains place called here which you not responsible for that name
would never be but we're certainly men dressed as women
carrying guns appearing pitchforks came down out of the mess i know
and drove away charcoal burners and drove away forest guards why because it lost access
to go we
to pass through there miserable animal
because the wealthy big surprise get the longer side is the price at which goes
they don't like grand saline remainder events i'm going to have to move to toulouse
in the grand great-grandchildren work l speciality air industry there is a i remain number
two and three one but they fought for their dignity and for sense of moral
that they thought existed at one time taken away by economic changes they couldn't control
and then i think an example from the south of england from the same time
eighteen twenty nine eighteen thirty
when they find people that did with only dandelions in the stomach dead of hunger
and then these people start marching
the poor direction poor world labour start marching and threatening people with threshing machines why
threshing machines threshing machines was taking away
their work as harvesters
and one day they found signs that prevented from the
it is on the wing
from i i determined
captain swing
suggest that there were many
they were right
they were just
they are they ready
the happens to exist
there we go
and they get lost their they get defeated some of them are harmless numbers sent
the president port arthur tasmania
percent australia
that's why when the australians played english about australian thing we know that older song
yellow submarine now we should don't remember which i vaguely remember we all we all
live in a convict colony economy colony accounts colony
happens when they lost they went down fighting is bitter hard to write the history
remainders but when you look at it from that you look what what's going on
when you look at people fighting for green fighting for food are fighting is larger
so that they can they can control
but it tells you what was going on with the big picture
so that's another one
and then there's just obstacle one more
maybe never attended seminary my home
they then then you can go hope to come back
war as a dynamic change
eighteen centuries of warfare changes with napoleon
there already changes in the eighteenth century but there still basically professional armies people it
is scripted in the british navy because they were drunk at the wrong place at
the wrong time outside of the tavern in portsmouth or something that's another throwing up
onto ships
bobbing off
it's hard english empire
but but warfare changes with the nation-state the french called living on my for mass
conscription the centre defending the nation
and there's this magic moment where the artists in paris defeat
the highly professional are wise army at windmill called find me
in the east to france and it changes the way things were napoleon is arguably
the first total war because of the war against civilians in our there are no
longer the traditional limits between fighting against civilians and fighting against against another that had
existed in the thirty years' war not talk about that next time around but but
the water very different you know there were other famous goya paintings of peasants being
gunned down by french soldiers and and atrocities against the peasants in calabria in the
south of italy for warfare really changes but it becomes the dynamic of change if
you think about the russian revolution
and i'm going to focus attention on the classification problem
and some of the ideas that you'll see are
pretty cutting edge
in terms of the best theory is that i'm aware of four
classification trees the type i described earlier
so to begin with
i want just revisit
really precisely what the classification problem is
our feature space acts are are feature spaces activities
are say vectors of features are
and the output space y are class labels and for the most part i'll focus
on refer exclusively focus on
the labels being one or zero but extensions to multi category cases and so forth
are possible
so the problem is given a feature we want to predict the label
and the can motivate this'll give you a little example that's been bothering me and
i'm trying to work on solving
really routinely walks around the dalai so i devised a method to try to distinguish
whether they seemed on holds him or salvador dali by making some measurements of the
mass action i and based on a set of training data from pictures of really
pictures salvador dali from the web got a classifier is a classifier is a camera
that fast but the idea of course is the training data and there's some decision
boundary that we try to determine then we
label on either side of prediction rules blue really already covered
OK so it here is again the probabilistic framework
the parents of feature and label is a random variable with probability measure p
the risk is the probability of error which is equivalent to the expected absolute error
between f of x and y
and the optimal classifier the bayes classifier is the
mapping out that minimizes the probability of error over all measurable functions called that f
and here this picture illustrates was going on we have training data which are distributed
according to
joint probability law p of x y
we don't know that usually that's the problem
we just have the training data
the conditional probability of y one given x equal little axis is shown for example
caused by these data might look something like this
where you see transitioning from black zero two y one and there are some
sort of transition region where the probability moves through the levels set one half on
that level set
one half is exactly
so the bayes decision rule so i'm showing down there at the lower right the
bayes decision rule that's the set of points of that conditional probability
that where the value takes it takes on value of one here so above that
we say one below that level which is zero
there are these two
competing effects we're trying to understand control one is approximation and the others estimationerrorpr o
approximation error has to do with this idea of bicycle
there is the true bayesian decision regions
and over there on on the left surround right i'm showing an approximation for example
polygonal approximation to that decision tree
and so
question about how well can we approximate the true bayesian decision regions with some simple
model like the piecewise linear model essentially
the other question is how easily could this approximation be selected based on training since
we don't have access to the true probability distribution
this is what's called
model selection this is the estimation part of the problem the stochastic part which leads
to various so how easily can i take the data and get to this good
to two
can you sense one way to view the
difficulties and challenges involved in classification going to focus exclusively on
the approximation part of the problem for now so i'm not going to talk about
reindeer for the next few slides and think about approximation
and the reason for doing this is it'll help us understand where few of the
kind of key aspects of the underlying probability distribution that might affect how learnable a
particular problem
so what
FBI collection of classifiers
and for each
classifier after this script we essentially have said she's about which is the indicator of
where the
classifier assigns labels one
so here i'm showing the conditional probability
again and to the right is the optimal decision regions g f star where f
stars the bayes classifier
and what we're going to do is look at the
approximation problem which is really a problem of approximation sets where i'm going to compare
risk the best that i can get over my collection through that relative to the
the risk of the probability of error associated with the bayes classifier
so we can
look at the air this way
she's about stars the bayes decisions that g seven after some candidate approximations
and the delta f come f star is what's known as the symmetric difference between
those two sets of the red region shows you the difference between she's about start
and it's just defined formally as i show
below here
now using that symmetric difference we can talk exactly about what is the approximation error
in this case all the approximation error the difference of our that RDF stars just
the difference between the probability of error i achieved with the approximation after
and the
minimum probability of error delivered by the bayes classifier f star
ninety of the y
and we know that those two probability there must agree the symmetric difference that because
the two classifiers are both saying one or both saying zero outside the symmetric difference
so i can specialize my attention to that that and look at the probability of
landing in that sense and then condition on landing in that symmetric difference that i
look at the difference between the two
probability of air
this is clear
so that gives us the sort of decomposition fact more more more precisely factorizations the
the difference between the probability of error approximation these classifiers before he delta in q
where p delta is just the probability of falling in the symmetric difference set and
q delta is the difference of the probabilities of air and that symmetric difference
those two
areas can be described you there are facts can can be understood
it has been covered by two sorts of phenomena one is the smoothness of the
here i'm showing very smooth decision boundary at the left and more irregular decision boundary
at the right
and the smoother this decision boundary
it should be obvious that in some sense will be able to approximate this much
easily say with piecewise linear approximation than than the regular one on the right
so smooth around three means
a faster air decay in this approximation error
the other
factor that kind of governance how fast this approximation error
reduces i use user better and better approximation is the smoothness of the transition zone
between say
one and zero more precisely the smoothness of the behaviour of the conditional probability function
in the vicinity of the level set one half
so here i'm showing situation where you have a very smooth transition another right very
the entropy itself is also going to be additive for independent sources
so one thing that someone mentioned mutual information earlier when isabel was talking about feature
selection someone mentioned mutual information is as as a way of
as a way of selecting features a quantity that is very related to mutual information
is the conditional entropy
so so what's the conditional entropy
OK says here are the average uncertainty remaining about x if we have observed y
so it's a bit like
if i were
if i walk into my house when my mum says you know there's been this
train accident whatever OK you know that has a certain observing that
has has a certain charm information content so the so my mom is a random
saying you know random things perhaps not around them from from a finite alphabet has
certain entropy OK
assuming that have talked with my mom already when i go into my dad
how much entropy does that source now have OK
you can sort of see that
it it's really going to depend a lot on on what the joint entropy was
so how how how do we computed in the expression is actually is actually very
very intuitive right it's it's the joint
a minus b
minus sort of the the entropy of y
and you can see that if the if the sources are independent
then the conditional entropy does not decrease by the fact that that i that i
know about why OK
so you can sort of see that the sources are independent actually seeing why
doesn't doesn't tell you much about it doesn't decrease my uncertainty about x
now the mutual information works to be the opposite way round right so the the
mutual information what it says
is how much information is shared between x and y
so let me just give to the let me skip to the next OK before
saying that now if sources are independent the mutual information
is zero but i think
this figure here which again is stolen from the same book actually explains things in
imagine a much easier way
let let this be
the joint entropy
of x and y OK
and this is sort of the maximum entropy there can be
OK there no more OK in the way
any of the other quantities
is smaller
imagine x y were independent what would happen then
what happens is that
the joint entropy would be equal to two to the entropy of x plus the
entropy of life OK so this guy
and this guy was sort of more here the line what would that imply that
would imply that the mutual information
is actually zero is gone
and what that also would imply is the conditional entropy would actually be equal to
the entropy because conditioning doesn't reduce entropy
now houses useful in in feature selection you want you want to predict
let's let's say you want to predict y it's sort of more than the more
usual notation right you want to predict y and now you can condition on some
of the inputs you can say
what happens if i had this feature here so what you could do is compute
the entropy of y in sort of empirical way and then you could go in
and computed conditional because sort of compute the average
reduction in entropy given that you've observed x and you would take the features that
reduce this entropy the most
or set in other words the ones that that maximize mutual information the most OK
so mutual information class conditional entropy is equal to entropy
OK so we have
so we have two more slides on
on information theory and then maybe we can take a sort of a five-minute break
or something like that so we
the guys have discarded when we have
to stop
my gun
OK OK
OK let's go through these two slides and then we we take a little little
small five-minute break and then we'll
try to sort of it enough time to some extent
so here's the quantity who who who knows about the kullback leibler divergence
very nice
what's what's it also has it also has a different name it's also called
the relative entropy
sort of wondering whether i got it right
so this is this is the one quantity where you systematically get wrong which one
goes up and which one was down
so tomorrow
will actually look into the kullback leibler divergence a lot more than today
and we use it for the for the so-called EMI grid and the expectation maximisation
algorithm whose
was familiar with the EM algorithm
OK very nice for tomorrow we talk about the algorithm some more OK
and we can sort of see why it's important you can think about the the
KL divergence
as this and the similarity measure
now many people get very very nervous if you say the KL distance
and the reason for that is that distances
should be symmetric but the KL divergence is not symmetric and you can you can
see that by inspecting the equations right
there's this you can write the
kl divergence
you can write the mutual information sorry as as the KL divergence in the following
forced to is just one
is almost the same number problem
chosen by the loss to
that's what had
to do so
falls all
what is that
this is is
this is
the user
it is
the red
just great
this is the first
it was a shown change the middle east
the walls seems to be
that we don't
this is the case
in this
and she was a
it is they want to
so want to see was twenty six
so say
close to the moment and of course the two
presentation of the way she goes to the user
as well as the best chance of that
sure you
so should we try to
you have to go on
what is
no action
it was just this morning
this this
so this use of the word which is the continuation
this was
they just a vision for the future of this one
as it is
which is called the rules for all fiction she c two
these is three
so this is just show
so she was just a small
the this is just same
that was
so the value of the
so it was just
this is because she
that such important changes in the front of the features
and this is what we do know that
what is it
we show that that's so nature
in one these is
for instance this
because she was going to
that's chris also
so the she was
and others domain is
the first he was
this is a
one of the three
for the next
he thing
the citizens of the city was it is only
six issues
of course we
six seven
he was a
she wants to the statistical
so these
the structure that we must
not quite
this is is in
he's also have all of these things that you can do is being the formation
pressure is just
three days
he the formation what's the
from what seen in the world
the classification
this species
one of them is the cause
this forces who
the shape of the
also the direction that
the formation of these structures
so as you can see here
not all of them
the answer is no
the symmetric from innovation
and you also really improvement the spread of the weights
so you really have
dynamical effects that play a role
during the fission process
we have what we call a resident critics agreement experiment
so all these cities here when i call about accuracy agreement it's something that do
not contain any free parameters so we cannot use these for application because we don't
very very big accuracy
but we're happy to see that
this from something which is as the so possible we can find something with his
was experiment that is what is summarized here
we have extended coherent determination of the properties of the fissioning systems
so efficient values vision landscapes fission isomers that i've presented yesterday
but also fission dynamics with sufficient mass fragment mass distribution
observables of the fragments like the kinetic energy neutron number operations
so that's why
we are going to continue in this direction and there are many words that are
and i've taken
just to slide before the end so first for all that we need many experiments
and it's really important to have a super from experimental side
we are supporting a lot of experiments concerning static properties of the fissioning systems collective
dynamics with sufficient
from a distribution and properties of the fragments also spectroscopy
and for new
the parameters
where are you
really can have some precise measurements directly comparible with what we obtain the problem is
for the moment the fragments are not
fully identified experimentally so you don't have both the charge and mass either what is
easier to have the child
of this
light fragment
but i would like to know precisely is the number of proton and neutron of
each fragment to really compare
so this
current project that we built in the future
so that's why there is any need for existing facilities like end-of-year results here but
although one everywhere and for future there are many
things are for example this pair just behind well for the far future the reason
some general conclusions about THE nuclear physics so there are lots of subjects that are
currently the
i looked at in the community so i present a lot yesterday
and today devoted to fish and so
i remind you that four concerning is exotic nuclei there are a lot of nuclei
that are not known a lot of experiments theoretical calculations
can really improve our
the way we understand
and you a lot of work concerning exotic nuclei
also a lot of work theoretical in the theoretical part
concerning the resolution of the many body problem
and then what i presented today i think it's a lot to do to have
a career and approach from both structure and nuclear reactions not an efficient but
pos very actually and for telling induced fish whatever so it's really something
that is for the future
OK so morning and welcome to the
tutorial on how to publish linked data on the web
my name's tom heath from talents in the UK in this tutorial is a collaborative
effort between five different people from five different institutions
hausenblas from your name
austria crisp it's from free university berlin
richard cyganiak from derry galway and olaf hartig from the more university in berlin as
these are quite small group i thought to be nice to take some quick introductions
from from the floor as well so that we all know who each other are
so i'm going to ask them to start in the corner if you just say
your name and your affiliation degree
great welcome to all of you
so the objectives of this morning's tutorial really to introduce you to the concept of
linked data might be considered some of you are familiar with if not that's not
a problem of generic introduction to start with
which will conclude with some information about why you might want to publish linked data
on the web so hopefully that will be the motivating
the motivating background to the rest of the tutorial
well then go on to introduce the principles and best practices publishing linked data on
the web and go through the technical details of how to actually conduct this process
and talk to some of the kind of design decisions which you need to make
you publish linked data
there will be a session about how the data might be consumed from
the web and to provide a kind of
an indication of the fact that it's not just about publishing is the whole cycle
here publication consumption
and then we'll wrap up with a kind of look at the future what's happening
in two thousand nine and some of the challenges that we face in the broad
field of linked data so we hope to do the end is to have a
kind of linked data clinic
which may be sounds it's is less invasive than it sounds with the idea is
that we can hopefully take have a nice discussion session and take questions from the
floor and hopefully debug any any questions you have about data on some these planning
this is the schedule as it stands
chris will start shortly on a general introduction about data won why
and then we'll get onto the
the the the needs of the
session which is publishing linked data that already adopted the first coffee break
eleven will come back carry on with the publishing
section and then go through the rest of the items on the programme here
the due the slide you have on the USB stick and a kind of early
drafts so we've we've enhanced them further in the time between when we had to
in the months since submitted and so will circulate the
the updated version put them on the on the tutorial website as well since we
can get a reliable upstream connections
over to chris now
thank you for small thing
very much
hello good morning everybody i'm talking a bit about the general concept of linked data
as the what and why
my name is chris bits from the free university of berlin and
we have done here
semantic web things and linked data things for quite awhile
my talk will be separated into three parts
first ever get the kind of overview of
the current transition of of that of documents to a web of data compelling data
it is
the API is microformats and
these two things
to give an overview about what linked data is out there on the web so
different publishing efforts and how the different data sets play together
and look at some applications that people have built on the set of data so
linked data browsers search engines mash ups things like this
so to understand the general concept of linked data to get rid of this hand
to understand the general concept of linked data it's good
step back a bit and look at what made that itself
what made this a successful is
is one single information space
so all those HTML pages that published published into a single information space
so can clearly tell what
the pages online which are not
so one thing having a single information space the other thing is
i stand that's where the classical rep
there are URL's as unique
i d four web pages but also has unique
this global retrieval mechanism
but the URL in your browser something shows
so one thing it's another thing is HTML is shared content from
the start really important a hyperlinks
kind of the who
that kept the classic that to get
and the idea of linked data is not to apply these principles that proved useful
the going to talk about the doppler effect
it is best known for sound they probably remind you of your high school days
if you move towards the result you hear the pitch of the whistle higher than
the whistle
and if you move away from the whistle then you you local pitch than
it's of the whistle
or if if there was almost to ulu hear higher pitch and when the whistle
moved away from you your local pitch
so you may think now
when you move in a certain speed towards the whistle
or whether they were so moved with the same speed you
that you will use the same increase in pitch
but that is not true
there's is actually
the big difference the situation is not symmetric
if you move towards the whistle
with the speed of sound
and the frequency that you hear is twice the frequency of the whistle
but if there is so moves towards you with the speed of sound
you will hear nothing
because all the sound stays with the whistle
until the whistle
passes you know you you form of sound frequency goes to infinity
you break the sound barrier so to speak if you survive it
so there is a large asymmetry between
the speed of sound
is about three hundred and forty meters per second
at room temperature
about seven hundred seventy miles per hour that's the reason why commercial airplanes
do not fly any faster relative to air then seven hundred seventy miles per hour
because they are not designed to break the sound barrier
that's the limiting factor for commercial airlines
let this be
the transmitter of sound
and this is the receiver of sound that could be you
and that is assumed
that you move
with a certain velocity i call this the plus direction
and you move with the velocity v are
and that the transmitter moves with the velocity v t
and the transmitter
it produces sound f
but what you receive is frequency
f prime so f is the frequency
so if you go in the velocity in this direction that's positive
and the velocity in this direction then becomes negative
then f primal
is f
the speed of sound
might as we are
divided by the speed of sound
minus vt
you should be able to derive that on their own and it's very asymmetric you
can see that immediately
i make the are
the same as vs
so he upstairs become zero
so f prime
close to zero that's obvious
if you walk away from the sound source was the speed of sound the sound
never reaches you
you walk as fast as the sum comes to you
so you nothing
but that's immediately obvious that f prime then has to become zero
but if we now make the
the sound source go away from you is the speed of sound
so again
this in between the two view grows so now
of the transmitter
make mine is
the speed of sound
then notice what happens
the frequency i receive is simply one how
f so f prime
is now we have f a c enormous difference
in the two you walk away from the source with the speed of sound
and you nothing
and if the sound moves away from you with the speed of sound all you
hear is half the frequency of the sound source
i have four thousand hertz tuning fork there
so f
four thousand words
and i'm going to move my hand towards you as fast as i can which
is about one meter per second
in other words
i'm the transmitter
so vt
it is approximately class
one meter per second
and and then you should hear then f prime
which is about point three percent higher than efforts about four thousand
and then i will move my hand away from you was about
one meter per second so
i have to put a minus sign in there
and then i will find
europe we consider you will hear is about
and if you like many of these problems are ones which to go to make
to make a connection back to what nielsen is ones which introduced traditional statistics and
a lot of
conventional statistical machine learning we leave to the human human data analysts rather than the
model we let humans
tried to decide what is the right form of knowledge to apply in this case
this case or exactly how complex model can we get away with that of course
there are there are heuristics their statistical guidelines there automatic methods but ultimately these choices
rest in the hands of the human data analyst and the goal of machine learning
to to automate those
similarly if the goal of cognitive science understand how human who's truly autonomous learning agent
is able to solve these problems over a much wider scope of of data and
problem that are typically capture only one kind of machine learning task
one last question which i want to say very much about although tom griffiths was
a lot of some about i think later on in the class
is for the
lecture series is how can all these inferences go on so
fast how can they be so accurate yet so efficient
all of these are challenges that we need to understand
and the exciting thing for me about the energy between these two fields is that
we have a tool kit of technical ideas that putting together can help to address
the so there's a rough alignment here
between these five questions in these five kinds of technical ideas but of course it's
that's just rough
the the the the key thing is just as the key challenges how to all
these questions go together in formulating what's interesting about how the mind works these techniques
are most interesting when you understand how they work together
and i don't want to suggest that these are the only interesting ideas in machine
learning for cognitive science just as these are not the only interesting problems in cognitive
science but what motivates a lot of us here are problems like these and we
look to modern machine learning for techniques like these so this includes just to solve
the basic problem of how do you use knowledge to guide inference sparse data well
that's why many of us like bayesian paradigm because it very naturally captures that with
the idea of a probabilistic generative model that provides some kind of office space and
prior for interpreting finding the hidden unobservable stuff of the world from the data we
if the question is what form does knowledge take well there we're excited about the
idea that we can do statistical learning and inference not just in high dimensional vector
spaces but over various different forms and structures of representation things that look more like
the traditional symbolic computational paradigms like graphs grammars predicate logic or even programs so you'll
see these days in some of the state of the art in machine learning and
probabilistic AI and cognitive science people defining probabilistic models over literally you know
statements in first-order logic or publishing models over programs reuse the idea of of the
program to which ultimately you know
approach what a program does this it's a formal description of the process is the
idea of a program to describe the processes in the world is very rich universal
representation of causality and if we want to understand how you make the kind of
causal inferences that we're talking about you know like that or
you know what newton or or mental we're doing thinking about as a kind of
probabilistic programme induction seems to be the set of potentially
valuable way to go
it's hard but interesting if you want to talk about where abstract knowledge comes from
not just how it's used we've been very interested in hierarchical probabilistic models are somewhat
sometimes called hierarchical bayes where instead of just having a single hypothesis space provides the
prior for interpreting data you have hypothesis spaces in price at multiple levels of hypothesis
spaces of hypothesis spaces and priors on priors my doing inference is all level of
that hierarchical model you can talk about not just how abstract knowledge constraints instance one
so there's there's parameter gamma here
no we call these
kernel parameters
or if you're greedy the kernel parameters
so the brand kernel parameters correspond to different mapping functions
so similar school and you have to decide what the penalty parameter see that you
also have to decide the kernel parameter
parameters common or eighty in the it so there's always an issue
so now let's talk more about kernels so no unification is it really useful
formerly they have to high dimensional space
it is hard
half of that convince you that
but i think they had to be space data
can really be separated there some theoretical results proving that we in probability that
o thing higher space then the probability that how can be separated is a big
search results
and as you can see here is
the kernel may may help to separate the training data
this is similar situation in space
for any independent vectors
they actually linearly separable
why is that
well just run it just so solve the equation so you simply the sentences they
are linearly independent
well as it is so to say
so i suppose i have i have made
each each training instance twenty two a that mission of space
two and dimensional space so this considered in the eye of space and you independent
vectors and i have many instances so i actually have a square matrix you so
i wrote this good metrics you know that's some the simple linear equations it is
going to increase the independence is matrix is incredible
so i can always
so i just is that with the right hand side to be plus or minus
one i mean depending on the state is the first or second class
so there should be separate training instances
OK so what we have this page that is what we know so little about
if you're
kernel matrix is positive definite
if you're a kernel matrix is positive definite then you are guaranteed to separate all
training expenses
so if you're weighting function be used true positive definite kernel matrix
then you they had can be fully separated
OK so now that actually may not be good because it and we want to
avoid overfitting
so on the one hand we we've we've made it so that
in in principle training data can can all be separated them from that we
we use other adjustments like parameters you something else so we avoid overfitting
results mentioning this is that
if you're a kernel is positive definite then they can be before is positive definite
it you can do it for us civilization to air transports then in a sense
you can see that you are transforming your training instances tools two independent vectors in
this is not this is it is not the case and i am should they
ever by a square matrix and the number of training instances
so so this is one way to explain the kernels help to separate training data
so there are a lot of the ships
so now you may ask what kind of kernel should i use
so you are
are you asking what kind of making functions should i use
another usually is what kind of functions that the kernel
so you even just a function of x and y how do you know that
it can be separated into the inner product of two vectors
then we use automation kernel parameters
so for the same type of kernels
different parameters
that that actually means
i mean the meanings different meaning functions so how do we decide that solos i
e shows that we have to hand we will discuss the data
so let's assume that all
now we already have the kernel function and we
not only that we have even solve the dual problem
goodbye by by introducing deal
by introducing her
now we can write on matrix q so we really do problems with all so
it is annihilation but as soon as we already saw it so we get the
to have
so we have to live by the primal dual relationship we also have to be
well looks good
USA we still have a problem
even estimating phylogenies
it is an infinite vector then it is impossible to use to explicitly right down
the the top right even even if we know those coefficients have so there's no
way to write on the subject that where it turns out that you don't have
to do that using this relationship we put it into these function so we w
transpose these testing data explorer b
there could be some fall into this inner product we get the mention of actually
training instances and testing instance
so if we can calculate the inner product between training and testing data
that means the kernel function and we have we never have to write this is
a good idea
the only thing we need to know is up to what we have and those
but since the prose nice separable nothing happens
nothing really happens
and i can see something happened
the separating hyperplane a little bit
but the now
so those
green service respond to support vectors
so what you can see is
on the side of the raids
of course all the rates that go beyond that lie
line are support vectors
margin errors
anything beyond there will be actually are
now for the blue dots
the same thing
anything that's on that line and beyond
the support vector
and what we will see now is this week crank c
this final match
because now there is actually with the trade-off between
making a few margin errors
and the smallest land
but in a smaller market they see
march is getting smaller
and i jumped again
six built those points
the good news is
four trained doctor asian concert doesn't matter
very noisy data having a large regularizer means that we get a very narrow margin
so this really tries very hard to do a the job even if the country
do it
and that may lead to overfitting
thing is cleaned up has very few support vectors
we go back
the scene
there are only three support vectors
as if we go to noisy data
but if you
nice start of course means that you will also see the points in the margin
this explains why support vectors initially got popular by doing optical character recognition
that's the problem we assume that you be able to separate from the but the
dotted with a very large margin
so mean it would not be acceptable to have more than the percent errors
support vectors really blossomed in this area
and this is why they could work on sixty thousand of the right
even at the time
a large rock station was one with thirty two megabytes of memory
this is how you can actually solve this
they just import
in SVM
from elephants
don't worry me she will be doing this in the practical sessions before more
hst five some kernels
so on that the linear function or an RBF kernel with a certain way
important classifiers
you just run the train
and you can
all taste and do something useful here
this is the only thing that really changed in the optimisation problem if we wanted
to limit
the influence innovation
this the soft margin optimisation problem
so before that we had out i
being great people here and nothing else
now we will get an upper bound on the offline policy
they seem to what it means is every single observation may contribute to the problem
only to the extent that c
nothing more than that
this is also an interesting thing in the sense that if we had feasible from
the problem the dual problem could become unbounded
unbounded simply means that this minimization problem can diverge to minus infinity
by found this this cannot happen so fine
it's actually nice connection to robust statistics in the sense that
you want to limit the influence of a single observation
and so
you could from that comes compute something like an influence function
so the optimisation problems almost identical
and there
efficient solvers will now not tomorrow sorry
it was for a different set of slides
this another picture from are
this was how to sell the internet
so you would have
while inputs
OK you would have various prototypes like those digits
the map m into feature space taking the product you they have to wait
and then you have some decision function on top of it
this is
and it's kind of nice almost a thousand reasons rather than anything else
this is how you know you would also described in order to defeat some data
in you have some lights and then you get a higher level
synaptic weights and so on
here's an example
now the non linear experience
using gas in
and now i'm going to go through
organisation consul as you can see
there's a reason why they asked me and neural computation whether the good-looking of biological
samples and this looks like an amoeba something
the interesting bit notice however is
i mean this is the actual actually relevance line of separation
it's not too bad even if i crank up the organization
genetic differences
there is a nice example
by richard lewington be that the geneticists where
he imagines two plots
but what is some sort of a week
two plots of land
and each one has a set of seed
and i know there were no there anyway
one of them you fertiliser line
the other one you fertilizer little
now within each plot
much deceived grows is actually largely determined by the genetics of the seed
and so you find high heritability for growth in the seats
but the difference
between groups
has no genetic cause at all it's caused by which group to fertilize more than
here's another way to do
to the logic suppose
from the middle
down here
you guys i hate
i really hate only
and i like you
so i make up two midterms
you provided no better two midterms this imagery was officially hard
savagely hard too many beautiful and the class it
this mid-term was you know
which is bigger than a dog or an elephant
because i like you and i want you all to succeed now
so you have two different groups you guys new that
within each group some people are going to do better than others
the explanation for that might actually have two proteins
the environment how much is studied all sorts of reasons for that within each group
some of you will do better in the hard test and then others and are
to some better easy test
then than than than others and easy this
how do we explain the group difference i have nothing to do with g is
the group difference about you will do much worse than you have to do the
exams like it
my point again is that is no logical difference between within group difference
within this half of the class and the difference between groups within between this group
and this group
what do we know
about so that the shows are not the same thing but what the fact that
the matter what do we know
about human differences between different human groups
again the textbook has a good discussion of this
i'm no
give two reasons
from the textbook badly screwed differences are used to a large extent environmental energy that
one is that the differences we finite you seem to correspond better to socially defined
groups then genetically defined groups
this seems to correspond to groups defined in terms of how people treat you and
how people think about you as opposed to DNA
and extend that turns out to be true
that would mean that that genetic explanation is not reasonable for those differences
a second factor
that we know IQ can differ radically
without any genetic differences at all
and the most dramatic evidence of that
is the flynn effect
before fact is one three clear findings
the flynn effect is the finding that
people have been getting smarter
you are much smarter
on average than their parents
and the IQ test hide
here's why they hide
behind that because they always make a hundred the average
so you come along and say that then i just an IQ test i got
one hundred twenty
and if i could works on i got one hundred twenty two
when i was your age
but what needed you acknowledge is your test was much harder as people got better
had to make the test harder and harder
and this is plotted by the people in fact one of these lines is
one of these lines american one is that i don't know which is which
but the gist of it is that that somebody would have
if you
in nineteen eighty
would take
the nineteen fifty test your average person in nineteen eighty which score hundred twenty and
in nineteen fifty s
with this means that you take your your persons average now
and pushing back through time twenty years thirty years
initial value of the weights so typically use simple either from
a gaussian or uniform in this case i mentioned the uniform case
between some negative value a positive value between some negative
and positive balance and here's one formula that comes from this
paper by that the whole in your bengio were
part of the attempt here and this was actually derived for tanh
age is to initially get been a situation where the units are not
saturating too much and you get a nice propagation of gradients
across layers ok but there's still does not exactly n
exact science there can be variations on the initialisations
and the bounds of each choose to classically sampling
unit for the s something units that might also work well or even
better potentially so the the surprise if you see other rules are
other code out that it's using a different way of initializing weights
are randomly but the main important thing is
to break symmetry and you might want to be careful when you initialise
weight just make sure please that none of the units are
from the get go all saturated and you get a gradient that is passing
through the layers effectively so what you might do then is that
initialization look at the gradient on all hidden units and
all activation layers make sure there perhaps about the same range
and at least that you know none of them are zero yes
yeah that's a good point so i think i think that can be so the
question is whether or not initialization can also be helpful
and maybe some people use that with some success that is another
trick that indeed some people use especially for
record neural nets but i think can also be useful for
the for nets yeah
yeah yeah
yeah so so indeed in terms of the analysis
of your initialization thinking about
what is the initial structure of the cobian view gradients
is is actually and important thing i'm a particularly crucial
to think about this specific issue when you talk about record
nets i suspect joshua we'll talk about that
or not we have to
right so so that covers the whole stochastic gradient descent
procedure there's still a few other details to be aware of so one
of them is model selection that is how to select the hyperparameters
so which your model those parameters effectively those those
degrees of freedom that are not train explicitly
with stochastic gradient descent so that includes the number
of hidden layers the size of each hidden layer
regularization factor lambda the choice of the activation functions
all these different choices you make
that are not changed by stochastic gradient descent procedure
so as i don't know mention you know the typical set up is that you
have a training set on which are trying to model you run stochastic
gradient descent then you have a validation set and use that to
try different options for the values of these hyperparameters
and at the end you take the model that was trained
with hyperparameters as the best performance on the validation
set but ultimately the performance would report in a paper
where you're trying to valley what is the actual on
generalization performance and on dice it would be the performance
on a separate test set and that's the thing that you
report you report the training set error because it's optimistic
it's seen this data and the models so obviously it's going to
be pretty good on the training set you don't also report the validation
set performance because you did chuen hyperparameters on it so it
is also though much less but still slightly bias in optimistic
way around good performance that's why you need to set
those correspond to these unseen examples the performance on
which you really care about in terms of
developing a good model so how do you actually do this model selection
how do you take you know suggestions hyperparameters to try
and run experiment to measure the validation set
what has been useful long time and to some extent it's still use
for a bit is grid search so grid search in this case you would
list out all of your hyperparameters
so to make a simple they are to the number of hidden layers and
the the choice of the learning rate the step size
so then you going to lists a finite number of values you want
to try out for each for the number
of some number of hidden layers things let's say one to three
and then for the learning rate maybe zero point one zero one zero
one zero zero zero one that's okay so then
in grid search you are going to try all combinations of choices for
these two hyperparameters sets three times three that's nine configuration
so that's actually a whole lot and that's one big problem which
search will tend to a explode and the number configurations you
get the more choices try to make for each individual hyperparameter
it turns out this this this is not is not too large to be prevented
from working so this this is much smaller than what you get
using something wrong
there has been no further
i don't think about fifty years
in statistics it's called stochastic approximation
and very intelligent
statisticians as we cannot understand
conditions that required on the learning rate and the number of transitions performed each time
that in which the optimal solution
of course from the training time
so simple but if you want to implement this
first of all it rather simple
and about the fact that
i said you a few decades after each weight update actually the only one
and that you
small so that it doesn't change world
between best so that in fact the markov chain
can run fast enough to keep up with the model
it is not going to
i have i usually use one hundred
so that when you get it pretty good samples instead of one
reduces variance between your gradient estimates
as i mentioned smaller is needed as well in particular the same approach
but using a one
you can also that sufficiently powerful itself
well it was
these estimates themselves larger
so you still have the same amount
so if you have received
that very easy to convert it to pieces
just right static or global negative data
and then from the
so i think it that's all
so some experiments first the references
new system and so
what we did is we took the and the
for two o five five five five pixel patches from
so with twenty five feasibility study in
and full collectivity
this twenty five visible units
units in this model
so is the
nice for small
this is for IBM
the tractable part of the gradient
you are increasingly
probability of your training data
becomes very simple for this model
to do is
i was looking at the average of the training set
the data
in two each gradient estimate
the thing part is so difficult part but that's what this algorithm
so as to make it easier
as a result
compared to pseudo likelihood training to persistent contrastive divergence training
after this access
so that after about thirty seconds of training times
this performance is better
so it doesn't have to be expensive
if you do training with the exact likelihood gradient which is what which takes time
but this fact for this time not because it's only
twenty five percent that
that's what you want to ask them to two with persistent contrastive divergence if you
have a lot of training time
so after about five seconds like so many
so this morning don't and indeed this this is
the business model in almost exactly
the great
and that you need
so if you look at
the entropy of the data sets which is a bit like this would be the
best possible this can be achieved with the help of these models do not have
sufficient capacity to model that
the thing that was
the city you can get as good as you can get with exact likelihood trained
gradient training
experiments with the
this is four times
with the hidden units so that they can everything is tractable
in fuel from well as you can see a fixed amount of training time
this work
so that classification
with the number of reasons but to by your local show
so i agree you don't want to use regions of interest
too much
take for example are automatic labeling systems of the brain and then you can kind
of construct like a large number of different regions of interest and try to each
to a different region of interest the key idea is you want to be unbiased
you want to search through the whole grain
i know we've used we use we used regions of interest as well and actually
found some fascinating things if we don't use regions of interest for example we find
is that if you take the classic physic face area
here's take the sorry object processing you take a classic object localiza when you get
the l c the famous bites man institute area
well so that you can get it in different ways and you always see the
same area and now
if you do this
looking just for recordable information about objects
independent of the orientation
and you see
and this region more interior color schemes
rotation invariant information
so how about objects
so you want to win this is based on the region of interest
look at this you only getting half the story because actually the interesting part
i mean for classification analysis only getting half the story not saying that localizes the
wrong but for classification of is getting only half the story because the actually interesting
information is in different parts of the brain
as long as
i agree
no they were not that i agree
we have a certain assumptions and the assumption is we look for information is local
and the reason we look for the information is local that
is the belief that the core
storage format of information in the brain is in local
but distributed
colin are
maps that are specific for one type of information in one graph that's the law
that rational here
there might be you see that the point is then at least you know that
something would be able to see this information
if you take the voxel in prefrontal cortex and one in the cerebellum you might
end up in the case where the you have to take to sign up this
information can get together
and that's very difficult to interpret similar to whole brain decoding announces they're all very
nice for for for for building machines
that can classify something if you want to kind of build a lie detector or
something like that but they're not very useful for localizing information in the brain
OK so
so next i'm going to address in a different issue which is just now
every one of you chose
adding or subtracting
and now
if you were to report
on how you make your choice
can i just ask how many people chose adding and so can help chose adding
and who chose subtracting
again i'm not going to stop it's just forget about this
skip over the experiments
and talk directly about our experiment because otherwise it will be enough time
in this study what we were interested in was question how
this information
o point in time and in the brain influence decisions that are made data
and we did a version of the famous limited experiment
and so subjects were given a box in the left hand
and they were instructed
after the in the prediction and
correctly updated the corrected one and the and the
and k matrix that the how that enters the enters the correct
i'm not sure which of these formats to tackle
yes certainly
this this is like
so this is like this state equation
the is the state equation so i i guess i can keep thinking of this
example that
it might
somehow reflect newton's laws mean this this this guy is moving
and we're we're we're trying to find it
so it's where you is position and velocity or something
so like so you is the vector position and velocity
and if we know the position and velocity at the previous time
o and say it
freefall then we could
predict where it should be
but of course
it would be exactly
correct our prediction would would have made some assumptions and those would be errors in
that form
right OK
often i suppose it would be if the time step was the same but this
i mean the the strength and the weakness of
how general is
i mean
well you might say well was a little bit limited to this
a single step
what if there was a second order equations with common be dead
i mean
what is methods fail
what do you think if it if if the state if the state equation that
control this was like newton's law second order equations would we be dead now
we were defined
you have to be
position and velocity
the old trick of reducing second order equations of coupled first-order system so we could
get back to first order system
well we couldn't recover from is that the state
dependent on the state zero
and and and the state one hundred also depended on zero that's what
that would screw the screw-up try diagonal picture and common could could
but apart from that
we have a very large generality here
and i was going to have a mention winner in the first lecture
in the first year this afternoon
i was gonna say OK what did we introduce because we with that at this
job before coming
also what did we were doing what did come and do that was no
well what we never did was handle problems where the may where the matrix
time invariant
where it started probably at minus infinity so there was nobody knows you know no
no trouble with the starting point and matrix didn't change it was exactly like our
matrices in that first lecture you remember the comments we made
one the very first time we looked at the matrix k and we said OK
what are it's obvious properties
symmetric was obvious
prior diagonal was obvious
and the other obvious thing was the
i doubt it was constant diagram
now what's the point of that the point of that is as as was later
lectures will focus on that
special situation of constant diagonal time invariant
the point is
four it takes over
you can move in the frequency domain for those problems and that's where we are
he was
specialists in fourier a massive fourier analysis
was like his
is about
so that he
gave formulas in the fourier domain which are
simpler better in you know you know they've you're using all that extra structure
but then kalman showed up with his
state in the time domain
state space approach
so that was like a big revolution in this whole subject
that to move from winners frequency domain approach which was limited to
time invariant and how to take over time
assumes that anything was time varying
two kalman who could live with that he could deal with time varying he was
really doing linear algebra or try diagonal matrices
OK that's that's like
relations so that when we seeing at a later date to how to deal with
time invariant stuff by
taking a fourier transform
and remember that that's where we want
the work
because it wasn't totally simple
i have to say this
four e eight
requires time invariant
but it also
like it like no boundary like time invariant from
from forever to forever
and we don't have that we've got you know we're coming up to some time
so these matrices are
constant diagonal but they m
so you would say well then
the it's not directly related so the number of parameters may not be directly related
to the complexity and actually you can construct cases where you have infinitely many parameters
very small complexity or
very large complexity with only one parameter
at least what you can get from these bounds is
what is the quantity that controls the complexity of my class of functions
OK but now the
the risk when you use bound is this
but you may be tempted to justify
some other
from the bound that
from the analysis of this algorithm
OK so doing this is fine
doing this is dangerous
even wrong
so why is that wrong
here is the trick
you give me a class of functions
and i define on this class some functional
so something that take function and gives the number
so if i take two values
one is smaller than the other one
the set of functions forward the functional is less than x is
obviously including in the set of functions for the function is less than one
if i compute the complexity of this
the set of of the subset of functions
complexity in one of the sense that i mentioned before
of course it will be
a nondecreasing function of x rights
the larger s x the largest the set so large that the complexity it kind
chris if you add more functions
now if i
so just write down the bound that involve
the set of function of function and then i will have about that tells me
the smaller the x the better or in other terms the smaller dysfunctional better
right so i have constructed this way about that tells
i should minimize this function you know if you if you interpreted directly it says
you will
in your own words and try to make this as small as possible
right then i can put here whatever you want i can say well this is
the margin of my function
and then i justify this way
maximizing the so sorry this is one of the margin and this way i justify
maximising the margin i can say well this is some
specific property of my classifier and then i i can justify any algorithm that minimizes
this property of the function
and that's
this prior
p that we put so this morning but still
it doesn't mean that you can do that period but it doesn't mean that the
algorithm should do that to do a good job
it means that if
was minimizes this quantity
and when you compute the quantity on the function that is constructed
it's actually small and you have a small error in the same time there
you're in good shape but it's
and OK that's the same thing in terms of these
weight weighted union bound so that you can do the same trick
you choose p that gives more weight to function that satisfies the property
and of course the bot will tell you
or if you look at it
directly to will tell you
try and minimise the so that maximize the probability so minimize logw on working
but what you shouldn't do from that
is this
i couldn't say well because i have found that involve this quantity
my algorithm is justified
so that's why is very
tricky because when you do write the bounds for certain reasons
you end up with what it is
that are either artificial or intrinsic
artificial would be quantities such that this
or quantities that come from the the way you set up the bounds all you
set up the analysis
intrinsic would be the quantity that come from this geometry again
and it's hard to tell whether what you're thinking about
it is really
intrinsic or not
OK so to summarise this part about how to use bound
the first thing is forget about the value
at least now maybe ten years twenty years people would have better techniques but for
now i guess
it's hopeless
and right rather try to
capture the meaningful information that is in the valley and distinguish between what you have
put even
without noticing it in the bound and what comes out of the interesting analysis
it turns out
now i'm i'm becoming very philosophical in the whale now i i want to
give some
remarks of or some ideas that
are very
debatable but
OK you would contradict me at the end you will have time for asking questions
giving your point of view
so when OK now back to the design of organism
so when you want to design
i was
and that's very personal opinion
i would recommend to
not make assumptions in the when you make these algorithms lists
be sure that
these assumptions that you made
are really assumptions and they are not something that you believe is true
unless you really some someone tells you that it's true some some expert from the
domain that from which the problem constantly OK this is property of the
of the system is is true because i checked it or something but if this
is not the case
try not to make assumptions about trying not to be too
to realize that i mean to rely too much in your assumptions
so these are some typical examples
and extends to vector composition single could have factory from the age of more than
one variable
and then a different functions g g i and then you could have combinations of
these theorems were
decreasing in some components and increasing and others and then gk
also our
convex or concave
so for example the sum of the logarithm of GI effects is concave
if the functions GIR positive and concave
it follows from these rules
log of the sum of the exponential g i fx is convex if g functions
GIF convex
and it follows from the fact that locks some of x
is a convex function that's one of the examples i gave
and then we apply one of these composition rules
and this is complicated function but is often used as a smooth
approximation of the maximum of these functions g i
because log some of exp of several variables
it is a smooth function
and it's often used as a smooth approximation for the maximum
then there are two more i think the next one this minimisation rule that looks
very similar to the supremum
property that i give
three slides ago
the this case again we start with the function of two variables x and y
we minimize over the second variable
and that defines in new
the function g of x
and in the previous case we had maximisation of the function of two variables we
maximize over the second one
so the difference here is that this function f
so under certain conditions the resulting function g is convex
and the properties are much more restrictive than in the other case
so here if must be a convex function jointly in x and y
and in the other case in this maximisation rule there are no assumptions on how
it depends on
for fixed white had to be convex in x
here is convex joint in x and y
and also the sets
over which we minimize it must be a convex set
so if that's true then the resulting function is convex
so an example is for example this this is still convex set is always convex
and that's true in any more
to see this we just use this apply this property so we can write the
distance as
you take the distance of x to point y in the set
using any any particular norms so that's always convex because norms are convex and and
and it's just a linear combination of
x y so this is a convex function jointly in XLI
and then you minimize over y
so if y is convex c is convex then this is convex
so this is still convex set is always the convex function
that's true in any normal and also for any set is convex
another application of this that's very useful is
in sensitivity analysis
for example suppose we consider here we consider linear program in y is terrible
so we have a linear objective seat i suppose y the product of CNY
and constraints on y
with the right hand side x
so the constraints on what ordered a wider vector y is componentwise less than x
so that's only program in y
and this is the optimal value
of the linear programme
if minimize over wide and this is the optimal value
and i can define a new function of x
that takes as its value the
the optimal value of the LP is a function of the right hand side effects
and in many applications it's interesting to know how the optimal value of an optimisation
problem as an LP varies with the