and then we also focus on that last number there
so what i'm going to do is the following
i going think about looking at the correlation matrix of the following vector
right so what i could do is i could take groups
i'm gonna make a vector is a vector in four dimensions
it's random vector it's got one on the first coordinate x one x two x
three and then i'm going to take that column vector an outer product with the
row vector and take the expectation of that and i'm going to look at what
i get
you have a question
right so what happens
we can sort of read off the first row the first row is like the
expectation of one times one that's one one times x one that's mu one
but if you look at how i define mu one one times x two expectations
mu two and u three
now the second row should look like this
can somebody explain why the second row should look like that
right these are all moments
so i think the only interesting one is why is the diagonal mu one
right because it's binary if you take expectation of x one squared
that's equal to x one expectation x one so you get you that on the
columns that using the binary nest when i start to get the products get x
one times x two i get mu one mu two
we're sorry you want to use two three so i feel this out i get
a four by four matrix
right now filled with moments
moments or i cherry-picked elements of my marginal
what can we say about that matrix
right to be positive semi definite
we do not guarantee this so nonnegative i can values
right so if you go back and look at this example that i gave to
you earlier this one right here
if you plug those numbers
right these numbers
this around plugging them into this matrix and you take the determiner just compute the
i can values to see it's not positive definite
or semidefinite
right so that's telling us that that violate
these constraints
that's i think the quickest way you can check this other ways but that's a
very quick way
right and that's actually very useful way because this is the convex constraints and probably
even mention this that when you take these are called linear matrix inequalities when you
linear functions of whatever parameters are interested in and you require that things are positive
semi definite that's like cone membership constraint you're saying in the positive definite semidefinite cone
so that's convex so you can imagine adding that constraint to LP relaxation and you
would get a hybrid you get something like step is an LP plus an SDP
etc etc it's better relaxation
so there's been some study of these things and has been more in in computers
are theoretical computer science in combinatorics but machine learning i don't think these things have
been exploited as much as they could be
part of the issues algorithm of course in machine learning we have very large scale
problems lps are very easy to solve expecially when they're graph structured so you can
do message passing but i think various people are working on fast ways of solving
sdps and so i think this is an interesting direction to look at things like
this and these types of constraints
so let me walk a bit more slowly you jumped us all crawl and then
so for binary problems i was exploring things like this happen that expectation of x
one square is mu one there's nothing specific about this approach to binary if you
had a general the discrete variables you can just use this you have to take
an indicator vector for to equal one two three you have and many states you
have to blow up the matrix
you're exactly right if you have continuous problems
you could again define functions of your continuous random vector and impose these kinds of
so there is for those of you interested this sort of a much more general
theory of this
related to what's called polynomial programming by this air jones
c is a series of very nice papers about semidefinite relaxations and hierarchies the sort
of the canonical hierarchy that works for continuous things he's not thinking about graphical models
he's coming from a very different point of view but his techniques certainly have nice
consequences for graphical models
any other questions
OK so the question is why do what did i do this weird thing what
i put a constant random variable
so the reason that i mean this is what lesser does its part of a
special case general scheme but the reason for that is that if you didn't put
the one you get the submatrix
right so that's OK
but the constraint the extra thing you get by adding this row is good it
helps you for instance
this submatrix right here
this two by two submatrix on these variables
that two by two submatrix is positive semi definite this is actually equivalent to the
linear programming constraint
right because this is making
sorry if you add one more row two it becomes equivalent to the LP constraint
so in general you want to i mean modular computational complexity you want to add
whatever you can to the SDP and this is just one rho so it's it's
not bad
the way you generalize this of course is you can see the generalisation right instead
of one x one x two x three i could now take x one times
x two x two times x we have to keep lifting so these these sequences
relaxations of people study for instance these are called lifting the procedures is called lifting
because you're taking your original problem and you're listening to higher spaces and getting better
so there there are nice very powerful but again there is a trade-off with computation
yes i think this is worth exploring more
i think there's some jews in these
now we have
three these of processes
it means here
have axis of
we have also
this is a very particular kind of approximation
fogelson would have and square root
we impose also a particular structure
she was saying that
like terms
in fact
the only way
there is hope
to each other
i j
the result was respected
of the of the system
so now
we need to look at
you can the try likelihood the job is going to be
i just want to gaussians
must all these
that's why situation
to be
for example the utility is the vector
it is
sigma two
matrix here is that the matrix
OK so now we can work out our result
approximation to the posterior
to do that by in
and that is how to choose from
what is actually good
that values to use these problems
the key idea to me
he is should
it's a
based on the observations of
what i mean
if you look at at the posterior distribution for
to size
it has the highest
this country fire
which tells you how to
smooth line
terms from cases
so this is defined by case
these representative
approximation of
all these like terms are approximated
that's not the case
which is exactly what i
what we do is
we can actually handle
the one-dimensional version of gas
this single it can actually be wrong
what's going on
great job
problem into a series of one
by using
approximation are all of
one thing which is
what is
activation of
i see
you might decide that
what is the
distribution over
if i leave
i observation
why are you here as
approximate likelihood terms is
all of this is that
this is things all
now again
that's the easiest way to find that look at the
joint distribution with all the
all right
here is part of
you want to find
they a
the main thing is that the
at iteration
it is
that's she had mean
so i and then
it was red
so now we we have to
what is the what
approximately wire has been
the last thing we need to
introduces the idea is to use exactly
we're gonna
process will habit which i
exact like that he
distribution exactly the
now we're going to be find
figure out
what we do best approximation
to use this
and approximate
i don't know
but it was
these are the same
this is that
so i'm here
like the function
so this is the observation
which one is in the underlying function
it should be
that's the
and like down
and you
at each something else which depends on the order of
o thing going on all the time all
now i want my like
you get something like this
looks as here
because like drop
now it's OK
let's try to find the best possible approximation as an approximation
to this day
sigma two
and now we start and with are archie
two p act
and our pi i two p while
so this is our valence electron configuration for b two
right so what would you expect the bonding water for b two to b
shouted out if you know
and i can right up there but it is one and we can see that
it's one because it's one have
two four minus two so what happened to the bonding water is going to be
equal to one
so let's move on to another example let's talk about carbon here again we're just
talking about the valence electrons so carbon has four valence electrons so we talk about
the two again we're going to start filling in our molecular orbitals and now we're
going to have eight
electrons to fill into our molecular orbitals so put two and sigma two as two
and sigma two n star
and now we're going to fill one-on-one into each of our pi two px and
two py y
but we still have two electrons left so what we're going to do is double
in terms of our two px and two py y
so let's think about what this account electron configuration is first the two
and again i want you to have practiced drawing out in the form you always
need to start with the same and then write the number of the orbit also
sigma two as it has two electrons sigma two s star
with two electrons
and now we have sigma two p at how many electrons here
and sigma two p
two electrons here
scuse me pi two PY thank you pi two px and py two PY
so let's talk about what the bonding water is going to be first CTO so
what's the bonding order for c two
two OK so
we have to
four six
minus two
so we have
one had
six minus two so that's one half of four so we have a bonding order
of two
for carbon two
so we would expect to see a double bond force the two where we would
expect to see
single bonds and double bond first e two a single bond for b two
and that is in fact what we can surmise if we look at the different
dissociation energies for the tube on so b two which is the single bond that's
two hundred eighty nine killing joules per mole the break and it takes us more
energy to break this double bond for carbon which is five hundred ninety nine code
rules from all
so in general what we see in this is always true for comparing the same
pattern and in general for comparing different types of molecules but we know that the
single bond is always weaker than the double bond which is weaker than the triple
bonds and obviously no bond is the weakest of all that's not bonding
right so let's look at now in the case where we do have two p
the orbitals that we're talking about so again what we're talking about the linear combination
of atomic two p orbitals an hour talking about two pv
so if we have a constructive interference between the two
what we're going to see if the atomic orbital look a molecular orbital look something
like this
to predict that this will be a sigma or pi orbital
right i hear a little bit of time varying current state here are quite a
few people think sigma this is in fact the sigma two pz orbital is what
this orbital is called the reason that i i think about it if you look
at the bonding axis here is that there is no nodal plane along the bond
in access
also it is cylindrically symmetric
across around the bonding axis so this is how we know that the sigma orbital
so some p orbitals form pi molecular orbitals in some form sigma p orbital specifically
it's always the
that forms the sigma orbital and the reason is at least at the minimum for
this class we always define the into nuclear axis is the axis so this is
always always the axis was always going to be the two p that are coming
together head on
the reason that there is increased electron density here you can see
that these two orbitals come together and constructively interfere
as it is and and figure out how to solve for
how to solve OK just so this is now a quick review of linear algebra
with apologies to those who master the subject completely in the summer and this is
this is I have to
what where my headed
well I have to talk about solving linear equations
and for what
part of this lecture I'll actually go through a little of the mechanic but of
Matlab is going to do the job for
but in the mechanics so this solving this equation by elimination so I'm going to
solve it by eliminating
so that means I do a lot of row operations right I multiply this rule
by suitable multiplier and I use it on to the next Schroeder produces 0 and
remember the key idea of solving equations as the make them systematically simpler
at Parliament that since spaces
getting shorter let medium to by 2
OK so take the 2 by 2 cases
OK so
so this is just k OK and it's got some x y equals we take
some whatever right hand side
so as
equals some right-hand side if 1 of 2 OK
OK have a system like that
well elimination is the way to do it
so what is elimination
it means that I
In words I would like to add half of that wrote to that 1
that would be
that would then produces this sold elimination word
and half of them the 1st equation will change to minus 1 will still multiply
X Y and still produce
if 1 but what will be the 2nd equation after elimination
so I'm going to add half of that to the
In order to produce said 0
and then when I had half of that so that's minus have added to the
to the left with 1 half 3
x y and here I have ever 1 plus the fact of the 2 of
if 2 is what I had and I added on half of 1
the right
again forgive me for a
dealing with 2 by 2 system but it's
see all clearly see the whole steps OK so
so we a multiplication
and I patiently copied the unknown x y
but that was a waste of time
time and space and I also followed up on the right hand side of the
due to the right hand side wanted the left but the serious
effort the thinking is all in the matrix in going from this matrix which was
our original matrix
so this matrix which is our matrix which we call that
good for upper upper triangular
so that the idea of elimination start with your matrix
do these row operations and end up with an upper triangular me OK
OK if thinking about a better give some names to some of the the numbers
that showing up here this number 2
is called the 1st paper
this is pivoting steps
so so here president change so it's still there
the number 2 is the 1st
I use it so I use that 1st pivot to clear out the column below
and now I'm over here
now I use the 2nd well I don't even actually
forces the last thing that I don't have anything more to do with it but
still accounts so that those appear 2 and 3 had
for this matrix
for this for this 2 by 2 this is key to
OK now what is that I
wanted to ask about k 2
well the same questions I asked about k 3
now should be easier for k to 1st of all
symmetric to us about all these stories
now it's it's these harder questions I'm I'm interested in is k 2
is the matrix is invertible and you don't know allowed to take it's the what's
I I claim that I can see from what's written on the board that invertible
because what
because once I get here I know
no problems I can solve the right
when the pivots are not 0
that's the test for invertibility that's not where
the pivots so invertible let me let me write that down invertible means also that
part of the non parameter never 0
OK but
i wanted it just as the set theoretic
all it is is to simple as that i claim
that i'll put evaluation
remember this is a maximal consistent set of formulae so the p fifty three say
somewhere along the line this enumeration is p fifty three
the been there and the negation of p fifty three is going to be
so what's the valuation that i put it there
happy nor p one p two on the p no p one p two dollars
and all i do is i second this maximal consistent set
and if is in a you make contribute you make it false if it's in
there you make true etcetera you see what i'm doing
in words
something like this
there is an edge from w to v
it's this one merely from the are in the and box
this one is the other way
all the really
in the
but diamond
so what i'm saying is unless i made the new better have diamond sign
OK i've already
it is approved there is well i not going to go through the proof
see if you can
little w and little v
i forgot to say a little w and little they are members of the big
w set right all consistent sets
sorry i should have said that
so t
is the set of all maximal consistent extension of gamma it's an infinite set
infinite sets of formulae
now what i'm going to do is take any one of those states take any
other of cities and i'm going to put a relation between
the canonical model relation
so this w and this these are maximal consistent set
of gamma
OK so
how you extend
the construction and the canonical model construction tomorrow large that's why i had done about
i want you to have some of which explain what's going on all the books
formerly from w are in the
the truth
can you see that
the membership relation here it's cashing out as truthful
box finding here means box Y's y
well wherever you go
five is going to be in there
so i'm going to be able to leave this membership valuation right in to bigger
and similarly
if there is a diamond signs say
it says well
there's going to be at least one
world which has signed
so the diamonds are going to be happy as well
that's basically the the triple technical
mumbo-jumbo which
classical logic are not going to go through the details because it takes
to do this it takes a long time
so the lemma
now is what
is the essence
of lifting membership
to what we know
whenever p nor using in the peano what is true that says what about logical
form can i say whenever logic formulas in it's true OK so
let's just go through if not fighting w then five million the design right because
we means we consistent that's that's easy
if i knew then this
so what you have to say
well suppose find size and i'll show flies in w inside
and on the reverse
and you've got the definition of maximal consistent sets that i
i showed you can get it and it
i'm not going to go through the details but the crux of these two
this property here
that's why we defined
because see all of this stuff is to do with truth tables all of this
stuff that john told you
i need to model stuff to go through
they actually got one which shows you can buy
what time we suppose
twelve thirty
this was
what do you want to see the so what you need to see what else
i got
OK so the
so much for for this kind of
inference but if you turn it again to the bottom up approach that was
mister morse and pluck the smaller
and do this he often
namely the next step was once we have obtained is kind of individuals
we were about to
generalized youth concept descriptions or if concept and fiona concept interesting the concept descriptions
pakistan done by
and inference namely these comes up some more
OK so the first we look again at the at the definition
so these concepts what is now
defined with respect to the set of input concept descriptions so this comes up some
of the set of concept description in certain description logic OWL
it's not the concept in the same description logic
such that it fulfills two conditions
namely again subsumes all or some of the input concepts generalize all the input and
it is again the least with respect to subsumption similar to the embassy we construct
a concept description of some of the best fitting
with respect subsumption so we cannot find another concept in the description logic that somehow
captures the idea
the common ideas of the input concepts
the fact so the FCS some of the best fitting concept description that we can
just construct in the description logic which was
with we
with which we are working
again i want to point out constructing the concept descriptions so it's not finding something
that's already captured t books but
really making the use of concept operators that are available in description logic to come
up with the best fitting description so you can think of the LCS of something
like it captures
what the concepts basically agree on
so expect the commonality
if we want to apply the LCS what do we have to take a look
at all but what kind of constraints to we have so again
the least common subsumer is implemented only four unfold which he works so we can
have this case where only have the name on the left-hand side and complex cont
the description on the right hand side which is then a fix
and here the the most explosive description logic for which
it is available as a eli and so it its extends on
the description logic we have seen so far in my demo by number restrictions so
that we can say that things like
at least
something has at least three
or has at most
five kind of role fillers
so this is what is
in favour of plcs
if it
turn back to
to the demo
we want to do this this step now
for the concerts we have obtained in the first step forward
and here we can
start from these concepts that we have
find out in the first step so this is what the bottom-up approach would just
and you saw if concept of feeling concept and i didn't even carla concept and
then we have this beautiful buttons here which linked to two sonic
we click
these concepts in the pattern
and so
authorities was one
so we don't want to we're not interested in in the
this comes from of all of them so i mean find out that person's but
this is of course correct is of course not very interesting it is much more
interesting of course to see
but these
two concepts down to because they were
much more like if you recall these words to concepts speaking about students which had
an advisor which were some kind of professor
so if we take a look of what we can find out what kind of
communities you can find out about these two concepts hard to get something slightly more
interesting was to find out that these are questions but you see also
that they have an adviser which is a person
also on the faculty appears slightly redundant
and these these persons are professors
while working for certain organisations
and i see also way
or you get an idea why
line is only squared
we can go
almost end of story
i'm going to rewrite it a little the only french in his book rewrites it
again in different ways
the last to work with QC put cues in there
i'm going to devote divide upstairs and downstairs by omega squid
and when i do that i get a zero
get the gummi here
i get two and here
and then
i get omega zero squared
divided by omega
mine omega
please come up with
that's what i get
that's not the only way you can write it
that's one way you can write me check that
i have
i have zero created i have got
two and here
and we have this
so the time has come now
to try to see through this equation
remember last lecture we spend the whole lecture not to look at this time equation
but to see through it
and we were able to see through it the all its idiosyncrasies
let's look
you use increases of this average power over one
cycle or multiple cycles
that first
they got my infinitely large don't look even at the equation
infinitely large
that means is an infinite amount of friction
the system never gets going
there's no way to ever move
so clearly
the average power
must go to zero
and indeed
you see that the government is downstairs
gamma goes to infinity
power is zero
that's the make them as infinitely large if the mass is infinitely large an infinite
high inertia
nothing will ever get going no force will ever get the mass going
that means
the expected the power
goes to zero
and indeed you see here is and goes to infinity
the power goes to zero
let's say
the force
goes to zero were not even driving it well if we're not even driving it
i hope you will agree with me you don't have to put in any work
right nothing gets going so clearly you expect
that power will go
two zero and indeed it have zero goes to zero
that the power is zero
suppose you make or break
so that means
there will never be any velocity you never pick up any velocity
six infinitely long omega
so clearly
if nothing ever moves
the power
look if omega make zero
this is zero
this one goes to infinity
and therefore the power goes to zero
so you need no equations for that
just common sense
two immediately conclude that this has to be
the case
suppose you go
to infinity was omega
very very fast
if you go infinitely fast
because of the inertia of the system it can never react
i can never get going so i will predict
then the power
must go
and if you put omega infinity
this goes to zero is goes to infinity and so it all goes to zero
so all this is complete common sense
all of these you could have predicted without that equation but isn't it nice
that the equation supports my intuition
now comes the question if omega
goes to omega zero
that's the reason why i wrote it in this way
notice when omega goes to zero
when omega goes omega zero this one goes to zero
and therefore
now i begin today
this is by the way
regular practice on this is as close as i get to bulleted powerpoint it's all
i ought to have got through
those topics by the end of the lecture if i don't not to worry i'll
pick up where the dotted line emerges in the subsequent lectures
but in any case i thought i'd begin today by a
making a few remarks about the title of our courts
because it has some big words and theory
and literature but also introduction i think it's worth saying word two
about the word introduction
as well
no theory
has a very complicated etymological history that i won't trouble you with the trouble with
the etymology of theory in the way in which the word has been used traditionally
is that sometimes it actually means practice and then another historical period it means something
very different from practice something typically from which practice is derived well that's the sense
of theory that i i like to work with on and i would over by
saying that after all there is a difference in which and we shouldn't too quickly
at least confuse the terms there is no difference between theory and methodology yes it's
fair enough to say that methodology is applied theory on but there's great danger in
supposing that every aspect of theory has an immediate applications theory is very often a
purely speculative undertaking it's an hypothesis about something the exact nature of which one need
necessarily have in view
it's the supposition that whatever the object theory might be it must owing to whatever
intellectual constraints one can imagine be of such form
and at this level of abstraction
plainly there isn't all that much incentive to apply
thinking of that time but on the other hand undoubtedly
theory does exist for the most part to be applied
very frequently courses of this kind of have a text
a list of this
the riemannian error
a short story
and then once in a while they a
disquisition of lecture will parse the text will be produced and whatever theory has recently
been talked about will be
applied to the text so that you get a postcolonial reading of the riemannian married
something by the way which is absolutely fascinating and important to do
and so on through the courts now i suppose it's my
the reluctance to get into the intricacies of questions having to do with applied theory
that makes me
prefer to keep it simple
our text
it is a story for toddlers
called tony the tow truck
i've decided not to pass today because after all i want to get into the
right hands you can read it unless you take the course
and so
now i know a little bit we don't we don't come back to least for
the moment and that you see
that's mercifully short
and as time passes we will do
so rather interesting tricks with we will
revert as others revert to listen to this too
donna the tow truck for the purpose of introducing questions are applied there
this may suggest certain condescension both theory and taught literary texts which is not at
all intended it's much more question reminding that i reminding you that if you can
do that with this you can do it with anything but also
reminding you that after all reading reading just anything is a complex and potentially almost
unlimited activity that's one of the good things that theory teaches us that i hope
to be able to get across in our in in the in the course of
our part of of our varied approaches to
tony the total truck
resembles philosophy
perhaps in this that it
asks fundamental questions and also at times builds system that is to say theory has
certain ambitions to a total isation of what can be thought of that resembles arrivals
but theory differs from philosophy and this is something that i'm going to be coming
back to
you are persisting late in the in the second half of this lecture and many
times hereafter
it differs from most philosophy
in that it involves a certain and this is by no means self-evident why should
this be is one of the questions were going to be asking involves a certain
skepticism there seems to be
i doubt
a variety of doubts
about the foundations of what we can think about the basis of our opinions that
pervades theory seems somehow or another to characterize its history
now not all theory that we read in this course is skeptical
some of the most powerful and profound thought that's been devoted to
the subjective theory literature are is positive in its intentions and views but by and
large you will
happily or unhappily come to terms with the fact that much of what you're going
to be reading this semester is under
grid or perhaps i should say undermined by this persisting skepticism
it's crucial as i say that i'm going to be comeback coming back to it
but it's just the point i want to make in passing about the nature theory
turning to the word literature
this is not a theory of relativity theory music theory of government this is a
course in
and serious literature shares in common with other kinds of literature other kinds of theory
the need for definition that is to say may be the most central infamy infamy
possibly the most fascinating question here as it is well what literature
how do we know when we see it
how can we define now much of what will be reading takes up the question
stepping in the negative gradient directions
if you toss in a component which is equal to the last step to just
so now that know your step is the combination of the latest gradient and the
previous step
it's cool heavy ball causing this in a sense this is kind of momentum to
right it's kind of your tending to move along the same direction that you just
moved in but you tweak it a little bit with the latest great OK
now you've got two knobs to turn you get to choose not only alpha but
also by the so the question is by turning those two knobs can you get
a faster convergence rate
well it turns out to be easy to analyse two in the way analyses is
you just collapse two successive areas into a single vector
so if on this vector wk which is the dimension two n
and i look at what this recurrences in terms of wk well it turns out
it's approximately this
from wk wk plus one year approximately operate under because the linear operator b
or in matrix b
two n by two n matrix it looks like this
and there little remainder term which is due to the nonlinearity in f k
so what's be look like well b is blocked two by two matrix very simple
except that there is the hessian of f appearing here and close to the solution
you know this WK we small
b be very close will be is essentially this
our aim is to choose alpha and so that b has nice spectral properties and
you'll know that when you got linear recurrence and you're looking to
converge to zero
the name of the game is to try and make sure your occurrence matrix b
has the same value strictly less than one and is much less than one as
you can possibly make them
so we're going to try to choose alpha invaded
to minimize the maximum igon value b
so that's the game now
you can do a similarity transformation on the to just reduced this passionate the
next to just its diagonal with news that i can values on the diagonal
and when you look at that you can sort of now write down what they
are there is pretty much just in closed form and and it turns out that
you know it's pretty simple a little bit of simple arithmetic
to figure out what all from beira and here
you have to model for is that europa will baiters that
if you got an ill conditioned problem where kappa is large
batteries pretty close to one
health is going to be pretty small in general OK and so you only taking
a little bit of energy in a negative gradient direction you attending mostly to move
in the same direction as the previous step she took
but this is the convergence rate
it looks like the linear convergence rate that we were getting only but this really
important difference
now we just got the square root of kappa in the denominator is not cap
and that can be a huge difference OK
in fact if your goal is to take
it is to reduce your initial error by a factor epsilon so you want to
figure out out how many steps you need to take
to reduce here by epsilon if you've got a rate constant like this
it's going to take you something like kappa over two log epsilon steps
if you go to a concert like this the one we just got
it's going to take you recap to serve cap is one hundred which is still
moderately condition problem not too bad
you need ten times as many steps if you're using one of these concepts
the heavy ball method can be remarkable improvement just the naive gradient descent
the conjugate gradient is probably something you love you've heard of in
you if you take in any kind of
linear algebra course or optimisation course
the idea consecrated great is very very similar to heavy ball in fact you know
the really
almost identical in the sense the motivated maybe slightly differently but you can see in
conjugate gradient step to take is in the direction pk NP again it's just a
combination of the latest gradient and the previous step
OK and really can't agree there just different methods of choosing how to balance of
these two components and another set motivated a little bit differently in fact we can
identify with the heavy ball method by
noting the relationship between the gamma
in the country gradient and the baiter inevitable and we'll get you know pretty much
the same thing
now there are many variants of CG CG of course that originally came up as
a way to solve the linear equations with symmetric positive definite coefficient matrices
but that's the same as minimizing the quadratic convex objective and you can generalize to
the two main methods for minimizing general
large amount
so for those of you who used matlab if you go back slash
that's all i was doing it doing the squares but
it's not doing this
now you want to
it's possible for the matrix but let's look at this formula in trying to understand
a little bit even though numerically unstable to give some intuition for this one say
it says the location which relates y
that's the parameters theta here
it is the correlation between x and y
but you don't want to be confused by the correlations between the inputs themselves
so we have divided by
the cross correlation matrix of the input
this is exactly like the winner filter in which you have the correlation between signal
and noise is the power in the signal divided by
power in the noise
this is exactly the same idea
as we have
but of course the discrete setting here and if you want to make this formula
comes from
and you don't like to think in sort of
you know a continuous
derivatives and scalar variables
we can do this for the innovation and the switch to this is
as long as
we can do a whole generation using matrix algebra
you can write the
as just a sum over data points
of y n minus
it is but it's
and we know that the norse
is just
the product of a vector with itself
so this is x
the same thing
because this is an inner product we can write it as the trace of the
so this is the trace here
why big matrix y which is all of the
data stacked on top of of each other
this is the same thing
we can expand this matrix
one of the terms
that appearance so the term which is why transpose y
there's a term which is twice
they data transpose
well i guess
here the
the terms
which is
see here
so then the charge
which is
extract from
they transpose
and i now because traces only operation you can take the derivative inside the trace
and take the derivative of each of these terms with respect to
to date data and so when you take the derivative this term with respect to
data you get two
one here when you take the derivative
this term with respect to remember that this is the trace
and so we can always permute the cyclic products of the trace as much as
we want
in some particular this term here
is equal to trace
then transpose x x transpose and then we can probably one more time
the basis for the data experience of data and now we take the derivative of
that's the quadratic form
and so we get
and now we set this zero install repair we get the
the discrete ricci flow can be done in matrix algebra if you prefer this style
of their
a lot of people think that the style derivation is much more confusing than the
continuous about regime but it's much faster when you have lots of matrices and vectors
i i one
OK so
they can i'm having a disagreement about his life
OK trying
you can try
do some independent component analysis in your mind
remove the picture and just reveal underneath the equations you want to tell you a
little bit about the idea of sufficient statistics alex is given a research level talk
on this time next week on the relationship between some kernel models and sufficient statistic
and feature space but just to cover the basic idea here
a sufficient statistic is a possibly vector valued functions
the set of random variables
and it has the the property that if the sufficient statistic of one data set
is equal to the sufficient statistic of another dataset
then the likelihood function of one dataset
is equal to the likelihood function of another
and in a formal way of thinking about the sufficient statistic is sufficient statistic is
a property of the model
ninety days property of model and it tells you what you need to know about
a dataset
in order to do maximum likelihood estimation under that model
let's go back to some of the examples here and you can begin to understand
what a sufficient statistic is
so for example let's go back to to the coin tosses
by calling i flipped a thousand times and written on this piece of paper
the sequence has himself
also which represent exactly the thousand points
and what do maximum likelihood estimation the bias of the point but
i mean nasty and i refuse to show you the diff
one summary of the data you need to ask me for in order to be
able do maximum likelihood
exactly just the number of nodes and the number of
once know the number of nodes and the number of and or the number of
cells in the total number of flips
you can the original data was
and therefore the number
and the number of tails is a sufficient statistic
for maximum likelihood estimation in the
bernoulli model
so that's says what property of the dataset that i'm hiding from you do need
to know before you can do maximum likelihood estimation
same thing in the multinomial
you don't need to know the whole sequence of coin dice rolls you just need
to know the number of times that i came out to three became that's sufficient
they were going to continue
wissen playing with liquid
i have an object that floats
a simple cylinder
floating some liquid
there is a year the mass
of the cylinder
it is and
the density of the cylinder is rho
and in length
is al
the surface area is a
so this
let the liquid line
and the flow it has a density rho fluid
i call this level y one
his level y two
this separation is a child
and right on top you know is the atmospheric pressure p two
which is the same
as it is here
on the liquid
and here we have
in the liquid
put is object
two float
we need equilibrium between on the one hand
the force mg
there is a force
up here we tackle one
and there is a force down here
tackle have two
barometric pressure
fort is always perpendicular to the surface couldn't be any tangential component because dr starts
to flow
and its static
and here we have f one
which contains the
i just added pressure
so p one
minus two as the last time from moscow
of the fluid
and y two minus y one
which is a ge
that's the difference between
the pressure p one and p two
for this to be in equilibrium
f one
miners after minus
you have to be zero
and this
we call
the buoyant force
i'm going to spell in a very strange way
the you all why
a and t
always have to think about
it's the buoyant force everyone
because every time he one
and it and f two
is the area
and two
so it is the area times one minus two
and that
real fluids
i'm doing
and h
and when you look at this
this is exactly the weight
of the displaced fluid
area times age is the volume of the fluid
which displaced by this
and you multiply by density that gives it
multiplied by g weight
so this is the weight
of the displaced fluid
and this is a very special case
of a
general principle which is called archimedes principle
archimedes principle this follows the buoyant force
on an emerging body
has the same magnitude as the weights
of the fluid which is displaced by the body
according to legend
i q made is about this while he was
taking it back
and i have a picture of that year
i don't know
from when that dates
what you see in there in the past
which you also see
are there two crowns
there's a reason why does crowns are there
i recommend lifting the thirty
century BC
archimedes had been given the task
to determine
whether a crown that was made for king here on the second
was pure gold
the problem for him was to determine the density
well what's difficult what's fundamentally difficult here
is that
the obvious way find the argmax would involve enumerating all possible y
and why is it comes from the discrete set so
in principle i could enumerate all possible y
but the number of different y is exponential so it's going to be
in practice intractable to enumerate all possible y
this is one dollar needs to solve the problem is
to evaluate
the probability of y
i must
we need to compute
xe x on w
the sum of all life crime
of ax
some of the j
wj fj
so noticed that
so this is the normalisation constant makes probably add up to one
and if i want to find out what has the highest probability
i don't actually need to evaluate this nomination called and i can just ignore it
but if i want to
find out
if i want to find out the true probability
then i do need to evaluate the normalisation constant
the intuitive difficulty in evaluating the normalisation constant is the same involves enumerating explicitly overall
more so i'm going to
provide algorithms for
solving these two problems and then i'm going to provide training our conditional random fields
which is stochastic gradient descent and that's going to be those those are the three
basic algorithms for conditional random fields
the the algorithm for these two problems it's
well they don't there's no somehow invalid just regression with you don't have similar problems
but the algorithm for training is similar our the four
logistic regression because
it's some also stochastic gradient method
let's come back in one
five thirty
more and will be refreshed i'll be refreshed to give these algorithms
get started on the on line
OK much
we want to do
why is argmax
over y
over j
x y so
this is
we want to do we want to do this in polynomial time but actually going
to be i think quadratic in the length of y
linear in the length of wire quadratic in something else
is not going to expand the definition of the high level feature function
some of the j
and then some of my
little fj
why i minus one y i
x far i noticed
just to note his confused so here j is ranging over the feature functions
and then i
his ranging over the length of x and y so this is for a single
test example x i is not ranging over multiple training examples going over the length
of one example
let me
OK so
what i'm going to do
must just
the order of these summations
o alive are
some of
and then
what i have is
some of the j
little fj why i minus one y expx y
and then i'm going to call this
meiji function
i'm going to call this
g i
why i minus one
why i
there are in
going from here to here
this function
as a function of y i minus one y i
and so i still have those arguments wireless won why i but this argument i
am just making it into the subscripts have different g function for each i and
then x and w
object then you would get documents from soap standard specification
and i think that that's the web services would be seen
this is again about the so
well similarly let's see if you were typing i think which very close to a
solve this problem
doesn't work
i would need to society
and this is just a an pair
it didn't didn't do any of the need to close the window and
run it again i think
let's a
much work
if for instance would mean either of the or
they perform at
a for which we use in europe
and let's see paper
paper would be here
remove it here then you get everything about this
this is a nice example where we put together a little bit of this text
mining techniques and some from ten to some back components
let's continue its
this is textarc is one
interesting textures asia text visualisation system as well
there we can analyse entities within a larger pieces of text so i want go
here to the data can
go to this that are text text are about common probably so this is the
position of hamlet and here we can see relationships between hamlet and other entities which
appear in the book and it
nice little
java applets which actually can be quite useful for some
four high-level browsing of text
this this one is also quite
interesting even used by many
news portals so this is one way how to visualize news stories and one the
idea here is just if the topic is more important before on the previous positions
we saw in the topic is more important than we
to make a larger mountain the geographical map here we just right the topic or
titling bigger font nothing and the topics are also categorized by the color based on
the from which to the
area news area they
they are and the whole thing can actually you can see
what's going on in
quite efficient efficient way
this is the
picture from today
and now i show this visualisation of this our system which we call document atlas
which is also free to get it from this the dots plus the ideas site
so here we visualize
well short they must but this
one is
but hard to visualize project so this was actually a demonstration which we may to
our but for european commission
agency which was financing our project so this is a shelf
two years of work of two hundred fifty scientists but you cannot see much but
let me first show what how
this can be understood so each cross here is one person and two persons are
close or on the map the
the work they did see what they publish similar style of content
now if we turn on the
document names but we will get all the people
which are in the project now if it decreases
so here we get just the most intensive once
and we see the structure market this is interesting especially if you know the people
that you would recognise that this or relatively if it's what you can turn off
and we can ask question about one particular part of the of this picture about
these are kind of content work which
came directly from the
documents which are visualized here here we would recognise that this is about project is
actually a network of excellence which works in different fields of machine learning can this
area here with corresponds to
text mining can natural language processing this would be multimedia and this is small kernel
methods and theory
and so if we don't
on this magnifying glass we can zoom in certain parts let's say here
here it's me
we can visualize so
whatever it covered by this
circle somehow is visualized by the most relevant keywords which are
in this in this article
as i said so if if you know the content of documents this can make
you quite efficient
the show also the second data set which is visualizing new stories through time as
so here visualizing
here we visualize a hundred thousand news from writers
so we took hundred thousand using calculate this
this this man
on this map and the
calculated the profile of each of the named entities which appear in these articles and
put his name entity on the place which feeds
which is the on the on the place where it is the best
and this is this
happens through time so here is the date
so that if we we move this
through time the
we learn this model using the variational approaches just described and compare we also used
the equivalent variation approach just using the phrase states
and we use the
j rank algorithm the second half the which is a kernel method for jointly learning
the content and the collaborative data
to then ordinal classification to this
and we also used a set of naive bayes classifier one classifier reaches
train a classifier using the content data
and order predict the
so in first experiment we randomly held out test data and
created the
held out data and calculate the pharmacy on this how the data
we found some model outperforms the other three models
and i find this kind of what's the problem that motivates this look this problem
in the first place
if you call
one thing is that
mean it's interesting combining content and collaborative data
was the fact that after filtering alone generally works poorly when we've got a new
movie or new items
so we wanted to have a way of finding out well
how to method for on in the movie
so to do this we took the movielens data
simulate the effects of the new movie just really being released hardly has any ratings
so out for dataset we chose two hundred is random out of the set of
all movies that had
two hundred ratings
and we removed almost all the ratings for these movies leaving behind three norton ten
these two hundred movies
this was to community that only a handful of people who reviewed
we then predicted the remaining held out data using the former as before
it was found be more significant improvement in the treatment factorisation method where we were
including the content and the
richard data rather than just covered data
and compared with the other two methods can be for combining content interpret data
this is very nice
we made a big assumption
which is this how data is nice and friendly gaussians
which always nice and convenient but it's not always appropriate
probably a reasonable model for the ratings villains
but there are many situations which less appropriate so for example
if you have
rather than ratings have some sort of implicit preference given by the number of times
a user listening to
online radio is listened to certain artist certain song
and i think that's more likely to be possible distributed then distributed similarly if you
don't have ratings eighteen just have information about whether you support or not
so nice
if you knew the distribution for cricket
so stop with the bayesian exponential family PCA model which was presented by muhammad earlier
in the main conference
to allow
inference in the general exponentially for the general exponential family case
learning most places
so basically exponential family PCA
is is
it's PCA method where the
matrix are is that since the natural parameters of the exponential family was chosen to
use to represent data
so this is shown
they are unlikely
matrix has shown but imagine this all
and that is if you will
so here we have the on matrix is
drawn from the exponential family
parameterized by a linear combination of vectors b
and that is a where
he is drawn from the family conjugate to the exponential family and a is the
scale set of
scaling factors which are drawn from a gaussian distribution and
on counting distribution we put a calcium prior on the mean and they inverse gamma
prior prior on the variance
this is based on exponential family PCA
we can extend this to multiple HC's
by holding the
well we can extend this locomotive season in one of two ways
either in the ways i've described here where we have
two mixes of partially separating data are fully observed content data being the same exponential
family where we hold the conjugate
OK last time
well it's on just the where
what you can prove the classical
and again you couldn't prove otherwise and the negation free formula
and that
that's the real one not it
do the truth lies etc etc etc there
i was going to do the proof they while we're waiting for people come in
most of you back areas
i'm not
there's the people left out there
i don't come
we don't need
you or on the last day
i think people
it must be flagging and understand that after two weeks of this logic we can
i have a sort of an energy drink and not taking it personal insults
absolute crap
maybe i should not
in europe
is move on to
a different style
action system i'm well
this is the styles are really
about by restall
in his name got all the nodes on the right
things and everything email them to you or your email cells in fact i
a new style sorry not him around so much
a different style of is that's more like a hybrid between in the system
and calculus
it's the sequent style natural deduction system so the
in sequent calculus against and sequent calculus the one ingenious about it doesn't
he invented both the americans and both
characters and the national to show how to
drive one from the other
he in in heat
the thing interesting but the sequent calculus
this is the
don't have introduction elimination rules like you do the natural deduction system
also about adding connectors on the right of the turnstile adding them on the left
one is that interest
is anybody know
why it's important
get wire sequence started
yeah it backwards against was doing this in nineteen thirty three or whatever
he was
computers as we do is but that's that's why we are interested in them still
but what sort of analog
the computation with everything back there
what were they thinking that something that we would as we have more often
i mean
you what you implement implemented decision procedure
that's why
we are scientists
ten methods and this course you you have my tableau methods because for the least
but is the tableaux for atlas or a lot of the modal logics you looked
give us
right that's kind of is one procedure terminates and in the right way and is
say all branches
yes it's the theorem good
that's a decision procedure
sequence for which is large for classical logic
the case is not the case
is that what you can do
in start from the new work your way up and slowly
surely removed
you end up with these what are called leaves from the tree that you build
that's it into function
centered on that point
so for instance the cosine function if we use a gaussian kernel
OK so the point is mapped into a function that we have to say what
we mean by the dot product between functions and also we have to turn the
space into a linear space with different steps involved in the construction but it's basically
on elementary and i think
we should all understand it because
it's very basic nevertheless it's PD that a lot of people work and support vector
machines and don't know how to construct a feature space
OK so the first step is OK we want to we want to construct a
dot product satisfying this thing
you know to construct dot product we need we first need a vector space of
in our space and then on that space we have to construct something that satisfies
the conditions that the product has to satisfy
OK so the first thing is turn it into a linear space and it's trivial
in the sense we just turn it into a linear space by adding all functions
of this form
two our space
so we just say OK certainly these elements have to be all space because that's
what the mapping produces but
i we'll say that also these functions i now space weather and phi are real
coefficients real numbers and if we just require that these elements of all spaced then
this space is automatically closed under additions because if i take two such functions and
i get another such function just possibly with lot of some so that's so these
are all finite sums
by two such functions
it's called the other one g
a bit different expansion points here if i had two such function i will again
get a function of this type may be with the largest some different coefficients so
this space is closed under addition
the space is also closed under multiplication is with the scale are things like that
you could take all the different properties of vector spaces you'll see that this is
a vector space or in r space
OK so the next step is to construct the dot product in that space and
it should be not just any dot product by the dot product that satisfies this
inequality here that this equality
now special case if we substitute this k means
in our case it has to satisfy
the quality
OK so that means
must be equal
the dot product between the kernel itself
in some sense
that's why this kernel is called also called the reproducing kernel
so we have to construct dot product that satisfies
this condition
and actually this this condition already fixes the whole dot product because if this should
be true
and if the
but i have to be linear
then there's only one way in which we can define the dot product between that
such functions f and g
so basically dot product
between f and g
OK so the product has to be equal
this thing here
so if you look at this you will see that special case of this is
if the only if you forget about the sum you just substitute single kernels and
so one kernels in the next one comes centered on y
you also don't get this and what your recovery is exactly this equation up here
so this is equal to
this thing here only that of called y instead of x primal
OK so this is our definition of the dot product but we're not allowed to
call it the dot product because the output products have to satisfy
certain conditions
in fact
so instance is missing in fact we don't even know yet whether this thing is
well defined
by this i mean if we have to this these are functions from all space
but it could be the same function can be expanded differently in terms of different
kernels different coefficients
but the dot product to be a property really of the function so it should
should be a property of f and g
and it shouldn't depend on what particular expansion we use for f and g
it turns out there's a simple way of seeing that this is well defined and
the way as follows
let's just compute the dot product between f and
a kernel
sitting on
so it directly here
we can see OK the effort is expended in terms of alpha phi k of
x i
so what we can do is we can replace
we can rewrite this as a
some of the time
some were black and white
and you want to match between colour and black-and-white in different resolutions
now you could probably sit down and actually make a fairly good educated guesses as
what the good compatibility between
features in this case will be
they will biggest nonetheless and you wouldn't really know whether this case is going to
be particularly good
so the point is why not use statistics
to help us with this case
so i said you might have different resolutions
you might actually have different image content
different representation has well so for instance if i have already map of italy but
satellite image
so they may have on the one hand pixel image
on the other cases symbolic representation
and i want to match those of it's not quite true
you also want to have another and that scales
if you
you something that
doesn't work very well
well with low polynomial coefficient have problem
i mean for very large graphs people use very clever heuristics and the idea was
a little bit well what can we do
actually learning things
what is
the key point is that this is essentially what will be exploited
while in general the problem of graph matching is really hard
usually when we want to apply it applied we will applied only in the restricted
we know what we're going to apply to we know it's an image problem or
we know its chemistry or whatever
therefore using an the shelf general purpose grant matcher to solve the specific problem
should not
promises very good results but least we should expect that in the restricted domain will
be doing much better
for instance if
i think i restrict myself to very very
small subset of grass very special property sometimes the matching problem is trivial
for instance if i have attributed graphs and they wanted to exact matches
this trivial
especially if all the attributes are unique saying i can just really match up all
the vertices and edges cheque with images of the same
and that has also subgraphs and other problems are fairly straightforward to solve
you would think well hey this kind of trivial but differently for quite awhile people
didn't use that
so a possible case was one of the biggest earlier people actually did this
i was very surprised when they get to talking camera and city of all people
and and before and
so thought well it's obvious but in hindsight yesterday is like many things are in
but the key point here is
there are lots of interesting applications
where if you just restrict yourself to that small application the matching problem actually becomes
so i'm not talking about a general purpose souls everything type of graph matching algorithm
but one
for specific applications when
the right problem for the specific application will actually be do fairly able to the
fairly well
for instance you might have graphs where the local neighborhood of a vertex
might tell you enough that overall you can actually match things up
so this is also where humans are good at so if you give human to
graphs and he looks at individual points in
this is that the neighborhoods are similar he'll probably go and maxim
in two
close related
matches and then
just work from there
that's when humans are actually pretty good at it
they're not very good if things extremely symmetry can have lots of ambiguities
but the point is actually a lot of problems don't have to is ambiguity so
we might be able to take advantage of this
the other thing is that this is quite don't have
inexact graph matching problem so people actually make the problem harder than it is
because the two graphs are not identical only when you're just asking for well what's
the best match that will correspond to
two graphs
on the market today
i hope i've explained a little bit
what applications will be
and by the way if you have any questions at any time during my talk
is just lazy and
and interrupt also during the talk because i mean sixty minutes talk
it's unlikely will also remember what was unclear at the end of the talk
so i ask early
now we need a little bit of notation
so let's have graphs g and g prime
and that's some vertices that footage
so the prime always indicates
the other graphs
and so
i would just also have corresponding matrix by city i j is one
if there is an edge between i and j
and is a zero sum
g is also
used so anonymously for the
graph edges
the adjacency matrix
and will be
by the system vertex i and also it's attributes if there are any
so anyway
let's for the moment just to keep things simple deal with graphs which are the
the same size if they're different sized and we need to extend things a little
bit but it's not a big deal
essentially what we're doing is given two graphs
give us a permutation such that maps
that maps one graph into the other really well
that's at the end of today the problem we're trying to solve
so pi
a permutation matrix
it's doubly stochastic so there are something the column sums are all ones
and it has only zero and one injuries
so while i j
is one if is mapped into track
and it's zero otherwise
there is the
probably the most famous matching algorithm which is the linear assignment
and that one works as follows
well i compute some score some compatibility score CIJ
for the match between vertices ui ai and bj
so that's one graph to ceylon
what do they want to do is
you want to find some permutation point i j
such that this sum is minimized
so CIJ j is zero if there is a very good match it's very large
and if there is a very bad match
some people use incompatibility scores and then you would simply going maximize this and you
would have
different CIJ definitions here but
well just
assume that the IJCAI
if there is a perfect match and it's larger than zero
it's not such a batch
so we just
optimized for this
which is
permutation and
i'll talk a little bit about the moment i could actually go about doing this
so if we had graphs with unique attributes
and you know and teaches these sort of on the order of employees due to
the power of these are the scales exponentially in d
this is a very high dimensional feature vector
but again you can implicitly construct the feature vector and ten
in the province in
so very computationally efficient because just compute
the product between xin zhi at seeing take that one of the party
and by putting this into kernel implicitly working in an extremely high dimensional space
well given in just a few specific examples of how to create kernels
so let's see what happens just a few specific examples of kernels and so was
also more generally if face new machine learning problem how do you come up with
the kernel
on the the many ways to think about it but his one intuition that sort
of useful
so given
so that to actually going to use the feature vector phi of x
and given the attributes you can use the input feature vector five z
and so the kernel is computing the inner product between five x five e
and so on one intuition
this portion intuition this all the right
here isn't isn't isn't isn't the rigours intuition is useful is that if x is
you are very similar
then phi xit phi as you will be pointing in the same direction
and therefore phi and therefore the inner product will be large
all words in contrast if x is you very dissimilar
then five x five xeon only point in different directions and so the product may
be small
OK that conditions is not rigorous one the sort of the user want to think
and so on
if a new learning problem the if i give you something some some some random
thing the classifier
you want to decide
how to come of the kernel
one way is
to try to come up with a function x
that is on the same knowledge if you want to any algorithm to think exactly
and small
in this this is always true but this one one of several intuitions
so should the cost by some bannu thing trying to you know
have indigenisation cos phi DNA sequences something just some strange thing you want to classify
what you could do is try to come the kernel that slot when you want
the album to think he's similar things
these are just
and so
this runs in the question of let's say i have something i want to classify
myself as i write down the function
i think it's a good measure of how similar or dissimilar axes you are
for my specific problem so let's a down here because equals e to the miners
the same right down the function
and i think this is a good measure it is that of
possible is e
the question then is is is really a valid kernel
so in other words
you have to understand how to construct kernels about our function like that on the
question is does the really exist some phi
such that a and c is equal to the enterprise
and that's the question is k valid kernel
and it turns out that there is a there is
just as the does the result that characterizes necessary and sufficient conditions
when the function you might choose
is valid kernels and
if the intuitionistic ahead and show power that result now
as the suppose k is a valid kernel
and when i say k is a kernel what i mean is that there doesn't
indeed exist some function force this holds true
that these are the points x one
the x m be given
and then we find the matrix k
and i apologize overloading notation now
OK i'm going to use to denote both the kernel function which is a function
of x and easy as well as the matrix m by n matrix unfortunately
and unfortunately the running of alpha the
they define the kernel matrix on
this is the
all three
one reason for the world
they are
o one
although the very rich
o thing
and children
i i
four o
and here is
all right
you be
well to first
or is
a lot of things
we are know
thank you
all of them are
five years
he said
three years
any other people
are very low
then when you
the problem
bye bye
right or wrong
she not
is not
all of the
it is wrong
on one
four of the
after one
that are
for role
you it
one more
so one of
the world