o whether the signs of the same for the signs are different
so what we have at that point is this sinusoid
it's really a sinusoidal carrier with transmitting at
this term here
is really something which expands and contracts slowly
so it's the beat
which says that if you're transmitting
from this source
at at the receiver
what you're hearing
there's something which
which contracts
then contracts then expands again there's nothing you can do about that problem either
there's just no energy they're part of the time
and this
and the sign term here
running along
sort of
changing from maximum to minimum
but if you millisecond time period if you have this vehicle traveling at sixty kilometres
sixty kilometres
sixty kilometres per hour
OK so you just work out the numbers there with the velocity of light in
all of that stuff
you find that you really can't communicate over yourself in that situation
because of these beat frequencies
it's it's too fast
it's it's
it is too slow
two ignoring right over it and it's too fast
to be able to get all of your data transmitted before it happens
so it's sort of this is a catastrophe
so that's what happens because of doppler shift
you get a response which is periodically fading
the doppler frequency this is called multipath fading are fast fading
called fast fading because it happened so fast
it is called multipath fading because it happens because of multiple pairs
which each have
lines which are changing relative to each other
OK let's go back
and look at the
look at the thing we had before
we just had a moving antenna
OK here you have shift also
why doesn't bother you
here you have the doppler shift
and your transmitting
i said gigahertz
and what the receiver is getting
is it gigahertz minus
so perhaps the colour something
OK so why isn't that problem
if i if i demodulate
at the carrier frequency
i'm sort of in bad luck because i have
a signal in which is changing very rapidly i have something which looks like
a time varying system
but what's going to happen
if i use the same kind of frequency recovery system we talked about earlier
frequency recovery system has all the time in the world
the track
that frequency which is one gigahertz minus the colour
track perfectly
which says the what happens is we start out with the signal
we move it up in frequency by one gigahertz
the doppler shift move down by color heard
we track that frequency then we move it down again by gigahertz minus colour hertz
and everything works fine and nobody even knows it is any doppler shift there
OK so the problem is not that shift
the problem is multiple doppler shifts which are at different speeds relative to each other
that's an important point and we will
come back to it as we move along
if you put all of those faces we neglected
in the analysis the we just went through
this is the equation that arises
i write stand up because it's important
because the node this in lecture twenty
having governor
because they
because in the sign term fails to put an iron which should be there
and this is the correct term
and that is off by ninety degrees
so if you
if you write this down
you will end
see what's going on
so equation seven nodes
as hasn't the to the two pi
after a minus b over c
which is not
the right thing
OK as we said the fading is due to the doppler spread between different parents
the single doppler shift does not bother at all
if you have a vehicle
which is traveling away
from the standing in ten
and you have some kind of reflector
which is not something you're running into which is the which is the reflector above
the reflector below or something like that the thing which is going to happen is
that both of those hands and
we're going to have roughly the same doppler shift in the
they both have roughly the same doppler shift
it's not going to be this kind of the cancellation so we have here which
is something you really can't get rid of
OK and the other thing this points out again
is that this variation
it's going to be in terms of minutes
four seconds
and anything you're going to track the signal is going to be adequate for that
until you get to the point where there just isn't enough energy anymore
and then of course you have to move to a different base station or something
OK i want to go through one more example
of electromagnetism because it's so surprising this was surprising to me when i found this
if you have sending ten
i think this is the base station which is high up about
maybe fifty meters or something
it's sending
some receive antennas
which is at some height above the ground usually quite a bit smaller
and suppose there's some
more or less partly reflecting plane like a rose
so so here we have the vehicle
which is traveling along the road
and we have a standing in ten
which is also close to the road which is sending the signal so we have
two pairs
one which is a direct path from sending antenna to receive antenna and the other
is the reflecting path which goes down here
it comes back up again
OK well the rather surprising thing here
thing that i couldn't believe what i saw because it contradicted all of my intuition
is the one gets quite big
the difference between these two path lengths
on the mass
and that is both
very nonintuitive with some of the piles of your car
does not matter
and that i
ask you the question to explain in your assignment number three
why race cars very y times there must be a reason for that
what you to think about
there is another way
that one can measure the
friction coefficient
which is
three more complicated and really that's not the reason why
i want you to see it
the reason why i want you to
go with me through these argument is that you begin to see how subtle
and how really difficult
friction is
i'm going to
put an object now
on an incline again
as we did before
instead of having it
sit on its own
i'm going to attached to it
a history
he was that object
he was strange
and appalling
and here restrict
he is an objec mass and two
this object
has mass and one
and the angle here
i'm looking for my green charles i want to use the same color convention
let's look at all the forces that we can think of uris and one gene
that's decompose that in y and x direction
and i will call
in this direction why as i always do perpendicular to the surface
we call this why
and i call this direction now
the positive x direction
you are free to choose any way you want
force here
and now comes the major problems
the biggest problem is
that you do not know in advance
whether this system will start to accelerate in this direction
what it will start to accelerate in this direction
or whether it will not accelerate at all
it's quite possible
and all these three cases as you will see have to be dealt with independently
you cannot do it was one equation as you will see
that first
decompose this force as we did before
in the y direction
so this one
equals and one gene
cosine of
and this one
x component using the minus x direction now
because and one
this one and one g cosine of how we never have to worry about there
is no acceleration in the y direction
so this normal force and
we'll kill this one
this is an one
the cosine of never have to worry about the y direction we notice no acceleration
we only deal with forty x direction
but have interest
there is a tension
in this string
now comes the problem
i don't know
in what direction the frictional forces
if this object has the tendency to go uphill
which i don't know yet
and the frictional forces in this direction because it poses always the direction in which
the object wants to go
if however this object wants to go in this direction which i don't know
then the frictional force has to be put in this direction
i don't
i know that
the only thing i do now
is that the maximum value
of the fraction
will be
new static
and which is what we
their remember that's the
maximum values that the friction can have times and one g
that i know
so now if i want to do is this
i have two
look at
three completely different situations
acceleration in this direction
in which the fraction is
we can here
acceleration in this direction in which the friction is pointing there were no acceleration at
there's also of course the tension here
this tension is exactly the same as that should discussed the last time i will
not go over that because this is an ideal
and of course on physical situation the poorly has no mass
forty is completely frictionless
and history
there's no mass to mass was street
and i argued last time
tension here
must be the same as attention there
we even know the attention
i'm going to evaluate for now only situations that the system is at rest
it's not yet
if the system is addressed
t must be and two gene because this object is not being accelerated
so we already know
that's all situations where the system is addressed
must be
she is non-negotiable this t
as well as that
i have to start splitting
in the following situation
my first option is
i make the assumption
that the system
is gn
just about
start accelerating upwards
it isn't doing it yet
it is just about to do that
if that's the case
then i know
that's the frictional force
will be in this direction
and it will have reached the maximum value
with the static friction coefficient
now i can write down in the x direction
system you will transform it
with regard to the alignment in order to get the results from the aligned ontology
but there are more recent application like peer-to-peer information sharing where you annotate your your
resources with some particular ontology but someone want to kill query from the standpoint of
another ontology OK so they will again using the alignment in order to transform the
query and get the results and they're all the same like web service composition you've
certainly already but mediation you take the guy in order to this one service into
the format of the input of the next one and i will talk about the
next one agent communication that transformation ontology evolution
so let's talk
this typically what i mentioned four catalogue integration you've got a particular database was your
your your product that you want to and it's written according to one scheme
and another marketplace use another schema
so what you do is that
what you want to do first is to to be able to export to do
all the database and information that you have in in order to do so
you will match the two on the two scheme order two ontologies you generate an
alignment and from this alignment you would be able to generate a transformation that we
do the work OK
and of course if one of the change you can we do the operation and
returned from the dead
you can do
it in query answering what i mentioned already what you want to do is as
everyone to issues a query towards another one but they use different ontology so what
you need is mediator that we reformulated query
and may be reformulated answer if it is necessary
and in this case again
you imagine two ontologies of two schema you will generate an alignment and you will
generate from this immediately so you can see the advantage of having this intermediate alignments
stuff in the middle of k
that is if you already got an alignment between these two ontologies and you can
generate immediately without doing the matching and also if it is part of pilot format
you can generate alignment with several different matching systems
and the last example goes with the agent communication you've got to agents using different
ontologies and what you want to do when you send a message to someone is
to be able to translate it into with regard to the target ontology
for doing this again you will do the same scene matching the ontology generate alignment
and generator transformation or you can do something different you would generate axioms that will
help the second agent to interpret the message without translation
so this is all the kind of application where you can involve ontology alignment and
it's always the same kind of process that you consider
and now natasha wylde
i tell you now
not how it is used but how to do it
now that you've somewhat convinced hopefully hopelessly is that this is something that that's that's
something that really need to do and the
ontology alignment is really a key component of a lot of this integration tasks
i want to talk about why is it difficult and why
you know any time you open the proceedings of the
semantic web conference is always least several papers on this topic whether the ontology matching
workshop every year attracts so many people
because it's far from a solved problem and so
to give an example of the types of difference is that we need to come
before on in this very simple case of two
very simple representations of conference sessions so let's let's take a look at these two
of ontologies so
first you know session in london sessions of the different names for essentially the same
concepts so then c
location in both places represented differently so the name of the properties different has location
location and also the weights represented as different iron one just string and another clays
players in other cases the instance of some class place
similarly the way time and it is represented in one case it's you know it's
value in another case it's actually an instance of another
class and complex object there
so for something you get this thing of trying to to figure out automatically trying
do you put two plus two to get for how you compose different facts on
the web to draw
conclusion that not explicitly stated at all
so let's start with entity resolution again this is part of the dissertation of alex
yates are basic idea is that we can determine the two objects are likely to
be the same one based on the relationships we find the textrunner runners found this
is related to earlier work by pantel and lin some technical differences but that is
not critically important right now so the basic idea is if i have a bunch
of these triples about x and i know that x was born in nineteen forty
one is the cities in the US is a friend of joe and have another
entity let's call it and for some of these facts are true but
m is also a friend of mary is basically the observation is that the probability
that x and they are the same is some function of the number of shared
and we can make this
a lot more sophisticated we can look at functional relationships rates effects and have the
same spouse
then that further increases the likelihood that they're the same person and so on and
so on so basic relational model the nice thing about this again is this is
completely generic we don't need hand labeled data we don't need specificity to a particular
domain this is for arbitrary entities in the web corpus and in fact we have
run resolver on our entire corpus another elegant thing here is you can do the
dual of this and applied to relations so here's the schematic example of two relations
are in our prime
and if they both apply between one and two
two and four et cetera et cetera i'm going to conclude that the probability that
relations are the same is again a direct function of the number of shared arguement
and in fact is the natural mutual recursion here between these two parts of the
algorithm writers you discover the more entities of the same you can then use that
to discover the more relationships are likely to be the same and you can go
backwards and forwards
so we have here this unsupervised probabilistic model the algorithm here is actually order and
log n so it's not entirely linear but still easy to run on millions and
tens of millions of documents
the next one probability of correctness so how likely is it that in extraction that
we get is is correct and that's kind of a subtle question even what is
correct means correct mean true doesn't mean a true truth preserving transformation on on the
original sentence right if i see
the sentence you know JFK was killed by elvis what exactly my supposed to
extract from that sentence right and we've mainly focused on on truth preserving notion of
correct strike we're going to be trying to do an accurate reflection of
what's in the text and a lot of factors to consider if you do this
analysis to state authority state this of the source there's your confidence and extraction method
but i'm going to show you now
is how we utilize the redundancy in the web corpus we ask
OK what's the number
independent extractions that you've gone and how is likelihood of correctness a function of
and this idea of counting extractions is actually not a new idea if you start
with lexico syntactic patterns which is an old idea goes back to the mat hurst
back in ninety two the idea is you have a sentence cities such as seattle
and boston and that contains the clue right that seattle and boston our cities right
such as their means that we have some class
in seattle and boston are members of the class
well does kinds of patterns are hints as to the meaning of the sentence they
suggest extractions now peter turney back in two thousand tunisian paper developed the PMI IR
algorithm the basic idea there was that could take
pointwise mutual information which we can just approximators co occurrence frequencies of different strings his
idea was you can estimate those from the number of results you get from a
search engine
OK and then based on the number of results you can compute confidence and membership
of the class so basically what this means is we're going to go to our
favourite search engine and type in the phrase for example cities such as seattle and
we'll look at the number of results that comes back in if that number is
higher than it is for some other string and cities such as avocado then we're
going to
be more confident in its elasticity than that of ocado the city and if you
play these kinds of games and lots of people have you find that these co-workers
frequencies are actually very telling
about what's what among the strings so the next step is we actually formalise this
and this gets very complicated in a hurry but you can actually as the following
precise question if you have some extraction x and it occurs k times in a
set of n
this thing sentences in each of these sentence has this kind of lexico syntactic extraction
patterns so each of them is basically suggesting that acts as a member of some
class what's actually the probability that x belongs to the class and again by class
i mean something like cities or can be
strings that belong to relation like mayor of the city
and by the way one really important thing here is that we only count
and this and that's what i'm trying to highlight their distinct sentences right if you
have a lot of copying of the web and we're we're that obviously and so
you don't want to be counting the same sentences just because it's been copied lots
of times but if we count distinct sentences it turns out that we can develop
combinatorial model recall there is model because it's the balls and earns type of model
i won't go through into the formal details but i'll just show you the the
punch line here
we can actually have a closed form expression for if x appears k times in
and draws a ball from the urn in other words in it appears k times
and extraction from out of extractions that we conclude that the probability is this nasty
looking expression haven't even define the notation here i'm not expecting you to read this
i just want to be impressed by our our equations get all refer to the
paper for further details if you do look at for second you see the does
behave in sort of reasonable ways you see that the answer the probability do increase
exponentially with k
right we in other words the more times
we see seattle being appearing in the sentence cities such as seattle we become exponentially
more confident in the fact that cells the city
the nodes also decrease exponentially with the number of extractions if a source seattle being
typically logical we want to do is one answer questions of the form
given this knowledge base is the following gradient entailed given what i know about this
patient that she has breast cancer or this you know breast cancer or maybe i
just don't know
OK so usually this these are the kinds of questions that we're trying to answer
propositional logic is very nice and simple it's also you know not very compact way
to say most things are very transparent way the same most things what people use
most of the time is first order logic
in first order logic we have all the structure that we just saw from propositional
logic but in addition to atoms now have internal structure
and that is no longer just the simple
but it's a predicate symbol followed by a list of arguments which can be other
variables or constants
so for example friends anna bob is the predicate and friends is the predicate symbol
this is an active friends and and actor
and is the constant and x is the variable
and we're going to call ground at
and that's where all the arguments are constants for example friends and x is not
around them but if i replace x by bob
friends anna bob now is the ground after and again we're going to be concerned
with ground atoms here
now in addition to athens not having internal structure we have two new connectors which
are the quantifiers
the universal quantifier and the existential quantifier
so for example if i write
for all for all x friends and x this means that and this friends with
everybody and if i right there exists an x such that friends and x this
means that a has at least one friend
and in this talk i'm going to focus on finite domains and interpretations if you
don't know what this means don't worry about it because it won't matter if you
know what this means and you know what i say
so the way
we are going to extend first-order logic to handle uncertainties by combining it with markov
so here is just a couple and then everybody knows about markov networks was that
he has a couple of slides just to get
you know the basics the and the
you know terminology down
so markov network is an undirected graphical model there's an old for every variable
and there's an another between any two variables that have direct dependence on each other
and the arts and direct
two two sets of nodes are conditionally independent given the third set iff when i
removed the third set from the graph the remaining graphs are are separated
so independence is just graph separation very simple
so the graph tells me what conditional independencies hold
the the parameters of the distribution are specified using what are called potential function
there's the potential function for every clique in the graph
a quick being completely connected set of nodes so this one click which is as
the cancer half
and like one click that smoking cancer
and potentials can take on any nonnegative real values so they don't they can be
more than one
so assuming that all the various
variables are billions
here's the potential table for smoking can possible potential table
and you'll see that that's what it's really doing is just assigning a lower value
through the state smoking chewing cancer false
and the way to think intuitively about potentials is that the value of the potential
state represents all compatible
the values in that state
for example because smoking causes cancer having smoking and not having cancer these two things
are less compatible than the others and that's why this has a lot of
another probability of the complete state is just the product
of the clique potentials for the for the states of the cliques in that
of course there a little problem here which is that with all this reason that
we have
the sum of the probabilities of all states is not necessarily one
and so we need to know the partition function which is just the sum over
of the of the states of the product with that
and by dividing by the partition function we cannot guarantee that the sum
the partition function of course looks very innocent but it's really you know at the
core of everything we can to try to do
if the partition function was easy to handle life would be good since it's not
easy to handle we're going to need to be smart about dealing with itself
we'll be hearing a lot more about it
another thing to notice here is that this representation is simple but it doesn't scale
because you need them make the size of the potential is exponential
in the number of variables in
so if i want to talk about dependencies among all other variables this doesn't work
very well
but they can be something else which is you know which is an equivalent forms
that of log the model instead of the products of factors i have an exponentiated
sum of weights features
and it's easy to see that can convert one from other just by having a
feature forty five
defining each possible state of the of the clique and having to wait that's the
log of the value of the potential
right so i can convert from i can convert from that from to this form
for example
if i find a feature that's one if you don't smoke or have consistency why
and give that feature weight of points fifty one
then this represents the same as the previous models
but it does so more compact
in this case i only see know went from four states to one feature but
imagine having an no clique with ten variables into the ten states
as long as i know that a small number of features that the relevant ones
i can just find the model compactly using those features
and you know we're going to be making good use of the
all right so
we would like to have a probabilistic knowledge bases
knowledge bases with the the formulas that we stated that no longer just true or
false but have probability
this is a long-standing question goes back to the nineteenth century
in a i it started that you know
at least in the eighties with the
nelson's work
so let's think about how we do this right the simplest way
to have a probabilistic knowledge base on the face of it
it's just to assign probabilities to find
instead of saying that you know smoking causes cancer i would say that with probability
point eight smoking causes cancer
this is a very natural thing to do
but you immediately run into a very big problem
the problem is that if i just stated bunch of formulas and their probabilities they
may not be consistent
i cannot for example so that the probability of a point eight and the probability
of a and b is point nine the probability of india has to be smaller
the probability of
so the first thing you have to do
is checked
that the formalism the probabilities that consists
and there are algorithms for doing this but unfortunately very you know this is an
intractable problem
let's suppose that you know you had somehow guarantee that all the funds consistent
hello everybody now unpublished opinion from the university of sheffield and i will try to
introduce you to the semantic web technologies for capturing sharing and
reusing knowledge
well the focus for a moment on to something that is called the knowledge lifecycle
this is because it's quite an important in my view to understand where we are
now start from the top we have discussed about knowledge acquisition of modelling basically building
ontologies the following step one the ontology will give you the definition of the domain
of task or whatever
the following steps to capture knowledge so that you can actually have instances of those
apologies for example and then when you have done it finally your
instances you might want to do something with those instances so for example in
to be industrial scenario you want to share it with our colleagues in one two
to enable the use of the knowledge
why do you want to manage knowledge
basically because you want to
enable use by people
it's not just the genetic uses typically timely and effective
so in order to do that you need to be able to share
in order to show
you need to capture
you see
if you go back to this
the scenario
actually defined goals
three years
and you have to go to be sure that you are able to go backwards
on this cycle
and at every step you provide the right solution so what i will talk about
is about
how to capture information
and i want to share it
to enable the years
this should have been this way
so this is what i was talking about so let's talk about knowledge capture
knowledge knowledge capture means collecting and creating knowledge within and across media archives this is
our interpretation you want to capture knowledge in reach semantically oriented way
and you have basically two task one is
you want to
annotate whatever is already structured
can be you want to have ontologies and you want to merge with
your ontologies or you want to create ontology using other ontologies more often
what you have you have databases and you want to use the database schema to
map to your ontology and create ontologies is here to instances coming from your database
so that it is compatible with your ontology we have seen more or less before
so i'm not going to talk about that but then you have
an awful lot of structured documents you have
a lot of knowledge that these in three texts and images is dating videos and
what you want to do you want to
you want to capture it
you want to make it available in form of
the way in a structured way you prefer
three instances into the ontology and this is exactly what i was talking about
again there are two moments in which you want to capture knowledge one is when
knowledge is generated
and the other one is on legacy documents take into account if you talk about
the average company you will see that in nineteen ninety five percent of the knowledge
is in unstructured documents so
a source
i mean so you can create methods you can use methods to
capture the information directly
in a structured way and possibly in an ontology oriented way
the on the legacy documents while there is much you can do is talk about
a very large scale sometimes let along the way you talk about the average large
enterprise you will discover that you may have several hundreds of thousands of documents and
you can have
probably millions of documents in a in some cases even opinions documents so we're talking
of large scale and what you want to get as outcome of the catch is
that the semantic representation of part of the content of the content is relevant to
your ontology or to your task
the first thing to say about documents is that is
the impression is quite common
data documents means stacks
had appeared text document does not mean
p text that text true
you can i would
you can have accept
a word and especially word also says
and powerpoint presentations and PDF documents are not text they tend to become documents contain
images and text the average web page is not just text so there is the
text that is the image
there can be video can be rolled eighty five measurements for example
and most of all you have media
that means that if you look at this powerpoint presentation of that image that is
that it's not very easy to see some faint that's description of something that is
in current interiors of car well the interiors of
description says a lot of things the textual description it doesn't tell you
the color of the searing searing with for example it doesn't tell you what kind
of instruments they are you can see by yourself in the image
so if you just consider the image you don't have a clue what it is
that you don't know what color easy to know what a wider images presented
and so on and so on but if you just read the text you miss
a lot of information we need to do to go cross media to understand
the picture the following the before
now how do you do was it was mentioned before but are typically what do
do you do ontology based annotation that means when you have an ontology you have
structural or unstructured data sources like a web page in this case when you try
to do you try to associate part portions of the page or the document
ontology by saying these are instances of those ontology for those concepts so in this
case you see there is an image
this shows the shock
humes is what they sell
and what they sell are animals in particular on the enhances overpriced
now if you just look at the heart of the web page there is an
awful lot of more information more or less meaningful more or less useful but what
you want to do you want to do
take your ontology that represents your task the things are interested in you want to
associated information so you can ask questions like
who says
and was surprised
none of these
one of the worst user are actually using in the page they can three this
page you can actually retrieve more than that you can say why
this this company says how successful six pounds so you just keep the data then
the the page clean input what you have is
or statistics
and this is an album by
several are all very famous people
and long
because i only meant to be in are in t
the press as well so i'm getting close to all the authors this is somewhat
all result but at the time was
a major breakthrough and still is an amazing
on august is
professor here should not from the are RSA
when i took my phd comprehensive what some time ago on the cover she was
the joke question
which as of the authors of the the worst case linear time order statistics
which of them is the most rich
was certainly was not greater part of the comprehensive it's have but it was an
amazing question i want answered here because we're on take the perhaps think about it
and maybe not
obvious but several them are rich this is the question was the most rich
anyway before they're rich they came up with the cell growth
come up with many of sense even after getting rich
but not so
what we want is a good pivot
guaranteed good so wrapped around the world is going to be really good and so
the simple suckers just pick a random pair that it's going to go with high
we want to force the good pivot
and the
the new idea here is we're generated recursively
what else could we do
recurse now
you should know from the recurrence is that if we did two recursive calls on
problems of half the size we're going to get and we have a linear extra
work that's the merger events two times one or two pos ordering should recite in
your sleep
that's and log again
so we can recurse on two problems of half the size we got to do
better somehow these recursions
i have to add up to strictly less than n
that's the magic
the cell
so this is just consulate the random select and it really depends on the right
but all focus on the i th element one slide
and the size of the array
we want to select an
and i'm going to write this algorithm slightly less formally
than random selection because it's a bit higher level of an algorithm
and i mean draw
over here
the picture
the algorithm so
the first sort of the weirdest and is the key idea
one of the key ideas you take the elements and there are no particular order
so instead drawing them online
i'm going to draw the
in a five lyon over five grid one
it unfortunate takes one to one draw
but it
will take you weekly long alongside
my time
it doesn't really matter with the with this but it should be
the result it should be with over five symmetry right figure accordingly
with the number five at the height should be exactly five
right i can count that i was five
and this should be well you know our number may not be divisible by five
so maybe
it ends up in sort of an odd way
but what i'd like is that these chunks should be florida over five
and then we'll have at most four elements left over time can ignore those that
really matters just a constant additive constant
so here are my here's my RFA i just happened to
right in this funny way
and i should say this is actually even not that different from what people do
in practice maybe happened during practice for a a long time to get the data
is only about the model is going to gain
but the interesting thing is you can prove that so you initialise this whole process
with the apprenticeship learning idea of learning from expert human pilot demonstration that you don't
even need to explore this none of this aggressive driving your helicopter the age of
the flight on the thing
and we can prove is that given a on
the number of examples from the demonstrator with a small number of iterations the algorithm
with high probability of converge to policy whose performance is nearly as good as the
human demonstrating that science so there's actually we can guarantee that he you can guarantee
because we comparing was saying we do as well as the human demonstrating the task
was egypt says will have you globally optimal performance on on the other hand it
means that we can do this without ever needing to explicitly it explicitly explore all
is actually an impact as we really need to do this more than two iterations
all quantities of interest member states what defines what is in the discrete states
action cases polynomial number states and actions in continuous state space case if you see
the model can be fit well using linear function approximation is polynomial in the dimension
of the state space
on there under certain assumptions that that that you know that linear regression with nominal
features small dynamics
this policy dimensional physics
so this is actually the way we file called film large number of helicopters launched
configurations and we pretty much only ever exploit to really explore the space
i guess you see
the action chris how many of you have seen you know one of helicopter videos
OK i was on this show different one
i'm gonna show different one that's where
oops that should a different video was the harder to see what's going on but
but is this is one that many of you probably won't have seen before
so call this issue two i guess that this is another
let's call the chaos over
i don't know how to to describe it other than to say there's a helicopter
rotating simultaneously on two axes the first time i saw it i actually had no
idea it was going on
well was
i know is is yes i i think it's good performance
actually to find the others
since i think
i think we'll see how pretty see what we call show ones
you know i don't think to have
what the hell
so i to i so and i should say really many people that worked on
autonomous helicopters most notably every runs where MIT and georgia tech
on you know
a period of many years were highly motivated to build the best possible time somehow
control because
and genuinely the only way within able to do so far is using human demonstrations
and forced
try lots of things before that
the first
second at the topic does it away which is to foster
pass horizontal circle
sixty roles in stage three clips is that those are so the whole this is
no this is smaller c helicopter
well i see yes
so we're fortunate to have won the best spies and
in the united states work with us and so he was able to demonstrate his
manoeuvres on the procedures so we actually know these manoeuvres better than he does because
of the details of the other but we don't have rough demonstration
so i think this article was a huge part and as it turns out that
when you're watching these videos from afar always when you actually there seem helicopter life
from afar
it turns out to be difficult to tell if a small helicopter which is this
one his last full-size helicopter people inside so what happens is very often is on
people see this in the common one
the helicopter crashing so that they show up on
this is about what is about to speak maybe you can hold in one hand
so from data to tell me about this space
it's the idea not for this wonderful one of the helicopters that relate the tip
of the role to play on
news and about one-third of the speed of sound so this big enough to be
dangerous enough to kill people
so the when thing did the pension learning is in some sense thinking along because
if you think about how human flies of human humankind flies helicopters i think that
if you or i were to
you know i tried to find these things with no one teaching also showing us
anything i know i know i don't have the hope of ever learning to find
these things if i were sort of saying all you know in grassy by myself
they have today
and i think the only way that human pilots is there to do these things
is because
of the knowledge that you know that you the
human society was society helicopter pilots required over of
years decades and if humans are these things about human demonstration i think this may
be extinct even maybe is
over the challenge is to expect of reinforcement learning how others do so without the
demonstration so that's why
i think are all and i was surprised by this one was out to recommend
its problems i wasn't expecting demonstrations it is important that given that humans really need
the demonstration themselves are going to do these things i think it's actually very nice
easy also a promising way to think about how to teach i want things to
there's a lot
there out how is one person you are so you know each of those maneuvers
was i i would guess taken up by one human and for one human to
discover all these maneuvers you know
this sort of
first elected so
become more clear there was no way to formalize what the problem is the next
question is how do we solve it and more importantly how do we efficiently solving
OK so i'm going to ask if you have any questions at all please and
after this lecture it often happen all the someone early on the thing and only
person this question one as
and that's not that that's not what lecture is not worth anything to so
please ask questions if you have the question one out there
also i have carefully hidden areas of my slides
OK it is your job to find them
so if you see something it doesn't make sense
i could be wrong and for the students classes that quite often
OK so let's let's let's think of some difference
areas where we can plan
in ways that might affect the world so in
don't be a whole range of of examples here so one kind of boring but
still interesting problem is only control
OK you got
eighty four the building that bangor six elevators ten elevators
people coming in every floor you don't know exactly how to come in you my
know distribution of how they arrived you've got people in elevators
OK how how you plan optimally
how do you know that the undulator later should go to the middle floor and
wait for someone to push the but OK or or or perhaps is not small
but how how you do it is clearly very difficult problem
OK and think about just the action space you have many actions you can take
any given time step if you had just six elevators until we can go
up down or stay in the same flawed
OK you got three six actions
as a huge axes space what you had ten elevators twenty elevators you can reasonably
exports entire joint action space you have to exploit some structure and that if you
want to be efficient
we'll talk about today
dynamics here you might have seen the people i randomly is important for the model
what's your objective an elevator control consoles can someone suggested that your objective what you
might want to optimize
right OK so there might be
average waiting time because you've got lot of people or other
or OK that's so i average waiting time will be one
but what if
what if i want to ensure that no one waits for some period of time
take the maximum waiting times and minimize that
it's not clear what the objective should be
certainly i know i think in
japan actually have walls and you can't wait any more than this amount an elevator
so when the the buildings they have to
and sure enough elevators two two two
sounds like a lot
now if we can be more intelligent in his fewer elevators and be more intelligent
about how you schedule this and you save money
it is interesting here you have a very practical future rival you get acting nothing
will happen in in the future
OK now you have certain constraints if you're elevator you is for neuron the six
years florence and suddenly start going down again
going up this so these are going to be really annoyed
back at eighty five minutes to get to your destination why we in the later
never to make progress really upset so you might have constraints on with set solutions
allows well for example you not reverse direction if someone's going to current direction
and in in
unison bends inside
so there with this boring application but it's still a very hard problem in one
thing so they can make a lot of money
OK now is more interesting games actually i have spent their time playing games and
that's what find is really cool year it has to teach itself to play
and if you look at a fellow
the best seller player exactly that it played itself learned
how to beat itself and i got better OK and and and the best fellow
players now
are much better than any human
come out to be the winner and when the system follows my will
and i'm going to
take the
the second derivative
so i get mine is omega squid
j omega comes out twice
so i get is omega squared
then they get close gamma
times j omega
then i get plus
omega zero squared
and the whole thing
multiplied by a two to power e g
omega t minus delta
that now equals
f is zero
divided by and times e could power j
omega three to the whole thing is now in the complex plane
and you see that it europarl apology omega t
cancels on both sides
so i lose i lose my cool apology omega t and i go to multiply
both sides by two apology personnel delta
so i lose my
delta here but it appears that here
so if i make that simple
change algebraic change
we're going to get minus
omega square
let's go my
was omega
zero square
multiplied by eight
must now be equal
zero divided by and thanks to the power j delta
oh my god he's got
and i moved the delta to the right side
we live that
and this
i can be written
zero divided by n
times the cosine of delta
postage j times the site of delta i'm still in the complex plane but that's
now let's compare the apples
was apples and oranges with oranges
this is an apple
and this is an apple that means it's real
that means that this is an apple
but they also oranges
this is an audience has j
and this is an orange
it has the j
and so for this equation
two always hold at all moments in time
the apples
must be
equal to the apples on this site and the oranges on this site must be
equal to the oranges on that site
so it looks like one equation but it really is
two equations
so we now get
that mine is omega squared
plus omega zero square
times a
must be equal to have zero divided by n
times the cosine of self
on both sides are equal
and now we get the oranges on both sides omega
must be equal
times a
i still have this a year
the game omega times age
divided by m
times the side of the altar
two equations with two unknowns any as unknown and delta as unknown
and easy to solve
if you square the
then you get signed squared delta cosine square they'll will tell you at the moment
that's one
so that immediately gives you then
what is
so a
it's going to be have zero
divided by an upstairs
and downstairs
we're going to get omega zero squared
miners omega square squared
omega gamma
this is the amplitude
of the object
will size that will talk about this would lease the next ten minutes is very
complicated function
we want to see through the equation what that actually means
and the tensions of delta
it is easy to find because you define this equation by that once you get
immediately the tendons of delta h disappear
and have zero over and disappear
so you get the tangent
of the angle delta
omega gamma
divided by
omega zero squared
miners omega script
we can now return to the real world
and if we return to the real world we have to change x
as he back into x
and so our final solution
which i will put in color
well then beta x
as a function of t
is this amplitude a
times the cosine
of omega t
minus delta
that is the omega
it's my will that i impose on the system
that there are are no
adjustable constants
which were so used to in the past
in the past we said well you can start the system at equal zero you
can define the position
you can give it a certain velocity so you always expects that a new solution
there are two
in order to
all these statements only making it only about let's say the shapes of primitive forms
of the of this properties right so but you would want something more because it's
not really clear how this how this property interact with each other right so the
next question we ask is how should sent the parameters psychology be said the initial
chain of three nodes are how should we said our image initiated so that we
can either mark match with all of the properties of the real
and so so this is the the
right we have
some real network somebody gives us our goal is to generate the synthetic network and
once we have this graph we would like to compare since it's
non non non trivial to compare graphs what we do is we take both of
and calculate some statistics and compare those statistics for example what we can do is
calculate the degree distribution this network degree distribution that networks and block them and if
they if they overlay
that that's that's OK so this is this is the goal
and what they showed so far is
we discuss briefly what are the properties like what should be measure
then what is a good model i should i just showed you kronecker another question
is how can we find the parameters of the model
the idea will be using is very simple so we've be doing maximum likelihood estimation
so somebody will give us the real graph
and the idea is
let's find these
the this matrix three by three or four by four that maximize the
likelihood of generating the graph
we have
in reality we won't really work with like zero one matrix but we have be
what like probabilistic equivalent of some instead of having zero and once with zero means
an absence of an edge in one presents in the presence of an edge we
will now have have probabilities gives every cell we have a probability of an edge
between them
and then the same machinery applies
and the idea is let's search over this matrices
to maximize this likelihood
and if you do this mainly
it will take like and victoria and square at time
and why is that
the then victorian effect comes from basic testing ground for graph isomorphism right we have
to consider all possible orderings of the nodes and if we play
and since we plan to fit this model sun
graphs of ten thousand twenty thousand fifty thousand nodes
this is be
much too expensive so that they can used here is
two two of what is called a super exponential complexity is basically by using
metropolis sampling and is basically users like constant time we to be constant
and then
the the in square and that comes from basic the fact that we have to
evaluate every cell of graph adjacency matrix if have to compare how many edges are
shared so we have to go and check every possible
and this is what one can do is one can exploit the property the properties
of kronecker graphs and the fact that real graphs are sparse what i mean by
this by sparse is that the number of edges in the
in the network is much smaller
and in the end square which is like the size of the adjacency matrix so
this would give us a linear effect so
what is the bottom line is that we can find the parameters of the kronecker
graph in linear time so the time proportional to the number of edges
i just show an experiment on the graph of sixty six thousand nodes and twenty
six thousand edges so finding the parameters takes less than twenty minutes
and if you go and compared the properties of the
through so the
circles and synthetic equivalent because you
the measure the man of the match the properties were so here is the degree
distribution so this is basically the distribution over the number of links and node has
and here we have a distribution over the that's in the network so basically says
that they are omitted in both cases around four of the real graph and the
and then we can do the same for spectral properties of the of the two
graphs of two adjacency matrices and again
we seem to be underestimated the components of the eigen values so here i blocking
logrank which is the log i can value
on the other but i'm putting blogrank which is the the log first i connected
components of the first arguement and again the sort of match
concludes the first part of
completed work when we looked at what is what how can we model of network
evolution and now i would like to study the second but if there are any
i could think about that for
so i so
in all experiments using the notion of effective diameter which means the distance within reach
ninety percent of
that's of nodes can be reached and the reason why we are using this is
for example i mean i wish o one one one example of of
before they of diameter of
coming microsoft messenger communication network cracking data is out there on the model of the
distribution is at seven and like ninety percent of reachable pairs
nineteen ninety percent of the people can be reached within a cops
but you call you can also find that sort like twenty thirty
hope so and so
do we basically just one person it so that we are less prone to
that's the reason that's what
i like those
it is
what happens is
OK this will be but still i would i mean i can take it off
line but the idea is that usually we can like densely connected part so usually
one one of the so we have this two by two matrix
i don't know
right and what usually happens is that here is something like point nine here is
small this is for the autonomous systems and here here is that i know something
like point four or something and here would be like point three something like that
so you you get this densely connected but this this result in graph where you
almost have included between the core of the of the network and then you have
the rest sort of attaching
and then this basically this to measure how much how much does go from here
to to here and the other way around
OK but how
i can explain what later so
let let me continue with the second part
and now
what i what what i want to talk about this
about the processes taking place on the networks and what we look at look at
here what we call cascades which are basically the propagation graphs and i defined them
a bit later and first we saw some properties of the lens of a simple
model and in some way how to explain this
OK so here he is
skip prezzo cascades were first studied by
in social sciences but and they define it as the phenomena where the idea of
some action becomes wide widely adopted by the influence of the so let's say this
is out this is our social networks
and this is the first person who i know buys a new product or something
and then that is
their friends
some of their friends will will due to these recommendations
i will also go by the product may make recommendations for what now this note
as he got two recommendations decided to buy
he recommended on
four and so on right and now this process it's like propagates over the network
given this
cascade is just the graph that is induced by these
processes that spreads over the network OK
and more specifically what we look at
this is a good
so that is an easy test
which sometimes
comes in handy
so now comes the question is a high-voltage always dangerous
namely putting my hands
nothing and right finger
the outlet is danger is always dangerous
high falls
well it often is
but i will show you today that i can generate
these are really thirty thousand volts
but it
and survive
if you call your hair in the winter
maybe not today but if you comment in the winter hair is dry nicely washed
the difference between the column in your hair could easily be thirty thousand four
and this voltage is so high
that's box can fly over
you hair
the com
it's like a spark plugs in the car
in a way it's like lightning
what is the current will flow through the air
three my hair
and the co
but there is so little electricity solar electric charge my head on the court
that the current will flow is not high enough the doesn't last long enough
to kill so it's completely innocent
even though
it is thirty thousand four
but the thirty thousand fold collapses to nothing the moment that
as part flights
raise your comb your hair
you may also use some cracking
and in fact when i was combing my hair early on with this experiment i
did hear some cracking with feel good
because that means
areas reasonably dry
you may use some crack because these parts that fly that you may not have
make some sound
and in fact if you do this in the winter and i would advise you
to do that
not all the lights off in the room make sure start
going from the familiar to make sure you have washed your hair that you hair
is dry
and you call your hair and you actually see sparks year them and you can
even better
i have done
countless times when i was
student pressure
what i would do is i was going from the from there
and i will and i sure you really should remain and should not
and then in in front of the mirror when everything is dark you take sure
of very slow
and they've seen zillions small parks and you sure is glowing like like
it's really a fantastic experience
so i recommend all of you to do that
wait until february
and it's even more fun if you do it with a friend we should do
i will
of course needless to say i was planning to do it today
but the humidity is too high so it
so you have to wait
until the area is really very dry and that's no joke makes a huge difference
how long the charge
can be kept and humidity
it's just
there's too low a
is the poor very poor insulator and so did the charge this leads off u
perhaps you remember when you sit in your car and you move on the seat
or when you scuff few feet
and then you touch the doorknob
you have sparked draws support
does it kill you know is unpleasant can be unpleasant you may get a small
and the
the difference in voltage between u
and the doorknob could easily be thirty thousand four
but the moment that you touch it
it collapses nothing current is not high enough doesn't last long enough
and so
there's no danger for you
you will
just a little bit of a nuisance but that's all
there was
when i was beating
but i was beating alex
there was easily thirty thousand volts between him and probably more
was still alive at least
i am
by duality
it looks like he's also life
now this phenomenon of part
as in a we call the electrical breakdown
so the higher the voltage
and the sharper
the objects are the easier it is for these sports development so here is ideal
because harris
sticking out like like needles so it's ideal for electrical breakdown
i have there in the corner
spectacular battery which runs only on water
and it can easily produce
in the winter
sixty thousand poles they
maybe only twenty thousand
o thirty thousand
and before i demonstrate this
i want you to understand
how easy it is to build one
because it is an ideal
to do with health
what you see here
at the top
a plastic bottle
i just want to
that will
so this
you might want to be
one is
c one
if you really want to write
division it
the you re
as much as
the original edition
need to
the full
it is quite strong
so it
so the
is the rules that
this is where the spirit
in two thousand
just so
is that
once you
with this is that
so use
you t
so why is
this is a list
what we
i think just
there's no
it is
some of the
we didn't really
this one
so strong was born into a world where you will can
the really wants to
obviously these this
this is c
you yes
it's always
he was
one of the things
OK to use
written in terms of
so what is it
the sea
he is
and here i have a square
just how much memory and you start stable
is this true as well
les s
and it is for this quantity and it is for this quantity one
four large as you can see that it is
is going to be much larger
four large as is going to be much like
so we're saving on representation and you will see that we're facing competition
that square so now the answer to your question so basically what you have is
that these factorizations is equivalent to other the opposite
just use
what to call
the bayes rule
was from the base
bayes rule
tells you
something that simple
know that
you know he's
so this is equal to p of a given b
p of the
this is equal to p of the given a
the of a
so we have these equality
is called
just use bayes rule
these quantities equal to this quantity
replace this quantity
that which is equal to this by this
and then you get another form
do this again you can another afford
them saying basically is that
a single conditional independence
thing those violence there
can be associated with this
two different representation
the trying to
OK so
you what you need to do it in you to write to conditional independent
and see how can simplify them so as to obtain the more general type dependency
for example
give an example
i have
you can do and make
i if you have
x one is independent
x two
x three
x one is independent of x three
in the next
let's assume that had
now he is what can now is an exercise
you can tell the x one is independent of x two
you can tell the next one is independent of x
this will fall from that
and this as an exercise just write these expressions
right expression and you figure out that both of these expressions correspond to the world
well the map has already been done before
several types and that's what i call properties in right
when you have a lot of the properties of conditional independence
so basically what
the property is basically right this thing is for example used is equivalent
so x two
independent of x one given x three
i just things equivalent to
can opinion is two things
well just do the math and that you can
that's a property of conditional independence
then you can write down as many properties which
well that's how i wrote it
i just
i just saw the graphical model
we'll see later
continuous discrete optimization problems and the assignment variables for object i are not copied to
the assignment variables for object j given the characteristics of fuel mixture coefficients and the
so if you do that conditioning off on your on your statistics the modes and
the mixing variables then the assignments of different objects are independent
and that is expressed by placing basically the linearity
here the linearity of CIA not being copied
see i prime
so tightly tishby has interpreted this scheme as is the bottleneck scheme is finding an
efficient code for your feature vectors you have to find product to build codebook vectors
x two and the
cost function which i just have to presented on the previous ten c can be
written as the difference between two mutual information and that's all of the nice interpretation
in terms of in terms of
and for information theoretic approach our image blocks are the axis here
they are supposed to be compressed into segment descriptors these are the x two is
here and what you want to preserve of is with these these segment descriptors you
want to preserve as much knowledge as possible about your features in the features might
be the colors although the local frequencies so the wise encoded you're you're colours and
local frequencies on local descriptors and you sort of compressed into context and that's the
way it tally tishby cells these ideas you compress your image patches in the context
sensitive way so that the
reciting description of your image patches is maximally informative first perspective the colour content and
the frequency content if you have selected why scholars for his
here you have the same think pictorial describe this is the feature space
this is the object space and you compress it sort of in in a reduced
representation by fixing this constraint on the minimal amount of informativeness of your clusters whereas
here you want to minimize the mutual information to get a generic descriptions of few
objects basically of your of your image patches
i think this is a very nice concept from the interpretation point of view on
a vertex
successfully surprisingly successful in in many different areas like document retrieval my first phd student
thomas hofmann has applied in document retrieval is very good designers the hebrew group is
using the concept for analyzing spike trains as well as galaxy information and they have
similar applications in bioinformatics and we have used in in in vision and and also
in some areas of land
now the segmentation is PD looks like this
here you have these image and basically on the on the basis of local colour
descriptors these types of statements you get
and so for many applications this is a good enough segmentation
we are currently participating in the competition set up by the money group they have
a large number of hand labeled images and what you cannot do is you can
basically use your favourite segmentation algorithm run it against the database and then do precision
recall analysis of uris size compared to the ground truth which is defined by by
berkeley undergraduate students so if you believe that is a good source for ground crews
then you can compare yourself against this database
since it's fully probabilistic model you can do resampling so this is the original image
where we use which we used to train our segmentation model and this is sort
of a sampling from that from that probabilistic model and you see it's the colour
segmentation approach and obviously screwed up the texture
and actually we could do that for texture as well but the the construction is
much more complicated than you have got all features two to go from feature space
back to the original space
it's worked sufficiently well and that's actually what we paid for in remote sensing imagery
so this was the original and this is the reason that image and for many
in that area
this was surprisingly good so they they
they bought into the model
mean outcome too
are there any questions
you need to get back that
no that was not used now since the the the the local windows are overlapping
you get you get an implicit coupling between different between different sites by feeding in
the same statistics
but what you really would like to know is if you for example
we have a markov random field model in the back of your head and you
had you had to your to your cost function for clustering local coupling of of
the of the CIA value to a neighbouring CI plus one LCI minus one object
then you would also have to have a smooth mapping
but then what i'm saying is we don't really know
the imperfections of the sphere there areas which have so big sharp points
and so
we will make it to one million volts we get a breakdown maybe add a
few hundred thousand maybe three hundred thousand people
you can also calculate what the maximum
charges on the vendor graph
because if the maximum potential three hundred thousand volts
you know rate is is point three
meters so you can calculate now
what the maximum
charges that you can put on the open graph using an equation
give you can microkernel
so the maximum potential for our underground
because of the order
of three
hundred thousand thousand people
gives you know feeling of qualitative
feeling four numbers
about the
because is down
so to give you an idea of what are when the graph can do and
later we will understand how the charge get there you have some feeling of potential
and four
the charges that are involved
here's my friend the graph
and i approached then the graph
with a
sphere which is connected to the earth and its positive charge on it
then this will become negatively charged through induction
and so you get field lines
we go from the vendor graph
so these object always perpendicular
the equipotentials
go like this
and so
electric field here
i will probably be
the strongest
and so the sparql then developed between the sphere and then graph provided that you're
close enough
so you do
achieve a
electric field close
so this sphere of about three million
paul's meeting
and i will show you that later you will see
more sparks today
you've never seen before in your life
but i want you to appreciate a little bit more
the sparks about lightning
i demonstrated that so you get a little bit more of it
if i approached then the ground
not with the sphere
but i would walk to defend the graph
being very courageous like this i'm also pretty good conductor
i'm also
connected with your
and the chances are
why develop first between my notes and the graph because that is
the smallest of the shops curvature the small brains
we're certainly my head would be
good candidate for being hit first
if i approach to graph like this with my hand stretched
then chances are of course that sparks will first developed my fingertips
because it's a very small radius
and they're very close to the graph
so that's where
the discharge real
walker so before
we will enjoy some of this
you will enjoy it i will enjoy it less
i want to talk a little about about lightning you first
because what you're going to see you know ways to form
of lightning
there are four hundred thousand thunderstorms every day on average honours
four hundred thousand thunderstorms there about hundred lightning flashes every second
the top of the thunder clouds
becomes positive and the bottom
becomes negative
the physics of that
not so easy and probably incomplete and i will not go into the details of
the physics but it does have to do
with the flow of water drops
become elongated can become charged because of friction
they can break off
and they can transport
i will simply
if you some facts
and so i will accept the fact that
the cloud
going to be charged
this is the cloud
positive at the top
negative at the bottom
and here is the
because of induction
yes of course will therefore
become positively charged here
so we're going to see field lines
electric field lines
go from the earth
the cloud always perpendicular
the equipotentials
something like this
you some dimensions
this may be
something like five kilometres
this vertical distance
it's about one kilometre
typical numbers of course can vary enormously
from thunderstorms thunderstorm
and this height
something typically
like ten kilometres
this allows us now to make some very interesting
calculations to get some feeling for the potential difference between the cloud and the earth
the first thing we can do
if we make the simplifying assumptions
that the electric field is more or less constant here is like having two parallel
but electric field is constant between them
then the potential difference delta p
between the bottom of the clouds and the earth's
is simply the electric field times the distance d
so this becomes a
times still
but if the breakdown occurs at three million volt per meter
by the way that's dry air
when when there's a thunderstorm is probably not so but let's take three million volts
per meter
so we get three times ten to six
that is for you
and the distance between the cloud and the earth let's take one kilometres for that
kind of the thirty metres
so we get the order of three
a billion volts between earth and the club
and the values that are typically measured by several hundred million to one billion involved
so it is not all that different
you expect that the
probably less than what we have calculated because clearly
we can assume that
this defect right full has the dirichlet distribution with some hyperparameters of
OK so i think
so i have
so it follows dirichlet distribution and then that the
the count
i i generated according to multinomial with that you know parameter vector and say we
just fix the document length OK we just assume the document is given right
so then we
you know we get of this we get this simple
creation here you know it's just that
and if we
and and here the the PFA did you give enough which has been the ocean
distribution cases just equation for the dirichlet distribution
what that does is basically
you know it just makes the
assumption like you do in this future if you've seen that before this hierarchical bayesian
modeling approach that you know all these parameters of the first level of the bottom
level of the fetus right come from the population might be drawn they come from
a common populations
in a way they get they get coupled right but through these hyperparameters
because basically you know there's one theta here and the second one it's kind of
more likely that you know they come from the same distribution
you know they they kind of influence each other so particular you know
right so it's
it's not very sophisticated coupling
OK but
but it's a very simple way of of
moving things here
well and then you can actually
what you can do is you can actually
following strategy like empirical bayes
OK so
empirical bayes what you would do then is
maximize the evidence
so you would actually
try to find the value of your hyperparameter far
that maximizes the evidence and that's basically the probability of all the counts that you
right given of
so what you do here you integrate out this
theta parameters right the fitted parameters are integrated out and then used to determine the
optimal phi and of course what you would really want to do is also integrate
you over of all possible outcomes but you know an empirical bayes
you know we just try to find an optimal estimate the point estimates for the
size of
so we can write down what is actually is
by explicitly integrating out the fate of
and then we we basically get this equation here we with a lot of gamma
OK and then you can look this up actually in the
the reference that i had before
here this mikalai i and
you know how you then actually go about optimizing
in computing the maximum of the function can in one way to do is just
to understand it you know new
the optimisation
however you know because that's often
a little bit involved people often
resort to what i call the popular approximation here
which is
you know instead of optimizing the evidence explicitly they just take it proportional to the
reference distribution
right so they just assume that holds
and just have one degree of freedom which is
you know what weight is given to the reference distribution so that the weight you
and then they use that OK so that's what the practice and people have found
that that's actually follow the the applications
you know doesn't you're not losing much compared to the
approach where you actually compute
the optimal find and you know the more sophisticated
so then if you
you know if you if you plug this big what you would get
as you're for years smoothing is basically that you know these these are weights that
you compute somehow
it's basically what you will add to your account
so the way you know again this this population approach comes into play
is that the columns are cemented by these pseudo com which are exactly these hyperparameters
and and if you plug in the that's what i call the popular approximation
if that if the offers are proportional to the reference distribution
with you know
scalar mu here you can plug those into this equation
and then
what you get is
this formula here
basically you see that in that case
you get again
and interpolation between the maximum likelihood estimate and the reference distribution
and you can also see that again
this has the nice property that the interpolation weights for long documents
this you will go to one
right the constant mews so you would do less moving for longer documents and for
sure documents he would most like so that comes out naturally
in this
bayesian framework
so it's a special case of linear interpolation
can i ask for the time this point seven
seven minutes OK
OK and then there's this if i know
three five five assuming that we're using decimal numbers one
don't cheat
hopefully these are not yet sorted we'd like to sort them
so the first thing we do is take the least significant digits
sort by the least significant digit
and whenever we have equal elements like these two nines we preserve the relative order
three to nine is going to remain above eighty three nine doesn't matter here because
we doing the last sort but the first sort
but in general we always using a stable sorting algorithm so when we
sorting by this column
first we get the zero so that's seven two zero then we get
six five three five five
then we get six
four three six
i mean i make mistake then we get the sevens
so we preserve the order
it happens to be the right order
may not be at this point
we've looked at the other digits
then we get that looks like the nines those two lines
three two nine
and eight three nine
right so far
now we sort by the middle digit
the next we significant
and we started out with looks like that chooses to appear
two down here
so first read the first in first
three two nine
then we sort by the we have the threes
so we have four three six
and it three nine
then we have a bunch of
five the looks like i missed anyone
there are no good
we have three five
we have three five five
we have four five seven
and we have six five seven
like to check that i haven't lost in helmand so we have seven here seven
here and seven elements here
finally we sort by the last digit one thing to notice by the way his
before we sort by last into currently these numbers don't resemble sort order at all
but if you look at everything beyond the data we haven't yet sorted so these
digits that's nice and sort it
two zero to nine three sixty nine five five five seven five seven critical
but was finishing off
so we stably sort by the first digit and the sparse number we get is
so the get three to nine
and then
three five five
then we get some four four three six
four five seven
then we get looks like a six
six seven
eight seven
and then we have an eight
check still have seven else because the lost anyone and indeed there are now in
sorted order
you can start to see was working when i have equal elements here i've already
sorted the suffix
so let's write perform
so what this algorithm is doing
what's nice about his we're not we're not partitioning independence we always keep a huge
batch of elements in one big pile
but we're just going through it multiple times
in general need to go through multiple times hopefully not too many times
but first argued reference
most families running time is a little bit tricky here
because it depends how you partition into digits
this is easy we and on the digit position
that we're currently sorting
let's call that t
and we can assume by induction
that sort of beyond agency
this is unmatched hypothesis
so we assume that
sorted on the low order
t minus one digits
and then the next thing we do is sort on the two stages
OK we need to check things work and we restore the induction hypothesis party instead
t minus one
when we sort entity digit there's two cases if we look at any two elements
who want to know whether they put in the right order
so yes
two elements
are the same
so they have the same t digital
this is the case if they have the same t digit
their order should not be changed by stability
we know that they remain in the same order
because the bill is supposed to preserve things that have the same key that we're
sorting them by the induction hypothesis
we know that keeps them in sorted order because they used to be
actually about this is that they used to be sort of
adding on this value in the front it's the same in both doesn't change anything
so there remains one
and if they have
it is
then this sorting step will put them in the right order
because that's what sorting does
this is the most significant digit so you've got off by the teeth vision if
they differ the rest are o
the proof here
of correct this is very simple
once you know the algorithm
any questions
before we go on
so we're going to use counting sort
we could use any story our algorithm we want individual digits
if you have a conditional random fields you need to use exactly the sampling techniques
that number talked about
two very will be talking a lot more about that in this graphical model scores
next week
we could for instance ask for all ask just count how many labels so wrong
that's a very simple one i mean you can think of much more complicated ones
just trying to keep things simple
this inner product between for fixed and y and w
would be just well i might have some w one
for that term here
w two for this
this these are of different data types
this is in some feature space that section number
they just need to wait which after corresponding datatype otherwise it doesn't work
the full column generation
i get this additional term here y i y fronts
what we actually have to do is we have to maximize
the sum of all of all those terms
if all the while i very independent of each other and no pairwise interactions are
happening this would be trivial right
i'll just pick whatever y is locally optimal like it decomposing some everything's fine
however here
i have
a function which depends on adjacent terms why i one plus one
now who
has heard of dynamic programming
who is implemented dynamic programming algorithm himself
i would say you have an advantage
let's go through it in detail
these are just way be part of the weight vector
so that this would actually be a number this would be something in feature space
now let me show you what how we can do this
sexual seventy thousand the slides
let's just go through it a very very slowly
so we have
the problem of maximizing
of y
going from articles one
to l
why i
why i plus one
by the way is it
is everybody OK
to see how the sum over all those terms can result in into this function
basically what's happening is see this time you just depends on why i OK so
i just like it straight here
the next but the pairwise terms i'm just prior to to april while i was
one that's the term that just depends on the singer y i think apply here
as well
and just ignoring things that the boundaries just because i'm being a bit sloppy
is a medical with that
and see where the sum goes from i one to l so that's a big
well i can write this out as follows
i can
right it as
the same thing as the max
y one
y two trails
often in
of well
y one
y two
plus the sum
i going from two
two l
why i
why i lost
what you can see is
but i can maximize
the second term doesn't depend on y one anymore
if i knew what y two would be
i could work out what the optimum value of y one is
so what in is for all possible values of y two
work at the optimal value of y one
it's not too hard because i mean what can only take on two different values
y one only takes into different values i just evaluate this piece
for all its four different quite possible configurations
and like it
the following function
of light two
just the mass
of y one
what i want
and y two
so now what i can do is
i can just get rid of the maximisation one
and they get the problem which looks as follows GFY two
plus this piece
and maximize the wife to y o
so i can write this
that's it somewhere i store
the function of
why one of y two
i support this
against all this in the two what to
as actually just need two numbers
y two being one i need to find out what happened before
y one y two being minus one thousand
so now
so this is
i can do the following
take the max o y two
now y three
to l
of y so
of y two
y three
plus the sum
i came from three
of f
of y i
what are plus one
i can again combine terms
and i get the
of y three
let's call this
g two
g three y three
just defined as the max
of y two
now g
and y three
and then i go
and for all
y two
the function of one three
and you continue
i'm not going to
do the same reasoning for why three now
you can easily see that if i keep on doing this at some point early
that at the end of this recursion
now at the end of the recursion what they will have
is the maximisation of one last variables
namely while plus one
now we know what values
i want to have this
i just went backwards pass
because i know what wales
will be as a function of wild was one
i think the look up for while minus one one minus two and i just
well basically and rounds entire recursion backwards
that's like the forward backward pass if you've
done something like to be i was before you life that's basically what's happening here
this is
i can solve
this maximization problem here in that time
the before
it will be
of l
well it kind of depends on what you think is driving the problem in each
of these things suggested different levels different types of things you might do so for
example if it's more convenient should you change the environment
to make the unhealthy food
convenient make healthy foods more convenient
that would make sense
but if this is the reason is what people like to eat what would you
do about that actually created drug that takes away the pleasure from some of these
unhealthy foods or could you train people to believe that they are not good for
you et cetera
if it's too heavily advertised well that screams out for government regulation to cut back
on marketing
o talk a lot about marketing what government can and cannot do about it
if it's more affordable of course you want to use an economic intervention
so could use taxes and subsidies for example
to raise the price of food that you think people should be doing less of
and lower the price of things you would like people even more certainly a possibility
and the people don't know which foods are healthy woman argues for education
but notice that that was almost almost trying things people said
so that would suggest that education is probably not going to get the job done
because that's not the mean
driving reason because most people know that they should need so much stuff
but education is what we default to when we think about what to do so
really all these things are potentially interesting possibilities
and the question is what makes most sense will sort through all these and discussed
what society might do to help change
food preferences in food intake patterns in the side
so we have to ask ourselves which of these is true
if people are eating too much junk food which of these is
and although
most of you would probably say well it's real all these things are involved in
least to some extent
society defaults to certain assumptions about what's driving food intake
and there are some people that default to environmental
explanation of this it's marketing its economics it's the environment is set up in such
a way to make these foods very appealing and very attractive people that's why the
but other people
in fact probably a larger percentage fall to the top option here
that these are personal health issues rather than public health issues
the people are making choices about what they
if they make bad choices is therefore
and so you either need to implore them to behave differently you need to coerce
to behave differently or you need to educate them
to behave differently
and you can see these two camps of thoughts would generate far different approaches to
dealing with dietary crises on the international scene
so we'll walk through these but of course there are players
now i'm going to show you two
you may have seen these on TV once from burger king
and one is from KFC
and what i showed this to you was we'll talk a lot about food marketing
in the united states because if you buy the premise that i laid out of
few moments ago that what we consider food and what we consider to taste good
it's pretty much a total social construction
i mean not to complete social construction for example know where in the world what
people consider a rock
because the rockies non-food across all cultures but aside from that there is great variability