then the people who take the celebrant right another way of saying it is there
isn't random assignment
of the subjects to the two conditions in the in the study
that's no random assignment experiment
you by not randomly assign people to these two conditions you may be capturing just
individual differences in the kind of person
who when there's a perfectly stable
save low bridge says one that bridge
you want to go the bridge rather with my life
to get the class
and then surprises that that's the kind of person who would
call perfect stranger on the telephone and writer sexy story give to
we're not so surprising so what we have to do of course is taken into
the lab
do this in a more systematic way
with random assignment this is how
i want to finish up
today we have to to until two forty five three forty five
three of take about
five or better to finish up now give us some time for
so how do you do this
in the lab
you can
bring people into the lab
and i can present you with a confederate
who said let's say you are all in condition one everybody on this side of
the room
and i can say to all of you
please weight here
will begin experiment
in a moment
while waiting please fill out this form
and the form includes how attractive how attractive you are
so the experiment
to me
i can do the same thing over here
i can so i can give you the form that's due to rate how attractive
you think i am
and i can give you the same instruction with the crucial
please wait here
we will begin the painful shock experiment
in one
please fill out this form is widely
what happens
the people who got a painful shock
or more likely to find the confederate
the trial
well there sitting there
thinking about painful shock it's making the heart beat faster
it's making their homes well
make you breathe harder maybe
and even though it's fairly obvious what's doing that there is no
this attribute that arousal two
i must be falling in love
even with that obvious
a even with that obvious instruction
you can do this in other ways you can bring
here here here is one of my favorite ones
you bring people in the lab lets will will make the control group this time
we bring you were not web we say this group of people
please weight here
i will begin experiment in a moment
you can follow these forms in the meantime the forms ask how attracted you are
to the experimenter
now the experimental group and i say
weight here
it will begin experiment moment are going to ask you for lots some farms but
first to get ready for this experiment likely to get on the treadmill
and run for ten minutes
so you run on the treadmill
you've just sat around the people run on the treadmill even when that that arousal
is fairly obvious you've got you do a little bit of aerobic exercise
you still find
the experimenter
more attractive
this is why the fourth floor of payne whitney gym is such a dangerous place
and i urge you as your dean
to be very careful
it's the combination of robotic exercise in spandex
leads to trouble
now here's the final experiment i apologize for this it is a bit sexist in
two thousand and seven
let me explain and we could never do this one could never do this experiment
that let me
let me let me go through with you and you apologize for its
some of its qualities
in this experiment male subjects were brought
into the lab
and they were asked to look at falls from playboy magazine
so these are essentially photographs of naked women
and they are wearing headphones
that amplify their heart
and they are asked among other things
how attracted or
to the centerfold
photograph that they're looking
maybe i don't remember how many they look at maybe it's about
so these slides are coming out
got the headphones on
the headphones amplifying their heart heartbeat
and the slides are moving one after another from
a few seconds each slot
and that was it
to their heart
slide one
slide two
slide three
slide four
slide five
slide six
and then there which one did you find most attractive
with what you most attractive
slide five absolutely
she's she's the woman i want to marry
what's happened is
they're using this
bodily q of their heart beating
to infer that that's what they find
more attractive
now here's the twist
they not actually listening
so there are
they're listening to a tape recording
of the heart beat
and the experimenters back there with the speed and are
at random intervals just speeds up take their hard
and then slows it down
and it doesn't matter which lie
speeds up the
tape of the heartbeat on that's the one
the subject is more likely to think
the person of the person attractor
so here you can this attribute real arousal you can even this attribute
forty around
arousal that isn't even coming from your body just coming that's just
it's just a place to you
random you can even
this attribute OK i these experiments are pure
which is a provides a humane way of looking at the antibodies in the bad
we don't have to believe the babies we just
after collect blood from
the sentences that appear after the baby is born
and the class of antibody that goes from the mother to the baby we can
look at
OK a kind of three-dimensional
principal component analysis and see that each baby
has more or less
the same
antibodies in this IDG classes the mother that's not surprising
because the mother is transporting to the baby
her experience
but if we look at another set
of antibody molecules such that is not transported from mother to baby we see a
totally different picture
instead of each mother and baby being a correlated per what we see here in
this IGN is that all babies are correlated it's human beings
are born
with a similar training sort
every activities
and the mothers then have different factors of development over there healthy experience
so let's of antibodies
that we begin life with
in which we take of our mothers immune experience
other sensory activities we begin life with in common
we do not partake of mothers experience but we have the basis for developing their
own experience and then each of us
as exemplified by the divergence of the model with this we can assume that the
also began in this
of repertoire
the immune system and then each one in their own healthy weight
goes off
in an individual kind of the development so we see
patterns of development associated with her
but using the same kind of technology we can see patterns in diseases such as
multiple sclerosis and here we're looking up
instead of principal component analysis for here kind of about
every activities
a thousand different activities and we can see that the colour-coded according to their intensity
we can see those are called
shared by all the healthy individuals
but if the groups of individual come down with different types
of multiple sclerosis
have different barcodes different patterns of reactivity that are shared by these individuals alike
with their
real activities that are individualized
the immune system begins
it begins life with individual patterns back from the mother
with species are so human patterns
develop in utero
by the way the system is looking at itself and we can
using this kind of a pathogen microarray approach
we can see that the immune system
adjusts within this city of individual
information and just
patterns that are indicative
a disease and its subdivisions but also patterns that will help us predict the response
to treatment
so here we get we go back to the
the utilitarian
aspects of looking at how the immune system deals with
the complexity of the body
when we look at the
complexity the immune system in response to what's going on in the body
we can use the immune system has a slow growth
for predicting
say the response to treatment in multiple sclerosis
which actually does have quite a lot of the structure in the data and it is even got
those little ninety degrees things which we can see
the extra noise ninety degrees it even got those features it we just two features
it said how many that take before thousand features
because the basis so high-dimensional all not so fantastic rotations you can upon finding this
rotation is just summing up all right pixels give you interesting structure in the data
you perform much better
i mean absolute error is rule really really small
and then
as you increase the number dimensions
it just goes to zero again zero three sixty one is a to zero three sixty anyone
three six-degrees-of-freedom yet again well i put it in the way i would put it is
because the data set
only has three hundred sixty data points the covariance
will be rank three sixty
so you discarding all the igon values there are actually another arm
three six four minus three sixty igon values if you think about the covariance matrix
here it's three six four eight by three six four
but it's made up
in a proactive uh
o operator go a long way back to find the creation again when i
is made up all
or home
naive and that's made up over
in my notation is this you
and in this case
this is the
three six four eight why is that why have
so this guy here
it is and this is like three sixty
so this guy he is a three sixty three
six four right
by three six four eight
matrix but his rank is only three hundred sixty
once you've got three hundred sixty dimensions that's all information the reason the data
that's a little bit old
there's a problem here
i just use the sample covariance matrix to solve the problem
by the data being presented in terms of distance interpoint distance
so what happened you can't necessarily
computer science like ubuntu interpoint distances how do you know what the sample
well that's another nice trick which has been known for a long time in statistics
and underpins some material from tomorrow so i wanna show you exact in some detail
so i understand the problem and i said with these methods is class methods on
being given the squared distance matrix for the data
but the digits i can compute because i had the original data but imagine someone
just gives me the squared distance
and they don't tell me the original data
when i went define the direction of maximum variance how did i find at given
i don't have the covariance which piece yeah relies on you
well this is the final bit principal coordinate analysis which you don't actually need the covariance you can deal with
the interpoint distance matrix directly
in order to solve these problems a squared distance matrix which i'm going right
baldi i can't write told of try to like that
i write these things as
in this form
so this is i'm assuming alliance entered here
i'll explain what i'm trying to do here
the moment
so in my other notation in the slide there's got hats on
that's all
okay so this
notation hear is in the matrix when expressing squared distances so in the normal way
of expressing square distances would say um
between why and why jay
it's de-iced data point why
minus two times while i transpose why jay
why jay transpose
why jay
which is simply the multiplying out the original
euclidean squared distance formula
that's one way of writing it this the squared l two norm or whatever so it's that's
now right in matrix form i need to take the diagonal
of this thing along the diagonals all those elements hear
and then i multiply him by ones on the outside to do the same for
the why jay-z i have to do the same thing transposed so that's just a
i'm using metric because it leads to a nice little proof
but how you can compute
thing you want so here
this is the inner product matrix of centred inner product matrix i talked about before
so we've been using why transpose why
and we don't have access to it so the first stage which is the bit
somehow has disappeared from my slides in the proof is to show you that you
can get
this why why transpose from this distance matrix
so i said i'm using sensors why in fact it doesn't matter because these are
distances so the centring doesn't matter
have you guys heard centring matrices
he's a magical devices
so this is vectors ones is my notation for vector of ones and this is a centering matrix
what is the centering matrix
centering matrix if i multiply why by age
it gives me why
so it's minus plus
why times the vector ones
over and
one transpose
so what's on the vector ones is just the sum of all the reason why
divided by
so that's the matrix m u
and then multiply by this one transpose just give me why
mu mu mu mu yeah
so it senses my dataset it's a very nice useful matrix because it also has the property that if i
multiply by any constant vector
so let's multiplied by the vector of ones
this is one minus one overran times one times one transpose what
so that's
ends up one transpose one and so the equals zero
so it's gone now space the constant i can vector now that's important
run out of space
that's important
going back to this equation hear
so if i print postmultiply this equation by the centering matrix age
what i get is
times the deed center distance matrix age
is equal to
okay so the premultiply on this diet isn't gonna do anything
but the postmultiply
on the one transpose is gonna give me zero
so is
we had some technical problems
which now so so
the result of the
introduction to
this is
is of the part
a very young girl who
is one
forces in this field
she was not see in normal
two thousand should be could be
group leader of opposition
i grew in the and
the most of the men
but the problems
so i don't think any more
time from the truth
thank you
so it's a great pleasure for me to be here so i'm going to
he knew four lectures on nuclear physics
so just to start
these are three
questions that seems to be
quite easy to and to answer
that which are quite tricky
so the you know what is the heaviest nucleus
that do exist on earth
you know how many nuclei do do exist
and what about the shapes of the nuclei
so it is something real meant that can help for
interpreting the experiments or is it completely and that is from the fact that we
are dealing with quantum
just to give you a flavor of nuclear physics this is what we call the
nuclear charts
i will tell you in five minutes that the
a nucleus is made of the proton and neutron
and you you
i have here
in yellow
two hundred ninety one stable nuclei that do exist on paris
but then you see that
two and
artificial nuclei have have been synthesized in the laboratory
and what about predictions so many prediction predicts that more than five thousand
two seven thousand
bound exotic nuclei could be discovered so
at to what we call these three lines here this the limit of existence
this is what we call that they could so a lot of nuclear i have
to be discovered in the future
concerning the shape only is the same just to have the flavor of what is
this theoretical prediction from the ground state nuclear deformation
so this is predicted by what we call the hartree fock bogoliubov method
which is a mean field based approach i will explain that in the second course
just to know it's what we call microscopic approach where the basic ingredients are the
nucleons proton and neutron
and the interaction so do not consider macroscopic through
but really consider the nucleons as a basic ingredient
and and these are the results
and you have here is the number of protons here the number of neutrons and
you have these mean deformation better here but i mean information
and you see that for great color you have only a few nuclei
that are predicted to be spherical so these are very cold
this correspond to what
you will learn
there are magic numbers
twenty twenty eight fifty
eighty to one hundred twenty six
make sure here you have
they form prolates nuclei
and on a few number of nuclei
light and heavy one hour
predicted to be oblate
so now the idea of a few of my lectures so first we talk about
some features about the nucleus discovery radius binding energy
lifetime storage activity
and applications of nuclear physics
then second course will be devoted to the modeling of the nucleus
i that what we call the liquid drop so benefit concert and the nucleus is
equal chance liquid drop
it's the macroscopic approach
that gives the was feature of the nuclei
two other approaches
she more than i mean field which are because competing approaches
then i will give you many examples of recent studies that have made all the
were some adherents
so concerning these exotic nuclei so all these new experiments or calculations concerning
these new nuclear that are newly synthesized
concerning isomer
they are in the nuclei in many metastable states that do exist
so they are very interesting to know about the
the physics
ship systems so there are some nuclei where different states are obtained
and seems to correspond to different shape of the nuclei
and concerning to
and then the last
course will be devoted to the description of the fission process
because many progress has been made recently concerning this subject
concerning some features including
so you may know that the structure of the atom was first brought in the
beginning of the twentieth century by russir fold
so in this experiment you had this rule
frightened of of alpha particles with radioactive decay of radium
that was collimated and that was directed into a sheet of very thin
gold five
then after clustering
these particles were detected here on the screen
this is that some back here
and i will show you that unexpected results demonstrated the existence of the atomic nuclei
because before the this experiment people thought that all the alpha particles should be
if elected only by if you read
but the observed particles that were deflected back and was angles much larger than ninety
so the rest of fraud after this experiment is interpreted that
in the fact that an was almost empty
except here of scattering center
containing most of the part of the
this is what we call the atomic nuclei
nuclear physics dealing with the thing here
is higher than a certain level
the bones
will break
one animal
not to break its bones when the math goes up by a certain factor is
a factor of four
in order for bowlers not to break
the square was also go up by a factor of four that's the key argument
in this case you really have to think that through careful
therefore i would argue
the mass
must be proportional
the square this is the breaking arg
now compare these two
the mass is proportional to the length of the femur
the power three
into the thickness of the femur to the power to
the thickness of the people he worked to the power to must be proportional to
the length l
and therefore the thickness of the femur
must be proportional
the output power we
very interesting
what is this result
telling you
it tells you
and if i have to animals
and one is ten times larger than the other
as is ten times larger
the length of the
leg ten times larger
that this
the thickness of
the film more
thirty five four
because it is helpful to our half if i were to compare models was analysis
elephant is about a hundred times larger in size
for the length of the femur of the elephant behind hundred the times larger than
that of models but the thickness of the more would have to be
thousand times
they have convinced galileo galilei
that's the reason why
the largest
animals as large as the eye because
clearly if you increase the mass
now comes the time
that the thickness of the bones
the same as the length of the bones
we all made of bone that is biologically
not feasible soda is a limit somewhere
set by this
scaling law
i really i want to bring this to test
after all i broke my grandmother
statement to test the why bringing galileo a statement with us
and so
i went to
where they have a beautiful collection
of famous
and i
ask them for the femur of a record and horse
record is this big
about four times bigger
the length
one of the few more of course must be about four times the length
of the record
i will not surprise
i measured the thickness
and i said to my
the length is four times higher
the thickness
has to be
eight times higher if this holds
and what i'm going to court for you you will see that shortly
is the divided by l
missus out
and that of course must be proportional
alpha the problem i think one l year
if i compare the horse
and i compared the recall
i would argue that
divided by the length of the femur
before the horse
must be the square root of four
as much as that of the recall
so i was very anxious to that
and i did that
and i show you the results
my first
we see their d of l explain to you why i prefer that
and you see the link
you see here to recall
you see the horse
and if you look carefully
then the deal fell for the horses only about one and half times larger than
the raccoon
well i wasn't too disappointed
one and a half is not but is in the right direction horse clearly have
larger value for p of l
i realized i needed more data
so i went back to our i said well
i need a small animal also maybe maybe rats maybe miles
and they said OK
they gave me
three more about
they gave me an antelope which is actually a bit larger than the recall
and they gave me awesome
and they gave me
a month
is the
of the
and the world
year is the one
one of the
here is the one
of the opossum
no you won't believe this
this is so
there is the money
isn't that beautiful
he's about to leave he knew little more
and now it is
and i am
i'm a lot
and if you look at what would look like
what is
i was shocked
i was really shocked
because look
or fifty times larger in size than the model
the difference in db is only a factor of two
i expected
more like factor
and so in d of hell where expect the factor of seven i only see
so i said to myself oh my goodness why didn't they i ask them for
an elephant
the real clincher would be dead because
if that goes way of scale maybe we can still rescue
statement by galileo galilei
and so i went back
and they said OK we'll give you
the theme of an elephant they also gave me one of the most believe it
or not i think they want to get rid of me by that time to
the rank of u
is the the more of an elephant
and then measure the
the length
and the thickness
usually this is represent the ideas presented so that when x is x is what
i don't know why i still very high dimensional vector giving an image
so it is around is random vector because we can assume that you know if
a if we posted the random vector then it means that we elect to looking
at the class of all images in the set in a certain environment
people talk about for example in natural images which means that you know if i
just if i take the images that i see seen my ordinary arrive or perhaps
that you know came and so in in their ordinary lives then you know that
that is the probability distribution for in the image space and that's a random vector
of natural
but what people
you hear people usually decompose this
this linear transformation like this so that you multiply each of the columns of y
by the corresponding element of this
because the point is that this is called the mixing matrix they and they are
now part of images or they are but i mean they were there in the
same space as images
so you will see that each image is represented as the sum of certain kinds
elements which will call them features
o it while mathematically of the basis
so this is this kind of ideas have been used in image processing for a
long time it what people do is they choose these basis vectors using some
some nice mathematical theories so they choose fixed basis vectors using the mathematical theory for
example if you use mathematics for its use fourier analysis you would see that well
this basis vectors should be signed sinusoids are called cosine functions
and the related that you can't use the discrete cosine transformation basis functions which are
very similar of if you if you go a bit further in the history i
mean if you go a bit forward in the history of mathematics you will find
things like wavelet all gabor functions to be used as
but another question that we post when we do i see a and b and
sparse coding modelling is that's what are actually the best basis vectors
again this has to be defined in some way so the idea is that what
the statistically best basis vectors for a set of basis vectors they have some nice
properties of their own but there's no reason to think that they would be really
statistically the best basis vectors
so it's just an illustration of what kind of basis vectors are typically used for
this because i transformed vectors so they are two different from
from sinusoidal functions and here are some way that basis functions which have the property
of being usually very localized so you get the idea is that great is in
each of these small so we know we are modelling only very small patches of
images in all of this size and each of these
but she here is one basis vector where
great is zero and black and white than positive or negative values for the for
the coefficients so that the nice thing in this in this case
kind of representation that's the way i actually images and conditional
so we go got to the idea of sparse coding which
we will see later is almost the same thing as i see it
but sparse coding and decided to do sparseness were proposed in vision research
before ICA invented actually
at least in seventy two although some there was an influential papers on the subject
and maybe was actually
now before that
so we inside when we go above i see if you can say that sparse
is actually one form of nongaussianity
that is typical of natural signals especially in natural images
higher order structure means something that goes exactly the high you when we talk about
higher order we can refer for example to cumulants in the sense that it is
something that is not in the covariance
well actually highly organised is is widely used but it actually has many different meanings
of maybe who wish for which we've talked about that
so what what's past this means is that variable is active only area where active
means that is significantly different from zero
so the idea is that here we have some random samples from a gaussian variable
so the time structure is not of importance actually there is no time structure is
are just random samples from a gaussian distribution
but you see
you can see the difference to this
a random sample from a sparse
well the mean the median is well the mean what is given here by the
horizontal line and actually also the variances of these two distributions are exactly the same
so that but this difference
is is therefore difference in nongaussianity
well what you see is that in the sparse case where you have sometimes very
large values much larger than what you have in the gaussian case but then on
the other hand much of the time you are extremely close to zero
so close to zero that you can't really
see the difference
so on the
in other words if you take the histogram of that of the be estimated you
get the PDF of the kind of response variable it should be something where you
have a high peak at zero
and our set of
solutions to second order homogeneous differential equations the one we've seen just before is of
dimension two as well
and i said two of our
is is actually of infinite dimension
some subspace that may be useful are hyperplanes and they are defined as subspaces of
of the original vector space
which have a separate elementary of dimension exactly one
so in rd
any subspace of dimension d minus one is the height of the tree
the reason why we define hyperplanes through their supplement there is a that if if
you have a separate set is infinite dimension at the beginning
then the appropriate and still has an infinite dimension so you can't really say the
hyperplane dimension
minus one
the dimension of the original space three that's what you think about
now there is the basis of of his face is generative and linearly independent i
mean subspace
they all have exactly the same cardinal
and they use the unique decomposition for any x in this subspace
in rd we've seen that the
vectors there
those vectors there are two you the basis
in know in two of the issue of two pi so the set of functions
that are square in trying to go to war in this interval zero
he o two pi
then you can show that the set of
function cosine and t and sign to fall
possible integers
is the basis as well
so that will tell you that if you have a square integrable function
on you to find and you can extract decomposes as as such as some
where the nndm are unique coefficients
so that enables you to see a function as a sum of
signs here
of cosines and sines for which you know the from the properties right those those
of simple functions which you can see really easy
what's next
it in our tool for example we talked about projection just before and we also
talk about the project so
actually the next question is that if you have such an composition how are you
going to find the m in the end
right how are you going to find the coefficients
in front of your disease vectors
and so an easy way to do that is that is when you're vector space
as on top of having the addition and multiplication motives here
also has the product
in our these you're the use of the product produced in before
and it's going to euclidean norm in rd
and you can see the dot product has
a measure of how
of what is the angle between x tool two vectors x and y
OK so
if you have a vector space with the product than any subspace of it has
a unique orthogonal supplementary which means
is that the
two sets s and it's also one of their
where which means that the disagreement areas this the spatial properties that if x is
in s and and y is in the supplementary then you are you automatically have
that the dot product is equal to zero
on that too
elements of s and f of the orthogonal
OK so that private beings you
you should think about this as the two vectors being also one of
and so on
now that you know if you have a unique supplementary then what you can do
is that it is easy the decompose
vectors and you have relations between the norm of the different parts of your vectors
and that's what's written here
if you have two separate there's spaces then
the norm of x is the squared is equal to the number of
it's part on on the subspace as implicit support on the the wall space
which is only saying that for example
the norm of this vector is the square of the slang this ranks right
this ranks is
this would be the the projection of a on your subspace
this would be the projection of a on your six space is orthogonal
so the norm of this vector square this vector square
i don't know this was that's your particular into right
i just remind you what it all means of their
and i'm not going to tell you again what is
so again as an oil spill also referred in only if they are the products
is zero and
so the last efficient mission i want to give is what is a hilbert space
so here space is a vector space
where you have the dot product
and additionally this basis closed for the norm that is used by the dot product
so again in two of our
such as the stress it's a vector space is the product of two functions is
the in the integration of the product of two functions
and these units and all which is the norm which he
the integration of squaring the square root of the interval of of square
and if you
again the fact that the space is closed means that if you have a sequence
of vector in h that converges tenure
sure that the limit is in it as well
so once you have your for going OTT you may look for so basis
and obviously usual visiting our these are not small enough so normal basis basis is
also normally if the dot product between two any two vector businesses is either one
we obtain this as the best horses so this classifies this at the wrong place
at the wrong but it is much better than this one because this is what
misclassified is too big
do this several times now increasingly for those
do this again
then we chose this hypothesis
then this one k
in in the end you just add those policies and you see some hard by
the colour you see essentially how positive the region came many put the threshold theorem
and that would mean this one here so this is the decision
OK this is just a linear combination of these
especially structure that functions
OK this upon the decision boundary
OK so
in know somebody for binary classification we have the hypotheses we have this hypothesis class
and we positive class and b essentially based on which can generate these functions of
the positive class
and we have these weights alpha one twelve t t is always the number of
so in the classification output is simply the majority of all these things forces invaded
majority so simply take this summer and then put it put this sign signals
this here
OK so how can you find the hypotheses and also the right
so there are several methods one this the first one thing was supporting the filtering
later there was a method by trying to ninety five forty by majority only prime
came up with something he called bagging similar
but the it's always constant and then later ninety six there was adaboost so like
ten years old
so the idea of boosting the training was to run the weak learner on different
so that was the idea of having different some examples so he generated they generated
different versions of training sets of points and OCR the just generated different versions of
let us by rotating or something and then they had just modification of the training
set and and then they looked at
they use the current function to filter out some of the
examples and then the combined somehow complexlly
to show the
performance guarantee on the other hand required knowledge on the performance of the baseline beginning
similar was foreseen by majority proposed ninety five he the main difference was that they
are linearly combined so the combination with simple but all the required knowledge on the
performance of the learner
prime proposed ninety six bagging and that is
quite a different idea but it looks quite similar
so and the idea is to run the base learner on different versions of the
training set so one simply creates bootstrap replicates of the training set one simply with
one sample from the training set with replacement so once takes subset essentially training set
and runs the base learner and that someone that way we get different hypotheses
but here the
i alpha t this property was simply one over t so these based these functions
simply averaged OK so there is no adaptation really going on
and and we can actually show its
quite i mean behaving quite differently from from adaboost
this is not emphasizing the difficult examples
i was not posting
i'm showing you
OK so this is actually the other side so that is the one which generated
these pictures both
OK let's go through this in the detail
so we i mean this is the algorithm which we are talking about four OK
so we have an examples so
x x one y and y one two x and y and n to be
have this rating on these examples and initially this weighting is just uniform every example
has the same weight
OK and is illustrated you OK so we have a look at t iterations capability
iterations and we have the the basis which we call
so the first step we call this base learner and we tried to get a
function which somehow considers this distribution and we obtain process that classifies points into a
plus or minus one simplicity
then we can simply compute the weighted error epsilon t that that's just some
all those rates of points which are misclassified case x h not htx and is
not equal to y
this should be smaller than high otherwise it will be when it OK
then compute the hypothesis may so we get this function here offered he's just this
quantity here and essentially this is large this weighted error is small
OK to give more weight to the function which is which is good i mean
which is classifying web
in the end we update the example distribution is the most important the most important
step you
OK so let's have a look at that so so the example distribution
so the weight of the example in the t plus first iteration is simply the
rate of the end the example in the teeth iterations times e to the minus
alpha t y and htxn OK so this is a y and h two x
that is minus one if the example is mis classified because then the the science
don't match and plus one it's correctly classified OK so and we simply when it's
correctly classified then this e to the minus something up it is positive OK so
this is download it and if this is negative here then this term here is
something which is large and one case it upgraded and we divided by the sum
of all those
so at the distribution so this sums up to one
OK we iterate this several times
and in every iteration we we generate one of these functions here and then combine
them in the end with with with some
any christian for that to be
it should be very clear
so what are so we use the use the space
we have to assume something on the space
so at least we should have some which is what this page should
so it should somehow
generate simple hypotheses so that means it should be used as a small base hypothesis
because the most amazing factor two there when they happen to be
so now it is all this is really easy this is a one square
he was an
so one
is the square root of n
so the cost that i'm getting over here l one class l two or l
one is the square n plus an over ten which is again and i get
to read
search cost
and caring about the costs and here because it will matter in a moment
two square to that
not caring about the additive constant for the multiplicative constant i care about
that seems
good we started with a linked list that search in
and time data and time per operation now we have two linked lists search and
data retention time
seems pretty good this is what the structure looks like we have
return guys here
this is in n
the local line
and we have one express stop which represents that then we have another it and
values in the
local line we have one
express stopped represents that these two are aligned
and so on
but that's in there
OK so they're each of these trunks has length through and and the number of
representatives up here is greater than the number of express stops discriminative that so clearly
things are balanced now i search for most worried about up here that i search
one of these was from elsewhere that
for every search takes them two
what should we do next
it's again ignore insertions and deletions i wanna make searches fastica scriven is not so
far as we know
more lines
what's at super express line
with that another linked list
this was to
one two three
so we started with the sorted linked lists
then we went to two
this gave us to swearing
i one three
sorted linked lists
any guesses what the running time might be
this is just guesswork don't think
from two square and you would go to
thank you
two square to force through and that's on the right track
both the constant and the rule change
but not quite sufficiently
three times the cube good
intuition is very helpful here
the matter whether the answers intuition
now you can prove that it's not so hard
you know have three lists and what you want to balance are
the length of the topless the ratio between the top two layers and the ratio
between the bottom two lists
see what these three
two multiply out
because that i mean
top times the ratio times the ratio that's legal and
and so that's where you get the cube of each of these should be equal
this that because the cost is the sum of those three things
he said each of the collaborative and there are three
check it at home
if you want
to be more sure
obviously we want a few more so think about k sorted lists k
so this will be a k times the case through the
will be just that are now
so what should we set k two
i don't want the exact minimum just
what's a good value
OK and
and it's kind of nice because and through and is just one
it's now that's and so
this is why i care about the lead constant because it's
going to grow as i had more or less
was the biggest reasonable value of k that i could use
log n
because how k out out there certainly don't is more than one and so on
log n times the log inference is a little hard to draw
now it is the log in through the event
that's the hero
he about
what is the log entry of n minus two
one of these good questions whose answers
the the definition of a word
OK is and so the one to reward and
however the definition of having a power
in the b
it's like
two the power of the game
so this is
so the log n
but hello again
which is
if you can get at this point
log entries and minus two is zero my favorite answer
this is too
so this whole thing is too long and
pretty nifty so you can be a little fancier sweet this little bit but to
log is planning good for me
clearly don't want to use a more less
log and la sounds pretty good i get now
logarithmic search
let's cheque i mean we said did this all intuitively let's draw what the list
looks like
but work
i gonna region
this example shows
you have to also
so let's redesign the new york city subway system
i want to leave or three blank lines up here
so far
this cameras now
i don't
so we're not want to change the focal lines
it would be nice
example of uniform univariate entities like what like like explanation is it is all of
those things it is so what other people have been talking about this is all
about multivariate statistics which is again cause much more complicated than one-dimensional statistical model
and then i talk about baseball component analysis which is some kind of ancestor we
independent component analysis and then of the very important principle of statistical independence was when
we talk about independent component analysis it is not perhaps it's certainly very surprising that
statistical independence will be
many imports
so just some basic notation so we have a random variables random variables are variables
will take random values or something like that well there i think some somewhat more
rigorous definitions available but
i didn't forget them so random variables
the distribution of the random variable
he is often described by a density function
well in in that case which is this possible in the case where where we
have a random variables which take which they collect
all kinds of values on the real axis for example we are not going to
talk about anything that takes discrete values in this in this lecture so it is
no we are never going to have something like the probability that a random variable
equals zero or the typical one everything is always continuous valued and actually based in
basically all cases these random variables can take all values on the real axis
and so
then in that case we can express the probability distribution function using the density function
and then of in particular we will be talking about random vectors which is simply
that we have a large number of of
random random variables
so it's like kind of a circle with multi dimensional random variable but usually random
variables on the variable here is restricted to one dimensional
and yes again you can then
you can express the distribution of
continuous valued random variables using a probability distribution function
well here
michael what gives has shows how
the distribution of the density function is related to the cumulative distribution function which is
well well-known stuff in in basics basics probability theory but well let's
going to that
well after this stuff these things like densities and so on certainly the most fundamental
thing in probability theory and statistics is the expectation
is a station
well in the in the basic case we talk about the mean
which is the expectation of a random it's
and while there are different kinds of technologies available but then people often talk about
expectation when they talk about some kind of the expectation of some of some function
of the size of the space of this random vector
the expectations are computed basically by an integral where you have well first this function
of x and then multiplied by
the probability density function and then well that's integrated all over the n dimensional space
as of the most interesting expectations in addition to me
correlations well well-backed licence so most interesting ones but let's say the most basic ones
actually i see one of the points in ICA is that is that these correlations
are just like the first step in analyzing random variables or random vectors and you
should not be just using the correlations
i have to explain what is actually the mean
of correlations
well correlations basically
tell you something about linear dependencies of its variables
so to say that we want to predict
x two
by x one
so this is a classic expressed as a linear regression model that i'm sure you've
all seen somewhere we have coefficients a here
and then we have some kind of noise or is it just to this trend
so the point is that
it tells us
well it's this
these are called the correlation between x one and x two well if it's if
it's positive and large
in some sense then it tells you that that's that when that's x two in
the same way follows x y
so that's when x one is large in this one will be large in the
next one is small this one will be be large now it turns out that
if we normalize these variables properly
then we will see
actually if we normalize them so if we normalized so that the variances of x
one and x two
both equal to one
well just
for those of you who don't remember i will i will remind you of the
definition of variance which is which is a measure of the the spread of the
random variable
so now what happens is that under these conditions this equals the correlation
it it equals expectation x
one times x two
is is that the hybrid is and is not in issue the book the different
chapters written by different authors so
again as above that's well worth looking at
more recent book by jensen is also very good and neapolitan book something else that
i recommend as well
he had a very good but back in the nineteen sixties which had been out
of print but i think the idea are this new book
nine times of books cover graphical models and variational methods from a learning perspective machine
and perspective there are there are very few
this is the first one is an edited book is the proceedings of the NATO
ASI edited by michael jordan was originally published by clue
but for those of you not multi millionaires you'll be pleased to know that it
was republished by MIT press in paperback and you can afford it for much less
than the price of family car so
i recommend the paperback version from MIT for that one
so that's an edited book so there are some tutorial type chapters in the beginning
of a whole bunch of research papers but it's it's it's very nice book this
sort of snapshot
this estimator workshop which might organised was actually very good because he deliberately bought together
twenty people from machine learning community twenty people from graphical models community and i was
lucky enough to be to get to go
and so i met all these people from this new community that i had no
idea that community existed and whole of stuff about graphical models simple this is really
interesting and really useful so might a fantastic job bringing those communities together
this book by brendan frey i think is really sort of his phd thesis is
published by
the MIT press it's quite tutorial and really really quite good so given that there
aren't any sort of great books around on this field i would recommend reading the
michael jordan himself the last few years has been writing a book i'm not sure
what his title going to be something
something that for models in the title
i think when this book is published it will be the sort of definitive book
on graphical models but you know textbooks take a long time to write
i think most of it exists in draft format i've no idea when it will
actually appear in print but do watch out for him but he is deaf to
get it will be very very good and
it's really quite introductory but also because all the way through to some very advanced
david mackay's book is not really biographical models or variational methods i think you know
touches on both but it's just a very good up-to-date book in the field so
i mentioned it as well
and then
three modesty to the wind
mention also writing a new book myself this but will have a chapter on graphical
models the chapter on variational methods and all of material that i'm presenting in here
is taken from the book in in the sentence
i'm not publishing
publishing with springer but even so i've got them to write into the contract that
the price will be kept low so that a maximum price and the maximum annual
increase the price of the locked into price furthermore more so six hundred pages hardback
it'll be in full color
it should be sort of student price not to not lower-priced
and then lots of great stuff to go with it
and this is the further from the front cover a pattern you can see if
you can recognise
OK so let's start to
talk about graphical models
so the idea of graphical models is to augment probability theory with some pictures
so everything that we're going to do with graphical models we could do without the
pictures we could
just take the
sum and product rule of probability
and just manipulate expressions using those rules just
large sheets of paper
grinding through all the mathematics
but we're going to
i have little
pictorial representations of probability distributions and that's going to give us in practice lot of
most people so perhaps not stuff interesting but i think most of us find drawing
pictures of things helps if know to explain the big pile of complicated mathematics
and so on
the drawing these pictures will
first of all was new insights into models that we already know and love
and that's already very useful
you can help motivate new models will see you
once you understand how models are represented graphically immediately say
well if this only depends on that can i just add another link to the
graph matching linked to the graph specifies certain things in terms of probability distributions tells
you how to construct the model of trying to give you some examples of this
how easy it is to go from
to take a model and then also the variance of that model
according to the particular application you have in mind so it's a wonderful life of
generating new models
and even more than that so said already
it gives this graph based algorithms for doing
calculation and even computation
so i think it's a very powerful framework i think anybody machine learning should really
understand this
this the basics of the field
so this hopefully is
painfully familiar to everybody
so the probability theory these two
very simple innocuous looking equations that's really all we need all we can do is
take the sum and product rule probability applied inconsistently to to learning problems
so just by
manipulating the product rule of course we obtain
bayes theorem the normalisation in bayes theorem
can be expressed the denominator expressed in terms of marginalization of the numerator so that
is equivalent
so you take the sum product rule probability now start to draw pictures of down
so we try to begin with directed
try to motivate the directed graph by considering this simple case we've got joint
probability distribution over three variables x y and z
we can simply apply
the chain rule of probability
apply the proper probability in the sort of in succession so p of x
y and z
we can write as p of x
the same color right so i don't know if the example that i did have
passenger being read or not but in general the passenger is whatever color
it one of the destination it wants to go to so the yellow circle wants
to go to the yellow square like that and if you do this if you
figured out probably if you did it twice get it but it turns out not
and in fact it's really interesting to see what normal is that to this kind
of very clever exploration is not is not the norm i think people and definitely
not in the program to talk about either so even the people in the model
did can significantly better in some ways than learning how we're going to tell you
about so
they get stuck more learning algorithms lisa ones and i tell you about are very
effective at actually figuring out what they have been tried yet and try new things
people i got into this mode where they would they would decide what it is
that they wanted to decide how it was going to work and they would just
stick to that
matter how long it was data so good so that is why do we play
this game other than it was sort of a fun way to break the ice
then i would say that this is an example of reinforcement learning environment so basically
you had task there was some kind of reward signal that you're trying to get
which was finishing the game you had actions that you could use that left out
of grade b and it possibly a sequence of actions was necessary to get higher
award in this case you need to get all through the sequence of steps to
win and you have some kind of state representation of some kind of information about
what the current state is on which to base your decisions
so there's other problems that fit into this setting as well this is an example
that we played with in the lab a couple years ago where we've got an
eyeball robot and what it's trying to do is decide it's just two choices it's
got a and b which in this case correspond to turning a little bit left
and turning on the right
and it's goal
in this case instead of dropping off the passenger was making visual contact with the
pink ball
OK so in some ways very simple task but otherwise it's real right it's actually
moving around in physical space and implementing these things it's not some kind of you
know theoretical data structure rather theoreticians in the robot but it's actually taking actions in
the real world and that's the data that's it using for its decision making
so again this is this is another
example that shows the different elements of the reinforcement learning problem maybe not in commercially
significant problem the turning around to see the pink ball problem i think is well
solved by the technology at the moment but it has all the pieces in and
it's and it was is
good first to experiment with with using noisy data as opposed to the standard simulated
very clean data
so when one is trying to trying to create a reinforcement learning system that's going
to solve one of these task i would say that there are three major pieces
at least in the model based perspective there's these three major pieces that have to
be addressed but the first one is using the knowledge that is gained from experience
r and applying it to new situations generalizing it so that actually applies to situations
that the decision-maker has necessarily seen before and that's really the learning problem that that's
the core problem in our community we have lots of different technologies that we can
use to solve problems like this
on the other side of things is what is not just about learning about the
environment it's about acting well in the environment and to do that the agent has
carry out sequential decision making access to take steps in the world
so so when we were playing on little taxi game
o it's called it's called the tax applied by the was introduced by time t
check a number of years ago
like three hundred some my papers i was able to find that the talk about
the problem because
anyway so all
what are the actions that you took to give you any kind of immediate
four didn't win the game because you chose left at a certain point with only
meeting together all those actions they got you to the final and so in this
particular case dealing with this delayed gratification is the planning problem it's sequencing actions to
achieve some kind of goal or map you maximizing water minimizing cost and that's actually
very well studied problem is what to get these two nice fairly well studied problems
that the piece that kind of use together and gives reinforcement learning its own the
problem to focus on is how do you put those two together how do you
do action choices in planning so that you get the right information out of the
learning so that you can apply that do well on the planet so solving this
exploration exploitation
balance is
one of the problems that makes reinforcement learning i think a lot of fun to
think about a lot of fun to work on and it's really significant a lot
of these problems are difficult to solve if the agent does figure out how to
explore and gain the data they need
all right so that the the formal model
that underpins a lot of work in reinforcement learning is the markov decision process here
this was introduced a number of years ago actually did not go over line said
i do people like me we devoted our lives to build and i don't think
that's quite true but the sense in which it is true is the introduced these
models a lot of what goes into solving reinforcement learning problems is about
solving what's known as the bellman equation this this q equation here at the bottom
so to just to set up for you imagine that the environment consists of some
member states called and in this case some set of actions that the agent gets
to choose among some discount factor which is controlling how important is it to get
reward now versus reward in the future the discount factor is very close to one
then words matter all throughout time it's the discount factor is closer to zero then
there was no really significant but you know who cares about later leaders later
i mean step time city the agent informed about its current state is what's the
state of the environment and gets to choose an action
from that it receives payoff or city
and the expected value which is determined by what's called the reward function reinforcement function
and then there's the transition to NXT in that transition it is governed by this
this t function the transition function which says that the probability that if you're in
some state s st and action eighty the probability and the next in status prime
is that expression
schematically we've got an agent environment having this conversation back and forth environments is the
state the aging gives the action the environment gives back toward the next day and
the game continues
now how do you solve a problem like this how do you decide what actions
take if you know the transition and reward function then this bellman equation here i
have one point
call this equation i should produce the point right to this equation right here gives
us a way of determining what to actually do so what this says years we're
going to determine this this thing called the q function that the q value of
being in some state s and taking some action a is
semantically what it is is how much reward you get aging get if it starts
off in state s choose action a and from then on does whatever the the
optimal thing is to do whatever maximizes expected reward
and we're going to move to compute that is by saying well we can get
that by saying what's going to get some immediate reward determined by the reward function
and then it's going to make a transition to a new state
and the transition probability that that state as prime is t s a s prime
want to get that new state is going to choose the optimal action
but in this case it's for pretending that we know what this q function is
is whichever
action in that state has the highest value
OK so
for now we look over all possible next states this is the weighted by the
this is still to be found out there on how to do this
i talked to little about event type hierarchy
you can see here that ontology reuse is being done there is a class event
which is a subclass of the dolce ontology event where we create events for the
domains that are needed like facebook event at facebook status feed which is very simple
hierarchical and hierarchy me and this is all RDF so everyone can go and extend
on each of these branches
rdf introduction here you can see
event example
in the format that came up with
so we created a system already to process these events on the fly in real
time by looking at RDF event properties
and this is how
we currently formalising these properties so the subject of the event is an IDE
and it's typed saying it's the average temperature event having a start time and end
time using the well-known XML datatypes this event can have members so it's linking
two other events so immediately we're combining
real time data with historic events which happened earlier
and this event has its source
which is
could be a device that could be service and this event has stream this is
the the interesting URL if you do reference this you will get more events of
the same type
which are happening right now so this is like a subscription referencing this URL
and then there are some payload data from arbitrary namespaces like the pedia talking about
the city of nice in france and its average temperature of twenty five degrees
and being
being correlated
with this measurement so the temperature of twenty five is only specific for this event
you won and not for the next obviously so this is a data modelling issue
here that we're not stating that a nice always has temperature twenty five but this
is just one measurement of along stream of endless data
what is important here is that an event ontology taxonomy of types is used
where average temperature event is inheriting from an upper class of events which gives us
the timestamps for example and and which can be specialized these events support interval based
modeling so i can have events which are just defined on time point
like a tweet
it is
posted a fixed time but i can also define longo ongoing events like i one
discover the
i don't know the average twitter frequency for keyword x over the last ten minutes
and this event should not have just one timestamp but this event should be modelled
over the last ten minutes because if this event is again going into computation in
another event pattern i need to take care that nested operators will not to use
these events in the wrong order
so overlapping intervals are dangerous way of
breaking the temporal semantics so this is why these interval based events are useful way
of fixing your notion of what sequence which two events are strictly in sequence and
which are not
many events
link to each other so events that average temp vendors linking to to all the
events and we are linking to the stream
and we chose a nice name of event processing dot org which is not project
relevance so we're hoping will live quite awhile longer than the research project in which
we're doing this for we're trying to create an ontology here to be reused for
event processing systems so we're trying to do this in a sustainable modelling way
the mail this was about events
and next thing is how do a query those events how do i write a
to combine
two or more of these events
the query language should obviously fit the RDF data model
and we want to carry real time and historic events
like also supported by this paper in the event processing conference this year and we
want to support typical temporal operators because events are always about timestamps about happening when
here alan in nineteen eighty one proposed most simple relationships with all possible relationships between
two and a lot of time and we want to support that for a minute
so this is where event processing sparql comes in you've heard a lot about sparql
the sparql protocol and RDF query language for static data and we're extending the syntax
of sparql so i'm very sorry not everything in real time can be done in
the same syntax so these are not strictly compatible but we're trying to model this
so that everyone who can do sequels or can do sparql will somehow find this
familiar so we extend the language by these temporal operators such as sequence or temporal
overlap which is called equals and time windows like a number of events inside
the range of ten minutes for example
this was first discussed in that paper and we extended to support more expressive events
which i'm going to detail and to use the useful function from x path
and two
deal with real time and historic parts you can see a rough patch of what
such core example could look like so we
using the constructor dialect
where we create a new triple which is the complex event
and we have lots of triples going in which is the simple events so there's
streams of events coming in
and this is the output of the query
there is a real time part
which is denoted by the event keywords
and by these temporal operators that are newly introduced
and there is a historic part which is a standard sparql so here you can
updates from
from your twitter feeds
with fixed data from the local triple store so so you can have in one
thank you
hello everybody it's a pleasure to be here
i haven't been in jerusalem in thirty years
it's changed quite a bit of feminism change quite a bit in thirty years it's
quite amazing and when i was here in jerusalem the last time thirty years ago
i stayed in the belgian house actually lived in the house
it's delightful to be here again we have
we're having a meeting on complexity and it's a very broad meaning on complexity and
broad enough that they've asked me to give a talk so my subject is most
of you are concerned with physics economics biology you know
more practical kinds of complexity
i'd like to talk about conceptual complexity complexity of ideas
and the main application
of these concepts are is actually and metamathematics it's in talking about incompleteness and the
limits of the limits of possibilities of of pure for pure reason
that's the sort of an unusual area to complexity
but but it's there
so i think complexity is very basic concept
you know normally people think fundamental physics is either very small right
particle physics high-energy physics are also very large cosmology and in the middle we have
complex systems like us to represent information and computer and interestingly enough also in pure
mathematics in the world of pure ideas there's a lot of complexity that's my
my subject and also i decided that message so that i have to take home
messages for you too
things take on one is that message that pure mathematics contains irreducible infinite complexity or
and also that the complexity of course when it becomes a successful subject you start
looking back precursors
and i would like to let you know that light and it's in my opinion
is an important name
in complexity theory this may come as a surprise
so i'd like to tell you some of that story today
and i have two other lectures later this week
so this is the prehistory of complexity and the way i heard about this was
reading herman viola
is a was mathematicians student of hilbert and mathematical physicist hermann von has a number
of books on mathematics the number of books on physics and two books on philosophy
and his smaller velocity is called the open world and they were lectures he gave
in nineteen thirty two years
university in new haven
and there
talks about how important an idea of leiden it's about complexity is he says it's
an essential
concept complexity in the philosophy of science in understanding what causality is or what law
of of nature is or what all a of physics is
and the way the term about what it is very dramatic this he could
this idea of light member formulated like this is a
if you allow arbitrarily complicated laws
then the concept of law becomes vacuous because there's always along this is about it
you see that what you're trying to distinguish between data that follow the law and
data that is lawless
so you want to understand what is this concept of the law what does it
mean to say how can we distinguish a world which follows LA
from the world which doesn't follow law
what so what is a law what does it mean to say that something about
law and what happens is if you allow arbitrary complicated laws there's always the law
and and then the notion of laws
it becomes meaningless
so i think that's a good point now how does
how does life put it like it's put it a little differently like it discusses
in you know most alignments are very interesting man most of whose work was not
published during his lifetime it was found long after his death in his private papers
or their letters to other intellectuals like this has a a a text called the
school the metaphysics
which is not the name the landscape he didn't given name this was an editor
who founded more than a century after died and let's throw the disc the metaphysical
sixteen eighty six
and the items five and six paragraphs five and six of the the metaphysics lightning
talks about complexity he really talks about simplicity in french
i speak a little french it's this french is very close to modern french
unfortunately it's not in latin i don't know any latin you can actually go and
look at this text in french the paragraphs five and six on complexity and the
light is not actually use the word complexity but he don't use the word simplicity
and for complexity he says for composing
which i think is
you know the opposite of sam
the sampler is for composite so that is
translated as complexity
but if you look at the original text i think it's important to say well
that's what is so
so one idea of alignments
the idea of life it is is is very simple and here how it goes
let's take a piece of paper and with a quill pen just put splattered with
things so you have a finite set of points
on the plane on this sheet of paper which are your experimental data
and now the question is what is it seems me to say that these points
follow or
let's go to the next valence girth
and cages low valence that sometimes called degree
four valency which we call it fearless
so what is of valence
o vertex valence of the vertex the number
of edges
that incident with that vertex where more precisely or
intuitively what we do
think of
during the little circles
around each vertex and then just count the number of edges emanating from the vertex
and cutting that
there's the valence
four simple graphs there is no problem with that
but if the graph is not simple
we may have problems that may show you here
how we call that
in this case
for instance in this case
four vertex one
according to this rule
the very
it would be
one two
four five
so the valence of one five
but we not
interested in this
situation right now because we're talking about
simple graph
lowercase delta g denotes the minimum of valence
upper case
that the g
you knows the maximal balance
over graphs
this means for instance in this case the minimum balances to and maximum analysis three
for this
the two values is the minimum and maximum the same
this means that all the edges of the same
and the graph in this case is called regular
for k regular
we've seen already some examples of regular graphs
complete graph is regular
cycle is regular
complete bipartite graph is regular if and it was an
other examples which are not regular for instance b and partha advertisements if n is
greater than two complete graphs complete bipartite graph is an different
they are not regular
so one vaillant two valence graphs are very simple
the first example
of let's a nontrivial
regular graphs are trivalent graphs or sometimes called cubic graphs were realistic was three
for instance here we have an example of a trivalent graphs
so each
valence three right
and this for instance in this particular case there's the graph
of the prison
triangular prisms
any questions
OK go
so god
g of g
of graph g
is the number of vertices
of the shortest cycle in g
so if g has no cycles
it's good is infinity
let me
maybe you some examples first
let's look at this
is here
so what would be
because of this graph here
we know what the right of the graph is
maybe this kind of graph
it's bipartite graph
it's a living off of configuration
has it occurred cannot be
must be sixty six
the other
are designed graph
you you get you can do that over the weekend
next family of graphs cages
what is a g cage
it is defined in the following way
we're talking about prevailing graphs of cubic graphs
that has girth g
they have the least number of vertices
among the graphs satisfying conditions one and two
such a graph is called good
so let me in this section
hoping to convince you that this is why there is essentially a goldmine
for two reasons one is
it increases the
so might be surprised advertising so so virtuous cycle
so that the search and i talked about brand that's
and i want to share with you is the results of the study we did
this very interesting
it actually shows me as to what this talk to you about
in this system the
are much more related than anybody
so here is how it goes
this is working with the company direct
people are shown these kinds of on properties like finance yahoo mail my
so imagine what we normally do
which is
if you that
i think you actually ask for example ask questions
you feel it is that you know how to
that's what it is and what is your favourite and these are the objects the
respectable numbers mean
people who so these
people who were in the the members of the police on you
this list
so that's how try to establish because this is the stuff works
but what i'm about to show you
this is good numbers but i'm about to show you actually blows my mind
i'm about to show is we decided to extend this to a bit for
so we have a a group of people who so that we have a group
of people we know that in the absence settlers continued to follow the behaviour of
a week later and see what they want search
so sure if you want to search sixty percent
more likely to search on that category just because they saw the
sixty percent to begin but it gets
forty percent more clicks on algorithmic results
two hundred fifty percent forty nine percent more click-through
on sponsored links that's what makes someone who is
two and a half times more likely to click on
one is sponsored links
because of graphical up to a week before
i don't want anyone in the world basically get ninety one percent
more activity that matters meaning conversions things like that as the
so this is very powerful ever again market
right well i have no idea that i just think about i spend a particular
i k
i don't think about the fact that when i spent i could actually enhance my
spent by a factor of two and
if i just thought about putting up some branding stuff to go with my search
that's not because the data that's what the markets had as it head
companies like extended to benefit a lot because you can you can make whole story
more complete
again all of this is based on the fact that
you can learn lot from the data
so we talk about advertising
after shameless advertising break
we are hiring people
so i going to the outside
if you are interested in your mind
they start to time
this should be
and the social media for the next twenty five
well you know what this means
but basically there is a huge change in the way
something new is happening something very different and actually extremely data mining really
example social media blog
sharing sites like flickr photo social search
i was about
some of these migrants we answers and so forth
web communities groups
the ocean
like youtube
and what's happening is
it's it's a new culture holding it's very compelling this set of new users are
using its
you know a lot about two point all which enables these things cultural participation user-generated
wisdom of the crowds to talk about some of them
and really moving beyond
right in all publishing
which states that if you have
as a strictly positive probability distribution
it's an arbitrary otherwise
probability distribution
the effects of all x
it is
distribution satisfies
the conditional independence statements implied by graph separation in the given graph
then it also factorizes according
what that means
if you have a graph like this
a b
c and d
if i give them
probability distribution
conditional independence statements implied by graph separation you for example
it is independent of the
even see right
eight is independent of the given c
because every path from a to b has to go to sea
this one conditional independence statements that directly
you can actually read from this graph
from graphs to play
another one is a is independent of the union
sign of b
given c
you need be
another one is
you know a
is condition depends on the
you can lead to a bunch of conditional independence statements corresponding to these
what he's doing says
is that if i have
probability distribution
respects the conditional
independence state as read from graph separation in the graph e
then the distribution can be written
as the product of functions over cliques of the
may seem a little bit abstract
but you will see why this is so important
well can look at the proof of this
before explaining what is important that should prove interesting
the three we use something called the using version
are made using version
which is this statement
the technical but still
i find it interesting that you can still write the proof of concept for a
the single slide
so this is
the image is
inversion lemma
the objects we have
the set
you should
think of
the collection of the run by the
a b and c are just subset of the rule of law
such that b is a c c e
this function
is the function that
from the power set of s
with the real ones
it's the powerset of the set
so what's the powerset of the set of nodes
yes the powerset of the set of all subsets
so for every subset of
i will
associate really
well in this case
it is well in this case you have a finite set up here
in this case
that's the power set defined just
all possible
it's not sufficient fuzzy
this is just the powerset
we going to define this function is a function that assigns
every element the person
so therefore
this function can be
applied to lightweight can be applied to be can be applied to see right
because this function can be applied to any subset of s
but for us
also these functions actually yes it probably from itself
it's actually logo
the negative logarithm of the like
the marginal probability
continue to
she will be fined as
he which is located in this case the finance just eleven he
and compute the in the some of the case
of the case where b is not the
so basically
you can also proved this lemma is not
people with the
let's just take forever for the
this is what this is saying is that
i can write these function of the time set
as as the sum of
this function
of the
with the proper signed for
the evolution of the function this subset
this is sign
the kind of knowledge of the difference is that
now what we're going to do this to show that whenever
we have
whenever he is not a clique
whenever the set b is not unique
we will have
this function is used
in other words it is sum over all subsets
and the sum for all subsets are not logically
what is zero
so the resulting sum
effective so we only over the
well suited the the clique is a subset
two types of subsets of variables given graph
you have to all subsets form a clique
and all subsets of items that do not
so what are going to see is that when we evaluate the function
in all those sets of another clique we get
so what remains is only
so sorry
the greeks
the conditional
independence state so let's see what the conditional independence day let's assume that there exist
two nodes in b the not connected
since we assume it back on traditional assumed to be is not case
it's just assume that is not
the subset of features
and then he choose
the words basically for me that was to express that a particular
and then he says something
bad good o
if i may not know basically
becomes a sort of
so this is essentially the model
decision among how
how this
it's not like
but of course is the simplified model this in case you can't catch for example
that these two things you can catch sometimes people talk about features relationship two features
for example you can see
the the the
the lens of his camera is still too close to the
to view fund
so he's talking about two things
and i think this is not being capturing is it's the
it's a degree
sometimes i really hate sex i mean something maybe to say this is
fine but you can improve certain aspects
but that's you can't get
so let me end this talk about opinion task hardly put these things
people have been doing into that model came to the them world
so that using spearing doing the first thing is
what is called sentiment analysis which is a canopy researchers been doing that for
a couple of years
so what i'm doing is basically tried to classify each document each review is a
positive review always an active view
o sometimes they have neutral as well
the classes so essentially classification problem
the cost of positive negative and neutral
so what is assumption assumption basic says
he focusing on a single object
so this document has been focusing on the same object
and they come from a single person
if he's talking about the model object they can't do this can do this
and then this
this is sort of
why this is
is in the model because
essentially the opinions about objects
this is the top the the the root node of the tree
so the centre castigation essentially try to find opening
about objects of
because we see also the object is feature
and then analyse the sentence level we've been dealing with sentences so this is something
sort of
sort of floating somewhere
it's not really
the feeling the model because it's itself it's sort of medium medium level
OK so this doesn't really tell you
what is it is and this is an active
the negative about what
negative what
so the issue here is
both of these things
is that the really tell you people like what people like or dislike
there were people like dislike
so now we we we go be further to be further there is actually what
it called the feature level
we go to the future
then what other tasks one of the task
so if you have obviously this fitting the model
so it has to be a success
and extract features
like extract features
and this is a difficult problem information extraction extraction so the second thing is if
you got the features
now what is
the opinion
what is your opinion on that particular feature
pretty feature
that of course
we have an to
pretty difficult task discard
the synapse
how do you know something is and so
because the next they wanted to us right because i remember when i first flight
we do the same you have to do some the summary you can't just let
people read it
so i did some reunion nordisk nonsense otherwise
picture the photo and image though
if you put in a different place and and i'm sure you've gonna laugh at
so in this particular work we focus on only task two
task two
so we assume
task one has been done
it's been so
if you're interested
you can take a look at the
how do you do the task one one
so what do we mean by summary apologising to some people are is in this
slide because this talk a few times
in various places
so what i mean by summary in this case in this case
if you read this
amazon review i did a lot of research last year before i bought this camera
kind person behind my
eleven mekong blah blah they're going to italy and something smaller and digital
and they say a picture coming out of this camera some amazing all the feature
takes great pictures most of the time and was digital
i don't want to waste your film in the picture
it doesn't come up something so we read this hosting
i mean who who cares where you're going to not so what interesting basically that's
only two words here which is terribly important
the first part we'll be
the pictures coming out of this thing is really amazing
OK so this is the part is terribly important and that of course to also
so how do we extract is two words
and then figure out
people like
in this case
so that you can
producer summary
w summary summary of the like
for the picture i say twelve people like
we'll discuss velocities and accelerations
i'll start with something simple
i have a
motion of an object along the straight line
recall that one-dimensional motion
and i'll tell you that the object is here at time t one
time t two it's here at time t three is there
ninety four it here and the time t five it's back
when it was it t one
and here you see the
positions in x
it is
located at that moment
in time
i will define this
to be the increasing value of x
it's my free choice but i've chosen this now
we will introduce
what we call the average velocity
i could borrow over it
that stands for average
between time warner time t two
that we define in physics
at x s ninety two
mine x
at time t one
divided by
two minus the one
that is our definition
in our case
because of the way that i defined the increasing value of ax
this is larger
and zero
if i take
the average
velocity between t one and t five
that would be zero because they are the same
upstairs is zero
if i had
chosen t four
and t two average velocity between time t two and t four
you would have seen
that that
is negative because the upstairs
notice that i haven't told you where i choose my zero on my x axis
unimportant for the average velocity it makes no difference
if i had chosen
this to be the
direction of increasing access
of course the signs would flip
then this would be negative
and and this would have been positive
so the direction that you are free to choose
determines the science
the location where you put your zero
is not important but signs
in physics do matter
signs are important
whether you owe me money or all you money
the difference is only a minus sign
but i think it's important for you
now i will give you
not only
the positions
as i did here on the x axis at the discrete moment in time
but i'm going to
tell you exactly where the object is at any moment in time
you see in xt diagram
so you see that t one
the object is at position
xt one
this is the road of the object is is the straight line with moving
it starts here
and it goes to this position
he goes to this one it comes back to t four and it comes back
i'll tell you now
moment in time in between
it goes
this is now
information that is way more
you have the information at any moment in time notice
that i now did choose
x equal zero
i chose it somewhere here
but i could have chosen at any other points
whatever follows you will see that it makes no difference so i have chosen zero
points sort i can make a graph
and no
we will look at the average velocity
in a somewhat different ways
say i choose my time t two
three i draw here now
this line
and this angle i call of five
and this
or it here
i call delta x
and this year
is delta t
so you could right now
if you careful about you sign convention
you could write down now
that the average velocity
he called delta x
dividing by delta t
physical chemistry and reasoned that if the fatty phase could be broken down to a
finer particle size
then the buoyancy forces would dominate the gravity forces
it wouldn't separate so homogenised milk is simply milk
in which the fatty phase has been reduced input clothing cluster size two of value
so small
that by the time
the gravity field is able to dominate the buoyancy feel the product is spoiled anyway
so for practical shelf-life of the product you don't have to deal with starting
by taking the milk out of the fridge and shaking it in order to get
good mixing
that's a good example
so in the case of something like blood the cluster size is far too large
for that to happen and so it's not
i homogeneous under illumination it's easy to filter and it will separate the gravity field
what we're seeing here is a demonstration of
the competition between the gravitational forces in the interfacial forces
interfacial forces are
the function of the kinds of bonds
so it's a
it's all there it's all there and lastly this colloid is i want you to
be aware of the definitions here i'm not going to quiz you on this i
simply wanted to have it so that it some point you might want to
go back and refer to what i'm not going to test your memory
but this this breaks down the the entire taxonomy of of colloids where we see
that there's a difference between what happens in a liquid dispersive medium i gas dispersive
medium in a solid this person opinion and you can see many of the common
products that we know are in fact these dual phase mixtures that involve very very
fine particles on the order of some hundreds of nanometers that we use in common
so much for the for the taxonomy but now want to turn to the question
of miss ability
and in order to do that i want you to consider this
example which have
actually taken from your reading i want to look at dissolution of
substances in a
liquid bilayer sort of put two vessels side-by-side and each will contain the same
liquid bilayer
the liquid bilayer is going to consist of the bottom layer and both vessels is
carbon capture chloride
and the upper layer is water
first of all let's ask why these don't mix they're both liquid at room temperature
why don't they mix well let's take a look at the electronic structure and bonding
whenever i asked why
got test coming up a week from now when i asked why try to work
something into the answer that speaks to
electronic structure
because that's the clue
that's the clue so what we know about carbon tax chloride it's not polar
it's not in polar so why does one carbon center chloride born other carbon tax
chloride and please don't tell me something to do with the electronegativity difference between carbon
and chlorine let's forget about that it's not always all we've got is weak van
der waals forces so we have the van der waals liquid
on the bottom it's density is about
one point four so it's
why under water
and water on the other hand in contrast to be non polar it's polar
and it has
hydrogen bonding capability
these are very different substances and they don't have the capacity to link to one
so they don't they choose
forces of
cohesion over forces of adhesion
so we have two separate layers so now i'm we're going to ask what happens
if we introduce
candidates all you so we really have a by layer of solvents
now we're going to
introduce one case where going to put in solid crystalline iodine in the other case
put in solid crystalline potassium manganese
why did we choose these
well first of all both solid solid going into liquid and secondly the both purple
both purple very important both purple
what happens is if we drop iodine into this
bilayer stir vigorously makes everything up and then wait
the two liquids will face separating the gravity field and then we'll find at the
end of the experiment we have a solution here iodine
carbon chloride
mixed at the
a molecular level
on the other side
vigorously wafer system two
equal break
layers phase separate now
here we have
a solution of potassium manganese water
we can see with the naked eye the upper layer is purple the lower layer
is clear and colorless
in this case the upper layer is clear and colourless the lower layer for
it's clear that
the idea has a strong affinity for carbon centre chloride potassium manganese has a strong
affinity for
water so what's going on let's look at the structure of the candidates of what's
iodine iodine is
a diatomic molecule
and it's not polar symmetric so it's event of all solid
then all solid
and the van waals solid dissolves in the van der waals liquid because together they
got fluctuating dipole interactions that can allow them to one to one another and former
solution was with water
it's less
less favoured
in this case potassium for manganese is an ionic compound
four potassium cations
and to rank in a an alliance
so we have
in ionic solid
ionic solid dissolving in a polar liquids
the polar liquid is it is able to attract
the positive and of the dipole attracts the
and i am the negative at the end of the dipole
tracks the cat
if you if you read the
the typical chemistry textbooks they don't go into such an elaborate solutions discussion they like
to simplify it
the slogan taglines
so you'll see this
i hope you don't see that hope to see it spelled correctly you'll see like
dissolves like
i look at that as it's too simplistic going to give you some examples of
where that doesn't happen
the size of this is i don't know what to look at that i wonder
if i'm reading something from california noted that the like dissolves like you know
ten year means never having to say you're sorry switches