so it's like like the background knowledge to make mistakes like mistake bound there's no
distribution assumption not surprisingly this is a harder problem right so anything to keep can
be quickly learned can be mistake bound learned because whenever years you say i don't
know you can just give us anything that turns anything mistake that you can learn
the mistake bound model you can pack one
but it's not the other way there's problems that you can mistake bound learn you
can quickly learn and it's especially when they are taking advantage of the fact that
you make a guess and if you're wrong you learn alot quick is not allowed
to make that gas and so of an adversary can
it's kind whittle away the hypothesis space and take a very very long time forcing
it to make lots and lots of i don't knows
i'm going to want to do is i'm going to present a bunch of examples
of the easier with the examples how how i i just say it's not allowed
to make mistakes
it's as simple as that
now have
we we could do some examples but let's put it this is the way that's
going to be
here's why this very well suited to model learning so we're going to do
have our exploration being driven by this known unknown distinction
so anything in the world that our learner can't predict we're going to have to
assume that something that's good
and get the optimism in the face of uncertainty get to go out there and
get the data once it gets there get that example find out the right answer
and and it will not know that anymore it was yes
i don't know that now
so here's an example of something that we can quickly really simple
we should all be able to get on board with which is learning the probability
that a weighted coin is going to come up heads
OK so of interest should we all know that if if we observe for n
trials and we have x successes we can estimate the probability p the cartoon version
of it is just x over and
and what they have to down does it tells us
the as a function of epsilon
how likely it is that are estimate is going to be released the least epsilon
close to the real answer
i soon that you've
the doing have been down earlier in the
course the come up before you know
interesting OK
OK within them is also a little bit more about it and so
suspenders concentration bound sort of thing so so so so what we're saying is
no matter how big exit and more we can still get that kind of estimate
right so i can flip the coin thirty times and it comes up heads five
times so i could say well i'd estimate five hundred thirty is the probability becomes
apparent the problem is that if we have the queen very much we should be
all that certain that that they answer really is
but as we get more and more data with high probability that the average we
compute is really going to be very close to the real as the law of
large numbers sort of thing so it to this just quantifies it says that if
you've got a sample of size m
and if you're interested in
a variable that varies between
being a right so the that's the range of values it can spit out
o how how what's the probability that our estimate is going to be within a
plant of that and it is this expression here you could take this and solve
for what the probability is so
sorry this is the probability you can take this and say if i'm saying i
want to be able to shore one minus delta sure that i'm with abseil on
you can solve for what i am what sample size is going to give you
that assurance
OK so what does this led to know is that one so if i want
to be
ninety five percent sure
that i'm within point o one of the right probability
we solve for and we say well here's how many examples you have to do
to be that sure
so that the quick algorithm quick quick learners good is going to say i don't
know m times to gather that data and once it's gathered that data estimate with
high probability is epsilon close and so we could just use that the estimate for
then non
OK want to say the function
but i'm going to give you an we're going to play this says you're going
to be a a quick learner
we hope this discussed and so so that means that i give you the input
and you have to give me the output and has to be correct
or you can say i don't know
but you can see forever because that would be cheating or so
our first input one
OK OK that's fair
the output is one for that case can
the next input is one
i heard i don't know
yes the output is one that's correct or the next input is zero
i mean was one also turns out
right next input is one
good next input is zero
we and we learn the function and you learn with no mistakes
by the way congratulations
all right so and how how many times you have sort of the ridiculous example
but it turns out lots of lots of functions have elaboration that idea in
so for this particular case how many mistakes not mistake sorry how many i don't
knows did you use
two and in fact is that bound for this class of functions
x y
c one
o sin omega
prior functions
x two
is c two
cosine omega
and x three
this is three
cosine omega
i was looking for omega
o now
they go
given by
i'm telling you with omega is
you're not going to negotiate that with
we only solving for c one c two and c three and the steady state
you will be able to do that because omega is non-negotiable you're going to get
three equations with three unknowns c one
he two
he three
you don't have to settle
two only calculate the ratios of the you know
going to get a real answer
four c one c two and four c three which of course will depend all
sure you know at
we worry about phase angles here not only because there is no then
and if there is no damping
videoobject in phase out of it because it then began disease phase angles in between
one hundred eighty degrees out of phase is a minus sign
so we have our
introduced on the it we face changes
and zero base
for that we have a plus and minus signs
you are going to
grind i did all the grinding
every detail on the
now i'm going to do
however i want to make sure that if you
go through that
make grinding
that you in the end up with the right
solution so in that sense i'm going to help you little bit by giving you
the d
which is the the that we have here
you have to
bring me to
so the
it's going to be
so we have to
bye bye and you have to also
omega as really
OK of shorthand notation
some of you may want to call it omega zero that's fine
there's only one
the only
the brain an open and things but i still call it the nest remind you
that it is
the resonance frequency of the single
then i d
becomes miners omega squid
always the result of the second derivative remember you only get miners omega square
you get plus two
omega as created
you get the second column minus
all we got was great
and in the third column you get a zero
no surprise
to get a zero in the third column
because the first differential equations
has no connection with x-ray you know all
and so
you never see
anything in the third column that will be zero
but if you look at the second differential equation that has x one and x
two and x three in
so now you don't is zero
so what you're going to see is minus
omega as
it's going to be a c one
germany you get your mind is omega great
i think it's plus two omega squid
and your last hop was minus
o mcguire's script
number further differential equations
there is no x one
this zero here
and then you get miners omega square
and then you get
is omega squid
two omega
and you have to take
of this matrix that is d
check to make sure
i didn't slip up was minus signs when you get home
you don't wonder why did you get that result
and i think
that looks good
remember all those omega square
always come from those second
after the second derivative of cosine omega t
always brings out the miners
omega square so no surprise this is mine this is mine
that's why
so now we want to know would see one is
the first column
really reflect
this actor
the right side now
it's going to be zero remember like the double pendulum
so you're going to get here
the first column
it's going to get omega
finds at the zero
and they're going to get a zero and zero
and then this column
and this column
that is the
you divided by d
that then
is c one
and of course
i only go one step further out to sea to that becomes a little boring
the two then
you get
this one
and then the second column
according to agreements rule is going to be omega as great
zero zero
and then
thirty one
and there you go and we divided by p of course
and then you can write on c three
your neurons
i help you
so when you do this
you could if you wanted to
first of all forty what we call the resonance frequency
the resonance frequencies either one
but i don't want to do that
so you may want to put in the equals zero
the made determinant equals zero
which gives you the three resonance frequencies which really we would have called
normal mode
in case we not driving
so for those of you work this out
the lowest
frequency resonance frequency which
the normal mode
minus the square root of two
this direction has this value
so let's write down now
newton's second law
in the x direction
so we have t
in the positive direction
and one gene
signed off on
its maximum force minus
and one
the cosine of
that now
according to newton's law must be one
times age if a is the acceleration uphill
one equation with two unknowns
you don't know eight
and you don't know t
or do you know t
what is to
what is the tension
what is the tension when that thing is being accelerated of
the courage to try
i think two g
you couldn't be more wrong
it's now moving into being accelerated
that means this object is going to be accelerated downward
and if this force is the same as this can never accelerate out
this team as get smaller
an object in an elevator being accelerated down loses weight it's losing weight
this object must be accelerated that we have to take that into account so the
pension wanted to start accelerating will go down
so i have the second equation for object number two
i call this plus the action
so for object number two
i have two
minus two
he calls and two
times age
it is very important that you see that the tension will change
now you have two equations with two unknowns
i can solve
very easy
you just have to and i leave you with that
i'll just give you the results
i find
that the acceleration
the course plus think three point eight five
it is correct
what's the point eight five
meters per second squared
and i find that pension
twelve point three
i want to dwell on this a little bit
i find forty acceleration of plus signs
had i found a minus sign
i would
i'm sure would have made a mistake why is it mandatory that i find plus
absolutely mandatory
who wants to try that one
you say
you say well i would have said it slightly differently we know that acceleration is
in the direction we derive that they're forty acceleration since i call that plus x
direction that was my last time must come out plus so this comes out negative
you made a mistake
i also want this number to be less than
if not i've made a mistake why does that number have to be less than
this object is going down
to put it the way we put it last time it lost weight is accelerating
downwards this and TG which is twenty better wins it from p otherwise it would
never be accelerated down so plus sign is the most
and this is
most and if you find
not a plus sign but minus sign you have to go back to your calculation
because you made a mistake
we take the same situation
i leave everything unchanged but i make the second mass and two
make it o point four kilogrammes
so now all the numbers remained the same that we have there
accepted and two g
now becomes four
now i'm going to test again
this and two g which is four
is that larger
then five
the frictional force static
four point three three
the answer is no
going to test for my second case
is an two g
then five
minus four point three three
the answer is no
so what do we conclude
what must be our conclusions
condition one is not met condition two is not met
conclusion is
is zero object
not to be
and the frictional force
it is going to just along the x direction so that the acceleration indeed is
how does the frictional force to that
this is that slope
he was that object
i only put in the forces
x direction i don't bother about the y direction
i know that there is an one g
sign of
and that one is five
so we have here
the component of gravity
which is the m one
time of
and we know that is five
we had there
i also note
that we have tension here
and the tension
i must be and two g because the object is not being accelerated we're back
where we were number two is not being accelerated the tension is twenty
sorry not twenty big ones i and two
tension is
g is is four
five newtons downhill for newton's uphill
somehow to separate
the red points from blue point so i would say something like this might be
pretty reasonable it's not exactly clear where there
so let me see what happens so any idea what will happen
with go like this
what about this point
so let me let me put
so this is the government the regularisation parameter remember how much i way
that norm thing so let me put axis thirty here
OK go
that's pretty good right
that's more or less what you expect
so what happens if i make this regularisation parameter much smaller
the regularisation parameter is
regularisation parameter is this guy is lambda so what happens when i make it much
much smaller
what happens when they make this escape much smaller is that i don't care about
the norm i concur very complex ponderous but
i want them to be fit
there i want i want the thing to fit the data very well
that's also known as overfitting
so i want to fit the data very well and i don't care about the
bombing so let me being let me make it
it doesn't work
so you see what happens
basically the global bond somehow doesn't instill much here but what happens is that all
of these guys
they get their own little bottle so now you fitting every point basically if says
that has to be correct so this is exactly what overfitting is
using well this point is probably some sort of noise really hear everything is blue
i o thing you want to classify this is to mister
and here is the same thing and i don't know here maybe maybe not
but basically what happens when you put this parameter to be quite low you start
getting very complex boundary but every point is classified correctly from the data but there
is no reason to think that when you get a new point p h one
one beretta probably in the likelihood that
so you're not doing very well here you doing much better with the hyperparameter gamma
so here you allowing more complex functions and you get better fit to the existing
data but you probably will get worse fit to new data points
OK so this is very good at least squares and
OK so another thing to emphasise here that of course this is a very standard
matrix inversion problem and you can solve a lot of problems like this
it's a
it works very well in many problems you can use it for digit classification and
all sorts of things they were very often but failed
why is this a good classifier they and if
the intuition is the following this thing
this function which we call basic
so this is going to produce a function which is pretty nice
and yet fits the data well that's why it's a good classifier
so somehow this penalty penalizes functions which change too much
i don't know if it answers your question
why is it the good classifier
right of course it depends on land right
but basically what you want you want to penalize functions was complicated behavior and this
is what what does of course it's a very simplistic olga from and in general
you often want to do something more sophisticated than that but it's a very simple
algorithm and work quite well over
a wide variety of
but you mean you have to see the correct date also sits on the floor
and this is actually very similar to support vector machines i was playing for commissions
i in the kernel case in the second
so what support vector machine so as you saw before support vector machines so now
of course i am i in this more general setting so support vector machines and
the following support vector machines
instead of analyzing the square feet
europe analyse this function and this is the following function if f basically has the
right side
and it's not least well used at least one
this doesn't produce any penalties so suppose y is plus one then if f is
bigger than one then this guy is going to be bigger than one one minus
something which is bigger than one is going to be negative when i take the
plus sign passed positive part of what is going to visit and plasters means take
zero if it's less than zero and take the same thing if it's possible
so four if f of x is bigger than one in why one that's fine
by the same token if f of x is less than one and y if
less than minus one and y
i use minus one so why i can only have two well this year
one minus that you can have more but that's the classification
so i think
then this is fine so basically if this doesn't analyse you if you have the
correct what about this well you still have some
so this is a loss function and this is
they tried to board the plane and they told me my passport was valid it
had suspicious river near the photograph so since incoming canberra they're worried about the safety
kevin rudd
and i thought i was in danger to and they
meaning often get a new passport which took a few days
so i'm here now
my name's at manassas you've probably read from and
you should garden
all nodes which were an extra two sets
in addition to
the ones the printing about that they and
o one told me that that
they now give you any
oh sorry there are two sets of nodes the the the the action and so
i give you should we have the class
they have all that i can see that
so i didn't see that consensus
disaster directly OK now
i'm not gonna stick entirely to the nodes working together partly because you've learned a
lot of a bit of natural deduction john slaney right
so we're not going to to go over the old material can set a little
bit to introduce
these ideas and since would sort of a compact enough five hours to learn about
non-classical logic is what i'd also like to touch on some things you have heard
about the lectures and relate to what we're doing
in here kitty but what i'm going to start out by the way
something kind useful to me and i don't starve all my
logic lectures how many of you are from sort of have a background in
OK so three of and how many have a background in
it's more and new science
OK linguistics anybody
now can talk a little bit about linguistics and last lecture but only very little
but i often find that
clusters are sometimes the philosophy student sometimes you want to learn about the mathematics because
it's enough to pick up things didn't pick up during their undergraduate years and sometimes
the computer scientist and the mathematicians one here but the false because that's something that
so we're going to have a mixture of all of these things
first of all i want one of the things i did that a little bit
unusual for me
is that took with called proof theoretic approach to this topic
my teaching on this was not that unusual now but my teaching has evolved on
when you're talking about
language philosophers positions of language is so strict separation between syntax and semantics
so syntaxes grammar and usually the theory proof
ah so you formation rules language in it and you're deduction system is natural deduction
sequent calculus hilbert style system whatever
right you've learned about all those things are we done the sequent calculus
OK great going to talk about that in the last few lectures i i mean
i can introduce sequent calculus sequent style natural deduction systems to hybrid systems that greg
restall someone else's often tartness like in this summer school
has developed
he and know i don't
but anyway out of over that later
so what we can do here
sorry so usually talk about that is the separation from
diffloss often like to talk about the proof theory and not all philosophers talk about
um information rules over one some grammar and proof on one side and semantics on
the other side and semantics especially with the theory of meaning in the theory of
also very meaning it's what we understand only
what these symbols really mean to us
well psychologically kind of sort of psychological and that's a long story but i'm not
going to go into that story too deeply because as in the philosophy of language
course and also we just don't have that much time fascinating though it is something
i'll be teaching a few weeks
back in my home university
well we're going to a a little bit more
this notion of semantics
what these symbols mean what their
what they represent
how we are supposed to understand
four caps for example
refers to
a little fuzzy things
and it sort of means well maybe
of the genus
species feline
but what are the logical symbols mean and or not
the traditional
but it traditional answers given in terms of model theory will now tradition
since the nineteen thirties
and you've learned a lot about model theoretically one possible world semantics eleven model theory
for first order logic regularly states so far
in courses right what the model theory sometimes people called semantics formal semantics
because it so closely tied with this notion of
the various connectors mean
but there is another tradition
in philosophy that goes back as well the nineteen thirties that's philosophy the philosophy of
good as well back to nineteen thirties
and is these days gaining a little more
it doesn't tend
philosophy textbooks or mathematics textbooks or any are computer science textbooks of the computer scientist
i find are a lot more open to these ideas
because of this idea
that you can treat program is approved
this the the
the programs as proof and the
the curry howard isomorphism
because of those
notions that you have taught touched on here and the other summer school
sometimes some sort very hard as morphisms
now OK but you learn what some of you learn about that elsewhere in order
to talk about it too much we might a little while later if we get
some time we talk about the sequent calculus because of those those ideas computer scientists
at least are little more open to this what is the idea
over all values of y i
and why i
plus one of the probability
why i
when i plus one
given x
corresponding value for a while
why i plus one
OK a
now these quantities
are exactly what i'm getting so forward backward algorithm
except that well in that case they would have two red dots next to each
so with some overall those variables
now we're all these
and with a slate which i mean just after normalize give me the probability of
y and y plus one
OK so i compute those numbers
plug them in here
and that gives me this expectation
well not not completely done yet
because at the end of the day
i will
then we need to compute maybe the inner product between that
and some theta
therefore if i take an approach between fatah and the expected value
that's been
the sum over all the y i
and why are plus one
why i
why i plus one
and then here i can just put
post is inappropriate
and this is an expression we know how to compute
the could
that's just some
expansion and we get the kernel directly
the question at that point
it's going
two one
OK so in
well in fact about three four slides down the track
i will be talking about in markov models
no actually
well that's
somewhat related
i mean the hidden markov SVM is in a way a precursor to the max
margin markov network
and just that they use a slightly different loss function all that
i am not going to
get into details about that this will be if you were to use the con
considered different loss functions and not going to do it now
if we have some time after the lectures
i can briefly mention i would do that in the structured SVM setting
i think it would confuse people if it is now
was the
it the country
yes this this this and it's an exponential family
the thing is if you don't have
the nice factorizations assumption
then it gets very very hard to the dynamic programming
so for instance yes i could use the solid for my family
and what
get nice
experiential like expansions
and i couldn't do that and programming efficiently
so yes in principle you can do it you get the convex programme
but no you cannot find it efficiently
at least i'm not aware of this we ever get such result i mean this
will be one famous paper
i wouldn't know at the moment how did that result we use
well i am not assuming conjugate priors or anything like that yes you could replace
well what what one of the problems of course first of all we have seen
very clearly for example as statisticians have been shouting for many many decades association is
not causation you can not least can not very simply
interpret associations as having causal meaning
so what are we going to do
so traditionally statistics
they do what i do with causes of a face as it is a hard
problem when i'm going to go there
OK touch that only deal with association correlation things is not completely true there's all
theories experimental design which is one of the
bright stars of twentieth century science thing
which which does address causal issues in experimental studies how to arrange your interventions in
order you can draw reliable causal conclusions
which is great but it does only restrict itself to interventional studies randomisation and things
like that
and therefore it doesn't take is very far the really important problems of understanding data
from observational studies
so what we're going to do to make inferences about causation
one way of thinking about the problem is that it's it's it's a really tricky
problem of induction
thinking about prediction the standard setting is that you've got some data
a new learning something about the system that produced the data
and you're thinking about using that to say what's going to happen in further examples
generated by the same system so
that the problem of induction from observed data to unobserved future cases and like every
problem of induction is nontrivial
at least your in the same
setting the same regime your thinking about induction to further examples of the same system
but with causality
causal inference from observational data you moving two different systems
few decades of from an on manipulated
unobserved and kicked system if you like
but your inferences to manipulated and kicked system
so we're moving from one regime the observation regime two different regimes interventional regime the
data is on the observation regime the question is about intervention regime we want to
make an induction from data to the future but it's a very bold induction which
has to skip across from one setting to another so we got
think about how we might do and very important how we might justify
now here's an interesting question i think
until lot about
well in implicitly about
uncertain outcomes and we don't know don't have the patience can recover or not so
clearly some
framework involving probability is going to be pretty important to us
somewhere some pro was going to be the is that enough
or do we need in order to understand these questions of causality do we need
to develop something novel
a whole new foundational framework
which will allow us to make sense of these questions and answers
do we need a new formal framework many
workers have decided the answer to that is yes unfortunately we haven't agreed on which
new formal framework it is that we need
my answer to that is not really we can pretty much model for what we
got already
so let's think about the various
framework that have been suggested
so at the very foundation level you know what are the fundamental building blocks
that's you might want to use
well the probability distributions maybe that's enough are trying to argue that is almost enough
and we don't really need to go much further but there's a very strong
enterprise lot of people who think that the way to think about causality is you've
got to think about potential responses so i'll explain shortly
what that's all about
but it's something new which goes beyond
the way we describe normal probability and association
the functional relationships this is based on bit of physics and the the idea that
if only had enough understanding of the causes of something there will be completely deterministic
i would suggest you understand understand the relationship between smoking and lung cancer you've got
to add just making all the other things that might also be involved in the
environment and
goodness knows what and then think of the functional relationship which actually outputs yes or
no you will always get cancer which is also very common very very very popular
i found odd because it's almost the antithesis of the statistical approach which says we
have uncertainty and mo and it's we have to live with that model
we don't we're not looking for certainty
and there's something which i call extended conditional independence which is just related to a
slight extension the idea of a simple probability modeling which again i will explain to
you in some detail in fact
so that we could say the fundamental building blocks and then there are various ways
of body like imagine how these the child's constructors that you can put them together
in various different ways of different structures which you can build on these things so
structural equations that built on the idea of functional relationships and this is very this
started out order by eighty years ago i think in in genetics was alright right
to become very popular in in econometrics and many other areas the idea of a
it might be that fraudsters
taking the maximum amount from the camp and then you try to
and then the bank will bring you up and say did you make the first
or it could be the other way around
excessively small transactions to test whether card has been blocked
whether they have yet detected for example the car has been stolen
small transactions go under the threshold of detection for example
we can
purchase of multiple small electrical items for example toasters and what machines and hairdryers because
these can be easily sold on in car boot sales and so on
all of those sort of examples of things which
mean fraud but they are they might be suspicious they should perhaps be
mixed in with other things and looked at
i'm going to talk about will based methods in detail
let me focus attention on the instead on supervised classification anomaly detection methods
the basic principle you're all familiar with this i'm sure the basic principle of supervised
classification methods is that you have enough context a set of known fraudulent and legitimate
or counts with the descriptive variables reach the seventy two eighty
variables for each transaction
and our aim is to condense
such a data set a retrospective transactions to rule enabling enabling us to correctly classify
new transactions just using their descriptive information just using the seventy to eighty variables
that's what they're trying to do
and as you know
there are a huge number of methods
for these kinds of
to protecting these problems developed by various different
intellectual communities
which are greater statistics and i've just listed some other methods and if your favorite
method isn't there i apologize there are too many but i got
the most important ones i think
but there are others there are many variants of these and someone could fill all
the slides in this presentation the the list of these
OK so let's look at a particular example of this is from one of the
banks which is
collaborating with us
still class k
so in this particular example
we've got one hundred seventy five million transactions which took place between the first of
in two thousand five to thirty to november two thousand five
sixteen point seventy million accounts
six thousand of these
seventeen million
had fraud
critical point of sale terminals
we had between seventy and eighty in this particular case we had seventy six more
per transaction most of them categorical some the continuous like amount of time
but others merchant category code for example
nature of the point of sale terminals
it will be categorical
in this particular is just an example of one of the analysis we did in
this particular example we use rolling window activity records summarise transactions over the last seven
days lost three days last one day zero here means we just looking at the
last transaction by itself
you take a stake in example you take the transactions over the last seven days
each of the transactions which occurred in the last seven days had seventy six variables
recording it
maybe there are five transactions they got five times seventy six variables which need to
be summarized in various ways process to extract useful descriptive information like this sort of
variables i described when i was talking about the
agency pattern
when we did that
we process to each of these activity records describe them in terms of eighty seven
so we got eighty seven variables describing each activity record
this particular study
evaluated compared various different classification methods
ranging from logistic the action
social support vector machines random forests
and so on
two investigations were carried out
this is quite an important point
in this sort of work you often find people use the holdout sample they
they randomly
split data into two
quite properly build the model on
one of the parts and tested on the other we all know
but that's very sensible thing do you don't want to build and test on the
dataset because the optimistic results the optimistic bias you get so splitting in two is
very sensible approach especially given that we got pretty large numbers
in this particular problem one of the
have made this clear one of the very important features is the things change over
i've talked about faustus changing in reaction to anything you do
but as we particularly aware the moment
economic conditions can change
we could be trundling along in very nice comfortable economic situation
the sub-prime crisis could occur in the united states which turns everything into a downward
all sorts of changes can occur new technology can come in to change things change
in the system
changes occurring all the time the so
when you take a holdout sample when you take your retrospective data randomly speak split
into two you are assuming that the few training test you are assuming that the
distributions constant which is unrealistic
so there is one
i doubt about the
how how accurately how originally you should interpret conclusions from this sort of analysis
the second sort of
one of the other analysis we did with this data set was we
to some extent try to allow for that by training on the first three months
of data and and testing it on them
the final months of data
that allows for
to some extent changing
conditions distributions and so it allows for population drift
but call population drift
well that's OK it illustrates how dramatically in one particular case
when change occurred around thirtieth of october
how things can how the predictive performance might degrade for example but of course the
economy could change in any things could change in any number of other ways so
anything here also should be interpreted cautiously with a pinch of salt
and we consider the topic of sparse learning on matrices
so in terms of features so series promising that we could get good results in
terms of predictive performance if log b
is at most equal to n but what happens when n equals one thousand
so we say the same thing that you could do is
exponential one thousand features
it's kind of a lot if you want to to run algorithm with that now
we see how we can use structure within the features to design algorithms can be
run in polynomial time in an even though you you are implicitly considering exponentially many
features as you could be evolving
ah norms which are grouped with groups of a both which may overlap
there is we a considerable source but into the matrices and this includes a lot
for applications of machine learning multitask multiclass
images completion image denoising topic models in them and that we must continue to types
sparsity low rank what people often called sparse PCA or dictionary learning
so this would be the outline of the tutorial the first part on the on
the last so with algorithms and
theoretical results
and one part of the state of victoria as we consider structured sparse methods and
finally sparse methods on matrices
so before i start to go into the details
i think of all the things that slice is going to be pretty pretty quick
so i one on leads to sparse solutions and one simple way to to see
that is to consider the constrained problem
the first first throughout this talk i will either be normalized by the l one
norm or constrained by the one norm and this is equivalent in the sense that
for any team weighted constraint there is a long day for which you can be
analyzed by lambda times norm of w
OK so we go back and forth between those two
and of course the mapping from london nineteen is not depends on data because as
well as equivalent between bit inputs so why does everyone on mister to sparsity is
here we have plotted the level sets of a quadratic function
OK so good as to minimize so if you do unconstrained minimisation it will end
up at the centre of of the ellipses and of course be constrained to the
to anyone but
and then and one ball is simply is quite that so you see that depending
on where the quadratic function is located we get
no zeros and then we get
the optimum is obtained when
the red curve touches the blue square you get no sparsity basis you have gone
out in the one ball would be attracted to the corners as these are exactly
the parts which we call to
because this is a simple
german confusion why one norm
little sparsity
because this is applied to be considered for the next half hour so
so here we assume a linear model in model where we excise often referred to
as covariates
and why i responses so we will
leave script capital why
unspecified so can be either numbers of discrete values
and so the group be considered is regularized we get arise problem we have is
sort of an unknown latent class
the regularizer
so here i would not include a constant term b because it just makes life
harder is this can be easily added
and again you can be either using capitalised formulation like that are constrained formulation
so when you have the square loss this has been used a lot in many
communities in signal processing this is called so-called basis pursuit
and the exact same machine learning it is called the lessor
so i would start first by the more review of nonsmooth convex analysis a convex
in a sense that one of is non differentiable these great some technicalities and i
would spend fifteen minutes trying to
did with those in the simplest possible way
so we go over analysis which will how can we say that we are optimal
and how we can optimize later so there's a nice sequence of books related to
but the easy languages and somewhat of a hard languages CC saying finish really hard
also somewhat surprising thing into german is very hard
and what is really easy is a french spanish spanish portuguese
jenny translating into english is pretty easy
so that's interesting metrics so
you might have noticed that local we have the european project for now
you have
put your matrix which happens by about this so why don't we just built the
systems for european languages and he said because did for all official EU languages
and we
didn't completely realized that point that means if you do over twenty three languages you
have to build about five hundred systems
but OK cluster computing currently building these systems
as part of the project we have this online evaluation so we have a website
which might be down right now because the computer science department bar moving
and all the computers get disconnected help that's going back up sometimes
they actually have they can actually look at least the output of all these empty
systems for some of the language that if multiple
so participating in producing outputs you can concurrency see with the performance
and if you build your own MT system you can upload their tickets automatically scored
cross against the evidence
and also you have the test set that is also a life sentence by sentence
the eleven languages
such that each
yes well well that different
so you have the same sentence
translated across eleven languages and you have two thousand of those sentences it's it's apparel
across the instances of course so here i am
also not entirely believe the blue because because
you compare against different references
it's part of the reason why finishes harder is finished build gigantic words
the finnish versus usually contain things like preposition
and also this german disease of sticking words together
so getting rid tried finish
it's much harder than getting it would write english
so getting rid finishes almost as good as getting three words writing in english
so getting high blues course finishes much much
part of because it
you judged on how often you get a falcon right
it's extremely difficult question posed to answer to basically have to answer the question is
this spanish sentence as bad as this german
it's very hard to get references and this is hard to get a handle on
all the core of the columns
well they have this compare against the same output language
does it really mean translating into german is harder than translate into english
it might be
but in the rose i mean you because you always compared the same output and
verasamy certainly the revelation manually if you translate from different source languages so they're blue
losing to correlate
will be different
so the big problem the germans ones word order
so typically the
if you don't get very bright in the sentence it has a lot of knock-off
affect everything else we just the language more likes to have build the sentence would
often loosen its auxiliaries left and right
so everything falls apart if you don't have the right to right play so that's
one of the reasons rich morphology is another reason
so if you look at the blue course finishes the religious mythology of all these
languages the hardest thing which translate
so those two
otherwise german english are very related languages in terms of vocabulary the use of of
the first look the same the kind of expressions you can use an english can
almost always
what can very often use the same expression in germany
which is not the case into chinese english and so on
so i like germany basically
german economist pose the challenge of getting syntax right mt
and in morphology otherwise it's easy language
OK so that we can make you thing it's single class of languages by how
well it translates it just takes the blue score say which two systems as close
going put them together so it's kind of greedy clustering the first class of languages
together very close to many clusters c one of the clusters of and if you
do that well i think it
i to tweak it a a little bit
i mean comes down to the similarity metric ninety computers but you get the nice
treaty of language pairs so
this you know it's just language related to the portuguese spanish french italian i'm all
related to the other ones
you can of get the same cluster of the romantic and dramatic languages and the
two in greek finnish
so here's the thing is said about what is where is kind of already talked
about this
you see that some languages are easier to translate into that out of fifty translate
if you if it ever all the scores of translating from german from english but
english is slightly easier but not much
twenty two point two
twenty three point eight
but if you look at this course into german into english and german is much
much harder ten point
different so there some languages that
can you hear me
right thank you for being here thanks for bringing here and try to make this
interesting for you so i'm going to talk about markov logic a unifying language for
information and knowledge management this is what that done at the university of washington with
stanley kok daniel out
four from paul matt richardson parag singla marc sumner and jue wang
here's is a brief outline of my talk i will begin with a little bit
of motivation
and then some necessary background and then i'll get to the heart of things which
is this new language called markov logic i'll talk a little about inference and learning
markov logic and the software open source software that are implemented in
and then i will talk about some of the things that we can do markov
logic and conclude with a little bit of discussion
so here's the motivation
and here's a cartoon you know very very oversimplified cartoon
of the state of information and knowledge management about twenty years ago
you can think of information lying on this axis
that because between structure on the one side and unstructured on the other
twenty years ago what happened was that there were these things that were from we
very much in the structured side like databases and knowledge bases
and the language is that people use to deal with them like sql datalog in
first order logic and its many variants
this was the structure into the spectral
and then there was the unstructured of the spectrum where you just had three text
and of course there was information retrieval the
three text and there was an LP that dealt with free text
and this is where things stood
now fast-forward to today
what happened
it's really amazing
this spectrum between structured and unstructured has become completely populated
the combinations of structured and unstructured degrees of structure you know have explored there's of
course hypertext and you know html
but then there's also things somewhat more structure that protects like semistructured information for example
XML there's deep web right which is kind of like structured masquerading as an unstructured
the semantic web you know things like RDF and OWL web services so that we
have in this things like information extraction that go from structure to structure and there's
even things like ubiquitous computing instances that produce all this data that is kind of
much easier
people used to
and on the one hand this is very exciting but all these things that we
can do today that we couldn't do before but on the other hand you know
this is a nightmare
sure you know for software engineer i know applications program out there in the real
world you know there's ever more things that you need to learn
even more things that you need to understand
and you know the question is can make this a little bit better
and what's happened as you know the spectrum got populated is that
not surprisingly people from both ends tries to
and they still trying to a lot of what's going on today including at this
conference they tried to extend
there's technology towards the middle and towards the other side
right so people you know in databases and it
figure that this conference is a lot of the work that appears there is really
trying to do with data that is less structured than the standard database like XML
for example
and so forth likewise on the unstructured side right we have information retrieval that uses
things like the links in the HTML of course and so forth
but the question is can we do better than just this plethora of approaches and
instead of you know can we somehow actually meet in the middle here come up
with the language and you know a way of doing things that actually accommodates the
full spectrum and makes life easier for everybody again first of all i would argue
that we have to try to do that
and second of all i'm going to talk about here is a proposal in that
direction markov logic and you will see that you know even though it's a fairly
young idea the they has some notable successes to its credit of course this is
much more to do with people you will get interested in
developing some of these things and then using them and so forth
and by the way i was looking at the program conference and i was happy
to notice that the topic of almost every tutorial is directly related to something that
you can see here
which makes me believe that this is not the time has come to try something
like this
to summarize
what we need is languages can both handle structured and unstructured information in a very
efficient combination of the
but now of course as before with SQL and you know TFIDF and what not
it's it's not enough to have an ice language we need efficient algorithms for doing
inference in that language including all the tasks that people have in the past than
with IR NLP or knowledge bases are databases and you know for going between them
light and do
the that kind of prior information hunch that we have about nature about the large-scale
structure of nature
about the fundamental invariances in nature
and two and that and that just looking at the symmetries themselves
can lead to
really powerful statement about the nature of physical laws
so this was physics this is one of the main driving forces been physics and
say well throughout the twentieth century versus a starting in the nineteen thirties
the question i'm going to address the talk is how to do something similar
with data so when we don't have a physical systems going in and out of
these operations but when we're looking at the invariances of naturally occurring data
so we're going to be looking at various groups in but most we're going to
be looking both the discrete groups and continuous groups
we're going to be looking at a finite and infinite groups
one distinction that we're going to have to make
his between commutative and noncommutative groups
so this is this is the fundamental thing if the group operation is commutative but
if it doesn't matter which order chain together these
these operations and then the group is called a billion or commutative and that was
considered this signifies the underlying theories so this is going to be like a dividing
in our discussion
in particular generalizing ideas from that being around to non abelian around is going to
be really
exciting and it turns out that
many ideas do generalize but they become sort of somehow more supple and lead to
more insights and otherwise you might imagine OK so that just a couple of
examples of groups having started from an abstract definition by the simplest series of groups
that one can think of are the so called cyclic groups which essentially just the
integers modulo n to take integer zero ten minus one
and then you consider addition modulo n this structure which you can think of is
kind of these numbers sitting around the circle and adding and then you add the
angles corresponding to each number but you always come back because they are in the
so-called this sort of thing is called the cyclic group of order n
the smallest group which has slightly more
interesting structure is called the fear group
it has four elements and
in which you can cause the one i j and k
obeys this multiplication table
so the small groups on way to just capture the group is to explicitly right
down the multiplication table this is what i'm doing here so if you carefully look
at this you can see that one is the identity element any
element squared gives you back one
and if you multiply any element by any other element then you get
third element
if you carefully look at the structure discovered that this is identical
taking the direct product of just two cyclic groups of order two so this is
like moving around on the unit square
the first non commutative group in and if you can kind of trying to start
writing groups is the quaternion group
so this is first eight element in a slightly more complicated multiplication tables
i'm not sure can you see the i mean even for me it's kind of
in fact our
and here the
here the essential thing is that
the multiplication is kind of induced by this cyclic permutation of i j and k
so if you want to buy a giant j i by j infinity g by
that i k by a chain
but if you multiply the other way around then you get into the class k
he would get minus care so this is the first example of non commutative group
we started talking about that because he drove
the symmetry group of the icosahedron is quite famous is called the alternating group
o five letters are not removed in the second part of this work and going
to say
a where that comes from
for our purposes what if are going to turn out to be more important are
the so-called symmetric groups these are just the groups of permutations
and so
if you take an object
and you see all bijections of those an object or a set of set one
two n into one so all possible maps one ten to one to all possible
possible matchings
there and victoria all of them included this forms a group
right so if you've had to consider of people regard the permutation has an operation
on these numbers one two in a particular way in which you exchange the numbers
one two and then one of these operations you can followed by another this is
what gives you the group structure and the resulting group is called the symmetric group
and denoted as n where n is the number of objects that you are using
so it might seem like this is the canonical thing in
indeed many
many results in from the theory of finite groups have their simplest nontrivial case
for the symmetric group but even this simple thing just considering all permutations of something
reveals a surprisingly
deep and intricate structure this is what we're going to have to talk about and
the second in the second half of the
talk today
going back to commutative groups
just integers
again with respect to addition
again former group
this is slightly confusing i must warn you that
that evolve
over time
we need to be able to to incorporate new information information
process the new information that a
is available
and we need to be able to take
and we have to sign
in the cluster structure or in the data the is phenomenon that is
i'm going to present the knowledge
for the last three
if you that working method
there are a lot of of this form
last three
the lot examples
what i'm talking about
it's about clustering
the call
this is important because
in the
standard approach
i cluster variables are clustering examples
we only apply
the trust also played related to do what metrics
and i have an algorithm for clustering examples
if i want to
cluster variables
i apply a threshold to play
and that's the applied field
but now consider that this problem in data streams that
the trust also played
is the blocking the plate what does it mean
but it only on the first part put them
after processing all
the input that
and in the stream not
this is not possible because
the size of the stream is
in clustering clusters
variables in streaming set
new all
request of britain's
that it that
if i can not use
the threshold but
two thousand six
the reason that i was in the knowledge to collapse
variables in streaming
this is
incremental clustering
use of the simulate
CNN called collapsed
the sole reason at the end of the cold structure
the leaves of structured course form
cool hand
the all
can detect texts
and last structure
and the take
and the at all saints in the data that is needed
the basic idea
the evolution
of the diameter of clusters diameter the diameter of the cluster is the
the maximum distance between the
two variables
the data are used to collect
is that expand the structure
is applies when
we have continuous side
new thing
so we have
much more and detailed information
used because we have
the more detailed information
we can define
a given cluster
and the fact is a class is
in two two new clubs
so this is the first
the second of data
it applies
when f
we did that
the the data that we adults have now
does not respond to to what
has been accepted by
this means that something is changing
in the
in can
the of the hypothesis class which has t functions combined by by this quantity
then you're results which are more type it's just the simplest case
so let's try to put things together so
adaboost needs at most two log and overcome iterations
when we assume a certain property of the baseline OK so if the base learner
achieves an error rate of at least half minus gamma then the
number of iterations to achieve your training error is too low and overcome squared is
what we had yesterday
so let d be the VC dimension of the basic policies class
the VC dimension of the class of functions
which are the most can choose from after t iterations is just this one here
so it's this is
logan becomes clear overcome clear this is the number of iterations
so it's the times t
times lock
t right so and
can just write this out so in terms of and so this is essentially dcterms
log n time slots there
OK so this is an example
for instance when you have if you see the image of the basic classes class
which is two
then you can consider for instance the number of this this plot here the number
of examples go increases year and the CBC dimension of the combined forces class and
then this is this function so this is essentially
the function here
and as you see the number of any you compare the VC dimension with the
number of examples this is going to be discrepancy and the bound you've seen this
quotient but i mean this is fraction of the VC dimension and the number of
examples so
therefore when you have more examples it gets better
now everything together so adaboost generates consistent hypothesis after a small number of iterations so
then the training of the characteristic
so the VC dimension of consistent combined forces can be found by
OK because the because of the fast convergence
so from the BBC bound to the type probability
so the one minus that holds that the expected around
smaller than the empirical error which is zero
plus some terms which depends on the sea dimension
and this term
it's just this one here and if you know just let go in
two if increase and then this whole term goes to zero
so therefore the expected
goes to zero
so that
i mean the transition there is essentially zero which is the training error class something
which depends on
and if you choose n large enough then this this respond becomes small
OK so the properties of the big learner imply exponential convergence
the past exponentially fast convergence ensures a small VC dimension of the combined forces class
therefore we have a small deviation from the empirical risk
and therefore we can choose
any epsilon and delta
that for any epsilon delta there exist some n
such that the
the error smaller than epsilon with high probability
therefore any weak learner which has this property which implies that this first can be
boosted to achieve arbitrarily high energy accuracy
OK so therefore we can have shown
that week learning is essentially equivalent to strongly
so by using this posting
on the other hand it just means that we can learning is not much less
than ten strong learning so the assumption that we can was already quite strong
so to assume that the weak learners
always achieves an error which is better than random guessing it's quite a strong assumption
for any training
other questions were that this is first part of the transition
OK so
what happened was the experiments and observed something strange
so this is an experiment results so this is the number of iterations you
and this is the training error this is the expected error so the the test
and what they found after a few iterations of this on some letter dataset using
boosting with c four point five
and what i observed was well the training error was already zero after five iterations
or something
and test runs
let me go back to this example of having
gulshan clouds which can be represented as as having the potential of this form
in this case
what will happen is that the
that is the density
you can see there is a
can use this
so specifically let's let's take the case of two clusters i'm going to draw one-dimensional
example but it can be in seven dimensions
so this is my
a potential u
and they have two clusters which means that
steady state density look something like this there are many many points here many many
points here only very few points here
so this is the first you can function
of the forward
the first
when the function of the backward operator call this
she left in this one few right
the first thing in front of the backward operator
means take this about minus this part and divided by this part was this part
so if you do that mentally you get exactly something like
so this is
different there
balls that indeed all explanation why
we have to clusters
the first thing function it depends on the direction between the clusters are not
each cluster itself
this is the thing that you can prove
because you had this formula
so for example if if you had equal amount of points in each cluster fifty
fifty percent
you can actually show that if you look
unsupervised and supervised few unsupervised clustering official according to the sign
opps i one
as n goes to infinity and obtain a goes to zero europe you approach the
the optimal bayes error
so this is quite remarkable
and this this analysis
true regardless of the dimension way
so here's
an example
i had my two clusters here's my backward
first they can function which again depends only on the x direction and not in
the y direction
indeed in a way for this
i only need one coordinate to describe the data
or the long-term evolution of the data
so in the one i applaud the first let's say three functions
with the tool
next ones are simply functions of the first one they don't add additional information
the first one already captures the important long-term evolution of this system
now i will present a little bit
of an application that interested there
me mean and another people group material
can we use
this method to analyse stochastic dynamical systems
this is a very huge field and very important one
and so once again the basic framework is that you have
some kind of the dynamical system which is driven by a force field
plus noise
you want to study
how it evolves and what happens with it
so in principle the time evolution is the forward ones
is described by a forward fokker planck equation
this is the steady state we needed to see this
both factor
obviously if you want to understand how you approach is that the state units somehow
to compute
the next
you can vectors are you function of this operator
the main challenge here is that if you take any system which is more than
three or four dimensional
yes you you know that these are again function of this operator
but it's defined in high dimensional space and you can not
compute functions
directly because that's the cause of this out if you do
if you a great
on your
set the number of grid points is exponential with dimension
however you can easily simulate
random walk
according to that equation
and you can
generate millions and millions of data points on then that only then you need to
i want to apply the
diffusion maps but
there's one problem is that
indeed if you can imagine there was a lot of them had a factor of
so they can function of this
i need
so how to get rid of this factor of two this is a marathon of
technicality anyway
if you
but your matrix based on a slightly different kernels
you can show that as n goes to infinite dimension goes to zero
the converse to this without the additional factor of two so exactly capture
begin functions of this dynamical system
how much time they have
fifteen minutes
of it
so first i want to show
one two analytical examples
where i can compute things analytically without a
so the simplest one is is to take the case where
i have the potential which is the
harmonic or or
so this is me this means that they has essentially only one well
so in this case i can even compute the
what happens when n goes to infinity but with finite epsilon
if you do all the math what you get is that
they can values go like this so that was the parameter of the potential and
epsilon was my with so you have something which is smaller than one of our
of k
you can functions are
some polynomials of degree k times the
this gaussians
if they get on zero
what you get is that these
converge to k
and these
polynomials converge to the helmet polynomials
this case has been
extensively studied music
the studied physics immediately organizing and functions of something
suppose now i do something in two dimensions
so i have
how many potential to dimensions
x one square the place that one x the school of applied to
and then consider the case where tau one is much larger than tau two so
somehow in one
direction you're doing a slow motion and you know when you're doing it fast motion
what happens then
your potential can be written as
as follows and also the kernel can be written as follows
and therefore you have this kind of a
outer product made other product structure fully in again functions
tells me
so this doesn't have to be
probability but it's a compatibility function that tells me
how likely
these two
values are too
occur together so it's in this case i said it's more likely that they both
and it's even more likely
they're both not famous
and the way this
it defines the semantics
is again i'm just going to
for a particular instantiation
and then i need to normalize them to sum to one
and so
key advantage of
these approaches is you don't have to worry about it
basically city
the bad news is the fact that you need to deal with computing this
normalisation term
i think the reason that the markov networks are
can mean
particularly popular these days is a lot of the kinds of things we want to
model now
big social networks we don't have a good causal understanding point
so it makes sense to just model this kind of
mutual influence but not necessarily model it in a directed way we don't know who's
influencing who we just know and there's an influence
frame based directed
frame based undirected models
kind of
capturing these
symmetric non causal interactions
social nets i mentioned
and web pages
the categories of the link
pages are correlated
and you can have patterns there
involve multiple
sets of entities
and so
the way this works is a lot like
we have the schema before
and we have the relations
and now
we have
edge potentials
that are potentially
at the same venue
for example
just like with the directed case
an instantiated RMN defined semantics in terms of the ground
markov network
the variables are the attributes of all objects and the dependencies are determined by the
template structure
so for learning
our approach is
these are mainly the work of ben taskar
and he and his thesis for discriminative training there
max margin markov networks and special case associative markov networks and i'm going to go
into detail about them here but
i will show
kind of cartoon of them
and then
one of the kind of areas for wine is
is for collective classification where you doing collective classification is big
unstructured are
linked network
and they have shown to be
very effective
the idea is you have
training data from this you're going to learn the markov network you have new data
and the need to approximate inference
to get out the conclusion
this can be seen as
you're doing that estimation
where you're maximizing
to learn the parameters
and then for the classification
then you're doing
the actual argmax two
predict the labels
building on the approaches from
lafferty are you can
here the model
a predictive model of the system
that turns out to be
common for like models or or or equivalently a better way of saying it really
more accurate saying it would be a linear dynamical systems so what's a linear dynamical
system i should
i have a slight slide so linear dynamical system is just a system in which
the underlying underlying hidden state
presented by some vector x
and t plus one is the next time step state is some matrix a times
x t plus an noise
a noise vector
and you don't get to see the axis is that you get to see why
so y t is equal to some some matrix b times xt plus some other
it's a major modifications some matrix a times
now well the comfort part comes in because you don't get to see the state
and you get to see a sequence of observations and you're trying to estimate estimate
stated that that is what call but
about linear dynamical system that is a linear dynamical system so the point is counted
for very very widely used in engineering to very powerful process systems but very rare
so common filtering is the process for you given the dynamical system and you're trying
to estimate the state of the observations we try to learn
the model
dynamic model for
and here is something that i think we should get rid of somehow you know
so popular
so you agree
you research looked at least some people agree
although the case
this is the case where winnow no
so whole
but if you put in the matrix i think would so
and i
not really
we make something more difficult but
the but it's actually doing is equivalent
it is not
so you have a lot of problems
i would assume
that's my
future observations of
these operations conditional
furthermore more
the right of the system the
this is an
the by state
so that was the late so why you
what people call he was that is it is that have and the next generation
one the key the history
the only is
i mean i thirty t over already
so my
representation of state
it's going to be this need discovery
representational state the mean of the next generation
the corvette
this morning
just like say if you are interested i see
but i have not international but parameter one inauguration speech
i would extend that to the one-dimensional galaxy
if i do that
he the next observation conditions of life that information get you
and that's what about he
so key parameters this
my and the first observation
and that in the next iteration
then so i will follow
it's easier
right about it
the key the key problem which is basis for all
is this
the list
it is called
with a
well according to the next generation
so i'm going to call this is going
cost cost so
and i feel we
well that's what i'm saying is one point out that
OK so
i don't know of any way of getting a good on that so long day's
regularisation parameter so you know what solution
you can very important problem
so i that methods the new people use really methods that is very important is
that somebody methods you would select levels one after the other this forward selection
and forward backward you can allow yourself to allow yourself to be to go back
so first this is non convex methods can because it's just completely just try to
do to solve the combinatorial optimization
so it's hard to analyse
it's a lot simpler to implement OK thanks with a few lines of
you may have some problems of stability which i will talk about later but
you get the same types of results as we use it also
OK so if you take all the conditions i've talked about for the last because
it stands to be efficient with those was pretty much greater minnesota get the same
types of results and domains organised then a lot of good work that so
current results do not distinguish between the two methods and in sparseness using convex optimization
which is kind of waiting for all the people do that too sparse methods one
of which include myself
because you should always compared with the method is simple to implement and elephants works
and so based methods i want i want to go then right because you have
ways of doing
stuff bayesian way
and maybe one or if that
if you use consider that so this is the square norm
OK to close in one long so if you if you look at that if
you see that the probability of
garson likelihood
and this you can consider that does not
probability of going solo plus factorized laplace prior
so if you want to do MAP estimation with priority to get back to so
life is nice and easy
the posterior if you do like some kind of a fully bayesian approach it because
poster you have no zeros because the posterior distribution of w
even today has no zeros you don't get sparsity the posterior another but it's a
good thing or a bad thing but just keep in mind that you don't get
exact zeros
this has led people to consider a proxy to sparsity
OK right you don't get zeros do that you actually can
OK i really looking for is yours are or you are you wanting in fact
to use a heavy tailed distributions so people have used all types of beta distributions
when the sitting
and one thing i want to mention that there is a lot less theory than
frequentist method can you have seen very few papers fantasy
how those vision methods behave in high dimensions things nice is nice open problem domains
that you can compare them
we compare them in a very simple we do oppose small pose questions one compare
them very simple problem when k
OK is the support size for sixty four levels piece from two hundred fifty six
so she signal to noise may still wish with one
so here on the left i compare these methods of the oracle
so if you know you should know and the support sets of course this is
independent of the number of the band of p because you know the icon so
even if you have a lot
of the variables this does does not change in red this is greedy blues one
and lugosi two
OK so this is a very simple
you can get few
so you see that
if you assume that the point is sparse which is the case because genetic data
we scale it called for my eyeballs out of this is form
o two two fifty six so we have a few variables would behaves the same
as soon as you add more and more irrelevant variables
and two norm go we do a very quickly and anyone on go includes likely
now function of the people which is somewhat is discredited by that surrounds
and the greedy in fact we will work better at the beginning work late we're
OK so this is those types of behavior are not supported by any type of
theory OK i know of six months ago and the greedy methods at the beginning
of bars
meaning that given that is easy sitting he doesn't average was but what it does
it is less stable this maybe be also
it's one of the nice TV is with business so that it is a lot
more stable
and of course also if you want days data OK so you stuff is your
sparse problem wrote that x
then your problem is non sparse animal and the norm should be totally envi into
that because you nominated by and by rotations
so the blues
the black curve is not changing a lot
there is this
this complicated looking formula the condition formula which tells us that every infinitely divisible random
variable has a characteristic function
of this
well we've got parameters
or rather characteristics mu is negative is is real
sigma squared is nonnegative and new
it is a measure
on the real line
and not
chanting zero
which has an integrability condition which means that it may be a finite measure or
it maybe infinite but if it is then it's still integrate x squared
around the world
so this is
this is what that result tells us and
rather than looking at the characteristic functions we could equally well be looking at the
moment generating functions provided these exist and you get exactly the same
formula with all
i size replaced by gammas
so we've got that term here in red which is going to play a very
important role in constructing
navy processes
yes wikipedia is exactly
measuring the energy that x has meaning that acts sort of corresponds to the jump
sizes of of the the process
so new is a measure that will be related to jobs as we will as
we will see
but first let's look at this formula
sort of explain where things are coming from
if we just look at the first time
this is what we
recorded at the moment generating function of the normal distribution
so we are really looking at a
normal random variables
something else
now that's something else we have also seen
at least part of it
when we were looking at the moment generating function of the compound possible process
we were looking at
the distribution
of the jumps of the compound possible crisis
and we we had that the integral of e to the gamma x minus one
against that distribution
so again we we know
what what this
this meaning is and we make that identification of x
as the
jump size and then
and in this sense of the combined for some purposes but there's more
well that more is essentially something that we also understand
what is new is doing is just shifting
mu if you look at the moment generating function of of constant new
then you get exactly that time there's no randomness
and this is another such term which is a multiple
of gamma
that's what what characterizes this interpretation so we are really looking at something constant here
except that
the integral
as it stands
does not converge
separately for this part and for that part in general
so that's where
with this
term has the second interpretation not just as
as shifts
by a constant but as convergence generating time in this
in this interval
we need to carefully look at how that convergence translates into properties of the
of the levy process that we
going to construct associated with such an infinitely divisible distribution
so what i have
talk you through was to say
well a random variable infinitely divisible random variable is
the sum of a
normally distributed random variables
of a
compound poisson distributed random variable
well there were some problems with this
with this integrability
near zero if this is to be a distribution it has to be a finite
measure this measure in general can be infinite
but what we can do is restrict attention to
to the range of
x values outside the interval minus one one
this is the interpretation of these excesses jump sizes so we're looking at big jumps
and that c one here now in my representation is
coming from a compound process
jump distributions
so that nu
restricted to minus one one complement
so the the big jumps
i've been generated
and they're being put into
in to see one
that lambda
was the rate of fire on process
and the interpretation in our formula i mean the land that was just sitting at
the fact to this time so we just move it out of the
the new
when we normalize it
and really identify that compon across
component here
small jumps that we've
forgotten about here
they are the
the term that's most problematic here
but what we can do is not just
do this argument for
jumps greater than one but we can do that argument four times greater than epsilon
for any small epsilon and we can construct such a compound pass on process
i have now chosen here
of sizes between epsilon and one in absolute value
with distribution just as in this case the restriction of our measure and u two
my is
one epsilon minus epsilon and epsilon up to one
we've got the right associated which is the
the measure
evaluated on that
epsilon to one in absolute value
and for every epsilon this quantity makes sense but to construct
the random variable and one we need to let
epsilon tend to zero
and there's some technicalities in form of an l to limit this
can be made mathematically precise
OK so this was just too
to say that i infinitely divisible random variable has such a structure because we recognise
the ingredients
of course we can now use this to construct a levy process along the lines
that i've
i've explained on the previous slide to take a brownian motion to give us that
OK listen
when this room things that
you are a programmer
not so we OK
i'm a programmer and developer i have a pretty thin
academic background and
the difference between
developer and research that
researchers usually
is looking for a problem
have to solve
the developer is looking for solutions
and this car that i decided to
give you it
course about information retrieval from a developer point of view
it's not about the problems it's about solutions to maybe maybe small solutions but real
practical solutions that we
user that created
information retrieval systems
talking about information retrieval
we are all
very young here and we
you have things that information is something new
but i can assure you that information retrieval is more than four thousand years old
and in ancient egypt they already had all this stuff
they definitely had storage overhead tanks in paper form
they have indexes
i'm sure about this and is
archaeological results they actually in this information they put it into some being they judge
differently this judge
they had hyperlink because documented documents were
one document
usually referred to another one
then they had search engine it was library and
and library librarians the people in library they search engine for all humankind from one
thousand years
and they had
all this stuff also and they were
one hundred percent
but i like because if you have a huge library
you have a a lot of librarians in this library and they work in parallel
but everything is not everything but a lot of
that changed in in the middle of the previous century when
digital computers became much more popular
and beginning from
this period of time program people who are working with computers
started to play started playing some role is in the information retrieval
it's true that information retrieval system
developed in nineteen fifty are around this
and different from the current systems is that
problem oriented
for example in this slide is not very clear but this interface of lexis nexis
lexis nexis is legal
information retrieval system is a very popular one and more than that
if talking about
controlled collection collection that we know how many documents are in the collection and somebody
on this
so somebody it on this on this collection lexisnexis is still the biggest
information to the system in the world
and you can see the interface is not i believe it's not very clear but
it's very very problem oriented it's again interface for librarians
and again people who developed the system so they invented all this stuff they invented
in texas and all this stuff they didn't talk to librarians
because they so a smart enough and they can implement everything from scratch
that's what happens
next about year two thousand internet
b became popular
and internet search engines from
so i'm not popular type of sites that are doing some searching some search databases
suddenly became huge festival because of
very good canonical model of information of search engine internet search engine
and again
information retrieval became like
something very new
people again invent all this real
in indexes and all of this stuff
what i'm going to talk about this very basic things that structures that are behind
search engine or all the information retrieval system
i'll give you an example from librarians to
the modern systems
but only one exception i'm not going to talk about
a real implementation in any commercial systems
first of all
if i have worked for some of these systems i simply cannot do this
if i