give me the crap
and the same thing teen clothing
two thousand six
the prophets ten k
so this is a kind of very interesting contrast because what happened is that
almost i did you know identical for product same time
the only thing is in two different cities
you know the two states
two provinces
you know the profits
incredibly different
it could be the local managers that
you know the
the culture of thirteen years is entirely different
or it could be
you know one place is very warm and all the clothes made was impossible to
is and pennsylvania maybe it's called it's quite good so this is the kind of
information they want to get
so that you see that is basically multidimensional except that we have the notion of
aggregation and that's what makes interesting you need to do the aggregation of these values
depending on how you putting this fast and then you have to mine that's what
makes this is a really interesting and also complicated
so i'm not going to give you the algorithms
and then
the sequence based contrasts patterns
it's really interesting this is done mainly in the in the context
in genomic kind of stuff
so basically
well you know when we did some mining
two protein families whatever i mean i have no idea what this protein families that
but what we found is that particular group of graph
are very prevalent
in ICDE two hits two
and never appeared in the
the other sequences
so this is you know when you do this kind things biologists are interesting because
they want to know
you know this is the kind of biomarker for them
so this analysis becomes
interesting and important
i and you know you know this is similar to the was trying to to
the bible i think
so what they found is that
you know the one of the things we say gaps means
the worst can appear
a certain distance you know you can constrain gaps
how much capital i
so for example the terms like having horns
this worship
stones price
and ornaments price appear multiple times
in the sentences in the book of revelation
but never in the book of genesis
so if you are guillotine maybe this is interesting
why they know these these kinds of things
so so they found lots of these things by the way this paper won the
best paper award in and ICDM conference
because it's quite tricky very difficult and tricky algorithms
which is by why the is given here
so the idea here is that
i just spend a few minutes on this because we want how much time
let's say you are given a sequence e one e two e n
and each of these elements i
it could be a particular of so for example if the DNA
they come from let's say
a CGT these are the
and amino
nuclear that is
and then we say is a subsequence of AGCA
notice that c
doesn't appear
one after the other you can have a gap so for example
you know g appears
in the main main structure AGCA
if we subsequent manages he's substrings substring means that you don't expect any
spruce things appearing in between
so when we do the is a subsequence
you might have some constraints some gap that means you you allow was listed one
one element to appear in between it a gap of one
OK so
so if the gap zero then the
we can automatically substrings
it is a an example
let's say you are given a sequence a c
a c b c b
and now we try to see
tell me
busy appearing so first of all what we do is that we index these elements
in the first phase one
season two
the next phase three three and so on
so if you look at the first one one five
what it says is a year
at position one
that is b appears at position five so still it is the subsequence but the
gap four
OK between those
and then
the next sequence you could also say is one seven
the first phase that the first thing
and the second
can be
appeared in seventh position
so four
so now i can go on to the next day which is location three
and then try to match the then it appears five
and the
and then i can also have several
so similarly if you're looking for a CB
we can build these sequences
so now what we can do is you put some constraints on the distances between
these elements and that's what we call this gap constraint
the game
you know these are interesting for
biology and other kinds of places
so it is again a very tricky algorithm and then you can define
this constraint on this for these things
the minimum frequency like you know once you find these sequences you might want to
say how many times they have to appear that is the minimum support and you
how that you know if you contest with another sequence said
what is the maximum that there can be allowed so this is actually our support
and then we develop a condition is there is no subsequence of p satisfying one
product or norm
the product of two functions in two
in the interwar of their products
and it's equivalent to your usual dot product in our here
which would be easy for you humans the vector u one
and the reason he one v two
then you're not products
is there some u one
u one class
u two two v two
so that product in it two
user norm which is the the square root of the integral of the square of
and that is going to be useful because you you defined with which is the
product norm you're going to be able to define things that are orthogonal and decomposing
vectors on sets of also in the thing is going to make your life easier
and the next thing you have been in two of our which is important is
its closeness so if you take a sequence of function f and that converges to
four which is the number of
different scholars in just two zero then the limit function is is in two
it's not always true right and sets are not always born
close issues take for example
it's use that is
the interval between zero and one but not continues you all one
and you can find
if you take x and
the sequence which is one of and for each and then x goes to zero
but you know is not in your
your yourself as
so which means that
you may have limit of things that are already in s
which is the limit is not in s and that's one has not closed
well to are as it is this ability that if you have a convergent sequence
are sure that the
images in order to steal and that's important
OK so
go to a formal different definition of vector spaces which is just summarizing what was
said so far
if you've said as it's called the vector space if the
additionally the war operations
if the addition is the addition is commutative and distributive and associated
as most of an known element for the addition
and every element of asthma be invertible for the addition so basically you have an
opposite minus an operation which is the minus
in addition if you want a real vector space you need to have
as which is favoured by multiplication by any real
or any skater either within the skater
learn that
and the multiplication by a scalar must have the property that it does it is
associative and distributive over addition
so all of this is basically just saying you have an addition
if you have two vectors it's still vector
OK you have to do the opposite of the vector does exists and the multiplication
of the vector of ice skater
is vector as well
so you thing when you want to see what's going on as a vector spaces
to divided into smaller spaces
and so subspaces basically subset of s which have the same property so they are
stable by addition
and still by matthew to plication may escape
nonlinear subspaces that of
help your article falls
your vector spaces in and also because of promontory subspaces
so inside i think two again
in my subspace as it is the one that is defined by my my friends
we have to make sure
so you want your
then if you take any other
vector that is not quality near to you one so that that is not in
the same direction as you one for example this one there v
the user subspace which is the
the set of all the them the
the vectors that are proportional to v
those who subspace there are
liquid crystal display in f one and f two
i actually see supplementary subspaces
which means that for any
and so that you have in our two
then you may write it as the sum of
so for the cause
projections there
so your vector x is that is can be written as
x one times the first vector u one this x two times the second vector
and actually is to to subspaces are said to be suppressed promontory if such a
decomposition always exists
train the notations are varied with this new thing with the x of s one
and the thing would be x
f two
now this space here f one generated by u one
and similarly if you take a family of vectors in as you can generate the
vector subspace
the new permutation has higher likelihood than the old one i always accept experimentation
otherwise i will accept it with this probability OK
this is you can think of this is some kind of similar to annealing great
i tried i have my current mediation i swapped elements if this is if there
is better attention more like a permutation and keep it if it doesn't
with some with some probability right i was thinking so this is this is the
segmentation of the body that so i'm just doing this swapping if it gets me
if it gets too better permutations right more likely permutation psyche that if you get
it was permutations i will keep it with some probability with this you taken from
she made this is just no i mean
just this just intonation
OK so the idea is if it if the if the and
change gets more likely to better part of the space of a given that that
otherwise just keep with some probability of i will show
so this is this is what you are doing the other thing that's very nice
here is right now we can do local changes in my distribution and then just
a asserting about my presentation in just swapping elements right so this is my
the adjacency matrix i that says what basically doing swapping the rows and columns of
this adjacency matrix sites so if i sort of elements jnk this means i'm swapping
jason case
o and call right so just swapping
this total single OK but what this means is that a large portion of the
adjacency matrix remains constant right so when i will get when i began creating this
ratio of this parts that we can slow
right so i don't really need to given the permutation i don't need to go
and evaluate everything i just need to invent
this tour also in columns
does it make sense
if you your
class lot of
and the changes
sure should i mean there are many ways how you could do this and nobody
says you want to do local local changes on your on your on your own
limitation because this would be this will be bad in the sense that it would
take long time to get to get completely random permutation for example that the strategy
would be to pick up some element element to transport and inserted at some other
random spotlight and this would then shift all the other elements by one and this
is much better shuffling strategy the problem with that some shopping strategy that it's a
better strategy so it needs to be more efficient or less less less samples to
or two to get that sample from the distribution but the problem is that it's
you it's not local so everything will change so we have to evaluate much more
i think the i mean it's not clear
it's not entirely clear why this would be obvious
i mean why is it obvious that that this here elements we can see why
because if i if i now slob this so it means i'm is taking this
one is i think it here then the whole documents one to the right so
we can use all
like one
it's better for getting it's about shuffling strategy
but because one
because it
i have all of the
because if you start you can show that i know
so now i'm just talking about but memory but i think it's started
but like all the permutation and you ask how long how many shuffles we need
to get to get to a random permutation for for this thing you i think
you will like water and square swaps well if you take and the one circuit
you will need like water and logan or something
so it's much better in this so we need less to get
to sample the whole space the problem is that you won't have this locality so
we have to every at every iteration it would cost more than OK but
so this is the idea how to get how to sample
how to sample these
limitations from the from distribution using these local moves this works quickly and the other
one is this this observation that makes everything given fast
OK now the other questions
so now i have this
so i have the parameters i have made i have the how they how they
how they calculate the probability and before we were so if you do you will
do it maybe you would have to evaluate every cell
of these adjacency matrix which takes children square but what you can notice is that
every element here we have is that this for so so if i have my
capital state that the parameter matrix which is let's say two by two then i
have four parameters so this is for free and then
the problem here will be like
so we first parameter some power second parameter some power and so on
in the sum of this parameter and this this this this this should sum to
some constant like let's say OK so here this this one of the things i
want to the k and then a b and c and d will be the
and and so on right so basically having
if you look carefully you get
really conditional distributions taken from these from joint models so
what i want do in the last third of forty five minutes here is to
try and give you a look at one way
of compact representing joint probability distributions and working with them they should always keeping in
mind the motivation for studying these joint probability distributions is this whole set up of
machine learning in the probabilistic approach to machine learning that just gave you but now
we're going to move to a more general discussion which is just about the joint
probability distributions and i'll try and try and go through that to give you some
sense of what this with this
field of graphical models really about
one of our goals here is to represent the joint distribution
compactly even when there are many many variables
so remember we said that if you have say variables with two hundred fifty five
settings are two hundred fifty six settings you have thousands of them then those two
hundred fifty six to the
thousand or to the ten thousand possible
inputs and so just to place the most general distribution you could which is a
just a histogram over those possible settings has far too many degrees of freedom
so that's one more compact representation and the second goal is to efficiently calculate marginal
and conditional
distributions of these joints given our representation
and that goal might
be a bit less
clearly motivated for you but i think just in a couple of equations here i
can convince you
why we care about that for example
let's say that you do manage to learn a joint distribution p of x y
all these are the inputs
of your learning machine and these easily output
let's say you did manage to learn this distribution from your training data which are
just samples from the joint distribution
what would you do if joint distribution
to answer question test time like what do you think the answer is the output
is for a new input
the best thing you can do in this sort of obvious thing is to look
at the conditional distribution
p of y given x
this is actually your machines
your machine is the conditional distribution you put the new input in here and your
machine tells you all for that input that you put in here i think that
the output is one with probability point four
it's actually better than a deterministic function deterministic functions gives you an answer i don't
know how it about that but this thing is uniform distribution over the outputs given
the inputs so you can see very simply that if you manage to learn the
joint distribution and you had an efficient way of calculating the conditional but you would
be able to answer queries at test time very nice
OK so that's the the motivation
OK so
the observation that we already made is that the arbitrary
naive representation of the joint distribution in the case of categorical variables is huge
it requires a huge number of entries
so we need to make some assumptions about the distribution and one assumption is
very very strong assumption it's complete factorizations
OK it says that the joint distribution is just the product of marginal distributions on
all the entries so that would be like saying the probability distribution over an image
is just the product of some individual probability distributions on each pixel
that's a very crazy distribution over images in particular tells you that knowing all the
pixels in a huge block that surround this one little pixel centre tells you nothing
about this pixel
it doesn't help predict that pixel at all
of course we all know the real world images this is true right
so image is represented by this kind of completely factorized distribution look like the snow
that you get when you tune your television to the incorrect just completely random
collections of pixels uncorrelated in space
but it has the advantage that very very compact right
so if you wanted to represent the distribution over binary images
with n pixels using this distribution how many numbers would you need
we just need it one number for every pixel which tells you what's the probability
that pixel is going to be on
so it is obviously much smaller than two d and minus one which is the
number of parameters you need to represent an arbitrary distribution over all possible binary images
OK so there's a huge gap from exponential to the the end delta and which
is factorized and the question is is there anything that lives inside that gap from
an arbitrary distribution over images which has so many parameters could never hope to learn
it to a factorized distribution which only has an parameters but is soul
restrictive that it's basically useless
so what's in the middle and that's what we're going to study today is what
is in the middle so rather than independence assumptions complete factorisation we can make what's
called conditional independence assumptions
so just a quick review for those of you who don't oh by the way
i should say that
i think the
in the notes there should be a quick probability and statistics review
for those of you who don't
no it so could look through those things in but
just very quickly
the notation for conditional independencies this inverted t
it says that a variable x is conditionally independent of another variable x given xc
and what that means is that knowing x c
knowing x b
does not tell you anything more about x a then you already knew
from having measured x
that's what this means
it means that if i tell you xie
only if i tell you see
x eight doesn't give you any more sorry XB doesn't give you any more information
about this
and that's the idea of conditional independence and you can write that down in two
ways you can write it down by saying the joint distribution over a and b
given x e is just the product of the conditional distributions for all settings of
c or you can write it down in this other re which just says that
the distribution of a given both b and c is the same as the distribution
of a given c real care about b
obviously for any particular independence assumption that we make might say oh pixel thirty is
conditionally independent of pixel eighteen given pixel twenty four
OK that some conditional independence then we can make for any particular independent state we
make like that only a tiny subset of all distributions satisfy that assumption
so the idea of graphical models are probabilistic graphical models
there is a very powerful and elegant way to specify a set of conditional independence
assumptions and thus specify a family restricted family of probability distributions
so the way probabilistic graphical models work is they represent large
and we even measured the period
and we found very very good agreement with the
theoretical predictions
you could ask not what is the kinetic energy of rotation
of these rods which changes with time
kinetic energy of rotation
is one half i omega squid
remember the linear kinetic energy is one half
MV squared
and becomes i you gotta rotation
becomes omega
so the kinetic energy of rotation
equals one half i omega scripts you'll find this equation
on the exam
this is i about four p
you know what fair use as a function of time
he calls
the theta DT
so you can find with omega is
you know what i of these which is calculated
so you know
what the kinetic energy of rotation is at any moment in time
it will change
it will be zero when this comes to a halt
and it will be a maximum
when it is here
it's a continuous conversion from gravitational potential energy which is the maximum here
to kinetic energy
which is the maximum
so this will
we time connecticut
energy of rotation
i thought problem
eight one wasn't nice example
of how to apply
couple lost newton's
laws of gravity
in the case that we have
an elliptical orbit
you we have
are it's not rotating it has no atmosphere
grant you a little bit artificial
we launch satellites
and the satellite
that's the velocity here
it was called the zero
as it is right here at the surface
this angle
twenty degrees
and we were told
the point farthest away was five
planet radio waves
if i try to
sketch the elliptical orbit assuming
that the velocities instantaneously reached mean this point must also be a point of the
if i try to make a sketch
that elliptical orbit
would look something like this
something like this
and then this distance
five four
i call this point eight
one that's farthest away from the sun
it's clear that the satellite will crashed back onto the planet
but that's no concern to us
when i draw this ellipse
i made the assumption
all the mass of the planet was inside the ellipse for instance somewhere here
so that is not the case
so only this part of the ellipse
is realistic
and this part of course is not
which you're being asked
to calculate what the zero was only based on the information of the five are
on the twenty degrees
and all the mass
and i can add to it
what is the velocity he a
and that's farthest away
and i can even add to it
what is the
so my major axis
where this is to a all that
comes for free
was that
and the knowledge that it goes out
five planet radio
and you meant to melt
articles are
and you know omentum
this conserved for these objects in orbit
mass little and but only
if you
take the angular momentum
relative to this point
i don't know what i call the point
looks like i call the he
i can hardly read quality for now
the angular momentum of this object in this orbit
is not conserved relative to any point
the only conservative to this point
sorry angular momentum relative to point c
at this moment in time
is the position vector which is capitol are
times the velocity
i have to multiplied by the sine of twenty degrees
so it is and
it is
and the right so we get a zero here
we get the capitol are here
and we get the sign
of twenty
are times
in the
that must also be
and the momentum
right here the the fact that the omentum is in the blackboard is no concern
to me i just want to know the magnitude
when the object is here
angular momentum is the position vector which is legs five or
the velocities v of eight
the angle is now ninety degrees of the sign of the angle is one
so i get an
ninety eight
nine five
i lose my deal and and i one equation with two unknowns
i don't know what the zero is
and i don't know what to ways
it is not a place
well these are conservative forces were dealing with gravity
mechanical energy must be conserved
what we used to use the same total energy of the system is conserved
the total energy of the system
is kinetic energy plus potential
must be conserved must be the same here
as it is there
one is the total energy here
kinetic energy
is one half
the zero square
what is the potential energy
this miners is and
and g
divided by
its distance to centre
which is capital are
that is the total energy
right here
the total energy here
could not have changed must therefore be
one half
if you have a scribd
and g
but now to these things
call five or
apart from the fact that i lose my little
notice i have the second equation
i didn't have any
well known
so i have two equations with two unknowns is zero
in view of a
and you can solve for that that you can find both
interestingly enough
you can also find the same major axis
because the total energy of the system
it's also minus and and
divided by
two a
this equation is also
on your exam
and so if you know v zero or you know v eight
then you can be and cancelled you can also calculate the so my major axis
doppler shift
let's do something about the operation
first doppler shift
of electromagnetic radiation lights
radio waves
a star moving relative to us
was the velocity v
since we're dealing with
electromagnetic radiation we don't have to ask whether the star is moving relative to us
we are moving relative to the stars the question is a meaningless question in special
you're here
you are receiving the frequency of prime
he was that star
and this the task is usually referred to as the sequence labeling
so we are given an input sequence a sequence x we want to reconstruct the
associated label sequence y where about the x and y have the equal length and
this of course sequence labelling can be used not only for named entity recognition before
many other tasks such as that
gene finding in computational biology for example
another task that involves structure that and we all analyse it is biological sequence alignment
and biological sequence alignment is especially useful when no one wanted to remind the similarity
between biological sequences in particular in this talk we concentrate my attention on global alignment
so we are given two sequences s one and s two
and the global alignment is an assignment of gaps such as to line up each
letter in one sequence either with a gap or a letter in the other sequence
this problem
can be modeled mathematically in this way we are given a sequence the player x
we want to predict the correct sequence y
of alignment operations in the simplest model we should just count the number of matches
mismatches and in its alignment and
alignments can be represented as you all probably know the park in the alignment graph
but that flows from the upper left to the lower right corner
in the graph
the problem that we analyse that involves structure that is the RNA secondary structure prediction
if the problem that we have an RNA sequence in the primary sector want to
predict the most likely secondary structure
and the secondary structure
his former since the sequence for the weights alpha two four f of the hydrogen
bomb and it's the study of her a secondary structure is particularly important in understanding
the function of around me
how do we model this problem when one of the problem of the sequence starting
problems so we are given an input sequence x i want to remind set part
three y if we have to find an appropriate context free grammar
as you probably already know i want to bring summaries
four two of object so we have a set of nonterminal symbols a set of
terminal symbols the set of rules that
connect the terminal and nonterminal symbols and starting symbol that should belong to the set
of non terminals
and for example on the right side of the screen we have an RNA sequence
we can afford it we can model the folding in that way
using the glamour that we have defined on the left of the screen
and for all the three problems that i have shown to you
no there is a generative a generative approach is possible
for example i will consider the most simple case in sequence labeling traditionally hidden markov
models and has been used for sequence labeling so but there are too many two
main drawback in using a HMM for this task the first drawback is that hmm
relies on independence assumption and so yes we assume that each observation is dependent only
on the current state and its state dependent only on the previous state and in
this way we can not model
long term the interaction between objects between was for example in a man the recognition
second drawback that we try to avoid is still is that it hmm if they
are typically trained by maximum likelihood estimation
this is suboptimal way of training has since the maximum likelihood criterium is not directly
related to the prediction accuracy of the model so we should try to devise a
method that is more directly related to the prediction accuracy
how to do that
recently discriminative models have been introduced and discriminative models essentially fifty five the probability of
possible output y
even an observation so they consider the conditional probability rather than joint probability and we
discriminative bottom models we do not have a problem of
independence assumptions like into narrative more and more of we can consider arbitrary features of
the observations and this can help us to model more complex problems in a more
effective way
it is a sample of conditional random fields in
an example is the chain conditional random fields that can show this morning
and so i already said that a lot of discriminative algorithms have emerged in the
last few years two
to solve this
the problem of complex structure prediction and you i would like to show how our
approaches for structure prediction and i will concentrate on the problem that i showed you
before so
the question that i have to answer are given a training set of correct pairs
of sentences and their associated entity types can we learn to extract entities from a
new word for new sentences
or given a training set of correct biological alignments can will to align two unknown
sequences and finally given a training set of corrects RNA secondary structures can we learn
to deter mine the secondary structure so for a new RNA sequence
of course this is not an exhaustive list of possible applications for example he managed
to make segmentation could be
another application or like gene gene finding in bioinformatics that there's a lot of applications
for this framework
well it's same thing you can use for selecting kernels
so this is a little bit about the current situation of SVM kernels
well so we we learn about the radial basis function kernel recalls her when only
there are quite a few a few other kernels
and you can even do combinations actually which is a bit later so so we
essentially physical situations so only only one we don't want to have to current
four uses they have trouble on selecting suitable kernel
but for researchers always singular which is designed kernels particulars the suitable for our target
you want knowledge
you should i those which should better cooperate domain knowledge as your current product
so it like we have two
contradictory goals
so that's why i think that those who thinks of contradicting his salary but practically
i think they the this is OK for to do is we actually very few
general kernels by general kernels
i mean
those are very very common basically what's
if you look at the four point of view is what related
so what do we do with the extension of the current so we see those
polynomial ten x i x j right so this a it's actually the middle son
of of going on so this somewhat related
so most to change the so-called generative model of similar types
so in this is we don't know many such kind of therefore for making this
they don't have many choices so that's good they don't have to worry so much
this is try some of them but
the researchers are also actively designing stationary kernels
please use this string string they so you're you're the instances and euclidean vectors any
more than you want to have some spatial kernels string kernels for such as it
it supports
i think without so
for beginners will just try to sequence but once you you know more than you
tried to to design your own kernels
so this is what saying that if you are
if you think we don't know yet you you have so that's why they are
so some of you are being
then you can use any of this function kernel for this reason is you look
at the end of the day you don't have any of these are used for
well this is a linear kernel then what i think is it is this is
a special case of you can so we have a theoretical results proving that the
performance of using exactly the same
you could under certain parameters
but use the internet for this year only for the last penalty parameter c but
these are the kind of these two parameters you don't need to tell you what
it was kernel parameters got so of course shows for the new kernel others and
see is a example of different kernels
we started seeing got
he says he tried parameters to set the parameters for kernel
well then you are guaranteed to perform at least as good as using these kernels
so that's assuming control you
because was
the issues here that this situation that i think still on the training in
and polynomial kernels with the reason of using it is because numerical difficulties
we doing this work curating available to
the degree of d which
did the inside of processes is actually smaller than one in
degrees small that this very is very very close to zero
the unconscious if it's quite one and the degrees all the
it becomes a very large so
in something you do it is easy interface numerical difficulties
one of the issues here is that the
many of these these models grow quite large and become unmanageable in terms of the
the overall size of the model for some of the common techniques applied for learning
joint models a so-called search and score methods and so it's more likely that what
are called constraint based methods these methods to look for local little evidence that is
valid and for the global model is a is going to be the better way
to go because
building and learning the structure and parameters of really large models large relational spatial and
temporal models seems to me unlikely to be tractable
finally i think social scientists again are going to have something to say about what
sort of algorithms we would want to use here there are unlikely to be willing
to turn over complete control to some algorithm and we talked for many years in
this field about
having interactive systems but i think social scientists with the for working with their going
to look at and so we really want this to be seriously interactive and also
not going to be able to encode all their domain knowledge in machine readable form
and so it's going to have to be more like a design environment then it
is a system for just dumping in your data and getting it last topic briefly
i want to talk about his privacy it's a kind of overriding issued all of
these things this is where the the snow story in our story diverge
snow was able to access large amounts of data about individuals because of the different
historical situation that we have today today's computational social scientists have a very different environment
was of
a paper published last year brief paper about computational social science in science magazine and
one of the quotes in that
i was about to perhaps what they call the thorniest challenges to computational social science
is about access to data and privacy of the individuals in the data
computational social sciences usually about people
and about their level actions and interactions and that is difficult to get access to
and unfortunately is now being increasingly silent individual organisations that can analyse their own data
but not go outside and the concern is that really good work in computational social
science will end up being all about a single organisations working only on the data
they have access to
now the news that i have on this is not a particularly good unfortunately but
it's some very recent work one of my students michael hay
has looked at networks and said well how does the privacy equation change in networks
if this is the original network we can imagine naively anonymizing by just taking off
identity and if we just remove identity then really it should be particularly identifiable unfortunately
what is shown is that if you have a little bit of information about node
say how many friends they have many friends the friends have you can very frequently
re identify individuals within the network this is true just of notional networks it's true
very large real networks here's the for instance
o point five million nodes if you know how many friends and individual house that's
what we call h one knowledge and it's only possible to return people in a
very small number of cases but if you know how many friends their friends how
you could really identify uniquely about half of the individuals in the network that network
signature provides of a quasi identifier for individuals
about the only positive thing that i can say right now is first of all
michael has worked out of several individual kinds of analyses that you can do meeting
very strong privacy definitions including looking at the degree distribution degree histogram but in terms
of many other kinds of analyses done in this community it's very hard to do
driven by the the observations
when you put that together with say this observation of one blue marble in one
bag what this is saying is well i know there's lots of different colours out
there but
mostly women in estimating that theta i should go with the observations since the observation
is blue
but i'm going to pay most of the way there and and and i'm not
going to get strictly just
spike on blue just delta function there because i have some role the priors like
get smoothing but my best guess is probably the next draws rogan the blue whereas
if i had this situation here just to contrast you would have done is just
all the bands from the same marble which just permute them across bags shuffle them
up so that all the bags are kind of look about the same intuitively or
he like all of the variation in the population of balls is now
on average there in any one individual bags
and then of course our status are going to be
much more blurred out but that's how the way we kept higher level is with
an alpha value now that's much greater than one is supposed to much less than
one that saying that for any for any given bad we expect if you like
the the prior to exert relatively much more weight than any one individual draw
so that when we see just this one little thing here well you know we
we do
so i think it's slightly more likely to be bluer than anything else but most
of our inference is based on
the prototype coming from the prior so we don't in the this is the case
in which we're not going to make a strong inference about what else coming because
i've seen basically the bags could be just about anything
OK so so is essentially what our model says here is we're going to we're
going to get out apply this disclaimer was question
this one
since we are
it is going to have to
yes it is one of the
apart from that of
a lot of
our article
yes it so that so
well probably the many possible and to that i would say that one of the
things we want to do here if you want to be able to learn an
inductive bias that's going to generalize to new categories and that we're going to do
this take a very simple representation in which will have the dimension of shape and
the dimension of color dimension of material essentially and it's high at
a many valued discrete
dimension like you know a multinomial with many bands which is kind of like constantly
thinking about basic level categories you know imagine that are our perceptual system gives us
two thousand ten thousand basic level shape categories as well as basic level color and
other sorts of things
then we want to be able to learn something which is going to generalize across
different values of this multinomial
and the pretty much the only way we can do that is if we have
some parameter which captures the abstract knowledge independent of any particular value that could be
it's just as all show you want i get to this concrete example we want
something which is going to generalize to
new values of
or you know values of this variable haven't even been observed
is that
help make sense
but OK
so so here's concretely how we apply this model to this case we say we're
gonna represent the objects with various dimensions which are going to be these each dimension
if you like is a high dimensional discrete variable so that i think in this
case there were no how high this is something like twenty or fifty shape categories
and various texture and colour categories and size categories
we we observed
just just as an experiment two objects in each of these four types and there
are those that to have the same shape value in each category but different values
of texture and color and so on and indeed also different values of shape across
categories and different values of texture and color
and then we're going to be given during testing some new object here
let's which let's say we're told is in category five also has a new shape
and also has a new texture also the nucleus it's different than the things we've
seen on every
but we want to be able to learn something which is going to generalize in
this case basically
so that's the way we do this is we're going to learn one of these
dirichlet multinomial models for each of these dimensions sort separately so we're basically we're trying
to learn for each dimension
how does the variation across the population
concentrate in bags versus across banks
and that allows us essentially to learn that the shape dimension looks like this so
it's it's very homogeneous within bags whereas the other dimensions look like this
and that's what i see in new
object it's only along the dimension shape and i'm going to be able to make
a strong generalizations about the
of hydrogen which is the fundamental spectrum of all time and then after that G
H cause they're out of ideas so that that was it so
now let's take a look at what l equals 0 l equals 0 this means
you have a satirical or circular
a spherical orbital a circular orbit and that's easy to remember because all is think
of it as perfect spheres
right when l equals 1 this is elliptical
you have an elliptical orbit you can think of that 0 is 0 and 1
can think of that as there's some elongated OK and when l equals to 1
l equals two I'll show you these later in the in about a week's time
they're just much more complex you get dumbbell shape doughnut shaped and all sorts of
things just say the more complex
so those are the numbers associated with certain shapes of the
orbital then the next quantum number he gave us was m m which is the
magnetic quantum number it's the magnetic quantum number and it speaks to the question of
orientation orientation
and the admissible values of M . L
l minus 1 3 0 0 down to
line itself so
spanning from plus delta minus across l is subject to the values of and so
in the case of n equals 1 when n equals 1
Elkan people only 0 so was 0 than this value and must always be zero
and indeed this confirms the observations there was no line splitting magnetic field for the
ground state wasn't
what happens when n equals 2 when equals to well l can take values of
1 and 0
1 and 0 so what do we have we have now an equals to l
equals 1 so can now go 1 0 and minus 1 1 0 and minus
so this is the 1 case where there is some value and thinking about the
Cartesian equivalent of this is very dangerous when you're talking about the a quantum ideas
to try to scribe physical attributes to them because in many cases just doesn't doesn't
work but in this case I think it does so let's look at 3 values
of the magnetic quantum number when we have an elliptical orbit
right so
1 way of thinking about it is here the 3 principal coordinate directions x y
and z
no I don't know where real X lies but once I choose x I can
use the right hand rule and I know where y and z have to be
there orthogonal
so this is X is why this is the
I have a non spherical nonaxisymmetric orbital so for simplicity just make it
well what the say it says can go 1 0 minus 1 which to my
mind represents the fact that there are 3 principal coordinate directions in which you can
orient so I think this is a nice example of mathematics imitating reality OK after
that it gets tickets and then the last quantum number this is where this is
where I
Sommerfeld left it but I'll finish by introducing the last quantum number last quantum number
came a little bit later it's lower case s which is the spin quantum number
in it represents the fact that the electron is considered have spent and it takes
values plus or minus 1 half
and here's the here's the basis for this value here I want to put this
all together so that I'm doing a little bit of
back to the future because this is 960 that's for Sommerfeld leaves this comes about
1925 but I want you to have all quantum numbers and then we can move
forward and what introduced this was
an experiment conducted by Stern Gerlach in front
and that was done around 19 21
you can make this up will have a look at all this is cute this
is what I think is unilaterally image here's this is this is Sommerfeld on the
occasion of his 80th birthday and as is the custom for about a Berthier so
and there's people from all over the world get together for a party and the
accompany this with the 2 or 3 affair in which people give scientific papers in
honor of the celebrate so this is taken from the book that was published on
the occasion of Sommerfeld 80th birthday and since Sommerfeld was the 1 that propose that
orbits could be spherical or elliptical they as a as a gag said that well
here's Sommerfeld here Sommerfeld somewhat the standard so this is l equals 0 and this
is l equals 1 and this was accompanied by the inscription said Sommerfeld was the
1 who taught us that the circle is the degenerate form of the ellipse
and that was really funny that's that's 19 twenties geek humor that was off roaring
cities but clearly it doesn't age well you're not you're not you're not sensing that's
OK here's the Stern Gerlach experiment very very cool experiment they were doing studies in
the early twenties to try to validate Maxwell's equations so they got over here is
a furnace with a crucible of liquid metal and the metal has obviously vapor pressure
above and there's a sled here and I'm gonna
we have to answer the question what howard hughes del threats directly we let's imagine
that we've we've sold out in a sense more question to is
how do you choose
between different measures the goodness-of-fit
i'm not saying you know these is a good
measure just the first one sort of
has anyone got another approach to
to this
methods to be more to optimize gradient descent which suggested that is not too important
how we optimize as long as we find
the optimal when we've done optimization it will spit out i guess
the animals that at the best fit value of lambda
there's anyone have
another approach because there are many approaches you get taught when you're being taught
ad hoc statistical methods
and i'm sure some of you sort of methods that don't look like this or this
product again since you say
so what's the problem gaussians approach to
answering the question what is lambda
okay so
what since you have in mind for this this problem
okay data points that's x-coordinates
okay the x coordinates all these guys are exponentially distributed maybe i need to make
it clear what the assumption is a accent
given lambda
the window edges eh
when i say exponential it's
one of these
this thing it's minus
x is
between three
and this
in the wrong order
where z is the normalisation constant z is integral
from i to be
it minus
so the actual probability density at each x if we knew lambda is
an exponential
there are possibly some gassings running around in this for example
if i define a bin
and if we measure the count of how many points arrived in not being
it may be true that the probability distribution in fact count
which is actually a distribution over integers it may be reasonably well approximated as a gas so that's a possible
direction you could go in the does that definitely does involve
gas fumes
but there's anyone else have a completely different
approach to this
what you know did anyone studied physics
one of the
yeah the physicist over there
isn't it the case that when
little young physicists setosa to do stuff with the data
they're told you get the data
rearrange the equation that predicts the data given the parameters in such a way that
you get a straight line graph
then for the straight line is not one of the rules of how to do
statistical inference
let me run the idea
this will be
given lambda i am be
this is minus one lambda
divided by z
z depends on lambda be
if we points x
how can we turn this law into some sort of straight line well
first multiplied by a little window
as we have people who have been side effects and given lambda be
times delta x
that's now
to the whole map of the sky
this mountain here if you look closely is
blue words which are kind of context what would seem
you would see that these are basically and threats from the texts so this is
the first works pretty well
and it's very what's even more important is very efficient to calculate
because music and we just need to
if you have to sort of vectors then we just need to look at the
intersection of the words which is
which can be calculated pretty fast by
using this low-level machine
o operations
and the end we get a similarity between zero and one so
zero meaning orthogonal documents in one more of the same
so what what the typical scenarios for visualisation
by having this so-called bag of words representation so this is the one which i
just explained
usually performed some kind of clustering algorithm so we try to cluster
group points which are kind of more similar together and then we reported by the
clusters so if he we would both rules
most of these position approaches we would
i see that most of them basically do clustering in some way
and then we basically metadata clusters into two d and three d space before we
one three example but we
we have also many other two d example
we to because the narrow which gives you a little bit later is also
visualizing text based on this score occurrences of words
and phrases
from the text so this is also the way how we can see certain certain
and so some of these people because in areas are is asian of document collections
before we had such an example of visualisation of search results from c
one examples like this and one example of was see also on the
position of the document timeline so let's in news stories and so
now i go briefly through a couple of
examples so maybe i can see the actual algorithm so this is to first i
was going to
systems are two algorithms which
we're being here in ghana
basically the first one is based on the
visualizing texts as so first we build a graph out of the document collection then
we basically visualizing the graph
me to give you an example so let's say if the
in this case we have a collection of seventeen hundred documents project descriptions from some
kind of project descriptions and here the
generate two clusters
and so
each cluster is represented by the most representative works of by by the highly weighted
words of the from which is basically the must point of that particular
last so
having just to cluster we don't see much we just see that there's a good
set of
documents of projects within the collection about services
that's where the system is so basically it's very general here
and the other one is about learning quantum so these are several topics are hidden
in this class if you go from two to three
topic kind leads into
two top topics then the future is clear
if you go
let's a two
then we already see the whole picture
again a little bit here here we can see
cultural heritage education museum studies of project which europe finding missing from this area education
in in
cultural heritage and so on so is one thing
clustering we can see also the
wikimedia projects in speech and so on and so
what we basically do
we take the texts
we perform k means clustering
and the connected clusters which are kind
more similar to each other the cause and this things the front between the mouth
points of the
each cluster
n but reconstructed the graph and then we just draw graphs and this is the
procedure here and then we already
sort of structure
so here think
musicians to twenty groups of the same got document collection here
you can see
to already about the details but let's say this is
medical project is this you station and and cultural heritage
and so on
another similar approach
again is based on the clustering but uses slightly different idea
o is
something what we call filing
based musician some some some other people you use the word three three men as
so the idea here is
again pretty similar as before but we use here instead of k means clustering so
flat clustering scheme uses
hierarchical class class
and basically on the first step we split all the documents which have in our
collection into
two clusters like before
and split also the area
the air drawing area was in the same proportions
how in the same proportion how many projects documents fell into one group or the
so obviously it is slightly more like and the next step
simply because perform clustering
for each of these groups so for the next step would be the discrete group
is split down into
distance between them then the affinity between w is going to be high is going
to be close to one in this case
if s and s are
the distant from each other then w and is going to be close to zero
not volume or node degree is the sum
all of the edges
that are connected to the nodes from the end
in the end is the creation of the critical quantity the corsican quantity and what
so it's important to remember the end
it is the sum of all edges
that are connected
to the end nodes
this is the no this is the volume of the volume of a cluster is
to compute the value of got to what we need to do is simply go
over all of the nodes in the cluster in some of the volumes
we basically go over each node in some of the edges that are connected
to that node
the cut between two clusters to subgraphs with this is a graph and one of
partition the graph into one subgraph in the second subgraph then the cut
it is the sum of the edges
but we need to take out
together partitioning
now we can think about different kind of graph cuts or a different kind of
criteria so to define the graph cut or to use the graph to find partitioning
one would simply be to find the partition we want to cluster made or putting
a partition the graph we can look for the partitioning of that
minimizes the cost to british and this is the graph we're looking for the partition
that minimizes
the edges of the weights of the edges to pick out get partitioning in this
what it means is that we need to think about this page
and if we want to partition the data this graph into two subgraphs
the end up having one subgraph theory
and the other one being the only the soul
that aside
this is this is not very good criteria to have a reasonable partitioning of graphs
a good partitioning of a graph and the reason here is that the reason is
that it tends to come out nodes that are on the edge
of the dataset and if you have an accuracy of one point which is far
then through and you will end up if you implement this if you this going
you you can end up separating between this outlier and the rest of the data
an alternative would be the normalized cut
the normalized cut is using the cut itself
this is exactly same cut this year
but the protein but it also introduce the trade in it
what about the cut made this quantity here now this quantity is the sum of
one over the volume of the first cluster
plus one over the volume of the second cluster
why why is it doing anything
which we might consider good because that if we look at the volume of a
if this cluster is a small number of nodes that it includes are small and
the volume of this cluster is small then the this quantity is going to be
and the trade-off between uris before between having
between picking out a small number of edges
but not ending up in same cluster clusters which volume that is too small get
balance between
making as few edges as we can but still think clusters which are relatively large
if you implement for example if do if you human this criterion if you optimize
this quality criterion you can end up having this kind of partitioning of data
now finding the solution for
for minimizing or the solution the minimizes to find a good source low normalized cut
is combinatorial this is the broken combinatorial problem so to find the solution is NP
and we know that we usually want to run away from NPR problems in one
five the approximation the partition the about here is the spectral graph partitioning
this is basically an approximation for this problem
i'm going to see different ways of looking at spectral clustering as an approximation
for minimizing the normalized cut
so what is expected clustering
one third somebody told me that so well with the with the loss of spectral
clustering is at the north pole clustering is take some affinity matrix you find tagging
and the k means over there and that's it
and his right i mean you a lot
o five or and you have a lot of criteria then you have a lot
of different ways of initializing there are many papers about the clustering and they lot
differences between them but the basic thing the basic idea in all of these methods
is that you're going to represent data is the graph
and instead of putting edges you can simply summarize it in the matrix
and then you're going to
find some other matrix this matrix w is the metrics that the n n entry
of this matrix would be the affinity between
the end in the end nodes
so we're going to take the data we can define some graph vary by
plugging all the affinity values in the matrix is defined new matrix a
if you look at
other people publishing about
potentially far more interesting topics and amazon
there's a fair number of interest
on making money into the air
you over a variety of forms and
before which all it
when we apply
machine learning techniques to
the interest from what we actually
look at whether which tried track and the i'm sure some people here
i gave
i gotta be complaining to me about
who is found so images
this guy that
brought understand we see it here so
the first categories they
the applies not mentioned so
so this is very much like emails from somebody's going to tag directly
that's right through something probably clicking the link
with transparent
so people tried to monetize
search is very similar to
people trying to monetize web searches
andrew if all spam which
spam it right to essentially
build out the following the follower network
and then sell it for money forum spam to them sometime in the future
so if you look at those dead spam
they can be classified into
low-dimensional stands short-term interests so they follow families
probably long-term interest because it takes time to build networks
and those guys are very much shorter
so as long as they can monetize things
pretty fast
is is a quick going for them
so the question is like can we actually the fact that the interesting patterns of things
for spam detection and don't
just a show you a couple of examples
probably not very visible here but
what this shows is essentially is they
patterns of user interaction
in terms of applying
four three users
you probably don't see those kinds of connections here but what is interesting here is like a lot of
normal users
quote unquote inter
communicate primality locally so people are friends
people they follow
in more or less
the same geographical location
if you look at the patterns found which probably not all the visible here but we should be seeing here
is that a lot of long term collections
coming from various places
and also many connections corresponding to
people living in the same area so those mentions essentially corresponding to
from interactions
so the the data
related to be
interaction and the network which is very meaningful for detecting spam
just to
wrap up really wanted to give credit to a lot of people
which were wear on building out infrastructure
from various size
both the core machine learning and the building pipelines
think feature extraction so you can create all of them
but those collective mind the primary
creators of the system
about half of the two
and the boston precautions i
so you may be interesting comment when you talked about what definition of big data
is in the definition with something like
if you have to have a data warehouse
that it's big data
and the like question is
researchers like us who don't happen to have data warehouses lying around actually ever do research on big data
i think so
i mean they interesting thing about the big data is
well to analyze various problems you very rarely need all the data at the same time
so if i say that really needs they
warehouse the processes they got
it means that all the components of the service
needed but these are the components and all parties graph
only a fraction of the data
so from the user's perspective
you can
look at
data repositories but no maybe which fit on on lot data center
can you may be talk about how you did the recommendations for the who to follow
task because this
doesn't really fit in but u
said so far i mean you can do it with the methods features
mentioned but maybe there
but the ones that most
well i can give you all the details on how it works
you know who to follow as a problem involving essentially commendation over a graph
so you might say about
are there variety of all
relevance propagation on the graph
we don't require machine learning
but i'm just going to say that if u
take the same signals which you can build you know heuristically or in
there is some formalism
and using in features in machine learning process we have labels from
using interactions
you can probably improve on this quite a bit
so hopefully up kind of request
they have indicators of how this is impacting in users
how is it impacting
on to decisions i mean how the
perceiving the benefit
of these different techniques and the
in the daily use of of of
i was sure i mean i cannot tell you well it's improving by x percent
very soon GPU
i will look into the catalogue
and you will see that there is no there is no such
compute that match demand
well maybe there but it's a
it's quite right
six in order to compute and that's it
it's very very when you don't need
another approach what you can do you can divide it up to a number of
and this is horizontal scale
and to be very very
naive and stupid judge just
a rule for summarisation
vertical scanning because the
horizontal scaling physical
so if you're developing an essay i need
OK so with that because you always you always have elements
elements of the modern state of the art hardware
and this limited things the kind but actually it's very easy to him
and when you can create
it is on the scale
it's always who
because he always kennedy
from secondhand cheap computation for the grand prize
and create huge data because way much more fully three and right now it's another
problem gases so
but at least you don't have radical colima close to you
how can do horizontal
we can do it in two dimensions
we can
because you know we always have data and algorithms data function
again group
data by function and became who function by date
about our search engine what does it mean
we can say OK
we don't want to remove documents from from computer to computer
implement all indexing on this the on
on this
and the do all snippet generation of this computer therefore this computer
keep all information about documents
but this candidate is not powerful enough to keep all index
so the whole all
of all of the form of the following this to another
all we can
another another way can simply divide collections to all computers and do inference
so it depends
but you always have these these two options how to solve this problem we always
had this charge
and of course the allow them all
right approach is something in the middle
sometimes moving functions sometimes moving day
the problem is why
so we are talking about the article scaling is good but
OK let's let's use only on the
horizontal sky
they don't use only for example scala
because it's not linear
you can always divide your original simply any number of parallel algorithms
and everything will be OK
simply because
you need to
so what if your charisma always not linear
if you are doing indicating a practicing all your documents in the number of computers
in parallel
there are some moments maybe in the future but you it's unavoidable when you merge
everything into one index
if you're doing so much you distribute your request with the class sunlight you need
to be combined together
well maybe
during the execution introduce some operations about the
this is the first problem
the second problem is that you when you create set
not all resources multiply
if you have to compute
speed of the network is maybe one gigabit per second
if you have three computers of for compute
you resources talking about CPU memory and all the time
committed twice
but the speed of your network if you want to go by second in you
one usually last
because there are collisions in network
so this is a principle limitation
what developer said that trying to find this limitation they're trying to
not what we don't need all synchronization and all communication based on the number of
big number of computers
they trying
not to use the resources that can be scale
combine this with sources such way that they can be used in a scalable way
we need a mathematical model because
as i said in the beginning a lot of people here the programmers in the
system is it's only considers two players because it was the chess and it in
a way it really disregard draws it's not very good at handling draws it doesn't
have this epsilon delta there the ideas that we model the probability that player i
wins over player j in a very similar way as we just did using a
cumulative calcium here this just the model that you have got for one player standard
at it that is skilled accounting for the other player in the sampling model is
that you you draw in number from each of these gaussians and it's then the
probability distribution of one of these numbers being greater than the other
so it's pretty much like our assumption was
but now in the user moving average estimators so
the probability is further out the first game
it is updated by just using the old estimator for that
and weighted by one minus of
and take with all the new result into account
so that's the underlying equation and in addition to make that work you have to
assume that a constant average skill so each game is really is zero sum game
is if two players play if one goes up and the other one has to
go down by the corresponding amount
also in you don't maintain the distribution over these assets but must represent the number
in addition in the there's a linear approximation made
because you have to use the phi function here
you approximate that phi functions in the early around zero
and you see that this is good in the
in a certain area
but becomes quite bad outside this area
but it makes the calculation much easier and
yes the result of that
what you see here is again the difference in skills if you like of the
two players and and he the update that results from the game
if one player wins against the other and what you see here is that again
there is relatively little happening in this regime which is no surprise regime but in
the surprise regime you see that the e update here and here
kind of thresholds so if you beat a much stronger player nominally stronger player then
you get only a very limited reward for that and that's the problem with you
look at the same time so this is in comparison our function at the same
time of course this form here create a certain robustness of the system because there
are certain outrageous game results do not spoil the statistics
so this is the update equation for you know which is really pretty straightforward if
you have a table of the phi function here and that's also used in many
video games
and just to summarise some of the properties you can view it as an approximation
of this music system but due to the linear approximation it deteriorates matchmaking using this
after this approximation was very good around zero when people had very similar nominal playing
strength but it became bad at this on the sides right so you need very
good match making you can just pair kasparov for example with the very weak chess
player that would lead the chances are still for example that they draw and that
would pull down kasparov in you know quite a bit so that's one of the
it was only when teams one
one point of the distribution and can essentially be viewed as a fixed stepsize version
there are some aspects of course you you know it's designed for two players but
so is is quite limited in in that respect
so there's a ranking in halo two as well but i would like to
the reason i would like to move on to some results because we tried out
the system on on the data that we obtain from this beta testing and we
just wanted to know what was going on that we didn't became first
and so there are five different so-called hoppers those different games time game types that
being played and for example in the free all hopper that's the one we just
want to ramp up as many kills as you possibly can there were sixty thousand
games there with about six thousand players and another hopper which is one where versus
one that's more like it dueling situation where one player a plays against one another
they played on different maps and they different games being played and since there were
not so many people the matchmaking had to be relatively relaxed so it happened that
you were paired with much stronger with much weaker players that of course it always
gets better if you have a larger population than you can always find better matches
now here's the plots for two players that we looked at charis is a hamlet
two legend
people regularly think that he cheats because he's so good
and the sequel wildman is the guy who won the freefall hopper
he's obviously working in the sequence of a group microsoft so here's the number of
games played and what you see here is the value of mu plus minus one
standard deviation for for these two players
and this is the typical kind of plot development over games that you can make
as he was looking inside the data space so this is a sensible can function
for this application
as you expand and again
so now we are here
if i correctly then you just stay where he was
as you leave the area
they fetching post
lessons from this is
of yourself
on the web for people is the set
you can see most slide them in there
you can sort of animating
but it is not
considering that the four hundred and five hundred sixty dimensional space you're trying to
this two-dimensional embedding in business
sort of constraints on what he
so i guess i'll just show quick digits one
there is a quite fun as well so we can do the same thing with
their digits dataset
this is a
let's look at this
these demos are on the web every experiment is on the web you can recreate
all this in the convenience of your own home
get these are the USPS digits i show the results from the small
so they had some three is over
they change shape
here's some to use the skinny too fat too
as the ones in here
so small associated with the ones that can move from the twos to the threes
and you get some sort of change the morphing into a three not necessary in
any way you might expect i think it's quite nice move to the falls on
there is at some point maybe it's not this visualization from the zero is where
you get the zeros with missing talks
so you go
unique solution has many different solutions that would be appropriate for this kernel is just
a visualisation you could run again with different initialisation into get something completely different
so you can evaluate as an advantage when it comes to you claim it's a
disadvantage what you clever you claim it's an advantage because you say things like
which would project into two spaces in latent space is one of the bank enterprise
you one for a tree branch
and for multimodality in the latent variable space which you can do with kernel PCA
you can do with this guy seems to depend on your application
space we observe space here
yes each x being given by
individual casting process
independent gaussian process
and that's what PCA tells us PCA is doing with linear
that's impressive
and said that PCA
but i think people have done this GTM as well is that we can consider
different types of models are here
we've got we've been talking that you know it's so far should move quickly on
so this isn't
which is binary a by images
database that we can either do
you know if you want to that i mean who knows what
i'm going to take advantage of the probabilistic
nature of the model and see what happens
which is previously seen before i delete pixels to reconstruct the
can reconstructing even with the united
constructing the threshold over what output is or
it is given one or zero
still have included let's just assume all missing pixels i now PCD
it is a sample of than the ones who pixels removed to use the pixels
removed is the reconstruction from noise is the reconstruction from the newly really nice
on the twenty three percent it's hard with to go
and i said this is that i mean the interpretation is that probabilistic model
and you can see
i mean is well known to british but typically the same
king these
which led to the tall
like this
what is the
being here which i think probably are
looks like it two which is what you would hope
i think this is the data set which has all the values so we're used
to getting with one or regression
i hope
so now
integrated missing
we can do
which is just a regular PCA
that's great
move away from the origin that's what we expect
and it's p and b
on the interesting things is probably too small
this is a clinic
or they were killed
i can see
i mean if you visual things in this world
if there is a region
well whole typically
that killed it so you might suggest that he might reconsider when he
he kills the horse
the GTM can have high dimensional spaces with TTN you have to increase the number
of points also with st network b
partitions that set different classifications different partitions the pattern is the same for each of
these but some of the partitions the harder to predict them out so this is
a significant so it in
as you do this kind of
you get a decrease in error rate so there is some validity in going to
harvard in two dimensions for that date
i probably won't have much time for discussion to one of the nice things about
this work
if someone else
downloaded from the web
and use it in inverse kinematics so since then
especially the united states
there is no
we then they are also human
it's not just on this
all that
in the real
this is lot
we don't
the model
show here
it's here
there are three
are not so the or
the people think it's only PCA is also something unsupervised and it's not difficult also
or you could say density estimation is also unsupervised to just get points and do
something with your points they're just very clearly find rest masses what you could do
that can be on
OK of course the second thing
that's the thing i want to go into
after the slides
that we don't really know what the ground truth is so
i said in density estimation its unsupervised but of course this the true density which
which generated our data and we know that even though we don't have any we
don't get hints about this density directly and we know that this is the thing
we want to achieve in the and so somehow even though we don't know what
this the ground truth in the back which might help us
to get our results are two to prove that certain evidence to what we want
to do whatever
and of course that's not the case in clustering because it's really hard to define
but OK we would see different definitions later on and one could say OK
now i give the definition so now is it easier
and then i think this is a very important point
which just sort of figured out the last half year so
in practice the thing which makes clustering
so difficult is that
the clustering of the data set something global
so somewhere in classification what you can do is to get a certain dataset
so you get a data set was
a positive points
the negative points
now someone asks you OK i guess this new point
which labelings should give to the this new point
and then you would say OK i mean you build classifier inference on but essentially
what this classifier what do it
so what is classified do is someone would looking local
neighborhood of your data points
and site
decide what this label should get based on the on the neighborhood of all the
and you and and like to design a classification algorithm in the end it's the
same you just have to use k nearest neighbour you just saying look at the
k nearest neighbour points and give them the label so somehow if i want to
solve the classification problem
the question which label i give to this data point has no influence whatsoever on
the question whether give the data so if i have enough data can just look
at my small pointed out and i can optimize my classifier locally that's a very
important point
and then clustering now are different because it might very well influence like if i
have a data point here for example which is in the middle
so clustering some the global property and just say i want to have groups of
points which are which has something to do with each other and if i decided
that maybe this point and this point has nothing to do with
then it would be stupid maybe to say
and i also have to point that those two point has something to do with
it some of their more global influences so interface i some optimisation problem like the
graph cut we
we just discussed yesterday
they just can't edges between different points you can just go to one data point
ignore the rest of the of your class of data points and say OK i
the the cluster label to decide which cluster this point is just look at the
local level that can do this because i need to look at everything
and that's why
and i think that's really important point that's why why clustering
in the end is
like optimisation problems to come up with much much harder
and that's what we had yesterday there always turn out to be NP hard whatever
you do
and it's not so easy to solve this thing that's
very important reason
OK now let's try how to come up so with different ways of defining what
the clustering so the simplest way we that's also what we did yesterday yesterday's
OK just invent your own quality funds and you say
clustering should minimize the normalized cut
normalized cut is a well-defined function some all and then you can go ahead and
normalize it and
everything is fine tunnels so that's a clear way of defining what clustering is
but of course it's also it's pretty ad hoc i mean you
just you just come up with some quality function and say k means to minimize
minimize something like so case the number of
o point in your clusters
thanks i minus exchange square and
now we take square area but we also could take the absolute value we could
look at different norm we could solve this normalizations i mean it's it's really something
pretty arbitrary so
so if you would like
if you would like to come up with a definition of clustering which would set
in fact satisfy everybody someone would really be hard to design objective function
everybody would agree to it
another approach to define what clustering is
it's based on density estimation so
it's more this in the statistics communities so people say OK we were in in
this setting that all data points have been drawn according to some probability distribution
and maybe if we would know the probability distribution it would look like this
in clusters on areas
where we have lots of density so because you have many points which
a very small distance to each other somehow we would say they form cluster because
they related to each other
then there's nothing in between
and then we have another cluster where we have lots of points which are very
close to each other
so somewhere you could say OK just defined classes two
sort of correspond to all clubs in identity
and that's what actually many people doing what many people work
of course we need to make it a bit modified precisely you could for example
clusters are density level sets to level set of identity
something very simple
at least in theory
so if you have a density
their probability
so we sum i have to make in order to marginalize some i have to
this three-dimensional matter applicable to this two-dimensional set
in a way that gives is exactly the value
that the marginal whitaker
OK and the way we do that is we take the preimage under projection now
what does that mean all the points
the put project to the set
and since the projection is axis parallel
that is the set which simply
we continue the same here
think of taking the set
and just moving in in both directions
up to infinity
so it's like if this will be a circle
and this set would be useful in
and they actually called probability actually called cylinder sets for exactly that reason
these concepts which are images production so if this is a then the set
is the preimage under the projection
o thing
OK and now we have we can we can compute are marginal down here
in terms of the measure mu j
by simply applying u j
to this
how does that fit in with the with the probability that we're are used to
what we have to do when you marginalized in terms of density
and one variable that you want to marginalize out you have to integrate right you
have to integrate the variable
and basically
integrating out the certain variables
corresponds to
if you if you think of integration as something something i walk along c
some set and summing up over the set and what you're doing is you're you're
walking in this direction
but the
this is the probability measure
and the overall space
justice has measure one total
so this might be infinitely large
but it does mean it has infinite measure
so some more green is that we are all the same is true is not
because you could have some somebody maybe like this and project to the set
but the preimage is much longer than that potentially
my name is
of the five
in my view be
that's right
so it's up product space if you will stop product of this product which which
defines something and j
this is the same
by one
you would have to delete in the two cases you would have to delete different
so if if if these two
if these two entries correspond to i one
and these structures correspond to i two
and the projection of onto i one would be to delete this are one and
the projection onto i two would be to first
it's really important to distinguish these different sets of letters of texas labels and not
just look at the dimension of the county dimensions
because they can overlap and we might have different marginal distributions on
i have about thirty five minutes i think i can make this mistake probably
three of one more time
OK now
we already said before that that if we if we have a stochastic process that
we take the marginals
then these marginals must sometimes be consistent
there must be
usually quite the same under marginalization and if we have this protection here
then we can formalise this in this manner he that we say
the marginal
so if we
we we posit measure mu j on each
on each finite dimensional subspace for each day
now if we
we can compute we know how to compute the marginal
on some subspace on the guy
another condition that we have is that the the the the measures that we start
with to define or process on the finite dimensional subspaces must be all marginals of
each other
and that is simply say
new JMU i are two members of my family and i take the and and
on the guy is the subspace of omega j
and it takes this projection which is marginalisation then have to end up with exactly
the space
with exactly the measure that i defined before
on my subspace omega i simply
consistency and under marginalisation
there are different names for such systems of probability distribution some people in probability called
consistent and some people called the projector
and i
i advertise calling them projective because we also doing lot statistics here
and the
in statistics were consistent simply has a a lot of different meanings and we don't
need to add another
another one right
i call this the projective projective family
and now what this this serum that i mentioned the congo extension theorem tells us
if we have a project family of measures
on all the finite dimensional subspaces of our space
then there exists a unique measure on the on the overall space
which has these as its marginal
OK let's let's think for
the intuition i would like to convey about this theorem is
it's not
you know you seem to have to wait too long either you run out of
memory can do anything you know you wait for three months and then finally
pc tells aidan of memory you know that
so so that's why it is limits you put in
from microarray data
there are thousands of genes you know they
you know
just saying no
up to two hundred
you know
my the probes could be put in there
so for all practical purposes there might be able to find
expressions in very very soon
the data sets
is going crazy
and typically proteins acting in humans
probably two million of them
so you can
get lots of important fourteen expressions
quite easily
so the problems are becoming harder and and how to deal with these things
formica my courage with did that so so the way
and i don't
was done what they've done is
they they did some initial
preprocessing before they went to
my fear is that it very simple
know entropy kind of based correlations to look back
then they said OK these genes seems to
behaved morally similarly
we reduce the dimensionality by looking at similarity groups and sometimes it's also possible that
the you know in the given discipline people might know that how the regulatory system
works or four
it's a for the humans
i and they can group proteins together because they have prior knowledge
so using those things you can reduce the dimensionality by grouping those and that's what
he has done when they did that they were able to actually mind the
these contrast patterns which i shown you earlier today
following cancer that's what they've done
so they could a gene club is a set of k genes strongly correlated with
a given gene and the classes so that that's how to do that
some emerging patterns discovered using this method were shown earlier and in is a set
the following patterns that are
hundred per cent appearing in one tissue
one kind of tissue
i'm almost no presence
in the other tissues
you can use for example
tree structures
again there's a guy
jerry how is now
university of illinois
he became incredibly families
by basically one paper
which is
if we treat
so once you become families then you especially if you're in good university
you become even more because you attract really branch to
the secret to become a families is you are not right when you were able
to get right
OK so
so there that there's so little circularity but you have to be good to get
good students as well but
but the real amplification comes with assurance so remember that
that's why the lower phd students and that's the right
so anyway this guy became very families because they did this african pattern three so
what have done is that they have taken the dataset
built a perfect three prefix tree means that
you know you take data set
and then you construct the branch
and you take the next data points
and then if it shares many of these nodes
you just shared the part of the structure
so in order to do that what you have to do is you have to
do a little bit of analysis is simple analysis like
the frequency of single items
so what you do is
in this slide
OK so typically what you do is
so let's assume we this is my
that's like saying a b c d
and the other one let's let's take a b c d e
the other one is like say a
f or g or something like that
so so what i do is a very simple analysis first of all
the items i have is
a b c d
then we have e
right so
they appeared in our database three times
and b appeared twice
see if you
three times
the other ones
he wants