now the algorithmic framework for all of this
has tended to have the following high-level picture
OK so there is some manifold
OK sitting in a high dimensional space
i don't know this manifold
i get a bunch of points on the manifold
so what am i to do
OK i have to recover something after recovery the maps from the manifold to some
low dimensional space to learn some function whose domain is the manifold and so on
what people do is well i don't know the manifold i have a bunch of
points let me actually make some kind of formation like structure of the graph like
structure by compared to combine could by a
connecting nearby points to each other
and i make a graph like this and this is my approximation to the manifold
and who the hell knows whether this is good or bad but this is what
people do a literal actually prove some theorems about this
kind of construction
but this is what people do the bayesian framework is i connect nearby points to
each other and nearby means nearby in the euclidean space in which the points are
embedded because that's the only distance that can measure
all my points are living in a euclidean space given any two points they can
measure the euclidean distance and that in fact the only thing i can do
OK so i make this nearest neighbour graph
so it's common to many of these methods and that's going to be my approximation
to the manifold and so if i wanted to do something on the manifold i
will do something on the graph instead
so let's discuss the first of these schemes OK this is isomap
is an algorithm i'm good now go through several algorithms most of these are the
terms do not come with its
proofs of the correctness of any sort
and then to give you a sense of what motivated people to think of algorithms
of this sort
and what would be more precise versions of the questions
these are the terms were trying to
sort of
so this is an algorithm isomap and this is what it does
you construct the nearest neighbour graph from all the state of data
you find the shortest path distances between all these points along the graph
OK you can use like stars at the time was something to find the shortest
path distance between all points
on this
so now i've got this set of distances d i j
this is already becoming somewhat intrinsic object because notice that d i g is not
simply the euclidean distance between the points x i and x j
OK so you made a graph where every vertex is identified with the data point
and between them
hi it's data point six i and the g data point six j
that is the euclidean distance between them but you made this
nearest neighbour graph and that is the shortest path distance between them and i've got
this this
new distance metric and this distance metric is trying to simulate the geodesic distance between
those two points if you are trying to go along the manifold
so the natural question is is this the idea close
to the geodesic distance
between x i and x j
and that i think under certain circumstances it is true
but this
sort of distance
distances between points and i would like to embed it into a low dimensional space
and embedded using this scheme called multidimensional scaling
so what is multidimensional scaling
multidimensional scaling is the following idea
i give you a matrix of distances
you go from that
two matrix of inner products somehow
and then from a matrix of inner products you go to an embedding
in two vectors whose distances
with will correspond to the distances that you've been given
by this distance metric
so how do we go from distances to inner products
you just make use of this identity
that if you take two points x and y two two vectors x and y
which are identified with point
then this is just
the distance between x and y the euclidean distance can be expressed in terms of
the inner product that gives you a relationship between inner products and distances and this
relationship of course is true only if
the distances are consistent with the inner products
this is actually not the case if the distances were actually distances geodesic distances on
the manifold
so multidimensional scaling says you give me a distance metric distance
a matrix of distances
if there is a set of points
in a euclidean space
from which this distance matrix could have arisen
then i can find those points for you
so if indeed there were a set of points from which these distance made this
distance matrix rows
then the inner products between those points which satisfy this relationship
and you can actually solve this and see that to call from d to d
which is the matrix of inner products is given by this
OK this is a little bit of linear algebra
last time we did
we discussed
the interference pattern of
two openings in the screen
which established the wave character of light
today i'm going to expand that
two and
capital and we will make and thousands of openings in the screen
when it comes to optical light we call those gratings
suppose here
each one of those dot
is a small opening in the screen
we all could be split perpendicular to the black
and imagine that plane waves are coming in
so each one of those openings
going to be
organ sources
and they're going to
radiates always
the the question now out we want to answer
if we
look in the direction theta
one way from the normal to that
screen what is then the light intensity that you will see a result of the
interference of all these
oregon sources
suppose that the separation between two adjacent sources
is d
words you is one
and here is the
this is a blow up
of what you see here
you see hundreds maybe thousands i have only two
and if that separation is the
then i can calculate
the phase difference between those two
this is the data
this is no different from
what we did
last time for the double slit
the past difference
this spherical wave to appoint far away
and an angle theta and this spherical wave that difference is this
and this is the
sin theta
so we will introduce just like we did before
the phase angle delta
which is the phase between the true away from this point and that point two
neighbouring points and here are thousands of these only between the two neighbouring sources
so first we want to know
how many times
can we fit wavelength on this path
and for each time that we can
wavelengths on their
we have a case different parts of the delta
is the phase difference and we had the same equation last time for obviously no
and if this delta is the multiple times two pi
then you will
i have
constructive interference michael today is way more ambitious i want to know what the light
intensities for any angle theta
have been extremely cool headed from
i first want to revisit some of your high school geometry
if you ever triangles
and this site is a
and this site is also a
the length of the triangle
the length of the sides
and if you want to know
what this one is
and if this angle is delta
on this side here
two a
the cosine
one that
we can revisit that your high school geometry but i need that today
and now i'm going to
due to superposition in vectorial superposition of capital and
he vector
that come from these various sources and the neighbouring ones
i doubt that's the phase angle between
i would
raise later but i'll first one
we're about to see what i do
i start with a
a circle
you will see shortly why i do that
radius of the circle is unimportant you'll see that
will cancel
so this radius
arbitrarily chosen
these are
this line here
it's also are
all these points seem
this point o
and this point p
and i'm going to
at three factors which are all set relative to each other over an angle about
that but i will make the calculation is if they were capital and
capital and could be a million
but i'm going to make the drawing only for three
this is one factor
that's a thousand ninety eight really the electric vector that's going to be
and in fact relate to the unelected vectors
so here's is the other
the second one
here is the third one
so the angle between
the second and the third one
this angle here
is delta
and this angle here
it's also delta
that's the delta between the neighbouring sources which we just right
it follows from the geometry of circle
this angle here is well
this angle here as
and this angle the also the
what that means
if i have capital and of these vectors
that this angle here
is then and times delta
and that means
of the sky taken with five or six for LSST  I think it's twelve different filters
different passbands and rather than a continuum of a spectra you get snapshots at
different passbands so it's a crude spectrum is this crude spectrum good enough to use to
get information about supernovae this is something that is not known yet it's it's a
it's a subject of ongoing research s s let me turn  now to baryon acoustic oscillations and
how we get information from baryon acoustic oscillations about dark energy again we have
talked about recombination I think in every lecture before recombination the universe was ionized the
photons provided enormous pressure and restoring force and perturbations were frozen they just oscillated like sound
waves after recombination the universe was neutral the photons travelled freely they were decoupled
from the baryons and perturbations grew so it's very easy to know what happened
in the tightly coupled limit and in the decoupled limit but this is a very interesting
and I wanna turn again to this movie that I've shown a couple of
times in these lectures this movie from Dan Eisenstein showing the evolution of dark
matter in black gas in blue photons in red and neutrinos in green so this is
movie showing what would happen to a density peak so you gather up
dark matter gas photons and neutrinos and make a density peak a very small one and then how
that spreads out over time the dark matter has if it's cold has no velocity
or very small velocity so it's just going to stay there the photons are going
to want to stream out of this over densit region however if the photons are
coupled tightly coupled to gas it can't stream out until the universe starts to go
through recombination so don't worry about the neutrinos the important thing to look here is
what happens to the gas and the photons so the ga the photons are going
to start to stream out but they're going to drag the baryons along and
then recombination will occur the baryons will stay behind and the photons
will continue propagating I just love this movie there's a lot of physics there so
there you see the gas and photons coupled then about three hundred thousand years every
combination occurs the pho the baryons are left behind  and the photons travel to us
the baryons are left behind in a little bump there the dark matter falls
into the baryon potential wells here the baryons fall into the dark matter potential
wells there and you end up with a power spectrum that has a memory
of the initial perturbation but there's a feature on the power spectrum a feature in
the inhomogeneity of the universe at a distance scale of about a hundred and fifty megaparsec so the
photons drag the baryons out to a hundred and fifty megaparsec so each overdense region is an overpressure that
launched a spherical sound wave the wave travelled outward with C over the square root of three
then the photons decouple travel to us observable is the CMB peaks then the sound
speed plummeted the sound speed of the wave plummeted because there was no pressure and
the wave stalled and the total distance travelled by this bunch of baryons was a
hundred and fifty  megaparsec so there's a bunch of baryons at a distance scale of a hundred and fifty
megaparsec that dark matter and they'll be a feature in the power spectrum
of density perturbations at a hundred and fifty megaparsec and that was first hints of this
were fir st seen in the two degree field survey and it was I believe convincingly
demonstrated by the Sloan Digital Sky Survey so this is a data from the Sloan
Digital Sky Survey  and here you see the feature of the acoustic peak so
there is  the I feature in the universe in the distribution of matter on a distance scale
of a hundred and fifty megaparsec and the exact size of this depends upon omega matter omega baryon cosmological
parameters but they are determined by the microwave background radiation because it's this the same parameters
enter in determining the position of this peak which is accurately determined now the feature
is a small effect because it's do originally to the baryons  and we know
that the baryons contribute only a small fraction of the total mass density so
there's a feature out there and let's make it simple here's a typical observer looking at this
feature that's a  hundred and  fifteem sper  spherical feature that's a hundred and fifty  megaparsec in this direction in that
direction  of course it's nevers  one feature you look at you look at
the statistical ensemble  but you can if you know this distance you can
measure the angular diameter and dark energy enters through the angular diameter distance relationship you
can also measure  by measuring the distance and the redshift the difference in the redshift in
the front of the feature and the back of the feature H here so dark
energy enters through D A and H and we can get information on dark energy from
baryon acoustic oscillations there is a tremendous virtue  on this technique it that it's
just geometry it's free of many of the systematic effects that are in other methods
so you don't have to worry about magnetic fields evolution metallicity reddening it's just geometry there
are problems to this technique one problem is that the amplitude is small so you
have to require you require large-scales and huge volumes you have to look at thousands
of hundred and fifty megaparsec cube volumes if you're looking at many many many objects perhaps
the ultimate is we'll be using photometric redshifts and we don't know how well that
works there's also an issue that there are nonlinear facts in the evolution
and you want to see anything
the naked eye that looks like anything has happened
in between you wanted the piston moving the gases turbulent
the pressure to find some reason law in some regions then it's stuff
this is the notion of systems in equilibrium
and in between the stage
the system which are not in equilibrium
but the system is in such equilibrium
we can assign to the temperature
that we call p
right now we don't know anything about this step has to be going to build
it up from scratch rather than your instinctive feeling for what happened to this
one of the loss of the more dynamic scholars zeroth law
is it a lot because they wrote on the first law
and they went back and had an idea what is even more profound
and they so we call it
zero line
zero total losses
if a and b are the same temperature
in b and c are the same temperature
in a and c are the same temperature
i see
this believe
the audience when called the and i think that is the key to i would
being able to speak about temperature globally is the assumption that the fact that the
monitor measure something there
they come back in the thermometer here
and agreed to same number then i may conclude these two entities which never made
it to the directly are also the same template
it's not
that seems pretty obvious to you but that is
the whole lotta countries is predicated on the fact that you can define an attribute
called temperature
that can be globally compared between two systems that never met directly but met the
third system
so once we hate once we have some idea of hot and cold
it was decided not to be more quantity
it's like saying you somebody solid shot is not enough we go into how tall
harmony harmony society millimeters
so we want to get quantity
all we have right now is notion of hot and cold
so what we try to do
is to find some way
to be more precise about how hard and how cool
what people said is
let's look at some things in the world that seem to depend on temperature
one thing that seems to depend on temperature is the following
you take this stick
the national bureau of standards kept some glass case at some temperature
you pull it out
make duplicate effort put it outside leaving the rule
what you may find this in the room was harder than the glass case
this rather than expand
two a new like
one runs outside the case when drug inside the case so the comparison is meaningful
nothing has been done this guy
in the condition glass case but this one is expanding
so one way to define temperature is to simply ask
how long is this rock and somehow
currently the length of the rod
with temperature by some fashion
so you can do that so what you need to do that what you need
to do first is to define
but some markings on it so that for needs extra something grows we get to
the temperature has gone up by some amount
so then we need units for temperature that's completely arbitrary
and you need some standards
this leads me to speak to you know not
at the intrinsic nature water meter we just made it up and so let's call
them either
in the case of the media the zero applies
if you bring me to stick next to mine and we agree
you can take the me to stick somewhere else
and find that to be the mean
because of the stickers as long as that one and this long is that one
of those two equal in length
the temperature you similarly going to use the rod
and say this rather settling and then kept on top of this bucket of some
and the same length but to keep it on that bucket
then the two buckets at the same temperature
so we can use
on this rock compared to the
on expander like this to measure of temperature
so what people do is to pick
something a little easier than this right
in know the liquid expands
when you heat that's why you know somebody if you your gas tank
you have to leave some room at the top
overflow can come out of the time
you should fill it completely
otherwise it first attack
so liquids expand
so one way to measure temperature maybe
take some liquid
put it there
and then
put it on hard rules and maybe what's the liquid expands the new high
and thence across the markings
need marking can be a certain temperature
but people have a better idea than this one
they have the following idea thermometer where
you have a lot of fluid in the reservoir
a very thin tubes
back way to the top
the fluid then
this year
so what's clever about this
is that
this expands by one percent year i should be good enough to see one percent
increase in
this fluid expands one percent in volume
that one person in volume in the planes of this nanotubes can play quite a
because the extra volume you get by expansion
it will be the eighty of the stu
times the extra delta x we would expect
your magnifying the expansion by making all the expander fluid climate is extremely narrow two
in fact the tube so narrow
you cannot probably even see well which is why there no prison that magnifies the
the mercurial alcoholism on
OK so we have some
we're falling temperature
we can draw some lines arbitrary doesn't matter that can be zero that can be
applied in nineteen is going to make sure is monotonic
then whenever
it's on twenty one b argue that twenty one is now part of the ninety
what you want to better skilled than that even though that's mathematically adequate in practice
what people decide
it is to do it as follows
this be one is that the thermometer so that people all over the world in
different parts of the world different countries different labs can all agree
so we will make it possible for everyone to make their own thermometers
by the following recipe
we will that this guy
in a bucket
it has got some i sent some water
called the melting point of water
so that
of the freezing point of water a melting point of ice to the freezing point
of water doesn't matter
we notice that as water cools down the world and suddenly i see he was
begin to form we go to the temperature at which that happens for the first
and we the the moment there
and what they were reading we get we will possibly to be
zero degrees centigrade
that is just a definition
we believe that's a good definition because people all over the world
you can do that cause if you live in kuwait
it's not going to work for the noise
but the
figure out when part the world when you had to use this is very good
you get eyes
you've got zero degrees
they said let's find another
accessible thing which as you all know is the boiling point of water
to put water on the stove which heats up and he his up and suddenly
begins to bubble and boiling evaporate
the that temperature is going to be called a hundred degrees
he is also the internal point here that kind of
it up here
now that i've done this this is this is so i know how each of
these individual points match so when actually updating still altarpiece on updating the individual points
this sixty point some not worrying about the mesh at all
the mesh is very important when when i'm doing the
the model synthesis but it's also very important when i'm doing in this composition
because what i can do
is i i will the piecewise mesh is not composed but each of the individual
triangles inside the mesh for
so what i can do is i can work out how what's find what between
here and here
delta p one
i want to find what
between here and here
delta p two
so and so forth
what i did then
to p three
each of the triangles
and what amount to do then is that i can
in terms of the source image so source image here
so the source images or larger
and this is my current guess
where where the triangle of with a with the triangular meshes inside the image so
this is my update with respect to the template and now i want to try
and apply this update two
the source image here
so what i what ends up happening
is that
i have a shift so i say actually apply
delta p one inverse here
delta p
three inverse here
two invest here so i do that
and i might end up
with this
that's the problem
when i invest close
i lose the thickness of all the points so so everything is not connected so
what i then after the approximation is is what i then do
it is i just take the average of all these things
and assume that this is one point seven here take the average of these two
points is one point here
the average here
and here
so mathematically
for the piece was the final it's not technically correct but the inverse copied this
sort the trick this approximate three tends to work very well and that and that's
what we so we actually do the inverse composition
on the actual triangles in the mesh
and then run reconstructed
that's a little bit too much detail but that's that's that's that's how we do
and so this is an example
another example of a running this was this is this super souped-up fast whatever so
they used
everything in the book to try and speed this up and
the nice thing here is that the go back tracking and also
this is the reason recent pieces of the phi space purely on the i competitions
and you can kind of see that it's actually rather than regular iron which is
kind of blocking does a bad job sometimes of representing different shapes and expressions because
with the coupling shape and appearance separately we actually a really good job of synthesizing
the facts so this is purely synthesized just from the linear model of appearance and
same here in the black
and yet we spoke about the high speed and then you can you might be
asking well
and this is an argument that kind of
so many in like a bit more on common not so hard but what i
say that the inverse composition makes it useful
is that if an editor it's a two hundred frames per second i could perhaps
have because this is the gradient descent top approach i could perhaps have ten different
within within the frame within within the frame of trying to align the facts so
it kind of talking about solar project how perhaps doesn't always work well but if
i do it fast enough i could have saved
ten different ten different tries to trying to get alignment
and so
this is this is kind of an argument for the two but i still like
to think that
i'm not a big fan site because it still tends to file sometimes the project
find you know
so we use
i don't know
the same time
that's what i think
you know why
in core
and this is very dangerous
at the moment
we can
so the
the document
they just happen
he has this
two one two
we call on
so that here
in the first place
you have to this is not
there's also these two put emphasis on what was the time
the station
so that's the
the weighting scheme of news
we can see a number of problems because
and you can
none of the world because of what we have
as you go away
effectively used
it was
you get
i think is full
talk critical
it's three
and the what she wants it is representation of
i think still not as far as
right to make it when your
you do
i really
so i think it's time to
well we talk about it
looking at with this idea
hi you have to present you have to
o thing
rules all
were you to think this is you all
so think
if there is if you want
forty seven or
we already
the idea
let me
so feature
is that
also in things like
i can see from six to five
you were
this is a region where the
she has subsequently
in the sequence
the reason for this sequence and use doesn't necessarily have to be used
in the use
the particular
one who is going to whatever it is nice to get the final
two hundred is always true
that each
we should
so this is not
example you know what we we have
this is looking at all
two two CA
please see
o two which is where
slightly more white
down by the
we to this is a so when
q such that we have to
he is going to do this
this is
she was the one that
imagine we find that if i can't just fall
in part three
that for
well thanks to
class being suitably rich
OK so
if found
if the infimum over as as n gets large we like you know the infimum
the union of these things so the overall of f of the of the virus
should be equal to the be the optimal fire
OK so this is just the dense this property for
we wanted to be to be similar which what the span in adaboost case span
this class of functions
to to
approximate the
the optimal
as accurately as we like
so that would take care of the approximation error term and you know i'm not
going to go into any details there there are there are simple
there are many examples where this is the case
right where where the approximation error term is asymptotically zero in the
reproducing kernel hilbert space
setting for instance all the euclidean space the gas in kernel has the property that
the you know the the RKHS
can can always give you for any probability distribution can give you the optimal fire
so it's universal in that sense
in finite dimensional girls don't have polynomial kernel trick
the other
two to ensure that the other terms
goes to zero
we need to
to worry about the regularisation either through the choice of of this this hierarchy fn
right by
the the well defined only if ten was
we weren't using these
these classes to grow suitably slowly or through the the explicit regularisation right so the
the regularisation term needs to go to zero
so that we do exercise the full classes but it should go to zero suitably
slowly so this term
the estimation error term goes to zero and then
under these two conditions then we can hope to have the fire escape approaching
the optimal fire stuff i start these two terms are going to both go to
zero and you know and when when the
phi is classification calibrated then we'll get some sort of consistency result right
but the risk actually approaches the bayes risk
which is the nice thing is the first thing that you might the first to
guarantee that you might want to have a better method of this
this kind
OK and the course
you might also be concerned with with rates
you might also be concerned with with help
rapidly the risk approaches the
the optimal bayes risk
i was a little bit about
about that
and about getting some kind of an oracle inequality i'm gonna skip now from
from talking about excess risk to talking just about to fire OK so let's let's
you keep in mind that we have this relationship between the two
focus on just the excess risk of a and c are rapidly that goes to
zero so
you know we will ignore this
side related to the quality really care about the the excess risk
OK so
let's think now
about a regularisation kind of approach that involves some sort of penalty
OK so once again i'm splitting things up into a hierarchy
if f one f two and so on
and i'm considering within each class k if k
and defining OK and is the minimiser of
they are the
which his words
provides a means to construct
from twenty five thirty sounds
that's the expressions
that enable us to
reveal everything everything
all movements all
right characterization rare
recognition using
on the
characters language
he said much
so really
created pair
normal use
and was
core features these ants you've lost
coming recently
a century ago prominently
raise question
how the elements of language
come into existence my speed
on the basis of his
from the position
and that's processes
in the solution
you've somehow
structure the
is definitely not
inference the
free expressions
there are typically the space
o that's
and it therefore follows that you test sounds like
it discovers evolutionary
his on
two hundred yes she calls
the very principles
underlying the original languages
the game u
so it make
these are ideas that
it was a strange day
then they
it it science here that
came dominate the field
then marginalize the destinations
in science fact this for years
he was same starting
six years
poking around like
and along with
this all the
behavioral science
well reformulating as
program which is right
the basic task is
to be
true nature interfaces true
so pragmatic
the for
should actually be
free expressions
along with questions
the solution
generally have
it is what
which is that he
the major is simple
it used to be easiest and simplest
and the test centers
then is to try to
and fact is full is possible
and should be
right in the
the is superficial
the station
these principles we
so the
this is
john is
the largest city
the central are science
it's actually
complex also the symbols in the world
find useful i
the task is to determine
how closely
language approximates well all know
refers to the
do any boundary conditions
what we can show is that you can really express this
the sum of the variances discarded columns so you want to minimize the sum of the variances
the discarded columns yeah
so that makes sense actually when you think about it
it also shows that this is a very interesting algorithm
so actually go much further
the algorithm is saying
the in order to match those distances in the best way
i should extract
the dimensions which have the largest variance
what is i mean rotated six it kinda makes sense because it means by rotated
six it will be the columns they're turning on and off in terms of pixels
the most
yeah so if there is a wide will be white columns which just stay why
because no pixel-level lands on a new discarding those
and we're retaining
pixels from representation where the variance is largest as it spins around
okay so let's do not
this is a two-dimensional visualization
this is now
the distances in latent space using the algorithm
okay what she is
not very good representation
you can see that these guys are completely similar completely severed completely similar
annotates triumph approximating what we saw on
in the diagonal yeah
but you can't see any serious features
and the mean absolute error is point two one five quite large
this is ten dimensions okay
hey you couldn't even see the similarity between all three sixty hey you can
stop trying to merge so this is like
ten pixels about data
so this discussion you do want to retain
quite a lot of your data you don't i throw away
all the ten pixels
but a hundred dimensions
small a mean absolute error
not all features item at a thousand dimensions
now we're really starting to see something with scientists e
on structure hear with those squares yeah
we're seeing
i mean this this band isn't quite tight enough that's pretty good approximation
so great job with reduce the dimensionality from three thousand six hundred forty eight dimensions two thousand and
not really very good
so this type of algorithm is not gonna work but there's a nice reason for
introducing it because there's a trick
what are we doing here when preserving interpoint distances
we are actually
taking a data set like this and this the two dimensional data set we want
to preserve interpoint distances in this two-dimensional dataset
we're projecting
the largest variance dimension on
x axis
and that's a reduced dimensional representation
yeah fair enough
but you can rotate the data set and preserve all interpoint distances so as far as our algorithm is concerned
a rotation and this data not an image rotation
but rotation of the actual
um vector space
in terms of like multiply why by a rotation matrix
doing this
doesn't actually affect
interpoint distance matrices at all
so if replace rotation
now what happens
now we project onto the x axis
we've got a much better representation about data
so what is that's
that's says the
why don't we insert just selecting columns why don't we rotate
the data set
once we rotated the data set
throw away
the columns the rotated data set with the smallest variance
yeah retain only those with the largest variance
so this algorithm is saying rotate dataset
and retain
the columns from x with the largest variance
here's what happens if possible that have little or
but happy
let's have a look at how
we can do about because it should be also does anyone know
what operation
you applied to data set
in order to find the rotation
which leads you which is in the direction of maximum variance
piece e eight
principal component analysis
this what person similar
it's useful to actually go through this go through this exercise due to the in
a different order and see what happens to the graph
what sort of key here you want to be very clear about this is when
you some
you end up modifying terms this term changed a bit because of the effect of
something this out
right and it it changed bit what's important is that there already was a potential
term sitting there
it got tweaked a little changed but i didn't add any new potential term nothing
new was added this changed this useful to think about what if you some to
the south
think about doing it here what effect would that have on the coupling of the
well go into details now but that's that's useful to think about the break the
order in which i did this matters a lot
i was nice to unite shows the good order
roughly speaking you can sort of see i was essentially moving outside to in i
was starting the the outside sixteen i got the five and i sort of collapse
the graph in word
but you can do this elimination in any ordering you want
but not order not all orderings are equal some orderings are much better than others
so this is an optimal ordering
some orderings can be very bad
so it's useful to play with this example just a little bit on your own
to understand why the order in which you do this might matter
right so the sort of summary years
the basic step is is very simple we're just distributing sum and product to do
partial some asians in some order
so you're fixing an elimination ordering in using distributive law as much as you can
without order
what sort of key graphically is that the minute you some over a particular variable
you get to eliminate that node and its edges from the graph
that's a good thing that makes you happy the graph is shrinking
but the bad thing that you have to be careful about you have to join
all of its neighbors
with extra edges
so as you join these extra edges
for instance one example of where this happened was right here
i didn't have an edge here initially
but once i sum over the x four at this point
it's going to be an edge that's added here you can see that it has
to be added because you get a new coupling term
and i'm doing that's going to start making your graph more and more connected it's
can actually increase
the size of the clique series making actually three clique there that didn't exist before
so what it turns out is if you do a bit of algebra to figure
out how much did you pay to do all this
at the end of the day how much to pay depends very much on how
big the cliques got in this new graph that gets created as you sort of
shrink the graph down
what sort of matters how many edges you have to add as you were eliminated
so here i ended up having to actually create a new three clique
only had three clique here but the biggest click that i would have gotten in
this graph is actually three clique there's nothing bigger than that there's no four cliques
if you choose define elimination ordering you'll see that you will get four clique
so the key thing is that elimination ordering matters a lot
there are good orderings and bad ones
unfortunately the figure out which is the optimal ordering that's not an easy problem
it's actually an NP hard problem in general
practically speaking there are a lot of heuristics to find reasonable orderings you might not
find the best one but you can certainly find reasonable ones
so that's that's elimination algorithm the intuition you want to take away from this is
that there is a really nice correspondence between analytically and you sort of manipulating the
or the y axis
in the generative frame assassination
i mean so if you have the assassination
abraham lincoln
i don't know
assassination of
the noun itself is indicated with now
the thing in the gender
it the that's so
these destination of a link
if we can be
the victim of this assassination of that
so you you could also
five relational nouns like mother
with this kind of
template translation
verbsemtrans is the prototypical example of these kinds of some transform
so here two random example verbsemtrans
the word scratches were
as it were
the the intransitive verb
no action which
which is scratching sound
chance crashed i guess that means
anyway that's what this is
it was related to the
subject of the
to the role primary objects moving
and i should think about what said
in the transitive friend have not only subject
that but also
the action is
scratching one's actions keyword
that corresponds to what the
for the first
object is
related to the action and its object is to change
and we have
the subject
is related to the action being done by
one so
you could
derived verbsemtrans entries from
from the
the other
a collection
potentially so give
you know you could say OK
i know that this
kind of actions
is a single participant action
it should correspond to infer that is intransitive
and nothing prevents you from inferring that
you can also these verbsemtrans entries
by hand
oh yes there yes some very good point
the show to better i think somebody was
not paying attention when they made
yes actually unfortunately copy pasted that from KB but
yes i did read but i think it's wrong
i think that's
good observation
maybe that's what they have in mind
transitive and reflexive
yes OK
i take it back
i'm sorry to whoever wrote that in the next lecture
there's sort of a shortcut for writing verbsemtrans entries that are canonical
the kinds of cases that you
right across often so regular transitive verb
have very
you can just use of assumptions not
this one says the word assassinate
the transitive verb means
denotes an event assassinatingsomeone and
subject is the perpetrator and the object is at the
right so far extremely notation so intense and
i'll go over gentemplate
of of
they well
who was
o o
this is the
in the first
so all all
it's all
so yes
this is hard
you a
this one
the better
for this
we're going to
the situation where you
first we need to
was published
four b
two b and c and d were only three b
and this has happened according and you can prove that if you are using
for the concord every every every character
i have according to be dubious the bias for the distribution
by the way
we can go not from down to topic and do it from top to down
we can divide simply some them and divided into two into port in two parts
with the same probability characters
from bottom to top we can do from top to bottom
how we call this called if somebody who is about information theory
if it if the building from bottom to top
this is
happen because if the building from top to bottom how because such code
because sharon was the guy who viewed all this area
i created this calls what he was not very right about average and so his
first idea was viewed from top to bottom
and there are some bond cases like such called is not optimal
so very good
so we can encode every day but the problem with this recording is pretty good
we can we can
compress out text
model is very very simple
if you're talking about this
first square compression models
with the competition model was simply that for this character have this probability that's it
nothing more
and you know that not true for a language because we have different probabilities for
what but also you know that we have a lot of repetitions in in every
string have made a lot of common
and this simple model doesn't work for
so what we can do can do the this is samples find actually this example
eleven pose even according
ln pose seventy eight
it's pretty simple type of encoding but it
very fast especially during decompression
and if you're going to use tax and you don't need random access so you
always the text from beginning to end
on the morning computers it's so we want to keep text compressed
because the compression
four because the compression data is also very simple let's add to all of about
one additional
one additional thing
and this is case that says that
a group of characters
the same characters as
before with some of
so for to be or not to be
the to be or not and then we see that we already stored
to be
the output of this case
and that putting that we need to
ford works
it will work
twelve symbols
two four single actually five hundred five symbols from this position
it's pretty simple
it's extremely fast
and if you were compression of
because they always compress that
maybe four times before
most of the land
and if again if your processes
natural that
you're in the
and the it's always want on on the current hardware if you don't need to
random access
the compress and process because of the compressed file
and with this we decided for all those search engine that
all collection coming to compress in
as compression or sort of the compression of the samples is another story
but this is very close
with five string bass compression algorithm
we don't know that the size of all compress data
the last hour in that they would be less than uncompressed data
and it's very common situation in modern search engines
if we are talking about local search engine something that you get on CD the
i'm not talking about huge search engines we have another dimension
it's always enjoyable to feed everything inside uncompressed data
so it is very common situation
the data what we have to have flags field called and all other stuff like
this like for example
talk to the first lecture about quality of
syntactic information is no no
is it no no no so
this is all flags and for all the selected in all the
they all have pretty stable distribution for example
words from title and not very common body the most common type of you in
our toy example so we know
like in this example these according to and all that
why do
they the most common the common situation and that will be and some other other
future where you have the document be
we can for all this data
we can create these have perfect recall
for all this stuff
and if we are going to
store all the data in our in using this court and that
right now we know that for
flag and all other attributes of feature that we extracted
we have
perfect called that works very well and we are going to use it in analysis
so that you know now how to store text
and if you know how to store attribute
and the next module while the system is
and for dictionary
but actually we need to
implement some special structure because
what is dictionary dictionary is the structure of doing here much
we are getting really get to work with church
in the dictionary for this road to get some additional information about this work
and then we going to do
really this addition information something if we for example
already so they were never so that's what we can simply add to put forth
leased additional points
if there
i haven't seen this work
this you know processing you can
and this what the dictionary
a lot of that stuff to read you know the early database papers they were
all fairly mathematical ways of explaining
the really why putting things in these tables matter
right so so one of my challenges to the community
is there
while may or may not be the necessary is piece of the story well linked
data may or may not be necessary as a piece of the story neither is
for the needs of this community academic community surviving into the future we must find
formalism that sort of our equivalent of a DB calculus or that takes what's going
on in the abox world and models of formally as we can model what's going
on the but also i want to model
when this began web that there's a whole lot of distributed sparql and all seven
to OWL
what i do is i all that distributed pakistan stuff until the baby is in
a box in the traditional sense and then i can talk about subsuming in various
things but i just want you know the real power stuff which is getting messed
in the first part of the web
i used every time i give semantic web to underline were web lots and lots
of times that's what's new about the way this is not the traditional
in AI experts system vision is embracing all that really powerful web technology
but it's not ignoring the eye vision is
right it's bringing those two things together so this is just one
think at the end of my talk by way
i have some slides and not the shape of research challenges for
propagate two or three years ago i lived there for those of you who are
looking for doctorate topic or something like that and and this sort of built in
the context of this thing is i knew i wouldn't have
so i think we need a sufficient formalism
that can define what
ontology is not an ontology really are
so what does it mean to be in the world of ontology is not have
includes all sorts of stuff about linking not external reference that are not find real
link that includes not so traditional ontology languages that these two great big things like
the maximal lyapunov but what i want to stuff and also the together
right one case which is very few very large things but other cases which is
i got three hundred twenty thousand databases literally that we've found from government websites that
we have put together
absolutely level and we'd like to be able to say something about winding them up
we're using a little bit of vocabulary it
it doesn't talk nice and research paper anything other than we built an nice government
and i think we have to figure out how to bring more and more discussion
of the so called non expressive formalism or in fact real world errors into into
our thing
as we bring rules and as we do other things and we get this to
famous slide what is an ontology
that we have to stop using likely likely most you have so early on and
i hope i don't see much use in some
but it was an idea to say that there is something that happens in the
form of space but now we need to say can we find an ontology that
in a sense covers all object we find the formalism model that covers all this
here's an idea about how to get the right i think you reminded me yesterday
but in fact you know you've all seen under the little robotic vacuum cleaners around
according to a recent thing i read write company i that sold a million of
them last year
that's a good consumer
once upon a time there were these big fights in the robotics community between those
folks who want everything to refer primarily doing mathematics
route planning and those people who are sorry using proxy
what happens somebody threw a meaning
in the called
robot vacuum cleaner
and what he did was he said let's ignore your stuff works just show me
one it
and here's some furniture furniture random room
and then show us your coverage
what it is the first one which have got together and said well you know
we covered ninety seven percent of object we cover eighty seven percent with seventeen minutes
and they said well you know we didn't ninety two percent of the room
in twenty three minutes
totally meaningless that
but then they put up the pictures
and the first one which was a big open space
it was completely evacuated but in your furniture really bad
and the second one
was greeted around furniture when you look at the big open spaces that were sort
you know gaps
the following year everybody had hybrid systems there was starting to get ninety seven percent
of the thirteen
to make everyone agreed was increased
now it improve the formalism but improve performance because they started thinking about common problem
like that shown in the last challenge and finding out today before i get my
summary is how do we e
develop hybrids have the best features of linked data
and the ontology and we started finding some problems that we can try
all of our stuff
not one piece of the
how do we bring that stuff together as a community
in summary
the infrastructure of say this is my summary this is actually summary slide from an
earlier time
but i want to point out so this talk was going back to two thousand
one where the agents we started remember this family
it's markup language for agents it was all about things that would help us to
process the information
nowadays when we look at most of the stuff coming out as and what we
don't see all that much of that that that my other challenges let's bring back
the agents
why the semantic web will never work no reason at all
the semantic web is here
it is working and will continue to do so
but it is not
the semantic web as vision fifteen years ago it's the first wave
if we want to see the second and third and eventually
you know the realization
to move to the next level
and to be all that we as a community aspired for nearly
we have to revisit and update the early versions of what we going for the
modern web web is different now now than it was ten years ago
we have to figure out our stuff the news
we must unify these competing models of linked data
machine readable vocabularies and all that and we have to to step up
to some research challenges that face it's not enough to just build a system that
works for being able to explain
why first four how do we compare
how do we evaluate it thank you
so when i told them that the were evaluated here
so the way it was but it
it's got to be evaluating the stuff in the vision and motion towards the vision
not how do we
how do we evaluate the stuff
message in real time you don't want to speak and then wait for a minute
or so until the message is decoded has to be done now
so this message passing out and we'll talk about let me just demonstrated in in
practice free on one of these codes
so what i'm showing you here it is
so it's a little demonstration of
how you might clean up an image
so i'm showing your code it has roughly ten thousand bits
so it means that the graphical model that has roughly ten thousand of those circular
and the way built it's got five thousand of those square variables those factor nodes
are those parity checks
right so big graphs
and what you observe is you observe this image which has been corrupted by some
speckle noise
and what we're going to do is we use the sum product algorithm can run
it on the underlying graph will see tomorrow what it does and you'll see that
cleans up the image
so it's running iterations
and it's done
so fourteen iterations there on ten thousand it essentially recovering the
the code word in this case which was the clean image recovered perfectly
no no tree graphs that's interesting things so you'd like it to be a tree
graph because then sum product algorithm would be exact will see this tomorrow but it
turns out that if you use trees to build codes they're not good codes there
sort of bad codes in the sense that can be made precise
so all good code things like turbo codes what this is what i'm showing you
is called a low density parity check code all good codes had cycles
and so this is one of the reasons why belief propagation or some product on
graphs with cycles this is probably the
the single largest success story of it in any application
right because it's it's in all of your devices as we speak
so it's key that has cycles
any other questions
let's look at this code quickly
i mean just explain what i was doing
so what this means was
when i was generating the noisy version i was flipping six per was on average
o was flipping a coin with the probability point zero six of making it a
bad pixels
so i crafting only six percent
six percent of the pixels
so you might as well you made it too easy so we can try slightly
harder problem all cruft about
seven and a half percent
and i don't know what's going to happen because it's random it may work it
may not this sort of
near the threshold of what this code can do
OK so that worked if i ran it again it might not work at that
if i go
two high i crop something like ten or twelve percent let's do ten percent it
it will fail i think
almost assuredly and now it's even more corrupted
and we'll see the algorithm because it's on graphs with cycles
you see that sort of partly cleaned up a bit of the image but now
it's just kind of oscillating it's bouncing back and forth
so the graph is not an actress who can see tomorrow doesn't always converge in
this case the problem is too hard for it it failed to decode properly
but that's not surprising because for those of you know about shannon theory
the the shannon limit for this problem
no matter whatever you do can do better than eleven percent so if you have
ten percent this code but eight percent that's that's actually quite good it's reasonable
OK so any other questions
so i took the image and i've had it with
yeah essentially the linear algebraic metric the images some sequence of zeros and ones
by shifting all the words by the image i can make the all zeros vector
are is the reflexive transitive closure of the sigma
and this looks really weird and you should be suspicious of it says if if
if i stroke
box five
in five through here and
in the next day for flies through
box if i is true here
well then phi is true here
and in the next day box if five true
sorry in the next eight books if of
five string which means that if phi is true here
and the faces of that means that phi is true
for five string
which says are five true here
which specifies true and so on
what this
is actually of fixed point
and that's why
one half of the fixed point equation is that
our is the reflexive transitive closure of sigma
this is our is in the reflexive transitive closure sigma this is equal to one
you can read this is an induction axiom
say something like this
the induction axiom you know for the integers
it says
if it's the case that all times in the future
five being true here
implies that phi is true in the next day
if at all times in the future it's the case that phi implies
next five
data that's true everywhere
as soon as five becomes true here
box five string here
i want to say
if you can
if the induction hypothesis takes you from
the i state-of-the-art plus first the
if you can do the induction step remained in plus one
starting at zero
it means you can prove
for all integers
think about it the more it exactly the induction
steady conduction that we do over the integers when we prove the property of the
this the
says that whenever you find to your site true
ben diamond if size to be true
and if you want to see the intuitions they
it's this park
whenever find two size true
there has to be a future point where size true that's demanded and then something
that's the first time
and this is also a fixed point equations like this
it says if i until zidane something so let's have a look at that
so this is if i until size true here
well that's the same as saying
that size true here
that was
your case where the q happen straight away
it says well with this i happen straight away
i don't care about the rest of the happy
there's nothing to do
as far as the five parties concerned because the until
happens right now
in the five part is always before
where the until happens so there's nothing to do
or else
size false here
five is true here
and in the next state
the thing
resurrects itself
right now i suppose the thing resurrects itself then it means that here
five until size true
now you do the same thing again what is that they will either size true
and your home
in which case we got financial
or else
not size tree here five true here and the thing resurrects itself is what i
mean by fixed point
and now you say well if that's true here then fine until size to be
true here
so either side true here in which case we got five until c
or else size falls five string and all that
and you keep going
because of this part
you know that sooner or later you're going to get to a point where you
say size true
and then you've got to the five
all the way
so five until size true
puzzled looks
that's it that's exactly the same of fleshing out the recursive definition
right because
what i'm saying is that if you flesh out the recursive definition
you don't go forever
fixed point means sooner or later you've got to start fleshing out the
the nation k
and that's
this aspect is about
it says you can't delay forever
right what he says he says
what's that character from pop by the sailor you know there's always prepared pay back
tomorrow something that
financial so i will not not today
borrows money from you don't pay you back tomorrow right
and the fixed points is not there's going to be a time when you actually
pay me back right
OK so it's exactly what you said it's the recursive equation so
it actually defines an infinite formula another way to look at this is actually that
this is effectively the conjunction an infinite conjunction
or an infinite disjunction sorry this one is actually an infinite disjunction
and the fixed points is no it's not infinite sooner or later it bottoms out
all right
now what i'd like to talk to you about these tableau calculus because i just
showed you hilbert calculus
i'm going to
do it
you know
algorithm form rather than
you know rule rule based form
the top thing says if you're interested in sequent calculi for these types of logics
then you either need an infinitary rule
or you can eliminate cut
and if you don't know what that means that's OK
if you do then
come talk to OK
so what do we do we say
one example could be the let's try have that if we try to prove box
if y
implies box if i
right so what am i gonna do
i'm going to negate this
because that's what tableau calculi do
so i'm going to say
so the topics
one slide there
just three elections
a little bit about agent agent architectures
the i
two hours
the first elections
and then
in the last lecture on talk talking about historical issues
and philosophical issues
and there's reference to this
this is the book
i if you're interested
you have to buy
this is by far the this book
very comprehensive
very modern up to date by two very strong people
and it's got
it's got the market share and they are the reason is because the book
in fact
much of the material the that
you'll be able to find in
the first two chapters
there are about
historical issues and
agent architecture
twenty six and twenty seven that the more about philosophical issues
so if you want to more detail and i recommend you do
this placed
so feel free to interrupt at any time when we got three hours
it's OK i can i try to answer questions about it gets all the slide
that's fine too
and w chance to talk
so if i understand correctly
we have a break
is it from two to fifty three three fifteen right
OK so i started the light which should we should elephants three
another break brightness of the break after that
and questions before we get started
the key idea here is that
artificial intelligence
is the
the study of how one deals
rational agents
russian rationality something to
describing the more detail later
so what's an agent
it's not affected
living environment
it can receive perceptron environment
and they can apply actions to the environment
typically it's got some some goals is trying to achieve something
and the task of i i would like to achieve
the goal one set for the edges
what is rationality means
well basically a rational agent does the right thing
and how do you define what right thing is
you have to have some kind of performance measure
the idea is motivated
but performance measure
it's trying to optimize its performance measure
we say that
if it does
and it's rational agent
i do not applications are
extremely personal
cover a couple of hours
in later in the afternoon
in fact this the concept is so general that practically every computer system can be
thought of as an agent some months
usefully but
the ones that doing something more sophisticated
can be thought of any useful as agents
and i should mention that
there is
some overlap between several fields here
there's an agent community
and there is an artificial intelligence community
and they largely overlap not completely
so i'm going to be concerned about
building intelligent systems this afternoon that's what elections at the rest later that
the computers they're intelligent
the other part of the asian communities interested in
that is more concerned directly with software engineering particular
moving software engineering from are into object oriented software engineering
the more sophisticated forms like a
of engineering
so there that we talk about intelligence
talk about building good computer systems the job that you want
and using
concepts from the agent
they're not directly concerned with
intelligence itself intelligence pass
the AI community
gets up in the morning because there
they want to solve this problem
have to tell the machine
and if you can go about building it
that's what motivates them the idea of building intelligent machines
imagine an environment to just trying introduce some terminology really
so you imagine that
this some environment
in which the agent is acting
and the environment can be many things will see some examples of the latter
the environment send signals
to the agent
and these are called percepts here all observations that equivalent words
so these percepts received by
the agent
the agent can apply actions back
to the environment in order to achieve some names
so the bottom of forgive got the inside the top of the the got the
percepts coming across
the signals that the agents getting from the environment and they can take many different
at the bottom is actions that the agent can apply back to the environment
in order to achieve what
it seems that
and those actions
are applied with what i call actuators
so here
the idea is that some kind of
and the actuators around the legs will something but actually they can be much more
of relative entropy
where you take the expectation with respect to the reference measure not with respect to
you can also do it in the original one but is not necessarily
OK so now this especially physicists like to call it keeps inequality
and this is actually the most important inequalities in information theory
without a doubt
use jensen's inequality wants to prove this one and then
ninety nine percent of the time you don't have to use jensen's inequality again or
use out the lower bounds on the lower them you just use this and then
i suppose you'll get
conditions under which whatever inequality you want to show
actually holds with equality
OK so
this is as i say here frequently known as gibbs inequality
now gates
it was kind of like the the father of five
statistical mechanics as we know it
mathematical statistical
mechanics thermodynamics and that's not what he showed
in in that they among other reasons because our defender b had not been invented
yet this was nineteen o one
this was well before
was actually well before jenson
it was well before
the definition of
convex functions actions
of course convex functions have been defined before force a real valued functions and an
functions on euclidean spaces but the modern definition of convex functions in abstract linear spaces
that is actually do to jensen that was
after this
beginning of the twentieth century even though it sounds like a very fundamental concept is
is about one hundred years old
so it's actually what he showed it's in that inequality for forty seven at the
bottom of actually what he showed was
a special case of the nonnegativity of mutual information
that's what that
inequality is showing
so it's not quite the nonnegativity of relative entropy
OK so let me show you now
a couple of
and then
are very important
particularly in information theory these are the bread and butter
of all the uses of relative entropy in
the really show why this is connected to the notion of information
so here the idea is that you have
think of this as a black box that has some kind of randomness inside
so we have a black box and then we drive that black box with
random objects that has distribution either px or qx
and of course those distributions then the indus an output distribution
all this is saying is there
relative entropy
at the input between these two distributions is derek well then the relative entropy at
the output
we quality
when when will quality well a special case that you will have equality is when
i hear what you have is just a one-to-one transformation
right to a one-to-one transformation is not going to change information but more
more importantly or more generally you're going to have equality
what you produce here is a sufficient statistic
for this pair of distributions
chris immediately you we receive their this notion
all of the information of preserving information is
essentially equivalent to preserving relative entropy
this one is kind of the wall here what we can is to black boxes
but only one input distribution
depending on the black box we have a different output distribution and what we're saying
is that the
relative entropy
on knowing the input
good writer
then the relative entropy not condition on knowing the input
in other words is always better to know
the nocturnal
at least for these purposes
OK so this is really
all there is here is the complexity of the fact that
a relative entropy is convex in the pair of distributions p and q
another very important property
is the chain rule
and no matter how many
random bible you can you have the joint distribution of several random variables but you
do have to have the same number
on both sides
unlike mutual information where you can have
anything you want on both sides
here remember that you have to have distributions that are defined on the same set
thanks to the user alone
the way the
helper that
well there's a square root
we now
we're very quickly with a lot of time but the going to be
is that what happens
when we think it is sufficiently large so we we get some some into the
on the bound so let me let me concentrate
we concentrate on the
this is about the whole
for any you offer anything the nonseparable
if the stream is terrible
then the this term and this term go away
so we left with the bound of the form
the minus one i
x pp where the
humans where there
the pair of
and now we look back to see what is the effect of changing the
the only thing we do
i mean the only our only criteria will be responded
in a separate prisoners
we can write
if we can write the because we look at this expression here
and now we can upper bound
part here in the following way
we've been mined
in the
x being
is created the
now this
corresponds to to the minus one
are you
two there
the whole thing but that's all over
and now
this is the well
the minus one
and then take across the commission here the times the maximum will be
which is the
we can write that
i don't think the math but we understand the math
like to the sea
if they can do
been on
of r anything nor would be
but there a lot of the people
i think
so is
so then
i get
the minus one
infinity norm squared
can pick it up
and i have seen
the that through all of you
because you can always write for my you which i
recall you're ugly to
if they think
log of d
where d is the dimension
number of components of a vector
but this choice
this is the most
a i get
ln b
this term
very upper bound to the stake they get x being
if is
and then this
it is
the route
the power of god divided by
two lnd
this is actually
e to b
ln the
between Exxon y all in fact you can move into generalized case that a secondary
that also distracted function is busy tradition only if we give military each between between
the or a menu structure on you Janet Accountability Act which is due make this
expression alongside them up between them from seeks to make stopped by to graduate look
of the characteristic function
and like that Dimitri on in fact which you'll of which featured which space
on the use of bulk of so it could be applied in the space of
a mattress authorship told fellow will always existed in our dedicated to the base of
the judiciary a symmetric matrices of in scariest you can express the the expiration of
the guide was characteristic function
the new you've sales that you have
Hudson of the other data that treats which is also involved in this approach on
the fallible Q. also wanted that size which is dedicated to exponential family alluding to
the gates of exponential factors in these during value facts and he's delighted to function
is to
2 on
violent scenes of which is given by the 2nd already knows of no characteristic function
is usually visit soon installation directory assistance in this specific case of parading there should
also be absolutely inch between and I just want to which we call on the
Commission geometry
what which is cooperating don't go processing the heart we want to computers and the
Internet to do with the between between 2 and is on the ballot some of
symmetry budget judicial so in fact exuded literature is a different approach to external the
geometric between of 2 computers which imagery commune but much of the Uganda computer intended
to push is a series of so initiates a buy it will buy a busy
will by on new computers is at the next iteration AAA acts of harmonic being
on the as I committee meeting of on each week on bills to true geometric
power but we use those expression is that fact it's is this week it's a
question of so it's very simple answers the geometric mean of this edition of seclusion
produced just have to to this fate this nitrates and tool to Mitch applied by
the country's seized on this side on then you could tell that the square off
will you because the square on the text of the square root of this situation
which is exist because the the system to give the mattress is on the menu
in which applied by
the square root of aid on each side on you as a final expiration of
the geometric mean 2 mattresses
on the judiciary could also complicate the GOP is unique in the space between 2
mattresses and even basic expressions so when she is equipped to do all the glory
days when she equal to 1 morning he on 43 . 1 as well as
to exactly the geometric mean between the 2 militaries
you could tell that we use as many times as the squalor defamatory so you
have different NATO to compute description of a film match which but also a radio
program using MATLAB 2 books
so where Jesus amid ideology inquisitive this terrific space in a case that
suggested that in Atqasuk appeared in geometry affect you have you as you know you
have this cemetery
the fastest Dimitri facts admitted communities and I don't believe he speaks is equipped with
to admit a community could be required to guide the souls who admitted communities in
value and by military on in fact when he walks on own on that fits
of the dictatorship but refused to Cemetery is just like a solicitation has been replaced
by application on admitting community and replaced by a geometric mean which is owned by
the city which is on the mend
on the extension of of Galileo case
given by the Commission consoling flights is the existence of a new symmetry which calls
for all those appoint a two-point beat all the invariant point is given by the
geometric mean between AMD onto dozens Cheerios which space that locality some sources
so it is
also related to 2 convicts were in fact the article effective so that the longer
bottle which is involved in complexity is replaced the and the exclusion
so we have defined what legitimately communion which is given by the British if we
would know what she's 6 we should also based some the law of a was
hitting the mattress
the Associated are so we have the expression of to the duties on in fact
if we use it as a result of differential geometry and so we have to
buy some thought of artists aren't just some of the Dungeons and so we have
expelled 6 1 6 to 2 which we don't want to see fossil of between
device found on each point we have the duty each we dungeon victory also was
a very sound of the
also the dungeon picked up judiciary should be equipped with you
do we as an expression of the we compute for each point the cheery deteriorated