of the pearson
inside the given full profile so you say this is the profile this is what
they want to know the name given to a given event
and here you have that the last time i believe way to use a simple
part which is you fix this subject to fix objective you ask for properties so
what that what he's is very relationship between me and union down separate bodies nos
so i know you're in
so simple but can be combined
in order to get more complex queries for instance
we are asking
to find the country
they capital and a population so
country is viable then you have to predicates the capital in the population and that
you have to viable
or here
give me the full of yuri
other pearson
name and the name of the friends so this is my fourth profile wants to
know my name what i know
and given what i know you want to know the name
OK so this is my answer we've
one variablebinding year more people variablebinding because i am i know several persons
and then
what you
and that
OK so my name you've got the name of multiple binding here because i i
know several person from these multiple binding
each of them you want to know the name
OK so this will answer in the guardian matthew that just enter room and so
forth OK
so these but there's basically go over database and extract all the people that match
this is where the selected
queries so a select query basically you give part and you get a table of
data out there but there are other kind of creating you ask queries were you
ever bullied answer so is this data inside the repository yes or no
you constant query that gives as a result
this is a graph
that contains the bindings as triples
so you can construct a new graph based on the information that you extract
and the last one is described which is the way you got information even without
knowing the triples the and the schema
so you see
this guy me these URL
and the system can answer with RDF that describe the specific URL and from that
you can learn the schema
so you ask for a URL of my fourth profile and you learn that the
reason name a side name and nickname and normal pages email and so you can
start writing queries that use that schema
all of these
is there a way to write the query
and the next thing is very is also way to send them
this is a query language for the web so it's not just a way to
express it clearly but also protocol to send the query to some engine and get
the result back
there is the protocol
in the sparql means i guess
simple protocol
and query language something like that i forgot so in any case these protocol inside
and the protocol is a way to send the query you can do it over
HTTP like these
so you are what you can see is very easy URL
query i'm exposing the sparql endpoint
and then i'm encoding using the
the name beginning the new way of writing get queries in http or the other
parameters so i'm saying query these graphs
so that pdfs and use this query select all the excess and they artist
i guess that if we here
i hope so at least
we're lucky get this comes from the
you see the URL that i wrote in the area of the binding
so i mean i've done something i send it to a sparql endpoint what i
got as a result is table
and the table contains all the artist better known inside the
this is i believe something quite cool but was really to bolster his idea semantic
web of creating multiple and points and so forth
any question
of course it is
just the minimal you can really read a lot i put links here just for
convenience in order to really is what i was trying
so going back to
our tutorial
we get into even more boring part of the tutorial which is the implementation details
of how you write code before we have really to design the last step which
is the design of application so we designed ontology of application we designed and built
the content we develop the simplest but we did not really design
the application this of course we will not be done in detail because i'm not
here to tell you about job i not about to java works actually i will
try to emphasise or only the things that are really to semantic web address these
java called you can download it and play with it if you really like to
do so
so designing the interface means two things means that
designing good design their applications so remains designing all the components and the interfaces among
and designing the
what the way the application works inside
first i will tell you about the interfaces the graphics user interfaces and interfaces to
the that sources
and then i will go into the design of mix as the program
but as to deal with the user interface and external data sources
more or less the disease
a pretty
straight representation of
what is outside next to outside mexico ever use any browser and the fact that
graphical model like the one on the right
where you see each variable like x three
being conditioned on all the previous ones
so these kind of the compositions had been used
before in the nineties in particular brand free in whose
toronto his thesis ninety seven proposed a
model that a essentially the has a logistic regression of each
bit in a vector given the previous bits
according to some order so you we're now not talking about sequences
so there's no role natural order but we can still pick an order
and then say we can model the conditional distribution of the aifb
variable given the ones from i from one to i'm minus one
and we just do a linear regression or
logistic aggression to obtain those conditions abilities
in in ninety nine with my brother semi we
sort of extended this to a neural net
where we said ok so that those conditional probabilities
instead of being computed by a linear model we going to be using
your net but instead of having a different neural net for each condition
probability now because we have these hidden units we can share
representation that we've learned for other earlier predictions
incoming up with the next prediction so this is very different
from normal recurrent net because in the normal recurrent net
there's this kind of translation variance in other words
we're assuming that what's you the parameters are good to predict
the next timestep are also good to predict that the one after one after
there is it doesn't matter we can take the data and then translated
and and the properties of those conditions butions remain the same
but here the the pixels could be yeah i mean that x one x two x
could be anything like any random variable there's no
there's no equivalent of i can translate and keep the semantics
so the parameters of conditionals you know for predicting
the third one would be different from the ones for taking
the fourth one now here we have the same thing but we can share because
when we makes a prediction for x three
given x one and x to extract some intermediate features are hitting
units and we could use these to predict x for a
well should our here i'm going from to to
p of x for yeah yeah so
a little later in two thousand eleven hugo who've who you've heard
monday a came up with a variation on this idea which
makes the computation
very efficient and also the statistical
representation more efficient so there's less parameters to
by introducing form of sharing that we didn't have so the idea here
is that the weights that go from x one to the first group of
hidden units will be the same as those go from x one to another
group of it's corresponding to the pretty if you want to make
in the future and so in this way have less parameters and
you can also organized computation so that it's actually
more efficient by reusing the computation that you've already made
for the earlier timesteps and you just have to add new terms when
we consider the next prediction say i now consider x three as an
extra input i don't need to redo the additions corresponding
to previous ones i just consider the new input and added
extra term to the sum so competition can be very efficient
now very efficient compared to previous models but it's still
very inefficient on like gp you because
this still very very sequential for each
group for each input and reach output we have to do next a little
bit of computation so it's kind of hard to paralyze but
but these kinds of models actually quite
work quite well and recently people have been using this style
model images and they're called pixel rnn's
and basically and these works surprisingly well so it's kind of
disappointing for people like me you've been working on
you know journ models with latent variables that these these
graphical models with our any latent variables so it's just like
a big recurrent net essentially our
with a particular structure can generate the next pixel
given the previously generated pixels so you can organize what's
previously generated in various ways for example on the top left
you see you just traverse you know all the rows and then you predict
the next pixel given everything seen before maybe you can organize
computation using this kind of triangle where use the information
from the top or like the one right i mean there are various architectures
you could use but the point as we define sequence
and we have a little recurrent net
which summarizes information you've seen in the path of the sequence
and is used for the next pixel and it's very slow because you have
OK so it doesn't make any difference
whether you detect little usage j a from
from the observation the subject a or whether you detect the vector
the use of capital j
from the whole set of of
the output piece of one of the visa capital
you get the same answer in both cases that you might say what happens in
some of these likelihood ratios come out to be right on the borderline equal to
one but doesn't make any difference because that's zero probability
o thing
if you want to worry about that you can worry about it and you get
the same answer you just have to be a little more careful
now here's something in the downside
it's also fairly important
here we're talking about the case where all these signals are independent of each other
which is sort of what we want to look at and communication because because the
most for what we're doing is we're taking is we're taking data some sort
resource processing it to make the bits coming up the channel be independent of each
and then we're going to be sending them
well except now we want to say well i suppose that these inputs are not
independent suppose for example we passed through an error correction
encoding device before transmitting them
the question is what happens then
well the trouble is that you had to spend you have dependencies between you want
a new subject i
so you can
you can still detect each of these
just by looking at the single output
and it's maximum likelihood detection based on that observations
but if you look at the entire observation v one up to visit capital cai
you get something better
however you get something better
well i know you get something better because in this case where you one of
the use of j
are dependent on each other these output variables these of one of the these capital
j depend on each other they are irrelevant
if you want to do the best
job of maximum likelihood detection given the observation of these of one of the visible
capital today
then you're going to use all those variables in your detection
and you're going to get better
and you're going to get a better decision in other words smaller probability then you
would have gotten otherwise
but the important thing that comes out of here
is that this simple-minded decision
where you make a decision on
i knew someone based just on visible on it's something you can do
you can do the maximum likelihood decision
can you know how it behaves you can calculate what the year probability is
but you know now automatically the year probability is going to be greater than or
equal to the air probability that you would get if you base that decisions on
the whole set of inputs
OK this is an argument that it seems hard for most people
that seems hard for most people to think
right at the beginning
which is really decide if you're doing an optimal detection it is optimal
in other words anything else and you do was worse
and you can always count on that they get
you know its count on that to get bounds between probabilities of severity you get
doing something stupid and probabilities of there that you get doing something intelligent and the
stupid thing is not only stupid this
i mean this stupid thing is sometimes better because it's cheaper but the air probability
is always worse there than if you do the actual optimum
OK so
so people in fact often do
detection where they have coded systems baby code each received symbol separately based on the
corresponding observation
they wind up with the larger probability than they should that it passes through
some kind of
some kind of error correction device
and they wind up with the system before that
the the sort of performs
reasonably and you as well what it would have performed better
if in fact what you did
was the way to make the final decision into that all the data
so we talk a little bit about various kinds of error control later when one
million to wireless
will see that some kinds of coding systems
can behave very easily and can make use of all this extra information
in other words can
algebraic kinds of schemes can seem to make use of the information
and various other kinds of schemes can make use of it
and if you want to understand what's happened in the year correction field
for the last five years twenty six four fifty one will be given free will
get all the details of this
but but the simplest ones sentence statement you can say i
is that the world has changed from algebraic coding techniques the probabilistic decoding techniques
and the primary reason for it is you want to make use of all that
extra information you get from looking at the full observation rather than just partial observations
now back to
fact the various signal sets
but this slide up last time
i what really talk about it this time
because for
for each number of degrees of freedom
you can define what's called an orthogonal codes
and the orthogonal codes for n equals two fram equals three
are now
so that's easy to do
but what if you want to be sure that this
bit string that with very high probability is irreducible has very little pattern what if
you want to be sure that this individual bits in the two got by this
hundred thousand
independent of the fair coin in fact
has very little pattern
well you know that it's essentially organically structure rather than random and the answer is
even though with overwhelming probability this is true
you can prove it
you really you can prove in individual cases
in individual cases so a little bit like quantum mechanics where you can say that
you know the short question with probabilities so to statistical theory and if i look
at individual atom i cannot predict whether it's going to be you know vision
i can only calculate the probabilities
here's an area of mathematics which behaves a little bit like
even though something is true with very high probability i can't be sure an individual
cases so i have statistical laws but i don't have
i can determine individual cases what's what's happening
i should
probably a good time to
stop and take questions or criticisms but let me just say what do i intend
to do in the in the next lecture in the second half
well it depends if you ask a lot of questions i'll try to explain things
better all over again but if it does if the things haven't gone bad we
would like to do in the second half of this morning is talk about an
even better example of lack of pattern or lack of structure or and algorithmic randomness
in pure mathematics and that's number called omega the halting probability
and that's my best example of lack of structure or something that notable in pure
i give you my one example now which was elegant programs
they have no structure bits
but i want to give you a better example
and that we and i'd i like to talk about
o briefly about some questions about his q like biologists like physics you know are
more philosophical questions like that but how about i stop now and take questions or
criticisms or
comments or whatever
you say
OK the all of these
the UK
on the
the problem with
so we
small stream is going to be taken
a program can hold
because we can
yes it's all connected it's all connected i agree
so i think
this is an information theoretic version of terms of the problem
in the way
that's the connectives
the difference is that here you have the idea of looking at the size of
the program
and you don't do that in terms of general formulation
but they're very strongly coupled
i agree
and you
you want
there is some connection
as you point out because
you're talking about a system
r cannot be explained in the simplest system where you're getting complexity
so in that sense what i'm doing is exactly the same thing
but not really exactly the same because to prove theorems
i deal with the grams and the size of programs and this is a very
o thing but i can prove results now
i don't know how to apply these ideas to the real world
you know
if you talk about biological complexity for example or emergence OF complexity about complexity of
economic systems and complexity of social systems complex psychological complexity and these are all wonderful
things and i agree the important to understand
but i do not definitely do not claim that these ideas
this notion of complexity
that i've given here the size in bits of the program
works very well in pure mathematics or metamathematics but i don't think it's the right
notion from biology you know from looking at ants were looking human society or human
you know my it's this is a very theoretical notion of complexity and that's why
i can prove theorems
now it seems to me that four different domains you probably need to have more
practical notion of complexity that applies in that domain and one of the things you'd
like it might be able to calculate the complexity in theory
you know my notion of complexity i can never calculate what it is you say
so i should apologize and say that i think this theory may be pretty but
it limited in its domain of applicability
i have to be honest about that this is not a theory of all possible
the new memories go in the same hardware this using for everything else
we don't know how
they're stored in the same hardware
andy importantly
that brains are robust hardware
so you can take a pigeon brain
we can take your brain and you can damage
many thousands of your neurons and you still
the following day
current functioning okay you do this whenever you drink alcohol
you you kill of neurons but you still keep going
craig in contrast if you reach into it and say well going destroy one per
cent of the transistors in this craig is can refine isn't it you find that
it is not fine
here's the hypothesis
the hypothesis is
the difference in the performance of the pigeon and the craig on this sort of realistic
real world image recognition task
because a very difference in style of computation
maybe the style computation
is the key
so maybe we should be getting away from serial if we are excited about being
able to solve problems that computers are still useless at
and maybe we should be going to genuinely parallel
maybe we should be looking at ways of using hardware that you have high conductivity distributed
and work in a completely different way
so in the next lecture we will come back to the task of storing and
recalling memories and will show a way of doing it
with a simple neural network model
i've just given you eh
fifteen minutes motivation for why we should be interested in
parallel distributed processing which is the name of one of the old bible the neural networks
anderson parallel distributed processing and talk about is
parallel-distributed-processing using
elementary devices that will call neurons
so we can have a single neuron
which is gonna be a thing that has the inputs
and output
and then we're going to why them up in a variety of ways
one way wiring them up is feedforward
which looks like this do have some inputs going in
some neurons
and then they connect small neurons
we can put arrows on these edges which way things go
and then we have another neuron
and then something comes out
so that's a forward
it's simple to describe because it's sort of deterministic just but in input these guys can compete these can
compute is can compute and then up
another way wiring these things up would be a feedback network where you say
let's allow
everyone outputs
to be
everyone else's inputs
what about
and then
and the dynamics depend on exactly how you define
the way
all the neurons interact
and maybe something more exciting happens
let's tell you a bit more about the single neuron
and then
for today's lecture i'll talk to you about
feedforward networks
and the next lecture will look at feedback
so here's how they
single neuron works
single neurons got inputs
the output
hand it's got some parameters
and the parameters are commonly called
and the parameters learned here between the inputs can be
multi neuron
and his works is very simple
if the weights are w one w two
not w
and if the inputs are
what the neuron does is it adds up though in weighted
some of its inputs
using its own weights
in our case only twenty
now some results for the in competition so just these results are going to be
preliminary since the official results but i just want to give you some impression of
this looks like
so it
their control competition conditions so there
they took the c elegans genome and took only ten percent of the genome for
training so they allowed only i mean they find what the training set is going
to be in the test set is going to be so this was ten percent
training ten percent for testing two cases one is a single predictions and then combining
predictions so combine and combine the predictions of seventeen i'm try to find a consensus
between seventeen typically
i mean there
but i haven't seen the results this just so that four categories one subunit two
gene finding this what have survived
then there is another category which can use other genome and see how much
certain sequence part arkansas so if something is concerned this usually means it
function and functional is probably part of x
so this gives you some additional information on the gene finding
OK so
families can use
sequences which provided and down this last category which can use any kind of relation
OK so let me just show you walk everyone briefly
so there are three evaluation category one is on the nucleotide level so we look
nucleotide all this would classified right
x x one in four orientations
and we get like our system is called in team and we get the highest
accuracy on the
the difference and on the here but there no
so much room
so in this escorting excellent so we count on
x the harmony express that identify correctly
and the last four years on the front of many genes already transcripts have been
predicted completely correct
so what you see here is different systems and
i mean
our system was like version zero one version one wasn't really i mean almost ready
to be submitted something so quite successful so we got the best result in a
nuclear level according level but that's the levels of other systems
and really
later figure out this is spring this is due to the definition of the loss
so we only had to incorporate incorporated losses on look at at heights and exons
but not on the front
and what you see is actually transcript of of of this is due to the
there are some other the other category that uses conservation interesting
the average performance in the category is actually worse than they had one even though
it uses more information the average among the other so all the was slightly better
than the category but the others here
actually we're encountering one
and the last one that uses some sequence information they can on
OK so
i discussed already so it's good on the nucleotide excision level suboptimal on the front
level and the reason was that genes will converge
so and this was because that's what i think
there's some possible improvements
we call over this would like to mention that typically
nineteen prediction isn't as easy so we don't know exactly what i mean there might
be several ways of splicing points for starting gene so this actually transcription one like
and and in a few cases it might be that you have to click here
except that in the middle there might be several very
delta v
cool three of five
thank you all for your time
and this one
is often called
there data is a cubicle
expansion coefficient as opposed to the linear one
so you will say well big deal
BYU talking about data because if we have the values for all five
all we have to do is we go to the volume
to make that
beta three all fine we're in business
well we have liquids
in general you don't find in the table values of
so when you deal with liquid for instance mercury
is one
i want to use today
then you find
that the
cubic expansion coefficient eighteen
times ten to the minus five
degrees centigrade
by compared with pyrex
you have to take three times this value
so it's very roughly ten to the minus five
o degrees centigrade
so now
you begin to smell the ideas
of the mercury
i put to mercury
in pyrex glass
and the pyrex glass is not going to explain very much
mercury real
and the mercury
which is in an enclosed environment
we have to expand
and it expands into my thermometer
and that's the way
we read the temperature
so here is the glass two which is very very narrow
this is close here
that's a really is here
it is only o point one millimeter
here is the reservoir
mister working example
and suppose we take
one cubic centimeter
the simple numbers
i just want to show you the
the basic idea behind the summer
i'm going to increase the temperature of this
say by ten degrees
delta t
then degrees centigrade
so how much will this
volume expension delta
because beta
eighteen times ten to the minus fit
times the volume which is one cubic centimeter let me just put the volume in
there you may want to do it in cubic metres only for the u
times the delta t
you'll find
the expansion in terms of cubic centimeters
is o point
o one eight
cubic centimeters
three in cubic centimetres
what you can do
you get your answer also argued that if you do not always
work after work and KS
so it is is extraordinarily small increase in terms of volume
the pyrex
it's not expanding at all you can just forget that for now
you want to calculate how much it is it's fine but is eighty times less
so the fact that the vessel get the larger
of course is important but i will just ignore that for now
so i'll just assume that all these mercury
will be driven up here
and so if the mercury then
changes its height
by an amount delta h
and if this is a tool with the radius point one millimetres
and this amount of mercury must be the same as by are screened
i fell for age
which is the volume
of the new colony increase in the column
so you
i take your point one millimetres
and you'll find the delta h
for this example that i chose
five point seven centimetres
that's a huge
it's very easy to see for ten cents ten degrees centigrade in increasing temperature gets
where else OK so
one thing that's kind of starting to
kind of
matter which kind of conceit
parents so let's call children as the descendants parents because of
parents kind of mass there's an important
children are are important
they have the
child parent is also important
when you put all this together you get something called the markov blanket
is a graphical model
there was
popularized but you apparel
and later
again the nodes are unbearable theatres indicate
link causation
quotation marks because it's not a causation
OK so
you know aliens come to earth the founders this device
the device
points in one direction to follow this direction and find the polar bear
and then they repeat this experiment ninety percent ninety seven point eight percent of the
times they followed this arrow define the polar bear
and they concluded this is the full of air indicator
correlations is not causation
the device being in all the point
the the semantic search we will have this
that your variable will depend will be
independent of the ancestors
given the parent so-called
given alarm
using that
it will be independent of all these variables
if you know
again there's of the situation is there's
an earthquake recording you're driving home
and in order to know whether an earthquake well you switch on the radio to
know whether this
the radio announcing an earthquake in l a or not
if the alarm burglary goes off in your home
and it calls yourself
you get large so you also know that there's a chance that it could be
so the alarm on your cell phone could either because because there was an earthquake
the house shakes well because of the comes in
and based on the alarm you gonna cell phone call
and what you are trying to establish here is
what's going on
OK when when you receive this call
OK so you receive this call
so we can see this case
the one case arising without knowing
the status of the radio
it would help you know there's an earthquake or burglary
OK because if you switch on the radio
and it tells you yes there's been an earthquake then you're kind of
burglary is less problem
so in particular
suppose you have call
so you shade shaded very with indicative of call
we're computing the probabilities for doing inference here we just think the marginalisation task
computing the probability of an earthquake
that you've received a call the probability that the earthquake is true
given that the you've received a call call true
and in addition you might have their point one here and
and you might have the probability of burglary being true beings are point seven because
after all this is a like rather
there's my brother is an earthquake
so this is your prior status of the world then you serve
the variable radio
OK and the radio station
everybody knows
do whatever you can do this if you like there's an earthquake
and based on that
here we compute this probability
the probability of an earthquake now that given that there was
he received a call and given that the radio confirmed that there was an earthquake
that goes to point ninety seven
and that goes to o point one
and i guess the reason why stochastic and it doesn't go to one is because
the things might
have hope their devices into the radio so that they could
tamper with your home
and this is called the sort of explaining away
effect on seattle variable
and that's what it's all about graphical models because you
you will get this
you will get the whole lecture on this next week
and i need to go back to wonder cargo
by the way if there's anything that's not clear which if any of these operations
so it's not completely convincing that we really made any progress but the fact is
we have by expanding i will beyond plain all repetition as a way of any
redundancy we've got the error probability into places it couldn't get to before
the next slide is going to show you
where you can get to by
inventing more block codes
i'm not going to tell you your main homework problem for tonight you may homework
problem is to invent another block code and the decoder for it and and added
to this diagram
invent a code
the decoder
work out what is our is
and look at what is the probability that error work that
and added to the diagram
so that's a fun homework problem for you
and these pluses shows where
people have got to with a whole bunch of codes you can find in textbooks
on coding theory the written in the sixties seventies and eighties and you can see
all of those policies
are to the right of way can get to with repetition codes remember where we
want to be is lower probability and largest possible rate so this arrow showing where
we want to get we like being in the bottom right-hand corner we'd love to
have a coat with a huge rate like one and the probability of zero which
log scale way down here
we love this
we don't like that
OK this is the linear scale
this is a log scale identical graphs but just on the right ones log scale
OK so that's your homework problem
the obvious question that this diagram is now raising who reason this exciting we can
do better than repetition codes well how good can it get where can we get
by being clever where we get to by generalizing the seven four hamming code and
coming up with other ideas and you can see just vague sort of scatter of
points and no
a clear indication of where we can get but you might imagine
but the answer to this question where is the boundary what's achievable
where the boundary between achievable
and knowledge she will point you might imagine that the answer to that question is
well surely it's line of some sort
the goes through the origin
so maybe
the question marks
the boundary look something like this
because that's what solves law would say would say you can't get something for nothing
if you want the error probability to get lower and lower and lower you will
be forced by this boundary to have rate the gets lower and lower as well
that certainly is consistent with what happens with the repetition codes if you want to
get the error probability down to the minors fifteen the rate had to go away
down here if you wanted to get ten to the minus fifty the rate would
have to get even lower so be push towards their that sort law that's the
way normal life is you you want something really really good you have to pay
for it and here the units you pay and with be rate and before
shannon came along and i'm sure everyone in the field of communication imagine this was
the case that the boundary between achievable
and not achievable points
it it was some sort of line
going through the origin
here is the most exciting results of the twentieth century
the most exciting result is the boundary between achievable
and ninety four points does not go through the origin
it comes down here
makes this axis
at a non-zero value
which is the property of the channel working with this property called the capacity of
the channel
is saying that
it's possible to get the error probability as small as you like
you get it down to ten five fifteen
what defines eighteen or five fifty or as small as you want all
at big rates and for this particular channel that we've been discussing today
which bought move on to now have lost track
it is
so this binary symmetric channel
the capacity is about half
that's a tiny bit bigger
and here's the formula for it is expressed in terms of the binary entropy function
what does this mean
this means a stunning fact it means that if you've got a totally lousy destroyed
the flipping ten percent of the bits
there exists an encoding and decoding system you can wrap around this this right such
that if you just hide two describes inbox
meaning that be working at a rate of one half
which is below capacity you can get there probably down ten minus eighteen
no problem
down to ten to fifty to one hundred it's possible
and all you need is to distracting in the box
so that's a topic for another lecture so the the question is what's the complexity
what i'm telling you is the theorem says there
there exists an encoder
the details
you can slap around the channel
and you can achieve any point on this diagram
the theorem just says it exists
and it's a very cheeky theorem because the proof is nonconstructive just says it exists
because of
what going
you know
or or
i mean
a four
the reason
i get
i'm quickly going through these two examples supervised classification anomaly detection outlier detection in the
talk after this dave weston is going to give you a detailed examination of the
same name class of methods that we've been looking at computer analysis but he's an
expert on that so can leave that one entirely to him
so returning to the second method outlier detection
the basic principle the build model for the norm for this customer
and detect when
transaction behavior begins to deviate from this norm
the norm can be based on various based on various datasets built in various ways
you can based on
this customer compared with their own previous behaviour
put jeanne jarring in brackets agenda are in is the
the term they use to describe
using different credit cards for different kinds of things so i might use a particular
credit card for hotel transactions another one supermarket transactions another one for petrol gas transactions
and not deviate from that sort of patterns
and then of course
if y
petrol station
credit card is used by connecticut or something
that to raise the flag because the behavior on that particular credit card is abnormal
so people practice can jarring and that's probably quite good take a message
it does enable more effective
for detection systems to be developed
so that's something you might think about
so that's one thing you can do you can build normal models based on the
is the the previous behaviour the customer
you can also build based on this customer compared with other customers
life stage
usage patterns
people who just got there first credit card behave differently
from people have been using cards
thirty years
you can segment customer financial behaviour types and of course you stick all these things
as i said the basic advantage of the one class approaches you can detect new
kinds of deviations from whatever you're norm
which might of course mean that you've got more
in a dynamic for the environment the you know one thing about this we know
is that the environment distributions change
so maybe these things
are important
the norm can be
you can model the norm in various ways you can assume distributional form for the
normal behaviour for example let's get very simple we can assume
the multivariate normal distribution and use mahalanobis distance to measure the distance multivariate normal distribution
for the transactions of the activity records measure distance using mahalanobis distance
that's good because you get accurate probability estimates if you have a mate with a
multivariate normal assumption
and so it can be what you can do with relatively small sample sizes
but of course
for any upside there's the downside another very water very sensitive the thing sensitive to
see this informative distribution skills this is probably not going to be terribly good
and to outliers you can try to overcome that by robustifying the estimates you know
whenever a problem occurs people try to solve it
you can also relax these things
we sacrifice some information about assumptions about the precise distributions you can measure relative distance
from some
center like mean in any direction using chebyshev inequality doesn't make distributional assumptions and so
and of course you can use nonparametric approaches
this is an example i'm going to give for example you can use kernel density
estimation to estimate the
probability density in any region the transaction or activity records space
and if it prop that is very small and something because there is suspicious
this sort of description if you like is the statistical description of these methods the
computer science work in this area which is really equivalent to it
often causes distance based methods but to just
well as the reciprocal ways of looking at the same thing
they can be subtle complications
and many if any of you have worked in this sort of area of familiar
you easily detect but this is
lying in sparse region is anomalous unusual kind of transaction
it's a long way from any other point it's different from any other point this
transactional activity record is different from any other point
but what about this one
the distance between this
o point and
its nearest point
is much the same as the distance between the so it probably wouldn't be flagged
as being very fast suspiciously far from its nearest neighbour
but of course
relative to the local density of points here it is
a long way away
that suggests a problem of approach to overcoming this sort of problem you could the
density estimate a particular transaction at point with that of nearby points rather than globally
and of course people who extended these you know we could talk all day about
these sorts of methods
but i want to move on to the example
another member of the team has been focusing on this this particular example
forty four thousand accounts
two point three million transactions
three of three thousand of these were fraudulent fifty three thousand four hundred transactions three
months of data so suddenly several variables remember between seventy and eighty in this case
this particular banks several variables and we just chose these i think yes eight
this to describe each transaction
some of them are continuous
some are
discrete is and merchant category code again without
around two thousand different categories
so the high number of categories
the merchant category code we the way we treat in this particular analysis we essentially
converted it to a continuous variables
what we did was we looked at each this this was ATM withdrawal data we
looked at
so cash machine withdrawals data we looked at each cash machine
and i looked at
which counts
which people use that cash machine
so that gives us a binary vector if you like
or you can look at how often they use that accounts which would give you
numbers are very sparse
binary vector
but nevertheless binary vector and you can define distances between the ATM machines
a lot of the state with
focus work with focal parts work
they actually used they use their cameras
and actually happens there is a sixty eight points they had thousands of points so
they're actually doing this in a very small
it's small about that would get very very good renderings
but because we insist on doing this past and we're more interested in registration at
the moment and synthesis
but we do need some work and synthesis
active appearance was actually we've got a we had an NSF project funded recently that
gotta lotta love interest at all
and it was doing some studies on human social dynamics
what we're doing with was that we were actually we tracking people in real time
and we make them having conversations with each other and so but the only the
people couldn't see each other they could on the computer screen
and what we would do we would animate and at the avatar of that person
things but the cool thing with i
is that because i can manipulate the appearance
and the shape of things i can start playing
with how the person looks so have the person perhaps even in sound so we
actually did some studies in two world
two people when a male male one mile and mile are in conversation
is there any change of actually changed the sex of the male to female even
though he a mild
this distance warping something like that and so the active appearance model sort of allied
to investigate these qualities school effects and also some things with voices and things in
a different animations and we're going to be a bit about the but that's a
little bit of it's kind of cool social experiment things so you can get
there is a similar thing in audio visual speech we could we would really the
researchers can really trying to look for
something that analogous to
the mcgurk effect is anyone ever had the mcgurk effect
it's essentially with mcgurk effect it's
the idea is this
is that
you could be sentence sounds alike by the classic like by god and
and unsurprisingly if all i mix up
so the sales and may visually
actually the visual movements above and
i oftentimes perceived neighbour
so if i go back in audio
god in video
and merge them together sometimes people perceive that
so it what's kind of indicating whatever it is that we don't necessary we rely
on both modalities and so what we can't of this research was kind of trying
to look for
mcgurk effect
with other other things towards say the face all six or or things like that
so and so it's it's a promising avenue and so we're trying to kind of
this together in this kind of more
the rest of this lecture will be basically what how to build a name which
i'm sure you guys wondering about how do you feel and name an image what
is the general approach
and how can we do it efficiently and we also talked about some extensions
so the way we're building a in we're talking about this before about is that
we actually have to sit lot unfortunately for you guys all the time the student
that sit down and they have two
the points in images and as i saying yesterday
not just one or two images like thousands upon thousands upon thousands of images
and you have to click these points consistent consistently
and you can kind of see that it actually is kind of tough fast sometimes
because OK sure enough i can probably reliably most people can reliably find the all
i want to hear the icon here
knows perhaps you the top and is here but you start getting into world
where exactly should be putting this point in the jaw
where exactly should be pointing this this point so
a big part of this is not only the scan the points but have a
good software package that can actually take care so in our software packages instead of
looking for individual points we have we got a choice of labelling something whether it's
circular contour along contour and we also have things in there so to say
it probably isn't very clearly hear what about some of the points you raise
and the primary points and their points that can be easily distinguished the collect anchor
points and then you got the green points where you kind of approximately know where
they are we let the algorithm also called make sure that they will interspersed well
placed things and so what do we do from that is essentially get sixty points
from the fact there's still a lot of open open questions and especially faces
how many landmarks should have obviously the more landmarks the better
but a problem occurs is that when i start adding more landmarks one seventy were
actually place landmarks can increases so you think you must be pretty good but when
stock going blog about sixty eight it becomes difficult because of course
i can heal
i'm sorry really going to pick up
can you part
what i mean
you clicking on point here so i may talking about clicking on the point two
active appearance models
well in is this is about your questions yes
so each should be they should be i mean i think there has been some
there has been some work done with infrared cameras and other cameras and things like
that so as long as you get a reasonable image and that the idea of
and still still applies and i believe it should still apply although would be kinda
with family images
but you could try we have not any way that you have
but it's the big thing is that
so you can't just saying that's a like a video sequence of
of the thermal image sequence whatever you actually have to make sure that the data
sets maps you actually have to have a lot of one data of thermal images
that have points click the
things such as usual there's some sort of match
and so
some of some the subject and then these all points were kind of physically clicked
on we one that we've got a lot of different datasets and
like i was talking about like the vocal the so the voltage and stop work
data drives this stuff so you can have the best album in the world but
if you don't have a lot of data
and this is like what you guys know machine learning when you don't know something
you make up for the data
and this is essentially what you have to do with a lot of this work
a lot of the leading
institutions that on this have a lot of this data set
that that's that's the real the real the real thing but it's a good reason
to question is that safer faces and for other objects whatever it's really well defined
because people are willing to consider and click on this point is a way that
we can kind
extend this work to other object classes were people willing to sit down can i
would like i do this in an unsupervised way
four different objects
and so we've actually been doing a little bit of work on that and we
call that unsupervised image alignment
and actually i don't have any so i might want to show you guys that
so this is basically equiv just because i have it up there
we refer to this as
seems to be here
concealing and i to showing this before
essentially what the task is here is that they are OK to sell these these
digits here but to say i have and have-not class where i don't have a
lot of people who are willing to sit you click on sort of can i
o line and issue the problem is this
what if there are four dimensional vectors
so it's the column space of a is a is a subspace
one of our four here
because a one
four by
a four by three matrix tell me
how many rows there are how many components in the column
and so we're in our four OK now what's in that
what's so the column space of a it's a subspace of our four
i call it the column space make it like that
so that's my
little symbol
for some subspace of our four
what's in our what's in that subspace
well that culture
one two three four this problem is in this column is in and what
so it's got the columns of a in it
but that's not enough to
right i don't have a subspace of i just put in three vectors
so how do i feel that out to be a subspace
i take
comm linear combination
so the column space of a is all
combinations of the column
and that does give me
a subspace does give me a vector space because of i one linear combination multiply
by eleven
i've got another linear combination
if i have a linear combination i had to another linear combination again the third
so that this is like the smallest space
like it's got to have those three problems in
and has to have their combinations and that's where we stop
i'm going to be interested in that
sort of like to get some idea of what's in that place how big is
that space is that space the whole four dimensional space
or is it a subspace inside
ten years
made to see if you can
i i mean
we can get a yes or no answer sometimes without
without being ready for the complete proofs
what do you think is the subspace
i'm talking about here combinations of those three guys that
all four dimensional space
maybe yes or no on that one
no somehow our feeling is
and it happens to be right
that if we start with three victories and take their combinations we can get the
whole four dimensional
so somehow we get a smaller space but how much smaller
that's OK i'm going come up here not so media
ah let me let me
make this critical connection with it
linear great
behind our
abstract definition we have a purpose
that is to understand a sequel the
so suppose i make the connection
a and he will be
always have a solution for every b
i have a
have a
for every
right hand side
i guess that's going to be a yes or no question
and then i'm going to have wait
right hand sides are OK
that's really the question i asked
with the right hand side b
make up you can see from the way i'm speaking what the answer to this
question as it is
the answer is no
actually will be does not have a solution for every
why why you say why do i say no
because they actually will be is
it's really this is
like this is for equation
and only three and
let me let me
the way that the whole
but the whole thing looks like
right now they actually will be
these columns are one two three four
one one one one
one two three four five
and of course has three components x one x two x three
and i'm trying to get
the right
right hand side b one b two b three and e four
so my first point is i can always do it
in way
that just says again what you told me five minutes ago
that the combinations
of these columns don't fill the whole four dimensional space
there's going to be some vectors b
a lot of factors be
that are not combinations of those of the recall
was the combination those columns are likely to be just a little plain something inside
inside our goal
so you see that i do have four equation
and only three unknown
so like everybody is going to say no you
don't you can usually solve for equations with only three
but now i want to say
sometimes you can
for some right hand side
i can solve
that the that's the one the right hand side that i'm interested in right now
with the right hand side
allow me to solve
that is the question but it
it's going to have like a nice clear and
so my question is so my question is
which vector b
allow me
system to be solved
i want you
so that's like
get two question marks indicate
that is the important question OK
first before we
given that give total answer give me just a partial answer
the only one right hand side that i know of
i can solve this
all the
OK that's the like
something b
the into
you see that the most likely sequence of length one two four
and you see this should here they all have some published the meaning
you can use indeed and learning for interpretation
later i mean this this very which we did a while ago
later became
much nicer way of looking at the classifier
can he certainly much more features we can also see that maybe link
but hey mister link the one
he came blink one b and four
in this area there are some came or
but you have a much higher resolution to look
i wouldn't
necessarily suggest to to use some of the ending point of the patient if you
have the other choice
a few things
these position twenty equal
or at least these kind of
there but for
what interesting
this is the projection of the vector from what in india
you know what the way that we can
what's the
i mean what's the linear OK
in europe the best
my question is
the first course if this is whether the weight vector of the classifier
OK and what is the projection of the weight vector and
in that case the whether the classifier is linear or not
one is the kernel used here debating so this is our last example very typically
use the for
this is similar to this year
we optimize the weights in the baby
we get a similar picture qualitatively get similar but you see
why if you want to
in this country
i i wonder in this case the weight far regularized
because it's the weight of
i probably didn't understand exactly what projection of the weighted mean in in the weighted
kernel learning fitting you did regularized the
the weight of the kernel now also regularly are regularized by actually l one wrong
so named by the by the most weight and the other case
twenty plot here
something like the maximum wage
paul heymann position
so we take the maximum all
so it so
there might be a large number of being channelled important but is this may be
something as important hold on
and that this maybe of
yes endurance
so then i continue with structured output learning so
this is going to be about hidden markov models that support dynamic programming
and this community hold for learning
these like one
so what about dynamic programming
people who could be able to implement the program
OK let OK that i can go
what you see now is
he talked about
and this is
he says got a product the feature vector
now we can extend this in two ways to
we talked about this just of the kernel you can be extended by taking a
linear combination of other way of handling it is too
don't the label
in the future
not only the input example but also take the output cells
into the
OK so so far was maybe really useful because we only had two possible labels
but if you want to compute something more of it you want to something more
complicated than maybe you
it's more useful to compute y in
this is good for learning
generally the task is that we have some
labelled data and we would like to predict labels input would like about
OK so in multiclass we which simply not get too close to home twelve times
policy have been shown which basically means a large number of plans
and you and you and actually did do some interesting work region was bought improving
so basically starting with a
approximate global policy
and improving it i think
we look at a couple of details of these
the first one are learning dimensions influencing the benevolent so the idea is you get
a bunch of land and you want to example plans you try to explain for
example why these plans are correct
so what pieces of these plans make them correct for these problems and use that
to essentially known rules which say that ran
these are the initial state literacy initiative these other goals features these must be the
action sequences issues
OK the EBL part here actually occurred
in doing that in there
analysis given the planned essentially that explain why is kind
in an example
o that of
the kind of thing that they do
so here they are shown i
here's on a simple problem simple plan which involves robot going into a different room
we at that by ball becoming the rule one and dropping it
OK and the
look at that sequence of states and actions and they learn a little rules here
which basically says that when you have these goals and these kinds of things instead
this must be the sequence of actions whose
OK now you have a different way shown here
and that leads to a different
such rules and then that the what essentially is trying to make sure that
you kind of what these things into a more general which covers what
and in essence what they're doing in their way of computing the approximate policy of
state schools to actions through these rules this is the representation of the policy
so the other way of looking at it is to say that a policy can
be seen as the classifier and so we can learn it
so if you have access to an traces of an optimal policy
so if you assume that there is an optimal policy for this domain which basically
six smg
and that's what the action is viewed that policy and generating places
and you have these decided degrees
you can just say
in a sense you can see that
it tells you about the conditions what are the states with certain actions are applicable
each tragically you you've state action state action
so you have examples positive examples saying this states
you should be doing is actions
OK carbon actually looking back in nineteen ninety nine
looks that are inductive learning problem and learn conditionally
which however as i said
because of course that you have access the assumption that you have access to an
optimal policy that somebody is showing you examples
there is some new work actually i think this is also connected to some of
the one that
that are detrimental to that and you but this is one of the more familiar
with you don't have access to places from an optimal policy
so what you could lose about his combine induction and reinforcement learning together
OK so
you start me an approximate policy
i could be completely bad
you know policy improvement
and when you do policy improvement
and then so you have a policy iteration step and policy learning step the policy
learning step here is similar to to
what and that's
and the improved isolation step
is if you remember the lecture by setting that they basically this issue after that
you can follow new policy iteration to improve policy my presentation
the tricky part here
it is
to make it actually work the wind up not doing so if you remember the
way the policy improvement is done you can what the policy value function and they
can with the value function back into politics
but without doing that you will also actually just if you only have an access
to assimilate
would simulate this policy i using those trajectories
you can do approximate
policy iteration which is basically what
if you want to do this is by the way the planet that i was
mentioning yesterday which they
then there and stochastic planning competition for last years
the nation made
not one
you get
the idea of all
back c
not all i like to be able feature selection
and so i think using
and then you
propagating the truth
or secrets mentions which is much more likely
i think there are this connection
in fact
so long as you can see just i was taken but the people of ideas
take back when he was hard on and enforcement learning
this would be nineteen
the nineteen ninety nine
so you can look it up
so so what they doing here is in a sense generating the trajectories for the
improved policy that's the tricky part and the way they do do it is
i mean i'm not going to be able to work details but in a sense
this is a tragic that the generated but putting broad policy starting rate
all the
so starting with a current policy
do policy iteration step which sort of generates that trajectories for improved policy
and once you know that article is for the input policy you can learn an
approximation you can learn essentially a closed form of the traditional from the improved policy
which then goes back to this look
trying to improve the
and the idea
of doing that he had essentially is not starting from st
they consider doing
it's possible action
and then actually generating a simulation of the policy that they currently have
and if it doesn't end in you know in planning one of the problems is
in terms of looking at
planning problems where there are records of achievement as an MDP
the reward function is very sparse
all right so i guess i just like to begin by thanking the organisers for
the opportunity to be here is real pleasure to be part of this this summer
school have been enjoying myself to release
OK so i'll be talking in this part of the graphical models message passing algorithms
and variational methods and will be that of overlap with the talk of sam roweis
but also be moving on to some more advanced topics sort of building on the
foundation that sam built for over the past couple days
so for those of you interested if you look at my web page there's copies
of these slides
also fortunately copies of films of course lectures so much more detail than i give
here this will be some more high-level than that full-length course for obvious reasons
but if you are interested in more details you can have a look at this
web page there
so sort of reviewing part of what's sam said graphical models are are really framework
for describing systems that are statistical in nature
but there are also large scale and multivariate
so you want to think about how many random variables and all interacting in possibly
quite complex ways
graphical models are actually
this is my country by the way
you wanted to make people hear me properly
OK so actually used and studied in many fields
of course there are widely used in machine learning but historically at least they were
used much earlier in other fields primarily in statistical physics to model things like crystals
and magnets in gas is basically very large systems were lots of things are interacting
in it's only more recently they have proven very useful in other fields of of
engineering and computer science so
i'll talk a bit about applications in computer vision
many applications in machine learning
lots of bioinformatics and computational biology
and also to sort of illustrate other applications that you might not be aware of
but there are very relevant given you're using computers and wireless devices all talk about
about how graphical models play a role in communication systems
some broad questions before we get into details
i think it's useful to think there's is there are several kinds of questions or
issues to think about when you're considering using a graphical model
and will get into a bit of detail on each of these
the first caller representational issues
so it's really an issue of you're given some phenomenon might be an image it
might be a text database
you might be trying to track vehicle
what you really want to understand is what graphical models are useful for capturing or
modelling the particular phenomenon that you are interested in
so it's really representational issues trying to understand how does what classes of models are
useful for what purposes
basically there is a tautology that no model can be good for everything
if someone tells you this model is good for everything they're lying to you it's
probably useless in fact
models are generally good for specific purposes but you need to understand what the sort
of trade-offs between different models are
there are also statistical issues with these models they are essentially statistical models for
fitting random variables probabilistic systems and so sam spoke about one important issues is really
that of inference
at a high level you want to think about this is how you move from
data you observing some data in the real world and you like to somehow on
the basis of measurements you'd like to make inferences you'd like to draw conclusions about
some underlying hidden phenomenon and i'll give you some examples of that in the next
few slides
sam also spoke about there's issues of how you fit parameters how do you choose
the best model to fit your data
and somewhat more broadly the question of model selection how do you actually choose the
class of models it's appropriate
this is the third sort of interrelated issues is really computational one
that has to do with the fact is as i mentioned these models are typically
very large scale
you know interesting things with one two or three subcomponents interesting things with hundreds of
thousands possibly millions of interacting components so computation issues of storage and efficiency really become
critical and so we're going to see is that the graphical models really help to
clarify some of the links there some very deep a nice connections very powerful connections
between the structure of the graph that you use sand was mentioning last time chains
and trees will be talking about somewhat more general graphs
and we'll see the connections between the structure and sort of what the inherent computational
complexity of applying using these models is
so anyway
feel free to jump in with questions whenever you feel so inclined
do you think about speakers
you should try and control your speakers somewhat this is what i tell my students
if you speak go too quickly then you should throw questions in the way to
slow them down if you speak goes too slowly then you should fall asleep and
and start making noises that encourages people to go quickly
OK so this is just an outline again part of this is actually piggy-backing on
on what sam spoke about so i'm going to go through this part of it
a bit more quickly than i i would normally in particular this message passing samarati
spoke about on trees i'm actually going presented from a slightly different perspective so you'll
be seeing the same material but from a somewhat different view and i think that
can be useful to it often useful to see things from different points of view
it gives you a deeper understanding
can values we discarding the so basically what we're getting rid of this
it would be to add diagonal term
two the covariance matrix which would actually eliminate all those negative and these positives as
and then it would just leave by adding the diagonal terms with and i can
with the value of about there it would just eliminate all that i would have
a positive definite covariance matrix so it saying the negative and this is in the
noise of but it is a difficult thing to interpret and it isn't correct
and it comes up in these situations where you to specify a distance matrix or
dissimilarity which is not necessarily euclidean and you doesn't necessarily conform to things the euclidean
distance should conform to
so be careful
you can see and habitually statisticians
you have ignored these
two classical scale
in practice in machine learning with actually typically being a lot more worried about them
and also say why that is in the moment it relates to sort of kernel
methods and so on and so forth
OK so here's the reconstructions the distance matrix
the left is the original distance matrix and on the right is the reconstructed distance
now you can see that they look pretty good
there are some i think down here for example
so i thought so in something that i mean this structure is broadly speaking
so we've got a good reconstruction in the distance matrix using only two dimensions using
classical scaling approach
you can use the similarity you can either start from the similarity in the eigenvalue
problem directly online at all
you can take distance and convert using this the covariance interpretation
be aware of similarity must be positive semi definite for the distance to be euclidean
why we can immediately can see positive definite is sufficient from the covariance interpretation well
if it is positive definite we know that this the similarity positive definite we know
that the could that distances must be
valid because the covariance interpretation they were expected distances which are going to be valid
the expected squared distances but then to see the proof that this is euclidean nature
between the similarity which is positive definite and distance pages see my is a lot
more involved in the my covariance interpretation which is the sufficient condition is not necessarily
a necessary condition but i think it gives you much better intuition as so what's
going on between these included in distances and this covariance matrix
OK so
the point in doing this background i mean you probably not seen many papers about
classical scaling or anything else in machine learning well why
well you have actually perhaps but they don't tend to
highlight the fact that what they're doing is really classical scaling what the history of
it is what these things mean and so in some sense
this part of the talk up till now
has really been about trying to give you a background in classical scaling which tries
to let you understand a lot of
methods for dimension reduction that we see
i have been developed in the last few years a machine learning
here's the cluster similarities for vector data for you seem mercer kernels with colin campbell
and everything else is you
so all mercer kernels are positive semi definite
so all valid
covariance functions
so for example the squared exponential kernel the RBF against
has this form
if we use this is a similarity matrix it leads to kernel like value problem
and it's known as kernel PCA
but it is also classical scale
the elegant thing about the kernel interpretation of PCA
if you think about remember that kernel matrix i showed you before
it was the center in the product matrix
so that's a linear kernel PCA just PCA
here we're doing non-linear kernel PCA
so the good thing about kernel PCA which are not really going to talk about
is that it gives you a mapping from the data space to latent space is
well in none of these approaches we mention mapping so far there is one associated
with PCA but
in general is not with this distance approach
i can now give you mapping
any point reasoning there are many point in sort of the cities don't have y
point so i can't even give you a white point next point map
the concept doesn't exist and if you've got major distances concept of mapping from y
to x doesn't exist finding kernel PCA
and constructing my similarity
on the white space
and now i can think of a mapping from the white space to the x
space as well so that exists
and so i get that free out of the algorithm and the algorithm is known
as kernel PCA
i want to show you next is why
you should never
use kernel PCA for dimensionality reduction it's an interesting technique it's useful technique
but it does not to dimensionality reduction with that can
you can say that all these methods are type of kernel PCA with this kernel
and with many other interesting kind of it won't do dimensionality reduction
so the question is what the equivalent distance associated with this kernel
so this is the distance we trying to match allied space remember because of a
classical multidimensional scaling interpretation
so the equivalent distance if k i i
class kjj minus two k i j all square roots
in this kind of if these points are a long way apart relative to the
length scale
this guy
becomes negative and large
and the result of the kernel is zero
transitions with probability getting state crime state as prime was one x equals one given
that you took
that you were in state one technical staying which is point nine
OK so it's probably best particles two given that sickles one nickel stay
conditional probably had some to one of the left hand side
o point one
they so here's i'm going to stay at one
publishers particles to get the same condition is just point one
OK discount them
not only cameras missing years in this country between zero one
brilliant so there are two ways to ensure that you don't get reward one is
that previously two sons and discount factor last one but roughly right
with some probability you always will
transition to testicles two
so three geometries can again you can show that that the the
everything ever-rising even with chemicals one here
we were still finding this case that's another way to get reward
so so you're you're confused because you say well
i mean the one i take action but i get the rewards
based on whether stay in articles water transition icicles to write so you asking why
the ten
that rendition but two and i don't
so if you stay in state schools one in the transition state eagles two
if you reward ascent
but it gets to decide
that's the point
so you probably is a bit confusing the way that here i do apologize
i could we define it so that i we get reward two for staying matter
had no matter where in the cluster different models
now it's crucial in DP to know how you want to act right because in
the end my goal is
how do i access to optimize reward in this model
OK and act and policy so what they want they have introduced a policy pi
and this tells me given the current state and
which action should i take
it's just the function for every state tells you which actually take that culture policy
OK so taking notes circle right down pi to policy
can you see this throughout throughout lecture
OK so what's the best policy here now OK
you might notice this is
you know what
now i always get reward to for staying
only were two staying from state one
what i do that because next slide subsumption
so this is
this is the probabilistic finite state automata you
this is the same but a dynamic time view of showing each vertical slice at
different time
OK but to see if you can interpret this correctly the probabilities and so on
are still saying i deserved unfolded
the previous model to show the tensions over time
so again one
you take the actions change uterus against a to take action state
with point nine you which states one point one dollar line against a two
only give rewards of two for staying illegally whatever changes state one
you only get one zero state
but stains
now again we must define workers and optimize so gamma equals one point o
no discount
west seattle policy
five day one which i do
chemicals one not discounting
the sum of all future rewards
yeah i don't calculated but i think staying should give you enough reward expectation that
the best way to go
OK time and stayed till what's best action
OK you know it doesn't matter to zero here
OK but the point is a policy tells you state what actions now
it point one i really don't care much for future now what's the best policy
being done by hundreds thousands of images so it it's definitely a good deal you
should have cashing in their it also is really nice because it gives you
reduce query latency kept time for cash is much lower than the time for to
actually go out all the index servers
you do ranking and retrieval and return results
and it also tends to be the queries that hit in cache tend to be
the more expensive queries tend to be ones where
you know more popular words in them or
popular phrases that are
and they have a lot of documents to score so
even more than just casual read the cost about
i agree that hit me cash is larger than just the catcher
what is going to be aware of when you introduce cash the system is that
you can get big latency spikes or capacity hits when the cache is flushed for
example or when you
switchover index data two
so the cash no longer applies and you end up to cache missus
essentially all your cash rate will drop to zero and then start to work its
way steadily
back up but in the moments drops after drops to zero you can have a
kind of operational disasters they have to be kind of war
OK so the crawling system around you know ninety eight to ninety nine with a
fairly simple batch oriented crawling system
the idea is you start with a few else actually it turns out you need
remarkably few
ctrl because most things can be reached from
just places new cross some pages extract new links from those pages you into a
q and you stop when you have decided that you've your budget of whatever you
can index
there are a lot of concerns and only calling system can focus on them too
much but you did not hit any site too hard
you need to prioritize among the uncrawled pages so that if you have
it's been available you facts
something that you think is more useful than a random page
you need some way of maintaining this uncrawled URL q and efficiently because you're for
every page crawl your extracting you know perhaps twenty links
and having to insert them into the cube and you don't want to do secret
one of those and you have to have some way of dealing with machine failures
in the crawling system
the indexing system
in those days was a fairly simple batch
indexing system was based on fairly simple
the tools there wasn't really any check pointing so machine failures were pretty painful in
those days
the and not only did early machine that have ECC memory that parity which is
very painful
if you're trying to actually use
in particular if you sort of terrified of data on the machine without parity
and the mostly sorted
if you sort it again it's mostly sorted by the way
one of my colleagues like this to programming with adversarial memory
and so one of the things we did to help employers from the adversarial memory
was we developed a little file system abstraction that had
ability to write records and checksum some them women insert sort of re synchronisation markers
and there's so very if few
it would insert checksums the the record he could know if it was corrupted and
you could also then we synchronize to the next available record with every single innovation
and ignore the crappy records in
one of the nice things about web searches enough data redundancy in the world that
if you drop you know document here there
due to corruption is not a big a deal
and i
was something really important
so index updates in those days the basic while they happen infrequently thank goodness because
there a lot of work they happen about once per month so you basically wait
until traffic flow you take some replicas offline you copy new index replicas and then
you start new front ends pointing up these replicas and
person traffic from there and he gradually migrated more and more machines to serving the
no april and next that of the mark one
one of the things that important in this based index is you want to use
the outer part of disk is faster
the index whichever process is actually a little bit more complicated you start with you
on the right these things
usually about
the problem of c
number one seems to be what
it's can interesting just read
it lies
very of why small then y
it just
that's it that
there is low
the case
the representation of
thank you one
on the distribution on
the red
well one
all right
so small
or just under
all right
when we get through
is there
that's going to and
was red
so long as well
it belongs to me
just a small
number coordinates we information about what else
and that's what i need to be in the world
he netherlands
with the president of the parameters that describe the operations of
the problem
the median
from there
after change
what happened to be
like a flash of light it
next let's do
that is the most of the day by c
the result
this is
from the life of around for one one
first of all the traditions
it is often easier
the property that look like
so what would the
like today
the above