a strategic thinking
which would help you predict
the move
other countries was a sexy
in glamorous idea whose idea whose time seem to have
now john nash was naturally
irreverent iconoclastic
when he was asked on his princeton graduate school application to state his religion he
wrote down shintaro
soon after he got to princeton he
zeroed in on the problem that he knew
i had eluded the great when i met
you see
john lennon had a good theory
only four all out rivalries in which
you're game
is my loss
and vice versa
but very few real life situations
certainly not in economics and if you think about it not even in nuclear warfare
very few
interesting real-life situations are in fact
zero sum games
so johnny cash
instead of focusing
on that model
focused instead on competitive situations in which mutual gain was possible
scenarios all the scenarios that lay
on the spectrum between
all out conflict
in total cooperation
one i'm in theory applied only to games with two players
again most real-life situations
that we might want to model
whether we're talking about
options for
collective bargaining or the war on terror
most interesting real-life situations involve several or many players
what nash proved in his thesis
was that no matter
how complex the scenario
no matter where it lies on this spectrum
there is always
at least
one situation
one set of circumstances in which each and every player says to him or herself
that they have done the best they can do
the choice is that the other players have made and therefore that they
i have no incentive
to make further move or otherwise change their positions
he called them the equilibrium point
i didn't tell you
show you
how you could get there
but he proved that always exists and he did that in twenty seven pages
in the movie
it's a very interesting scene
in a bar
that dramatize is i think in a very clever way
the dramatized the essence of nash's original idea
and of course
people are always asking me
so did he
really come up with this idea in in bar
now nash did hang out with with graduate students in the borough council street in
we're definitely not picking up girls
there were no co-eds at princeton in the late forties in fact not until the
and anyhow john nash
it i was fairly shy with girls at that point
at his high school prom
which is mother forced him to attend
with a date which she forced his younger sister
make for him
i prefer to spend the evening
dancing with the stack of chairs
and not
not the girl
anyway johnny cash's original idea got princeton doctorate in nineteen fifty that was a few
short of his twenty second birthday
it also got him an invitation to work at
you lead
cold war think tank the rand corporation in santa monica
ironically however it did not impress his fellow mathematicians much
despite the glamour that john von niemann lent
the subject of game theory
game theory was
considered slightly the class a
by princeton's pure mathematicians
because it looked as if it might actually be useful
i should tell you that one of the great pleasures enormous pleasures of working on
this book was the
many of the most eminent mathematicians of johnny cash's
so several who are in this room
and i have decided
in every interview
invariably after about a minute passed
the mathematician would stop and say
so the
before i go on this one thing that you must understand
that tries
those economies
that work
that those economies gave john nash
prize for
the most trivial thing he ever did
even before
john nash
finished his
pieces which would one day when the nobel prize
i started working on some other things that that you have
another problem in his back pocket to pull out just in case
the prince math department turned down
his thesis
so even before he finished he set really set out to prove
power is the pure mathematicians
someone to him to solve a deep problem that has baffled mathematicians since the nineteenth
he did
a few years later he once again a standard in the profession
by solving an equally difficult problems in the field of partial differential equations
in each instance
what he did was to simplify
a complex problems
that appear to defy solution
by pursuing a strategy
but the experts in the field and he
never tried to be an expert in any field because he felt that absorbing the
work of other people
would tell his creativity
pursuing a strategy
then the experts in the field
i said up front was impossible if not downright bizarre
a friend of his
once tried to describe nash is style of thinking to me
by saying
everyone else would climb a peak
by looking for piano somewhere in the mountains
we go
i would go over to completely different mountain climb completely different now and from that
two elements are included
or no x and y
four no x and y we have accessibility problems why
so edges are subsets
and vertices are the elements of this
i found herself is basically a
that's allison mixes up it's about common
OK lets herself
he of the hypergraph is a subset that it's all the edges
i mean i found herself
is it transfers
none of whose
the transfer
given the hypergraph so
the set of elements and a bunch stubs
he said the minimum transfer is a collection of subsets of the original set so
it's also
the claim is
if we take all
frequent sets and use them as high for
or if we take
he said in the positive border and u
its complement
as an edge in a hypergraph
so then why
subset of the set of elements used
h there is an excess
such that x is true
so you know is is why intersect all
the edges in the hypergraph
then it means
that is not included
in any case
on the set in the positive border
so if something is not included in any of the sets in the positive border
so why is not included in any of the maxima
frequent sets
it has be
you can't be frequent because of everything that is frequent would be a subset of
one of these
maximum frequency
so i why
not frequent if and only if
it transfer
the hypergraph containing
the complement of the
of the frequency
so now
the money transfer cells are the smallest things that intersect all edges in the hypergraph
so the minimum frequencies are exactly the minimal transversals
of the
compliments of the positive
of the things in the positive toward
so this shows that this concept of the transfer so many now transversal hypergraph theory
actually has a clear
two of humans in the context of
finding frequent patterns
and the reason why this might be of
interest is that
the problem of computing
transversal hypergraph it's it studies has long been open source credit money nineteen ninety so
that it had
the rest of ten to the power of love
and actually
finding maximum
finding an approximation of the maximal frequent sets
you could do that
with the
the pretty quickly
and the question that was asked before the break about the k to
about the problems with sparsity
so even for dense data one could find representation of all the frequent sets
not all the
not by listing all the frequency but finding the positive border by depth first search
and then verify
the result by computing the transfer of of the hypergraph and checking whether the things
would really be
minimize things would be non-free frequent
so one could do this if we know we know how to compute hypergraph transversals
unfortunately we don't know how to compute screen
on the basis of a little bit confused explanations of what it that not going
be this is just a straightforward outcome
convert it to an semi-definite program using the formulation we showed yesterday for example for the
maximum singular value suppose you in CVX I should have mentioned in CVX here we use
a variable X that's a vector variable but there are many other types of objects
you can  use instead of or other types of variables you can say
X is a symmetric matrix of a certain order or you can say X  is a rectangular
matrix variable of a certain dimension and CVX will handle all these things automatically so you don't have to
combine or collects all the optimization variables in a single vector X you can just
enumerate the variables as they several variables with the as matrices or vectors or et cetera
so if you have a a matrix variable and you have a constraint on the on
the matrix norm the maximum singular value then CVX will convert it into this linear
matrix inequality so then maximum  single singular value of X is less than T if
this matrix is positive semidefinite and so T times an identity matrix on the diagonal and then
X and X transpose on the in the other blocks if you want to impose a
bound on the nuclear norm so the sum of the singular values of a matrix X there is a
similar conversion you have to introduce new variables U and V  a matrix inequality and a scalar inequality
and then these inequalities combined are equivalent to this so it's very powerful and there is a
much longer list but in fact here I can simply refer to the user guide of
CVX everything in the user guide is basically very complete a list of constraints
and functions that can be converted into semi-definite or second order cone problems
this example also shows you some of the actual limitation of this modeling system so you
see that because you convert  the constraint into a semi-definite form that in this case that
requires auxiliary variables U and V of the dimensions determined by the dimensions of
X so if X is a P times Q matrix then you have an matrix U of
order P and a new variable V of order Q so the number of variables
you get in this problem if you do this transformation actually can be very large
so for very large problems this conversion to an semi-definite programming
by these automated modeling systems might become too expensive at some point because it converts
everything into semi-definite constraints and that may require introducing some auxiliary variables and increasing the
dimension of the problem so then these are some applications of these two other
cones the exponential cone and the power cone that are actually not s examples of functions
that cannot be directly written as second-order cone or semi-definite constraint for example if you
have an exponential or a logarithm so convex exponential the logarithm as a concave function or
an entropy then you can easily write these as linear functions with respect to the exponential cone
but if you want to write them using semi-definite cones you have to approximate these
nonlinear functions for example by polynomials or by piece-wise linear functions for the power cone
also is a little more general then  the functions you can handle using semi-definite
or second-order cones for example we've seen that powers of X can be written as
second-order cone constraints if P or Q are rational if it's not rational you either have to approximate it by
a rational number and write it as a second-order cone constraint and that may  require introducing
many new variables or you can directly write it as linear inequalities with respect to this power cone
because there you had  restriction so these are currently not  included in these
modeling systems it's not much of a limitation because these constraints can be easily approximated
which is the target value
OK it sounds unclear on given the model
i'm gonna policy amassed evaluated i just cycle through iteration
and you out in the end when he finishes
you have good estimate of the pie
how good it is a public policy pi
this is the
policy evaluation evaluation
now let's do
and as you do the same thing
you can do the same thing with the state action value what i want to
spend time with this is exactly the same iterations but only for the state action
pair rather than the that the
state values so it's
to say
what is unique
why you
the my question the question is is behind me
give height
is it you
and it is unique because you fix the policy some reward distribution and but for
the first principal definition by the value of a state as the policy pi the
expected discounted sum of rewards you would get
and everything is well formulated so you will get a unique value function
three pies inequality
what's not unique is the optimal policy get but i mean i get to that
talk about that
OK so now let's talk to control
optimal control is planning optimal control is given the model is given the transition probabilities
given the reward function and your task is to find the optimal policy
part that word is exactly the same idea
i'm going to do exactly the same thing called value iteration from dynamic programming i'm
sure recursive bellman optimality equation
that is i'm going to feed my initial guess
on the right-hand side of the left hand side my next guest cycle
so i'm said in my new guess who comedian max all actions of the media
award but the discounted expected current value of the next day
and again i will talk about why this converges in if you know in you
know when i don't like you know these convergence
and the same thing here
for state action values and in particularly for optimal control question state action values become
very meaningful minute so now you are getting every state action pair
and the next guess is the immediate reward plus
the discounted expected best value the next day
he cooks and you and you repeat this in every iteration converges to the queue
it converges in the limit to the optimal optimal value functions and what is stopping
criteria again stopping criterion is the same thing the difference between two iterations the max
norm the maximum difference
absolute difference between
a state action pairs of eyes or two iterations is less than that's what it's
right so this is the solution to the optimal control problem in in in in
the planning case
and talk about
let me prove to you
and just because i want to one of these proofs because they are the foundation
if you like of the proof to reinforcement learning has had has built over time
for forcefully bonds one illustrate the idea is very simple proof of the conclusion convergence
for value iteration using the state action values as the as the instance
so what would prove to you now is that
is what's called the contraction property and dynamic programming towards
we define that means so
let delta k
be the better
they the can iteration
that is it is the maximum
after the q set k
from q stock
so i'm looking at you start looking at which i don't know
you want to get to
but conceptually i'm saying let delta OK k with the at time step k defined
in this fashion that i'm looking all state action pairs and asking what the absolute
difference between of confused i'm going to prove to you is that qz campus one
it is close to
to q started his of k one
by a factor of gamma
i multiplicative factor again
let's do that proof
because it gives one that's come coming here
is the immediate reward plus the discounted expected best value of next day
so let's look at q of k
let's look at the can guess
i know they can guess by this definition
no more
then q star optimal value for the election papers delta k
that's what this definition means well defined as the k
so that this inequality holds
so replacing cues of k
by something
but i know is larger
q stock must have k
and now
the simple trick is the observation that delta k
it is independent of a is independent of s
so is put out
when i put out
i modified by gamma
so gamma delta k
and i'm left with things square brackets
and if you look at this
this is exactly
by the optimality equations
the optimal q value of state action pairs come i
thereby proving
after the configuration
exact solutions much before the tree with depending of course on the on the problem
the length of the what cycle
long cycles in some ways are good
tree with
two it is more related to
it goes up as you have short cycles roughly speaking
so if you have a grid
two by biogrid and in two dimensions you have cycles of length four
the tree with the the grid if you have a side length let's say a
square root and by square root and
the tree with asymptotically is of the same size as the side length
so it's a disaster it's like square root and
so instead of being exponential in n you're exponential square root and butt
you know it doesn't really matter when you talk about reasonable size and
yes so i i'm not doing this but it for those who don't know in
introductory chapter talks about junction tree it's very important framework due to low attendance beagle
halter essentially
any problem can be solved exactly if you're prepared to pay a price exponential in
the treewidth
but what's interesting for practical purposes that many graphs
i don't have low treewidth they have large treewidth so junction tree
it is known to be practical for those problems and that's that's where all these
approximation schemes are motivated by graphs with high treewidth
so it's been
a lot of work on the slides could be updated to be whole
another slides actually mention sort of convergence schemes globerson and jaakkola and in two thousand
seven had to convergence scheme comoros in two thousand five also had a slightly different
convergence scheme
there's been a whole line of work there's more than this more recent papers by
you where your wife and his group about
more generally and convex free energies and generalizations of this tree reweighted belief propagation
there's a whole line of work until dual decomposition as which i said is is
some related and there's various higher order relaxations
where did he go
so let's just go back to this example here
because i just want to sort of describe just i'm not going to go into
details but just as a guide for you and reading literature in addition to a
linear programming relaxation you you may well read about things like conic programming relaxations
and probably even mentions a second order cone programs and semi definite programs
so there are there other relaxations that you can do they are not linear programming
there's been some work on that but i think quite a bit less i actually
think there's there's probably more juice in that area because some of these relaxations have
very different field than the linear programming ones
so to give you a flavor let's go back to this problem here right so
if you remember this problem
this was this weird example i constructed this morning it was an example of the
problem where
everyone is pairwise happy
but globally something bad is going on so we had a pair that were agreeing
eighty percent of the time eighty percent of the time and then
this peer here were a green twenty percent of the time this was OK for
the local relaxation but we sort of reasoned well i told you and you have
to believe me that it's not globally feasible
so let me just show you quickly of give you a quick proof
of why it's not globally feasible and this will actually illustrate how semi definite constraints
can be used
so mean it's right here because i found that i destroy my slides less if
i do this so this does bear with me for one second and then i'll
put it up for us
OK so
all right so
what i'm doing here so what i'd like to do is to show you why
this thing is it's sort of bad i'm going to focus just on
let's focus on
this number here
so we give that name what's called that number
so the little bit of abuse of notation and call that mu one
a focus on that number there will call that mu one three
site abuse of notation but despair with me that number there were column u two
and similarly will call this mu three
this mu two
first thank you for inviting
in particular for
give me a chance of coming back to barcelona last year when i was here
at the time to explore the city i hope more can now
yes of this tutorial jointly with petrol is about combining logic and probability and very
happy to give this talk because i'm quite excited about this research topic
but it's not only me
it's actually quite a lot of people who are excited about that so well patronised
would like to thank all of them because without them
what we are talking about wouldn't be there so
in case
that you want to leave early
here's what you should take home with you right so the idea is that the
graph is not enough we need logic i mean given that we here i guess
you know what we need to graphical models are called
we don't say we need logical models we need
most likely new forms of models we need models which combine probability and logic across
not just
the roadmap to this goal
well so that you have to take away message that you go home and say
you could we can contribute there is little motivation
then very by is a short overview on what statistical relational learning statistical relational AI
and then many of the concepts mentioned here will be illustrated
using markov logic networks and the second or third part
there will be a break somewhere in the third part
but let's see car we can get
so motivation
and this is currently my most favourite motivation for the whole topic for two reasons
if you look at it i can ask you what you see
and i can ask myself what i would do a learn
about you
by looking at
but i also like it to my wife background just for you my wife is
psychologist so i cannot really tell you this doesn't work right we know that now
operators already it really does it doesn't tell me anything about you it doesn't tell
you anything about me by showing you that next to that my wife maybe like
but then this or its union are
he managed to come up with the world's best selling a lot
about computer science
because when i show you this slide and ask you what you see here i
guess you can come up with many and right
so for example you may say this is much more efficient right
or you may say
this is storage capacity
i say this is number of scientific publications
you may say this is the number of facebook users
it makes a number of web pages
all right
any other kind of so for example right now i was just coming back from
meeting on computational sustainability and can fairly say that similar curve get the data together
currently with rather low price and price and they are facing the problem of how
to make any sense of the of the data gathering
a similar project actually many people not only in the AI community or UAI community
of machine learning community but also in the database community are looking at this idea
of the world-wide mind right so we have these kinds of web pages we have
users who are willing to spend the time to put all the knowledge on the
web and imagine that we can extract all the knowledge they put them in
and every second
their lives are like if we can extract that hopefully we can make the machine
turned smarter so that's the idea here and there is another project you don't hear
sending someone to a clinic or not
data from
security personnel
taking shelter contain danger this is like a government
safety procedures
if i want to do this web scale
there's again this growing number of
of technology so if you look at this in in a bottom-up fashion there's more
real time data that today which can not be processed efficiently
so i
i have some goes to process this data on the fly
with the high throughput and distributed event processing
and i want to do this in an elastic way that it's not expensive for
me so that you if i want to use cloud resources to do this i'm
available i'm i'm able to
to use these computing resources into freedom again after i i did my processing
multi tenancy so having many different customers in isolation permissions and privacy
the parts of the goals
if you want to do this for the web
i need an event format how to describe my data which should be standardised and
extensible so that many people can take part in actually extend the system so i
don't expect to know all the use cases and to formalise all events so i
need this event format to be open to everyone
and then in this event pattern language
which matches the event formats only the matching query language to filter events and
i will probably need some thoughts sort of event marketplace because the fabric big and
i need to be able to find interesting sources
OK again an event is something that happened or is being contemplated is happening
and one want these as
first class citizens in our in our system so that there an event is of
information unit which can be stored queried merged with other events processed
so an event is really an object which i can hand from one function to
the next and from one system to the next and event is not inferred from
changes in value
or in class membership of something and it's not the function call per say
but it really the data object which i can handle around and also store for
a history events have
time properties as i said already an event is at least a data item and
timestamp but often times you will have type hierarchy is like saying this is something
from social media
more specifically this is from facebook more specifically this is a feat update of a
friend and
we'll probably have into event relationships where linking will come in again
many real life systems this domain of occurrences that can possibly happen is so large
and cannot be modelled at design time so we
model explicitly
the known relationships so if you think of a state machine where you have i
don't know facebook user in the state of sending something
and then coming into another state of having sent something you don't model all these
states because you don't know what facebook will allow today allow tomorrow but you model
the state transitions
by creating new event types
and the RDF the
w three c standard comes in because it allows open world assumption modelling so that
everybody can add new types and new subtypes to this large system
we want to be open extensible so everybody can produce or consume events and create
a new types to to work together with the web community
now more requirements if you want to build this for the web
his ontology reuse so we want to create an RDF model
i want to find ontologies which enabled me to do this we've heard in john
paul's talk about the adult top level ontology which defines endurant current were endurant is
something that is always true is static fact
and the current which is an event
so we can inherit from this data type and use this in our model defined
starttime and endtime for example like
in in
tweet i'll just have one timestamp but i can define them over an interval if
i want there's also a lot of ways of modelling location so i'll just inherited
from ontology for example the neo geo ontology which is based on the very simple
ECG o point
which is why you get to
points lines strings polygons to model that something happened on the city area of city
the goal is again to be open and extensible
and use RDF
precisely to use linked data you've heard a lot about that so i'll skip the
happy to use linked data for several purposes one is to get static context for
events so that additional information is being able to be retrieved so if i have
moving piece of data someone saying on facebook that he liked the movie x
i can always if it's linked
i can go to
wikipedia and query all the parameters of this movie like i can get to direct
i can get the year
and so there's a lot of additional information like which we call event context which
i can get from this linked data cloud there was shown yesterday also
structured information is very important that it's machine readable
not only the modelling of the data but also the publishing of the data is
interesting in terms of linked data
that you should use http
your eyes for events so that you can retrieve them by IDE and link to
all the events which happened before
and you should also be able to link two real-time updates so you're
able to connect events but also to have actually if your eyes to get the
latest updates so if you want to create a mashup with only the newest events
there will be a link for that everything is
pure http and restful communication
i was working
and working with a colleague
from i've been from our institute to create a paper on that and how to
publish event streams as linked data where we try to on all these linked data
principles that you heard about yesterday
and the
the hard part is to get this working for streaming so once you open once
you do reference such a URI in your browser you will not get a fixed
set of triples back but you will get an endless stream so
application integration is
for this sort of application and
some research
still needs or some
structure macro consequences but it
so how
local things when they interact
in apply some
overall behavior in other words when you have many small pieces
yet somehow interact together
you would be interested in
figuring out how the whole
right that's the typical case of happens in physics
when they
after something like
cuba eyes will t
so how can you actually
even though both things out theoretically how can you actually show
all these
things that happen in democracy structure arise from
the local
behaviour of atoms in this case
for example in physics and people have tried to to figure out how
i mean
i have a system of particles you want to understand
basically what's the overall state minimum energy because it's not
real systems like two
person who states of small energy
and basically
it's a very important question many problems in physics people out which configuration
system give you
most energy
for example
other systems may also have interacting parts and you are interested in not in the
interacting parts themselves but you are interested in some query about the consequence of the
entire system given interacting parts town
think about the college you have a set of
organisms animals or whatever
they can each assume certain types of behavior
in a given ecosystem for example
and then you have given interactions between these organisms you may assume for example that
some parts of the animal
they like other types of animals and is like the factors
and they also have some
preference towards certain behaviours maybe they
usually well-behaved or you bet
given that to put a bunch of these animals together
what's going to happen i mean
is that
ecosystems going to be clear every time i'm going to basically
drive towards extinction of some species mean what's going to happen
what's the actually bring
of such system and have very complex
small interacting
parts that are
somehow dynamically coupled
what's the overall leaving the
things like
i mean i'm starting with these examples outside computer science just to show
the generality of is
approach for let's talk a little bit more about
in computer science
image processing computer for example image processing in who
has work with or work from image processing related one
a few people so i mean image processing is is one example of a few
graphical models have had a strong impact as a matter of fact as far as
i mean
it's probably one of the
areas market from fields were applied
early eighties
image processing basically you have digital images you know and you want to
i mean
performance some
restoration of the image or some processing or something like you're doing denoising
you want to keep learning the job well
so again you can consider pixels of an image as
entities in the system
you can consider that neighboring pixels
are interacting
agents in the system
the goal is to figure out what could be the overall
the best solution
like for example a denoised image given noisy
we need to figure out
the analysis of an energy function for that system for example and minimize the energy
something in this line
you have here so
analogy and is called energy because
everything started in physics
the real ones that you really wanted to minimize was energy
which is the physical
should be understood that when we talk about energy minimisation image processing computer vision that's
the energy that's just across from from the one line
so many terms were
brought from
from physics because that's where
i started work
well there the case for example in computer vision i mean so
how many people that work on computer vision related problems and some people
so basically
also like an image processing are working with him on this
but in computer vision usually one
the sum
more type of high level
image analysis like for example interpreting
the content of visual scene or something
so for example if you want to match objects you may want to
match fingerprints for example we have to fingerprint
one fingerprint and one that basis
we want to match up the fingerprints to figure out whether this fingerprint is the
same as these
and you can extract features of the fingerprint but you need to ask some questions
like well
the fingerprint is
made up of several parts
right there are technical terms
social order that
and you know that some parts are close to each other
well if i have some parts of the close to each other in one fingerprint
they need to be close to each other and the other fingerprint as well
so that when a match up i need to keep this consistency
this can also be modeled as a graphical model because you also have this part
there's little parts social whatever you have this constraints that
things needs to
match under some
conditions to be created
find things in our final goal is to find what's the overall
matching the
better according to some criterion or in form
just some
types of
high-level example of
so basically what graphical models
corresponding to this value here correspond to feature which really does not separate well at
all the two classes however
taken together
the two features have much better
four separation that x one
the figure the deeper about what could be the meaning of these two features
we decided that only x one was really informative features
this corresponds to the abundance
of proteins area
and so
there are some
people who have no more abundant
protein and some other people
whereas this position here
doesn't really represents the abundance of
ten is just valid just protein that's equally
not present in all the patients of the population
the only difference is that we observe here are just noise
and it just so happens that there must be a systematic source of noise that
makes it that
on spectral simultaneously reason or
in this neighborhood here even though we had performed some based on removal there was
some residual error there was significant in
that it was useful
to add this feature x two
that is in local estimation
of the baseline here
so i'm showing you actually it is a very very small piece of a very
and so this is actually a close in the close neighborhood of this of the
so from my point of view having understood that
tracks two
in not really irrelevant feature
it is an indirect measure of some systematic error that should have been removing by
so i'm showing you this is real that actually this was an example but this
is the real data that we had
OK so so this is still a problem can shows up in in the case
of the ex or
and we also have real data example in which we have situations like this
in which in fact the the fact that we have separate clusters in this abrupt
change you know where when she was still a separating other one
and then all of a sudden for a a given value of another should change
is the other way around very often this is just a symptom of something that
that when the wrong for example there has been
shifting operator or
or something that happened to to the process there was a randomisation of the samples
in we're seeing some artifact here
interpreted in terms of the causal graph this is what happens
why is the target in that case this would be or disease
and x y is the abundance
some you know
components in
blood for example ban supporting this disease causes some changes
in the violence of protein
but simultaneously
they some
some noise
that also feeds into x y
some bad but variable
and so x one is the results of mixing
these two elements here
so knowing x two is actually useful
two making better prediction y
then not knowing it
but this doesn't mean that x two
tells us something about you know
how the how wide is related to x one
so for example in the case of you know of measuring instrument if i change
instrument if i would have now this which is calibrated in a different way
x one
x two will become completely useless variable whereas in the x y if it has
the reality in the system that we're interested in
it is the one that is relevant or important
what happens is that the reason why it's too becomes a relevant is that
for a particular value of x y then there's is the dependency which is induced
by x one
between x two and y
x two is independent of y
but given values of x y it becomes apparent reason being that x two
because information into two x one
it's the same thing happens here in the case of the chessboard problem for any
particular value of x y and we see that there is a separation
on the x two axis
between the two categories
so there's induced dependency
in reality is not really x two that causes x y it's probably more complicated
than that there may be a common cause
which is your systematic noise there is no that causes changing the baseline and resulting
in some observed value of the spectrum
that we call x y some of the values that we call x two
practically we can't differentiate between these two graphs just look at the data
but it's important to keep that in mind in order to interpret but we are
looking at
it's important to understand that as soon as we have measurements
measurements always consequences
of the phenomenon that we want to observe
and we are not immune to measurement errors
and we need to take into account
when we do feature selection
so i justify somehow
the discovery of causal relationships between x y x i and y
so in a sense if you ignore them you might make some bad decisions about
good morning
my name shown back off from the university of manchester
so like to thank him for that very interesting introduction made me think about a
few things i think it's always interesting to
so have a background in the context of the work they we're doing is introduced
i'd like to give you a kind overview and introduction to the language now known
like jim this is probably a lot more material in my slides that i'll be
able to present at the time i have available but the information is there that
if you want to look at the slides later on this there some resources for
you to look at
so i'm going to talk about some of the details of the
if a
and some of the motivation kind of why is the way it is and how
how the language is described
as a a brief this kind of overview introduction of an ontology language is a
language for describing all models describing the way that we think the world fit together
and it provides us with a very rich collection of operators for describing concept descriptions
and i'll say a little more about what i mean by concept descriptions later on
it's also w three c standards and i think this is very important so standardisation
is crucial for this kind of work if we're going to build applications and tools
interoperation they can share information so i can build an application that i can present
you with some data the application produces you can read that and understand using standard
is very important so i think that again with the kind of standardisation stack organisations
like the w three c provide is crucial
and i was also been designed to be compatible with existing web standards languages like
RDF and XML we're using to describe things in the web context
so genes already talked about the semantic web vision so i want say much here
but the key thing here is that we're aiming towards resources that are described
annotations that machine readable and machine understandable to a certain extent
OK so i'm going to achieve this by the using semantic markup system annotations metadata
annotations that describe content function of web resources so what what's in our web resources
what they do in the case of services for example
so what's what's the problem well i'm sure we all understand what this problem is
i mean this is this is kind of this is nothing new now that a
typical web page has some markup information OK have some HTML perhaps some stylesheet information
and this tells us how to render the page essentially so what we're doing is
we're making use of machines about rises to help to present information in a nice
way i have a web page here and all the presentational information the fonts colors
position of the things on the page is all contained within that markup
the semantic content of this page is accessible to me as a human being i
can read this page and i know that this is the page of the w
three c has some information about the workshop
tells me some useful something about mobile web initiative but the content of this page
is not particularly accessible to machines
the it has natural language OK so if i really wanted to understand what this
page is about i may have to use and sophisticated natural language techniques we some
more about that later on today
but if i really want to kind of get into the information here it's very
hard for me to describe this and way the machine on the stand
so the the idea now is to make a web resources more accessible to automated
processes extend existing market that we have
with the semantic markup so metadata annotations describing the content of the function of our
and in order to do this
we feel we need we need to use ontologies to provide vocabulary for annotations
so the vocab the ontologies provide us with a collection of terms we can use
to populate this metadata
and in particular
we want a rule system we want systems that kind of open to that in
the way that we can combine existing terms we can form new terms and we
have some formal notions underpinning the way in which these vocabularies are used and the
way in which we combined terms and i will go on to say more about
what i mean about this kind of formal notion of the combination terms
so a prerequisite here some kind of standardisation some standard language so we need to
agree some common syntax before we can share semantics some common representations that we can
use and share
and this
it will be then based on some some underlying language is like a city units
so the the technologies that we we need for the semantic web
things like metadata
OK so metadata
allows us to describe resources with descriptions of their content
it it's no good as providing this metadata OK unless everyone is speaking the same
language we need we need to have some common ground meat as some common language
that we used to represent this metadata and these annotations on our resources
and we can achieve this through the use of terminologies
so the terminology provides some shared common vocabulary the domain
OK so so we know that the terms that we are all using the same
the same collection of terms in this kind of restricts their
the problems with
with people using terms that we don't necessarily understand or know
but using a shared terminology still doesn't take it all the way that because there
are still problems with
with terms that have multiple meanings so we may have synonyms we may have word
has possibly different meanings in different contexts so it's important that we have
everybody meaning the same thing for sharing context terminologies and we can achieve this through
the use of ontology ontologies which give us some kind of notion of the meaning
of terms because described some of the underlying semantics and help us in doing this
they share a common understanding about domain
so to build the semantic web we need to go through three processes
essentially we need to to annotate things we need to annotate metadata resources cesar marking
up describing what resources are
the next speaker had
by him to the podium
so i used to be before in the state department psychology department
hand there is always a joke which is that a few
look to people interested in perception they were very perceptive people people study memory that every good memories
end people who are
studied rational thinking didn't actually very rational and so on so people tend to say
things they were good at and think that holds in statistics and here's a counter
example so here's one hour world experts in dynamical systems
hand i think you'll agree that might pretty dynamical individual
weather is stationary i don't know probably not
certainly nonlinear
what is predictable i let others make that call
anyway were delighted have might give the second is a lecture on basic foundations
again this will be an hour and a half hours fifteen minutes slot
questions afterwards and then we'll have a break for coffee
okay well
thank you michael for the introduction
hand thank you to the organizing
committee for the invitation
and hello kyoto hello is the twenty twelve but be been looking forward to this meeting for a few years
i is everybody comfortable
is everybody warming of
so i was invited to give one foundation lectures and despite the invitation and was
asked to give a sort of valencia old style tutorial overview which is what i
put together today
and a tutorial overview should start with these some allusion to where things began
i'm talking about state-space modeling
basically this is the fiftieth anniversary of two key papers
i'm sorry
a trigger-happy here
two key papers
the beginning thee nineteen sixties by geoff harrison really common
coming from very different perspectives
in the one case very subjective bayesian modeling in commercial environments time series problems with time
adapting to change in time is this is the essential
forecasting accuracy
and in the other case
very non bayesian
engineering perspective in control theory and control systems but utilizing machinery
bayesian state space modeling
there are a lot of other people other things that were happening around the same
time the all ingredient and all hardware
these are the world of dynamic modelling in
time series spatial systems and other kinds of contexts is as evolved from
but these were really what i identifies the essential and
people who kicked it off
so don't state space models
and what will be looking at some pictures from examples from business and finance
it's it's i think dennis lillian
late nineteen eighties
remarked that the state space modeling it has become about point really
most important practical
success for bayesian thinking this was pre-empts him see of course
where around
you know we were still doing calculations
on the backs of envelopes
business and finance
i will be talking about the physical sciences will be talking about biological sciences
will be talking about
a little bit
at least allusions to more recent and current kinds applications
in dynamic network modeling and computer modeling
these good ol fifty year old ideas
and methods that are based on those ideas
really driving creative challenging applications
ah some of my slides will have at the top of the time foundation is
a foundation lecture really talking about concepts
that i regard as foundational
and that of foundational to to to this particular field
the keep
concept is times the covariance
that stuff changes in time
anne due to ignore them at your peril
so here's a stylized model
i do apologize for this is just like
here's a stylized model where we have some data in time
possibly with some regression where theta here represents a regression parameter
andy parameter is changing in time in some way this is a mnemonic for more
elaborate models that you might use and people to use
and if you have such a circumstance and ignore the the time variation in the
parameters then all the variation you see about the regression gets lumped into the air
so you inflate your errors if
unpredictable pieces the model
you degrade forecasts
realize forecast uncertainties that just bigger and bigger than they should be
allowing for change in very simple ways of partitioning variation
by recognizing times the covariance is really the fundamental concept the foundation a state space model
so as an example and this is a textbook example that goes back a number of years to
only a textbook that's
it to time-series sales and the predicted market
that share similar patterns over time and if you simply looking
why against export
you be tempted to fit a regression
andy because a few then bring in the time covariate you see a slightly different picture repeatedly
are these sales data and you see an increasing
parameter vector regression relationship
if you ignore it
then you're tracking one step forecasts along here you're doing a very poor job in
forecasting your residual variances lead to inflated forecasts variances
whereas by comparison if you recognise it and even the very simple things
then the model will adapt and track the time-varying coefficient
improve forecasts reduced forecasts uncertainties and d and so you went out on both counts
so times the covariance
always worth considering times the covariate shift times it all in the context the problem
for these kinds reasons
the second foundation and an example leads into this is
very naturally in time series one is involved in sequential analysis
u model sequentially in time you look forward in time to think about how the
process that you are trying to understand is evolving
state space models
this is a linear guassian so the framework
to begin of course
a very natural
very naturally looked at in in a sequential format so here we have a signal and noise
the signal is a dynamic regression where the regression vector all state vector it's a state space model
undergoes a markovian evolution through time
the message
even though
which is
i don't think
do something but i don't think you know
i would tend to these
i mean when i was
it was
that's just saying the sentence i love
it connects everything
you know i
the good
q and
we can not
all the
what that
i don't think the message is
forget it be useful for the than
forget the old
because it was the only people
i don't think so
it's not
i think
more we should
we believe in that fine
i would like to thank you this is your
don't becomes part of
and it's the following approach by which i mean this is you know in the
you know the old yugoslavia
we get some are probably unfortunately not really
we will
but the community
well there fact that the best thing would be useful
streamline education and the
post something called
you get the point i was listening to a few people all education can
so going to be of some use to someone not interest to to learn how
maybe it was a
as you
both of which is going cause
it is important to note that the
now is this kind of you
the social usefulness
everything but we
the first element is that there
so i remember
they all get discovered by
or or they may just need to put it in the trunk
he and the other one
it comes from
OK we can construct the launch
one of those to me like tree
language which was just a a few months
wasn't there
four is these but by
you know
eight or nine to the environment in the problem
the space over which was
let's say for language which was the second and so on and so on so
more than we should
i think
to be nice to be in the of you use
the function of the brain it's let's stop speculating
let's focus on the economic problems these into
this is effectively from
o thing
don't blame me for his emergency
state route six you know
the corresponding stopped it was i think about and
but do we even know where you
what's going on the menu
on the one hand we have
people keep things think that goes on
we need to learn a stochastic changes he said you are all much they they
say that the solution goes
then we have
people who see brain
it time
a name for new if let's say you say the information was that has to
i do not going to
now why these but i think it
pros cons is actually to
most of our going all i think we
i think
going to make you know some kind of
basic orientation
cognitive coordinates which is why i think
two o
things are
getting what
we see
local the making
conspiracy theories are in the bottom and you can
what's going on
you see
well of what i will be
i don't recall which will be
the which is flow
is the dominant view
even if they are not christians
could be flavor a newspaper which is not forget
you know it's
it's actually ontology for which is that you just like to let you know that
they don't go don't
i think that's all you have to remove the intellectual so
this think
the game
the for
we should be aware of the opposition and he was between being made having
so far
i think there is any
so we have
and the lack of
i mean
it's very difficult to help people out you thought his
no gold nineteen ninety nine percent of us he wants
fukui fukui
basically he is
of course
be on the
there is a
if you feel that
we found the end
what frequency
in the in the document and waited
in the way by the the frequency of different words in the in the whole
database you don't want to work that is in every every document to be
the important it would be
so it's weighted this week
OK so in this representation
this sentence the boat in the sea
this ship in the ocean
would be considered as different
because they don't share
the important words
why and
representation should serve has two sentence such as surfing a wave of
and also to sort things internet which we human no
are not really related in this presentation we will have
kind of similarity since they share the this towards this the world surfing is is
is shared between the two sentences
this is one of the drawbacks of each of these
so the problem of text representation is that we looking for a representation of of
documents p of d
the money in the mapping phi takes into account the knowledge
about the links between words
so for example we human we know
that's both and sheep in fact
and the same thing so how how to
take this knowledge and and put it into into our representation of documents and the
idea is to gain this knowledge from the huge amount of very valuable documents in
digital format
which we have one
really which is for example into internet
there have been several probabilistic approaches for for this problem of text representation
they are trying to to model
the links between words and documents
among this one i'm going here to two
talk about tree
the probability is probabilistic
latent semantic analysis
latent dirichlet allocation
one that i propose which was the theme topic mixture model
this achievement of having in common their main assumption
which is that the distribution of words
in the document
is independent of this particular document if i have latent variable
so which is called usually topic
which partition the space
of the words into
to get objects have
OK topics and in fact i think that the
i will assume that the words in a document are generated but they this
by this topics belong to one of this topic
so that that's the main assumption of
this stream mothers
which can be
really we write and as as an equation so as i said
the main assumption is that the probability of words
the document
can be
can be seen as a as a mixture over the topics
of the probability of the word
given the topic
so here you see that we have
w w m which is a random variable representing the presence or the absence of
the word
in the document
we have the
variable case which is the topic
which has k values
and this is is is
in this x is how this of going to
to to be different but for so i think it as a generic
random but it is in the in the in the
document space
and of course since this fear more i can also represent it as
x is so you can see it in the in the graph
it's in fact i have this tree in the stream of x is it's how
do they they have all the tree
a different implementation of x
so i have a that's like generic more than just i'm not saying what is
for the moment
so something i didn't talk
to about it this representation with the plates
what does that mean
decomposition we get will be adapted to the kinds of questions we need to add
to discrimination between two classes
this is called extremely randomized clustering forests randomized and they're extremely randomized because we don't
essentially any information about the classes
to generate
we do use discriminative information
when we come to decide which trees will take
and although we do is that
three each tree
for each
feature we get
we put it down through the tree and gets to release
it's been the binary trees are coast live to ride gets down to leave
OK and it will go through several of the trees have several separate these those
now classically if you have
the decision tree
the leaves
coated with the class the tree decided i was going to give to the to
the leaf nodes could be because this is not council something so certainly these will
belong to cars those features as cars novelists who belong to non cars
OK and we get that information we train the trees we throw it away
we just use the spatial decomposition and then we train a separate SVM on these
on the sixteenth histogram
it turns out that that's a very good thing to do because the information from
the discrimination is not very reliable
but the spacial decompositions nevertheless adapted to the kinds of places we need to be
looking in space
and then we train an SVM on so we get good results
so this is pretty quick quick to do this
city quick to train
it works very well
the spatial decomposition
is very messy but it's it's relevant to problem and that's the thing that matters
in one point with all these models
in particular local features tend to characterize the
the current in particular object
what we can do
is that if we look for example and the nearest the find out which features
are important
for the particular discrimination of the object class we can look back and see where
those features were in the the image and it will give an idea
with the feature with the object is in the image so here's bicycles
it may be difficult to see that was meant massive bicycle where
this is the method is pick pick that the features that correspond to it and
you can do this in a kind of iterative loop that focuses on on the
region contains the bicycles suppressing the wrist so that when it calculates the histogram the
thing is going to use this on using those regions that strengthens the signal from
the high schools and you get an idea a nice relatively clean segmentation despite the
fact that there is no structural model tall for bicycle looks like
four cow whatever this thing is
OK so you can do that with basically and if these local feature methods and
it works pretty well to get first idea
if we the objects
OK latent aspect models so
all of these things
we've talked about we doing vector quantization whatever that is so high dimensional representation
from the features
and there high dimensional representations could be
subject to overfitting
so we'd like to regularize somehow
and one way to do this
is by some kind of dimensionality reduction
and what this corresponds to is that we're going to try to take out
particular thing signals that occur in the image
signals maybe not the right word
in particular
structures that occur in the image which which correspond to real world objects so for
example i've got an image here which is an building isn't trees and sky some
if i look at all the interest points that i get on buildings
we quite varied the buildings have different aspects of windows they is things like that
but they all tend to co occur in the images
because when i see building see see several of those aspects seagrass lc other kinds
of signals
OK so what these things do kind of pulls out
the cluster of things that co occur together
treats that is a single individual signals
and another cluster of things that can occur for graphs and treated as an individual
their models
this morning when i see you
a great weekend
if you didn't it wasn't because of the weather
so here i am once again member
walking wounded and we're talking about carbohydrates today's
they recall lists we were at the end of our discussion last time
so we made the point that
these multiple hydroxyl groups on the carbohydrates on the one hand determine the identity
of the various kinds of
the orientation three-dimensional orientation and
for one thing
and and for another that these multiple hydroxyl groups
represented the opportunity for forming covalent bonds with other models that right as indicated here
in the states rights or
covalent bonds and then to create large molecules
which will increase the speed of our discussion
i want i talk talk about are molecules which is used the phrase generically
so in principle
these and then joining of molecules
which involves the the dehydration and the formation of covalent bonds right here
can create molecules that are hundreds and even thousands of subunits along
so here we're talking about former
we refer to each one of these
some units of the former as being monomer
and the aggregate is the whole the singapore
so here we are we touched on the back towards the end of last lecture
at the very end
that one can write twenty crosslink these long linear chains of carbohydrates
here we see the fact that like engine
which is the form
glucose is stored in our liver
largely in small extent the model
actually it is
across different brands so if one looks at that if one draws on a much
smaller scale like molecule one might drop it looks like this
looks almost like a christmas tree with multiple branches
and the purpose of this is actually to sequester the glucose
to store the glucose metabolic rate inactive forms
until the time comes the organism leads once again the energy that is stored in
the calls upon which occasionally sponsor rapidly broken down
and the glucose is mobilized put into the circulation
four eventual disposition and use in certain specific tissues
while it's incumbent in these high molecular weight polymers
glucose is essentially
metabolic clinging to the by realise there
and we can have consequence
store large amounts of energy in supply chain molecules
and it can be stored indefinitely
now the fact is that
this this idea of end-to-end delivery station
that i just mentioned can be extended to other macromolecules
which also become linked and and
in a specific kinds of polymers
and here we are moving on to the naked into the notion of talking about
amino acid
we're talking
about proteins
if we look at amino acid
so what we see is an important
structure like this
the central carbon
and for the principle
the state society
where are represents some side chains that can be anyone as we will see shortly
twenty distinct identities
but we all know and share common property that they had the overall structure
and as you may recall from our discussions
of the discussions of last week
neutral ph it wouldn't a amino acid this or whatever are is would look like
this all
because the main group will attract extra proton causing it to become positively charged and
the carboxyl group which really
according to become negatively charged
and as you might be use from this
at very low ph d greatly increased concentration of protons free protons in the solution
equilibrium will be will be driven more in favor of reattach a proton to the
carboxyl group
because there are so many of these protons around
conversely is very high p
where the hydroxyl ions are in in
the government
they obviously tend to scavenge protons
reducing the level of protons to very low level in in the water and under
very high ph conditions
this proton will be released and pulled away by the hydroxyl ions causing this i
mean once again returned to its negative charge state
now the fact of the matter is
these amino acids are
there exists in a very specific three-dimensional configuration
and he was very much more nicely here than i could possibly
across the board
which in any case would be hopeless which is
there you can see in principle that once you have more distinct
so coming of carbon
there's principle two different ways
create them
this is sometimes called chirality
chiral form right here
hands are chiral
if i try my will to
so propose one hand
the big
the number of
just for you
it is
the root of
or right
all the goal
i mean it
it was this side there's factor
which is a function of x y
but there's also these factor here
just or thing by summing up six
this effect is also a function of x y
when multiply
these m six function with is c functions
and the thing in new function two
three five
and then a sum over x y
o thing function of x two and x three
now this is the function of x two and x three so it's a constant
with regard to the summation over or
this is the functional registration three
so this is
constantly that these
the measurements four so what can i do
you can use
once again the distributive law
correct can all these
outside of this information is it's also
two he
pushes the
because there's xt
is extreme
conclusion is that
now i just evaluate
these cells
over the next four
remember push and these in five
evaluate these works for function
which itself is a function of x two here in this image the axis of
constant vector this omission i push it outside
and then you just have to politics
and finally the so called
there's bug
are just the summation x two
yes but it's hard to find for graph
so basically if you want to find an optimal illumination
when i take graph that's from
will be as
but not by much of the original graph
well seriously by the maximum
of the allies were for the original graph with more information
in case of vision that in this case you just accumulation of graph
the key message here is that once we did things in this way
the instead of b
of the six because there are six old
it's just complexity of the three because
three is the size of the maximal clique
this is the general here whenever you have
uses elimination of with is
distributive law
essentially what you can do is to compute things
time exponential
on the size of the maximal clique
so the size of the maximum if the maximal cliques are small groups of two
or three
so the explanation which was used to that
so in the near the number of
so this is we're going to use this elimination ours whenever we have a very
specific type of query
so today
i will start with a general discussion on the waves
as in the introduction
two electromagnetic waves which we will discuss
next week
i will start with a very
down to earth equation
y equals one
thirty axis
i'm going to plot that for you
here's why
these acts
and that's a straight line through the origin
y equals one third x
suppose now i want this line to move
one this line to move with the speed of six meters per second in the
planes x ex-director
all i will have to do now
is to replace x
in that equation
by x minus
notice the minus sign i will go down in the plus x
creation then becomes y
equals one
time axis
so we going to achieve equals one
t equals zero
we already have the line
t equals one
you know i have y
equals one third x
that means
it will intersect minus two
and you it will intersect
class six
in the line
the first one
this line is now t
equals one
this is the
well zero and it has moved
in this direction was the speed of six meters
a second
so what this is telling us
if we ever want something to move
with speed
in the process acts direction
all we have to do in our equations to replace x
by x
minus the team
and if we wanted to move into minus x directions
then we replace x by x
all we have to do
i'm going to change
something that is the real way
i don't know why
he calls two
times size
of three acts
it's way
not moving not yet
i can make it plot
as a function of x
that plot will be like this
this is zero
the sign is zero
this is why divided by three
this is hundred eighty degrees and it's again zero
this is two pi divided by three
again zero
which we call the wavelength
let down
in this case from here to here
is goodbye
divided by three
was also from here
i will introduce symbol kdq often see we call the wave number
and k is simply defined
two pi
provided by land so in our specific case
OK sorry
this year
you know there is no more
you can immediately tell what the wavelength is
i want to have these wave moves
i will have traveling wave
and i want to have it moved with six meters per second into plus x
the recipe is now very simple
all i have to do is replace this ex
i x minus
six t
so now i get why
equals two
times x
and if you look at this curve
this equation
you plotted a little bit later in time than t zero this is already two
a little later in time
you will see that indeed
he has moved
plus direction
it is moving with a speed of six meters per second
so this equation when you look at it
holds all the characteristics of the oscillation
it's hold the amplitude
this too
the amplitude minus two
that's the amplitude
this information came
all the information on the wavelength
and this information
tells you what the
speed is
and the minus sign which is important
tell you is going into politics direction and not in the minors ecstatic
can we
such a traveling wave
we can do that actually quite easily
suppose i have here
a rotating wheel
rotate at angular frequency of omega
and that this has radius are
i give it two units so they get the same amplitude that i have here
and i attached to this history
put some tension on the string
so i creates
wave is rotated
the strings attached here
and as it rotates
we're going to propagate
in two
the string
with the velocity
that's a feat so i can generate
a traveling wave
the periods
of one oscillation
if you have on the string
you're going up going down going up you're going down so you're doing way passes
the period of one whole summation
it's obviously two pi divided by this omega
the wavelength lambda
that you're creating
well if you notice which which is this travelling
and you know it has been travelling capital three seconds one oscillations that distant land
is nothing more
the electromagnetic force but in disguise
history so i suppose the history of unification goes back as far as eighteen sixty
when maxwell first
united electricity and magnetism into what we call electromagnetism
a hundred years later
it was shown one of the proposed that the electromagnetic and weak forces could be
and what we call the electroweak force this uniting being based upon the idea that
there are w bosons the analogs photons with this one little problem w bosons have
to have mass
five percent
but the trick involved the higgs mechanism which is away
of starting off as if the w boson had no matter tool
playing this trick and they
again the mass without spawning the nice features the story the technical details of that
you only later but let me just for a moment take on board the fact
w and z
expected to have a mass will tell you very shortly
how big the mass is why work out beautifully
speedy for the w and z particles were found in experiments here it's by colliding
protons and antiprotons
a single class proton antiquark antiproton if they just by chance had the right energy
and the right formation flavours they could once the blue moon w or z rather
than shouting pions they normally produce so it is like looking for a needle in
a haystack but eventually was done during the linear
the prize for the discovery which actually was quite interesting given the
nobel prize for the theory had already been given even though these things have been
found so if it turned out to be wrong with the nobel committee but have
lost their first prize back again
speculation to having discovered the w and z
and this is a rather clumsy experiments with protons that we say well i mean
by that because it's quite relevant to the present station history with the OEC starting
protons antiprotons that complicated things they contain quarks i suggest the three quarks but the
simplest way of making them
the war resolution you look at these things with a course you don't see a
single class see that surrounded by a cloud of quark antiquark gluon so protein is
actually three quarks the cloud of quantum the quantum one real
missy bad stuff
the antiproton likewise
but the first experiment because it's the easiest way to get high energy is the
fact that these things are two thousand times more massive than an electron or positron
means part of punch so you can access new regions you never been to before
this is rather clumsy way
i mean discovered things in the case of
the nineteen eighties the w and z
you can then go to very clean probpsf like electrons and positrons
an electron positron are nothing more than electron positron you can control the energy precisely
and choose the energy of the collision to exactly what you want
and that was what was done in the nineteen nineties here met the large electoral
positron collider
and it was changed specifically to apply ninety gv because that energy z bozos
and they
united about ten million examples of producing z bosons and seeing how decay
looking it very precisely
and in the course of ten years because about six years experimentation
they found that you the same
is unstable
it decays
a democratically indicated to all possible things that could do
in particular it can be k
in two
neutrinos electron time
and and depression and to another neuron type and version the notion of the town
type incentive version
and the nature of any other types we have previously seen their devotion
so long as the light
now you can begin to see qualitatively here the more varieties of neutrino that there
might be in nature
the more opportunities there are for the z decay is like a bucket full of
water the water holes there are in it the quicker the water drains out the
channels for k is that there are
the children will live
and what was found remarkably is that z indeed is unstable it has
a width
and this manifests itself
in the following way that you collide electron positron not exactly ninety gv but sometimes
energies below through ninety over and you see the cross section the probability for something
to happen rises and falls
the rise and fall is what we call the z boson on residents
nine quantum mechanics
this thing is like the uncertainty in energy over which this thing is produced
and quantum mechanics the highs and the uncertainty principle tells you that uncertainty in energy
multiplied by uncertainty in time
is the order of plants
which he six times ten to the minus twenty five
gv time seconds
so by measuring the rate
of this
but you can work out how long
the particle that
maybe this a from that you find that the
said personal it's about ten to twenty five seconds in traditional time
but what is more beautiful
is that
you could span
very precisely over the the peak and the data points are the black dots on
the three lines are what theory would expect for the with the z if there
were only two varieties tree of course we mean know it's nonsense free
o four
and the line the three neutrinos goes beautifully through the data
so it is the precise measurements of the properties of the z in the nineteen
which shows that there are at most three varieties of like neutrinos
mean if there right neutrino weighs more than half the mass of the z like
fifty gv
then of course you would know that but if there is that something totally different
but we know there are three varieties of light neutrino
each country seems to be married to
the negatively charged lepton like an electron muon tau we infer
most three varieties of charged leptons seeing that each pair
these seem to be married to the pair of quarks up and down john strange
top and bottom we infer that if the system is right there are almost three
generations of these quarks
that one alternatively wrong but that's how it appears to be a white is we
don't know but this is to show that this is an experimental deduce facts that
we had
from left by studying is it precisely
and in nineteen sixty two thousand they did electron positron annihilation higher energies in the
hope what fact in the success of producing pairs of w bosons charged w plus
and minus to serve electric charge electron positron coming in w possibly minus have to
balance going out and you need much more energy to produce those so they started
quite a lot of detail the properties of z and w for many years
so think that the whole precision of the electroweak was confirmed
so now
what is going to do with unity
this is what i want to show you the idea of the weak force being
electromagnetism in disguise
although those back to this point that
when for came into the game
the for me
it's not a number is a dimensionless quantity ten to the minus five
divided by dimensions gv squared
and we now know
it's not a black box
it is
w boson being exchanged
so that you have something to think about
believe me is healthy
MIT student
to sleep
but also healthy sometimes not
sleepless nights
and worry
that's the way
but i had sleepless nights in high school
about or something
it's healthy
the reason why that's healthy because once you see seen solution
you say
i of course and you never forget it
whereas if someone tells you
from the start say
you forgot it in the next day
you don't remember
so i wanted to
c is remarkable
often also nations
that can be produced not by regions as we have seen
but by heat
and by calling
i have here
nice pipe
and there is a great here
i can touch it
touching it now
or is it opened by the great
what i need that grid
and call it
it generates
one hundred ten hurdles
should probably pressure wave
which you will be able to do
and i'll give you until
the end of december
maybe mid-december to come up with a
solution whites doing that
i mean the great now
model that was roughly
you want to play with this don't break it
try to
transfer liquid for seventeen seconds
i was part of the reason lecture
exactly five minutes from now
if you turn it into a tornado
rotate it
you open up a full of air
so it is never the problem that the
liquid cannot go through
there's always pressure equilibrium
and i don't remember how long it takes but i thought i was seventeen seconds
but if you want to we can time may even be less
i now want to
address the issue of
simple harmonic oscillation of a
as you will remember from a one
the pendulum
thanks al
mass and
and if the mass of the strange
is negligibly small
compared to the mass is hanging here
then the period of oscillation
two pi
i've described over g
g in the boston area
in two high degree of accuracy
nine point
eight zero meters per second squared
if you simply take l
approximately one meter
then you can see that you get the period of about two seconds
and if you make the legs
about twenty five centimeters that is four times shorter
then you would expect the spirit
which is two times
joint which is about one second
and without any pretense
just eyeballing
really testing
i just i will this to be about a meter
levi also back and forth
it's about two seconds for one oscillation
if however make twenty five centimetres
four times shorter
then it is
very close to one second
no interference here
when you look at the this equation is
that just like in the case of the spring
it is independent of the amplitude in other words when i have a large amplitude
four small amplitude will take the same amount of time to go back and forth
what pendulum
when we make
we derive this period you remember that you have to assume what we call small
angle approximation
you'll see that again and again was
you know it
called small angle
the small angle approximations
the final thing that is always the same as data in radiance
now if you ask me how small is small
it's a matter of taste
in twenty six one hundred we have
the mother of all kinds