and sometimes
bringing in the ideas of intervention
because if we can interpret it we can overlay on estimated factors in volatility matrices
as we track them over time
if we can overlay interpretation understanding link back
the fundamentals in this case fundamentals in the market economic circumstances
and that allows us to think about how defeat at learning into the next
a period of time into into modifying the model
to potentially improve forecasts
and these these kinds of methods are being used now for as i say forever twenty five years and
a substantial number of variables
as components bigger models that are used in management investment
what a my time
well on
everything i've said
could've been set twenty years ago
so there was the tutorial
and now can fast forward a little bit
and just touch on just a couple of vignettes
on some some more recent areas
in dynamic modelling
no surprise
datasets are getting bigger models are getting bigger
parameter dimension is getting bigger boy if the parameter domain if the parameters are varying
in time it all its infinite dimension by definition
we need more structure
if we're going to make sense bigger problems we need more highly structured models
small modular models
ann that's one dimensional sparsity we need sparsity in all its dimensions so these are
really you know it's no surprise for anybody else these are the three hot buttons
what i learned in tokyo
at theare
the wonderful workshop that some view attended in tokyo last week
at the institute of statistical mathematics
is that
big data is the fourth paradigm in science
i heard that
from cherokee our
in this presentation
president of the institute
and i had that from tommy goochie current president who's who
here i think
i don't think we're in the fourth paradigm yet
the fourth paradigm is big data
that's not a paradigm science it's what we do with the big data how we
how we model and how we how we store it how we communicate it
how we model it
and use that is the fourth paradigm
we're just opening the door when not not even
and even
starting to think about it had in store yet
i was starting to think that most at
so this is the fourth paradigm
i'm gonna give you a few slides just a show
just some snapshots of some other kinds of application areas where bayesian dynamic modeling
dealing with bigger datasets
bigger models bigger structure
where the needfor where
and sparsity and structure
is ever more pressing so here
i haven't talked about spatial structure so much in dynamic models is a context where spatial structure
is fundamental
so a high-rise satellite data where on a weekly basis if not a daily basis one is receiving
on thousands of grid cells on a lattice around there
various measures various aerosols in this case datasets these pictures come from
carbon monoxide
from various sources on
i huge datasets
really being gathered and uh uh an incredibly fast rate
end available and accessible and the problems that have a bearing on a hard interesting questions
so the kinds of dynamic models one is interested in here
would then
think about the danger has
on a lattice in very high dimension are as a vectorised version
in this context this is the context computer modeling
work physical models of predicting fluxes sio from their from various sources
and so that's if you like a set prior information
that feeds in you can treat it in different ways we like to treat it as a covariate information
because we don't believe it
we want to understand it and how it relates to the data we actually see
so will map through to the data through
dynamic parameters
and they will be modeled in various ways state space models random walks or other forms and models
because time is a covariance
andrew but lots of stuff that we don't have in this model we know has
a role in influencing the data
and then they other piece here
is everything that's left apart from measurement error
and that's a hugely
this is a highly spatially structured problem
and if you ignore that's a new u fit the model you find is a lot of spatial structure left
so this is where there is a need for
really highly structured and highly sparse models
one one isn't
going to be able to use guassian processes for spatial analysis on these kinds of scales
without lots of approximations
structure them
and make them more sparse and turn them into really different models so i think different kinds of models
graphically structured models
markov random field models which have lots of conditional independencies in them
as way to go there so integrating those kinds of models into into dynamic models
is a big part a v
aware in recent times
based in dynamic model
based in dynamic modeling has been going
backing up to a more general context and thinking about this idea a sparsity than
and again uh looking over thee
thee the last two or three years and where things are at right now in terms of applications
particularly in t in time series dynamic models
on a generic model for a vector a vector time series with some predictive information
andy all kinds of parameters that may or may not very in time
i flip my volatility matrix now to to its inverse to its precision
the natural parameter of the normal distribution zero mean normal
her for reasons which will become obvious
and if
could be
anyone in a number of things that could be something that we don't know that
so for blogs maybe i should put this slide on the right we have a
this is called a blog blocks the posts
and each blog post has timestamp and hyperlinks
right so this way because we have timestamps and we have hyperlinks we can go
and follow hyperlinks to other posts that are older than this post in this way
we can detect how how things were propagating
because every time every postbox talks about something and links relevant sources and now we
have the time stamp of the relevant source because you can follow the hyperlinks in
time and did and get to get the
get the cascades
we're going to follow the hyperlink so here's a different picture of the blogosphere right
the squares are blogs
blogs are composed of posts in this post
timestamp there are there are so we know the time between
so there are hyperlinks between the posts and we know the time of the posts
so we can go and follow these hyperlinks back in time to do to find
how the propagation how the information was propagating so for example if this was something
that i know the blog said that somebody referred to somebody else later referred to
it and so on
and this in this way we can follow o thing spreads and this now this
propagation graph is called the information cascade arc escape and
as i said the data we are using is this one year we were going
forty five thousand blogs that gives us ten million posts and from this we identified
three hundred fifty thousand cascades
some of those reasons
rather than for
it is
questions because this is what is
but but this is this is the cleanest right i mean i don't have to
do any so the reason that i want to do like topics i want to
sort of fall topics right and one way to do this sort of measure the
similarity between between posts and say all this because some of them are on the
same topic but through hyperlinks right
it's really obvious that the person who's refers to someone else and that someone else
existed before they have to have some relevant reason for saying they said that
most of
son who was
sure i i i could be missing a lot but this way
it's very clean what's going on so that's why why we decided just to follow
hyperlinks and of course there are other ways helping spread but then you get you
can get in various say tracks on how to to deal with
OK so this is this is blocked
so the first thing is now we basically asked which commonly blogs in three which
blogs should we read to to detect these big stories effective right and again so
i'm plotting the number of blogs we select and this is the
the population affected right so we want to be the first to know so we're
asking how many people get infected after after after US right so we want to
be the first to detect the story that's what you are optimizing and what you
see from here is that this is this is the quality of our solution
this would be
and the
the old traditional bounded by this tells us is that there on the solution the
optimal solution that we can't compute is somewhere in between the red and blue and
this is our new results which again which just says that no the optimal solution
is in between here right so instead of thinking that we are i know thirty
six o eight thirty six percent away from from the solution now we know that
we only ten percent away from the solution so this this this this this is
the same be thing much better
if nothing else
was run
society decided to use it
OK so so as i said instead of being is thinking that we have thirty
seven percent the way you know we are at most t
OK so this is good news
the second thing is about using the cost right so for example if you say
every got blocked because the same then we go and we are picking this like
big big room summarizing blogs and what the result is that
if you find now lot
the cost in the number of posts here
and just ignore the cost i get i get the following solution quality but if
and if you believe that labels are produced from images
so the label is conditionally independent of the
stuff given the image then the right way to do machine learning to discriminate objects
in images for example is to try and learn the function from images to labels
but almost nobody believes that
what you want to believe
is that stuff creates images of the same stuff creates labels
what's more the bandwidth between stuff in images is hard
that is what show you name you can tell a lot about the stuff that
created it but it is the dog you can tell me how big dog is
more colour it is and what direction it is facing whether jumping up in the
if i give you label like don't you can tell me hardly anything about the
stuff that created it
so that's a very low bandwidth
so now if you want to get permission labels you completely crazy to try a
direct mapping from installation
what you want to do
is learning
how to get stuff from the image height the high bandwidth pathway because image specifies
the stuff quite well
once you've learned that then to get the label from the stuff and maybe slightly
change the way in which you get stuff from images
that's a different view of how you're going to do
discriminative machine learning you first going to figure out what's going on and then you're
going to do the learning and the interesting bit is figuring out what's going on
so i want describe one application
which demonstrates that approach works
my contribution to this was to thoroughly indoctrinated one very smart student
he met another student in your about speech and until about the timit phone recognition
and he said OK what are used as input
and and sort of simplifying this would be the best you can see here so
they can correct it later
use the standard input which is thirty nine coefficients for framing eleven frames and you
have to predict the final label of the middle frame
once you predicted those phone labels they can go into post process so the user
by model of firms to predict what's really going on
so the students said well why don't i take these thirty nine times eleven input
variables and use two thousand units
and that unsupervised and another two thousand ten units and amount supervised and another two
thousand units around that unsupervised
if you told me i children to stop there because then another two thousand units
about unsupervised this companies units on top
and from this hunt or learn all unsupervised and then go a hundred and eighty
three context specific for labels which is very standard and back to fine-tune
fine tuning takes a few days on a very fast GPU board
but it turns out that just wipes out the record on the TIMIT recognition problem
the previous record was twenty four point four percent and this gets twenty three percent
more importantly all variations he tries along these lines get between twenty three and twenty
four percent so there will be record
and during
as a student called honglak lee has recently applied similar techniques to the classification task
where you're given the boundaries of the phone you told all these things are the
same for can you classify it
and he's round about the
the record for the classification task although i think michael collins has something a little
bit better
so this is the trend
it could be a benefit to the ideology you just take the input you have
lots and lots of unless you need to big data set of course
only the last letter weights is not pretrial and and that's why the penultimate then
needs to be small to keep the number small
and then you just train the hell out of it with backprop
and it wins
now in order to do that they had to be able to model the input
which was real valued melchett from coefficients
and so the both machine i told you about has binary visible units in binary
hidden units you can advise that have
real valued visible units and binary hidden units we sometimes call the gas in RBM
you make a very naive assumption which is that given the states of the hidden
units the visible units are conditionally independent so it's not good for data with high
but the milk catching coefficients are designed to get rid of the covariance is so
it's not about that later
you can write an energy function
the picture is better
around each visible unit you put a parabolic containment function you say is energy to
move away from where the visible unit would like to be
and then the effect of the hidden units
is two
impose an energy gradient this trying to move it away
and so the lowest energy point will be where the gradient of the blue line
is equal to gradient into the red army and so just move the problem sideways
that's the simple model and that's not a very good model data covariance is the
end of the talk i come back come to much better
so the new idea is that
the basic module
that has either
binary or real valued visible units binary hidden units has something deeply wrong with which
is it can't deal with multiplicative interactions and the world is full of multiplicative interactions
freeman ten by a long time ago had a paper on style and content which
is about a multiplicative interactions
well all the contents of faces about multiplicative interactions
whenever you get two guys in things in the world to get distributed very
and you multiply them together
you get a variable is very nongaussian distributed go very heavy tails and that's probably
why the world full of heavy tailed things
even if you believe in ghosts in distributed things
i want to give you one example of why what is multiplicative interactions it's from
a generative perspective if you're building generative models of multi layer and you want to
generate some interesting data
let's consider the problem of generating an image of the shape when i just tell
you that this is square
and it's got particular pose parameters where it is more orientations
you could generate whether parts on the edges of the square very accurately if you
had actually pose parameters
and then maybe you can maintain the constraints between the parts
but if you do any kind of sloppy generation of the parts
then the ages were quite meet and the calls were quite the right angles and
you get a very bad looking square
so if user talk time graphical model
basically getting modelling neutron generator me praying like this
it's more likely configuration but they are allowed to generate something like this or like
it unless you are very very accurate generation at each stage
the alternative is too sloppy generation
but also specify how to clean things up
and that's a much better way to go
so here's the picture
you know the shape in the pose you do sloppy generation probably redundant parts
and then you specify how the party should ensure
and i that things settle down
so in generation is going to be slow is going to settle and i get
a very clean structure
outer product of the vector x itself
so it means for example that x matrix has to be rank one
so it's nonlinear nonconvex
it should be because it's still equivalent to the original problem
so then the relaxation consistent actually simplifying this problem and making it convex by replacing
the difficult constrained by weaker constraint
i one way to do this is to replace the equality inequality
so if you say x is greater than or equal to x x extensible suppose
then that turns into a convex constraints
nonlinear because of the product of x and x transpose but you can write it
as an LMI by using should components
so that's a very important but this is now a complex problem and you can
solve it as a semidefinite programme so can solve very efficiently in polynomial time
and that's several exhibition it's
we replaced the feasible set of the original problem
my large set because we we can loosen the constraint that we had here
it's useful because this gives us a convex problem that will provide a lower bound
on the
the original value original optimal value
because they optimize the same objective over a larger set of ten and lower bound
so in general the also something
and sort of
later in the lecture so complexity of and is the p
if you saw it using interior point method
it's typically
the worst-case polynomial bounds is depends on the dimensions and it's this kind of the
order of the matrix inequality
so in this case this will turn into matrix inequality of size n plus one
if you like linearly
and so we kind of
that's a bound on the iterations an interior point method method
and then you have to multiply with cost of one iteration
linear algebra in one iteration of an interior point method and that will be a
polynomial function of
all the variables the number of people so that could be quite expensive but it's
still polynomials
because it's just the linear algebra of computing research directions
and you can try to look for
more efficient ways to do this by exploiting the structure
in the world
it's difficult immediately should be
so the original set would be this this unit cube to the corners the feasible
now we
lifted this to higher dimensions
so the
the dr
the in terms of x it would really be the projection
of course the semidefinite cone in high dimension
are and
so it's difficult to
people i think
you can find some pictures and so
papers book
but is sort of a given a convex set that includes the
the corners of this unit cube
a really big because of this listing
you it through the projection of the positive semidefinite cone in high dimensions
projected onto x x space
so the first use of this will be just to compute lower bounds
by convex optimisation very NP hard problem
the second one is if by accident at the optimum of this is the p
x happens to be equal to x x ten suppose
then you found the optimal actually
back since we solve the in NP hard problem
just to convex optimisation problem
and then in jolly one b two of course because this is just a convex
optimization problem then you can try to also try to use the answer of the
optimal solution of this is the p
suboptimal solutions for x might be doing some kind of around
and one of the many ways of rounding x two
plus or minus one because all we need to find a feasible point is effective
vector it plus minus one entries
the one method is suggested by this constraint because you can actually interpret this as
the vector x in the matrix XS moments of the distribution because say x the
vector is the mean of the distribution
and then x would be the second moment the correlation matrix
the mean and the second moment always that satisfy this inequality
so that would be one interpretation of the solution is computed here maybe
you can interpret it as a distribution
and then generate random samples x from the distribution and random
so that's called randomized rounding so the simple choice would be to use a normal
distribution with this mean x
covariance expires xx transpose
generate random vectors from the distribution
round two plus minus one
and then maybe repeat is and keep the best ones
so if you do this you get something like this
so this is for a problem it's an equal to one hundred so it's certainly
too many feasible point of possible points to consider by enumeration
and this is the
so the dashed line here is the is the people out the of the relaxation
normalized to be one
so that's the lower bound on the optimal value of this bullion optimisation problems
the reality optimal value is exactly
and this is an histogram of
suboptimal solutions
obtained by the randomized rounding using the solution
of the SDP
sample suboptimal values c
but now
i made this cancellation i can pass the limit
and all that happens is a surface delta x equal to zero and i get
minus one over here
right so that's the answer
so in other words what i've shown
we put it up here is the last time
is a minus one
now let's let's look at the graph just a little bit to check this for
plausibility right
what's happening here is first of all it's negative
i a it's less than zero
which is a good thing you see that slope there is negative
that's the simplest
check if you could
make and
the second thing
then i would just like to point out is that
x goes to infinity it as we go farther to the right it gets less
and less steep
and what's xk it goes to infinity not zero
sexier goes to infinity less and less
so that's also consistent here is one the very large is smaller and smaller numbers
in magnitude although it's always negative so slipping down
so i managed to fill the board so maybe i should stop for question two
so the question is to explain again
limiting process
so the formula here is we have basically two numbers
so in other words why is it that this expression when delta x tends to
is equal to minus one of squared
let me let me illustrated by sticking in number for x zero to make it
more explicit
all right so for instance
mister and here for x zero the number three
and it's minus one over three
what's delta x times three
that's the situation that we've got another question is what happens is this number gets
smaller and smaller and smaller
and gets to be practically
literally what we can do is just plug ins are there then you get three
plus zero times three in the denominator minus one in the numerator so this tends
tends to minus one over and over three square
and that's what i'm saying in general with this with this extra
number here other other questions
the question is how what happened between this step
and this step right it could explain this step here
right so there were two parts to that the first is
delta x was sitting in the denominator
i that all the way out front
so what's in the parentheses is supposed to be the same
is what's in the numerator
this other expression and then
at the same time is doing that i put
that expression which is the difference of two fractions
express it with the common denominator so in the denominator using the product of the
of the two fractions and then i just figured out the numerator had to be
without really
other questions
so now
so i claim
on the whole
calculus is gets a bad rap
it's actually easier
then then most things
but it has there's a perception that it's that's
it's harder
and so i really have a duty to to give you the
calculus made harder
the story here so we
we have to make things harder because that's that's our job
and this is what actually what most people doing calculus and the reason why calculus
that reputation so the
the secret
is that when people
as problems in calculus they generally as in in context
and there are many many other things going on
so the little piece of the problem which is calculus is actually fairly routine
and has to be isolated and gone through all the rest of the relies on
everything else you weren't
in mathematics up to the stage
from grade school to
through high school so
so that's
the complication so now we're going to do a little bit of calculus made hard
by talking about word prob
now we
we only have one sort of work from that we can
are we talked about is this geometry
o point of view so so far those are the only kinds of word problems
we can post so what we're going to do is just post prior to find
the area
and close
the axon
the tangent
y equals one
so that's the geometry problem
let me drop picture of it
it's practically the same as the picture for example one of course
so here's
we're only consider the first quadrant
here's our shape
right it's the
here's maybe one of our tangent lines
which is
coming in like this
and then
we're trying to find this area here
right so there's a problem so why does it have to do with calculus it
has to do with calculus because there's a tangent line and so remained need to
do some calculus
to to answer this question
but as you'll see
the calculus is the easy part
so let's get started with this problem
first of all
and the label of few things and one important thing to remember courses the curve
thank you
this is what you do this one
this is
this graph
i can tell you is that due
about this
well one
not really
that sort of you know
il gran
it's not all ships
we can do
mean this
so from
so if you want to
and so on
the it
and this is true
it is not
so when
is it just me or is it
it would be
let me
this is wrong
the one
is going to
right to
well to be
the the
so let me
you could reach
and so
the school is
we're not
this species somewhere right
along that route
this species
the problem
i'm going to show the same blue curve on all these slides i'm gonna move
the green curve around and that's all that changes the green curve showing the resulting
red curves to the red curve is a deterministic function of the green curve in
the car
i'm just showing what is the what is the red approximation get out from different
combinations of factor and context
and this is the the property that that you want to have happen is that
the context tells you where you need to be accurate into so the red curve
should always be good in the neighbourhood of the context
so this just showing you intuitively that has the baby we want so on the
right-hand case
it matches the the curve exactly want to match and what it does other than
that sure about approximation away from the context but doesn't really matter because be multiplying
by the context anyway
here's an interesting case so the context is right here
then we have to approximate this
convex curving up part of the likelihood function
and the only way to do that
it is to use the galaxy in with the negative variance in this is what
accounts negative looks like if you're wondering and as you can see these are very
useful actually from modeling certain like that that so if you likely to with with
the concave part you want to use constant winning inference model
that's what happened here so we get very nice approximation that like
in this in this region
OK so if we make the context wider
so before a very very narrow streets of the model one tiny part likely if
the context is a bit wider meaning you have as much data
then what you find is that it sort of it sort of takes more and
more averaged approximation citizens isn't locally specific anymore
so in this case
we we still get negative variance but it's it's sort of tries to be good
in bigger area in the early on the right
and if we make the context
very very wide
then we end up which is sort of one global overall constant approximation which is
what you would have expected in the beginning surviving but in say anything about what
is going multiply with the best you can do it just to make one big
moment last approximation
we make use medical
the reason there are some companies
well the the
OK so the question is
how can we understand the air that were making the approximations so you could locally
measure the air that you've made so after you've done after you made from the
red curve you could measure the air to the curve
and you could you could measure that when you can out of those approximations and
some people have done so without estimating there
that's certainly one thing to do
but i but i think what really happens is you run a busy you start
out with all of their approximations being very flat very broad and so you end
up in this case so everyone to make sort of broad averaged approximation but as
the as the algorithm iterates you get more and more information flowing in from all
these other factors and you end up getting narrower and narrower context and you get
more and more specific information
what is it
is the computational
i mean look a there's a policy interpretation the probabilistic interpretation is
if this blue curve was your prior
and this so if the green curve was your prior x and the blue curve
was likelihood
then you're posterior distribution will have a bigger variance then your prior to
that's essentially what this thread curve saying
so saying you need to you actually need to reduce the variance
of your of your prior and the posterior
so you can interpret this approximation disgusting approximations is being essentially what would be the
klingons and observation
as the likelihood as you're likely it will be will be so the klingons in
a thing that could observe and what this is saying is that the the closest
equivalent in the gaussian observation one negative variance meaning one that actually makes you more
uncertain observed that when one makes a lot more search
and that certainly does happen in some cases
i mean it is
please go all the old man
but now even more reasonable than to exclude the measurement
so the difference
given information about reasons for
OK so the question is should we just should running out to converge is known
throughout all of the messages that are negative variances and the answers i would say
no because you want your posture to have the correct amount of uncertainty in form
of your data point says that you should increase the amount of uncertainty then you
do that you don't should just ignore it because that's what has do
in particular this
this approximation
the reason that as negative right because you're likely does have that shape in that
region and so
just by
just by throwing out is likely because the shape you don't like it it doesn't
international resource sites
or resource platform which are managing from liver with all team of
european north american and japanese scholars in particular
we tried to put together
whatever is useful for q
oriented scholars
and you can find
but i think we can have a look at this later on in the course
including a
exhaustive bibliography
with about three thousand references
and some recent publications and working papers
and many other things
so please have a look at
comparison with three assists please
but or if you type in combat with two axes dot org
it is an american
religious group or sect
and you can pay a few thousand dollars and go to heaven
that's not what we offer with compressed
this is basically why we had to invent combats with three s right because was
already the
the main aim was already taken
right there is also some news about the application about software developments
and i want to stress that quite important that is going to be a new
feature on the site
it's just been launched
and damien ball with my sister in law is here in this room
yes answer recently a
former section which i mean the section in which people can interact and share experiences
and problems
we might want to use the course to begin to feed four actually and make
it available to the broader community
all right i have said enough in terms of very general introduction
and let me tell you what you see is about as my main point today
to start with
QCA which stands for qualitative comparative analysis
as of label
both methodology
and the set of techniques
by methodology i mean
a way to envisage
the dialogue as chosen put it between ideas and evidence
theory and data
four hypotheses and daytime evidence
the empirical world
also more about this later
it's also said techniques
data analysis
data processing techniques
i say the family
because it's like also
almost like paradigm
because they're all there's a whole set of assumptions
behind QCA
which need to be taken on board before you enter the techniques
what can be you
we can use them for different purposes
in very short i would say that the main use of these techniques
is to test models or theories of course you've got many other
needs to do that like
mainstream quantitative techniques
what is
quite specific but uses first that you you can do this
in a systematic way on the quite low number of cases
will see
in the course what we mean by this ready low number of cases
what is also
probably even more specific but
is that this
for the test series and
remains of keeps
core focus on complexity
because usually when you use quantitative methods
the main ones at least
there is a price to be paid for
when you test model of theories
the price is simplification
it is for instance when you regression analysis
take out the outliers right
we try to find a general tendency
what would you say what you do is quite the contrary
you keep the complexity
within each case
and you also keep the idea of diversity
diversity goes along with complexity
in particular we have one core
or can recall multiple congenital causation
what is the idea
in a non-technical way the idea is that if you are an ionizing that's a
twenty twenty five thirty cases
and you want to explain some outcome of interest
the outcome will be
what you would call
dependent variables right
well it may well be that there might be given explanation for three four five
that's one back
link the outcome then you may want you may have another
path for
three or four other cases and so on and so forth
each path
has its own logic
and each path
consists of
a different combination of factors
that's what we mean by
in very short by multiple contemporary causation
there's much more to it
but i cannot go into here
this is
technically qualified interest you
while we are attempting to
accomplish certain level
of text in models and trying to keep view complexity
so we think it's complexity complexity across the cases in terms of
the diversity of causal patterns
on it
so the question is is that effectively because you can produce any moment this way
and the answers effectively
if you have a sufficiently rich class linearity is you can
and that's exactly what i mean mappings are doing what we mapping into a space
which we
taxes are spent by linear functions of all the time and that's why every moment
becomes i mean you want so
that's what this theorem says
now remember from the last slide
this thing here looks familiar to us so we have some we've seen something like
we know that this quantity year so this is not the supremum over all could
all continuous functions it's the supremum over all functions in the unit ball of our
approach is countable space but it's also the supremum over pretty large class of functions
if outcome is sufficiently linearly so we have this supreme
and we know the supremum simply corresponds to the distance of the means
now let's look at this supremum is almost the same only that we have a
different from cost so first
let's use
our quality from the last slide and actually we going to replace this function class
by the unit ball in repertory company space special reproducing space we will which choose
one which is dense in the set of continuous functions that means every continuous function
can be approximated arbitrarily closely
by a function from our can space
it turns out we can also the the scaling here doesn't matter it's just the
scaling factor so of course all
functions you wanted link but it's sufficient if we can approximate every continuous function after
scan scaling factors so that doesn't matter and the whole proof
of the injectivity of all mapping can then be reduced to this classical result simply
with this observation by choosing kernel which has this property
but the reproducing kernel can space is dense in the set of continuous functions
in such kernels
i have been called universal before by who proved to results about approximation properties of
support vector machines and consistency properties of support vector machines so he defined this class
of kernels which
this is very rich hilbert spaces where every continuous function can be approximated in terms
of this class of kernels also does the job for us here i actually we
can use a slightly larger one we noticed later but i don't want to confuse
it turns out one example of such accounts goes into the ghost is always a
nice example of the kernel and the final statement is that
the vodka is universal in that sense
the mapping is injective in other words two distributions input points of the mappings are
identical if and only if
the means of the distribution the expectations the output of the mapping is identical
and this be identical is the same as that distance being zero because this is
a norm
OK so that's
quite nice and maybe just as too short side note
two observations
the made with that have been exploited it and maybe that be interesting for someone
to think about a bit more is
this image here so the mapping being injective means is invertible on its image
it doesn't have to be
he surjective doesn't have to map to the whole space but whatever it maps to
is invertible the the image of the map is something that's somehow called the marginal
in the second observation is of the second note is that this whole concept of
mapping distributions to
their means
sorry mapping distributions to the means of kernel functions
under the distribution is a generalization of what statisticians call the moment generating function of
a random variable so the moment generating function is defined like this so we take
expectation with respect to the distribution of the random variable
all of this special quantity here
and it turns out that decisions they have because this is the moment generating function
because from this thing you can compute all moments of the distribution of the random
which is not surprising france because if we look at this we see are that's
a special type of kernel it turns out this is a universal kernel so it
makes sense that this
these meaning it contains all the information that we can do it more generally we
can use any universal kernel and you we construct other types of
and we're generating functions
so this is just as i note above the main point for us is that
this thing gives us a convenient metric and probability distributions because now we know that
these distributions are the same if and only if their distance in that space is
the same
so we can use this distance as a metric to to test whether distributions are
somewhat different questions
so the image not for example was
yeah i mean positive measure should be no problem
OK so
it would be
a good point to take a short break people want
and then we'll try to meet again so
so what is that transform
several x depends on frequency
little x depends on time
these are the coefficients of
two pi periodic
series e to the minus side chain
and i
and all land in our
my signals are infinite
that is the discrete time for a transformer i started with a discrete time signal
what kind of
the result i got here what what
what kind of an object is this
fourier transform
the function
so all
a function of frequency
and what's the range of frequencies
this thing is two pi
it's has period two pi
so i it
normal take the range of frequencies b-minus pilot high
so let me do that
i mean
so it makes the figures nicer if i go from minus from this frequency here
pi to pi
somehow what i wanna plot
for this example
is that maybe was there are somehow
multiplayer the game the
frequency response function was just one
and i'm a was
this is the amazing
frequency but it's going to be periodic so
this is the highest frequency
everything happens on the
two pi
it's telling me that the frequency with the response to this frequency
is there zero
so maybe i used a lot
plot those key points
i'm talking here about low pass is going to be a low pass
there's averaging
is running at
running and
what's up
at the other frequencies what what's
what's the input
and what's the output
at other frequencies
OK i'm looking for
i guess i'm looking for and i can vector
this was an organ vector religon value one
i just came right up
this was an idea vector with i value
right is actually an old vector
notice that this is telling us that that we
cannot invert
this filter
this matrix
this matrix now which is which is
one half square league
those one half there
it's a very simple matrix but it isn't
it's not invertible
so what happens sitting on the diagonal
all the way
and one half is sitting
below the that
all the way
otherwise there
that's the main diagonal
and that matrix doesn't hurt
the bounded inverse because
we found the vector of skills
so what are the other one of the i can vectors
i mean this sort of weird to be using
we estimate i in vectors here but maybe that
maybe the main point is that when we have constant coefficient linear operation
the i can vectors are always the same guys
and therefore that's the way the study
every constant coefficient linear operation you have to study it
because by those i can vectors which are always
pure frequencies
pure harmonics
so let x
omega of and
this pure frequency
so so this is the
the there is
there's the pure
so these are the components of
there are there some sort harmonic discrete harmonic because it's these
and they were
is discrete time
so that's
so this was the main equals zero
that all the components were one
this was amazing part what we're all water all the components of this thing on
omega is pi
you see that this is the right thing for me is pi one one of
i got there
link is pi
he the i omega and is what
for filmmakers pi i have either applied which is
which is minus one to the
which is exactly are alternating guy
and in between for these other magazine between may is we've got well but
a little problem here what's my little problem on the graph
i've got complex numbers
for these two
cases all ones and pure alternating then i got real numbers so i started off
with this graph so happily but yes
well that's what i have to that's what i have to tell you now i
have to you know it's fine it's exactly what so i graph
these these why what comes out is is are
i sensible and
OK so we've heard so many times before yesterday the marginal likelihood on the upper
now let's start with
the gas distribution so it
in the talk today
the manipulating out in distribution all the time
gas distribution
in one dimension that regions of little
but like this has location has a certain which is distribution in which the one
june two apples here
in two dimensions i can show the content part of this is the the the
joint distribution in in the two dimensional space and the lines cross here is indicated
that the
the mean of the distribution and the contour lines
are equal probability contours using a particular value of the
of the probability of drawing a line with that
so what we talk about what i'm going to use that they are
much higher dimensional graphs here but i can draw the i can only draw three-dimensional
we have to sort of imagine
these sort of things in much higher dimension than the and here's the
expression for thousand going to use the notation
and four girls as mean
that here and the covariance matrix doing things
this is the actual expression and so it e to the minus
the distance between x and the mean i'm regret
what i mean
so the mean vector in this part mean vectors the
in the past there
and the
the covariance matrix
actually gives you the
something about what the
directions of their in particular
i mean values of the covariance matrix of the square of the
of the standard deviation
in the in the direction of the idea
that means the matrix find what the thing looks like
all right so i hope seen
now before
so the two things i need to the two ways only to manipulate got in
the i need to do conditioning of gaussians
and i need to do much of missionary couple to take a multi dimensional gaussians
with the government in two dimensions again
now i condition
on the on the
on this variable having one particular value and the value given by the blue line
because there well no i want to
look at what the conditional distribution of the
one variable given a particular value for the other one
i think get that by by like slicing through the
probability distribution
the nice thing about got in the that the conditional distribution for
are again
so in this case conditioning on that particular value which is out which has a
OK here
that's all seems reasonable enough
but means to be
on the other hand the conditioned on value which is much higher than the mean
will be
is much lower the of the conditional distribution
they could conditioning one operation then it
and if use and modernization one
the modernization means simply integrating out
some variables or something else memorable
again here the joint gaus distribution
now in some
this is the variable is is that with some go everything and again i can
the marginal distribution
other single variable is again accounted
OK so i won't try not to worry too much about exactly
what the
what the expression of these things like
because of it
but so that in the brain may
if you're interested
now so what's gas process
what i talk about some of our gas distribution
the the process is just generalization
the graphs and distribution
to infinitely many variables
so informally
it would be useful to think of a function
that's just being an infinitely long vector
this seems like a very impractical way of thinking about things it turns out to
to give you exactly the right intuition here we don't need to you need to
any fancy mathematical concept just think of the function if you think of the one
dimensional function just say well if i just specify what the function is
the function f of x if you just specify what f of x is for
every x
then you specify the function
so it seems a pretty
simple idea what is actually
the idea that we need to a function is just the vector
which is infinitely long because it has
it specifies what f of x is for every possible
OK so now now we want to try and look at what happens with the
for these distributions when we
when when when their distributions of these in a long
mathematically it is the definition of the golf course that
it's a collection of random variables any finite number of which have
gaston distribution so this is that
this about mathematicians definition which which avoids them
i'm taking this has to do with with infinity but they so shy away from
that and say well
any finite number of these have gotten distribution maybe maybe you avoid some technicalities
all right so
whereas the the the the multivariate doubts in distribution
what's best was fully specified by
he the mean vector
and the covariance matrix
the gas and process is now specified by
the infinite dimensional counterpart the
so the mean vector here now becomes an infinitely long mean
and since infinitely long vector function
the mean
out of the and the
right in the way right the function has distribution which is
i have the mean which i mean function mx and similarly for the covariance matrix
up here
we would now the matrix is in general and n by n matrix and dimensional
and we just
generalizes this to be
the function of two arguments
so this is
roughly speaking corresponds to an infinite plane in the matrix
and similarly
one thing which is useful to keep in mind is that
just such very simple world
i'm just saying
there's only two possibilities it's very simple world
and it's only one period between now and exercise so it's very simple
now i would say it's gonna development arbitrage theory of options going to say that
you want to
you take any profit opportunities restless
not to be possible to get a riskless profit opportunity here
by investing both in the stock in the option because there's only two possible values
for the star
and you've got both the stock and option there must be a riskless portfolio
because the price of the option depends only on the price of the stock
on the exercise date
so what we do is give optimal head ratio eight
that makes my portfolio i'm going to form a portfolio of the stock and the
i'm going to put them together
so that i have addressed this portfolio
all right and that's what i want to do
and out of that is going to fall
value for the price of the option
so this is what you want to do
we're looking for riskless profit up this consider this
we're going to write one call
and by h shares
and i going to pick h
so that i have no risk at all
it's easy to see how you do that
because we already know
before the exercise date
we know that if the price goes up
it will be worth u h
my portfolio
but h shares
the shares will be worth UHF
use us is the price
they share be were few a test
OK but i've written one call
so this will be worth UAH has minus the
price of call
similarly if the price stock if the stock price goes down
this is the value intrinsic value of the call
the next period on exercise date
the portfolio will be worth dhs minus
c so
so let's
choose h so that the two are the same
and all have to do is set this equal to this solve for h
that gives me the optimal
so it is equal to c
the view minus is the
however you minus the
times as
and now
it's very simple to get to option pricing
is that if i can
form this portfolio with
where i have
one call and it shares in the portfolio
it's a riskless portfolio
and so it has to run the risk this rate of interest
and that's what no arbitrage
sure as it can be possible to get a riskless portfolio
that means either more or less than the risk was right
because if if that did happen i would have
i would have a risk this opportunity
the ability to earn more than the rest straight with no rest
that that's contrary to our
are try
the return on since you you invested HS minus c
in the portfolio
the return of the total value of it has to equal one plus the response
and hs minus c
if so if you substitute in
for a test minus c
you find out that it equals
and substitute for h into this and you get the price of the call
today and that's
it's simple algebra
but there it is
so that's the
arbitrage theory
call option price
that might be less than intuitive to you but
you see that was very simple
arguing that got us there
we merely said
the way to think about options is that options move with the stock price
there are there are perfectly correlated with stock price over
this interval because
if the stock price goes up you know you've got c so this is the
view of the stock price goes down you know you gets said
so you have only one source of uncertainty but you have to assets
so you can put them together to eliminate risk
and if you put them together where they have to and the rest was right
and you just solve for and you get this value the call
this is the ins inherent inside the black and shoals
i came up with in there
classic nineteen
seventy three paper
an option pricing which i'll come to you but
this has to be the price of the car option the simple world
otherwise be arbitrage
the interesting thing about this is that there are no probabilities in this formula
what's in this form i've got
and these variables here which you need the covariance matrix by correlations between the variables
and you have me
and so on and so forth OK
so this allows you to describe joint distributions over
multiple outputs
so the other thing i want to mention it was which
we're not going to be used a lot
but it's there is very important in probability sample based approximations very often you can't
compute expectations that you're interested in exactly
but what you can do is you can have samples from
the density you're interested in and then you can have a sample in the law
of large numbers of and i was mentioning you can have a sample based approximations
to the expectation you're interested in
so that used to compute orbit because of course the sample mean is is we
always talk about means what we think of sample means but in some ways that's
just an approximation to the true mean but we say both of these things are
means but what we really mean when saying this is the sample mean i tend
to think of that being true mean
anything can be computed in that way
because when we're looking at data that's what we effectively have have some unknown distribution
and we have samples from it and the sort of thing but i was talking
about in terms of law of large numbers and convergence is making the sample based
approximations you've got samples from some unknown distribution
so that's as much as i wanted
talk about the review
probability hopefully it wasn't
well if it something in there
so this is what we had before so i'm not something to talk about error
and we said OK
this is how we measure the quality of our regression and we said we we're
get some across some output from some functions so this is the set of bases
that we had follow bumps
and these weighting of these bonds minus the actual target so this was like delta
y i square
and the sum of that for every data point we observed
the quadratic error function can be seen as the gaussians noise models so the way
that works is to imagine this is the data generating process and we often talk
about generative models and this is sort what we mean that x is inside the
basis function vector basis functions here
and what we are observing is why would the function of x which is a
linear weighted set of basis functions plus now this is the new this is what
we had before
x long long is calcium noise standard deviation sigma
this noise model assumption is still critical something you didn't see what bernard was talking
about because when he's generating a loss function
you're not actually considering the noise what you're considering is the penalty will pay for
getting things incorrect this is nothing to do with the penalty you'll pay for getting
things incorrect so let's say i'm ordering lumber
because i got supply and demand side i need to buy in london
to deliver to my customers
now these two things that can happen right if i don't have the right amount
of lumber i might have cost for having incorrect by running a pentecostal missiles if
i've got too much rots so there's an amount of money i can say that's
my cost right so that's one thing
but another thing is the demand for lumber
so the cost might be i don't know linear
in the amount of the incorrect this is my number predictions
but the demand for lumber
might be coming from gauss distribution so might be quadratic so these things are these
two things are important and different
in some ways actually i would say that what the the frequentist approach the but
i was describing is more correct because you're trying to take into account your cost
at the time the fitting your model
in the bayesian approach you do that and there's a reason why or in this
maximum likelihood approach you want to do that the reason why you don't do that
is you know
if your model is correct you don't need to worry about that you can prove
that you can say if the thing
the model you've got the system is correct you don't have to worry about the
cost until later
so that's really nice separation you can do these two things separately what about inference
as i recall it then you worry about your cost of course in practice that's
never really true never know you've got the correct models you can't really do that
separation but the nice thing about the separation is it makes everything simpler make model
construction simpler so
you have to be
more intelligent to be frequentist i would say
so i'm very because it's mechanical and i don't have to think so so i
can do more with my limited brain
OK so
this is calcium noise writing on here but is the product of the generating system
nothing to do with the cost
so once we got that this implies that we can write this down and this
is the sort of way we describe the likelihood in this case that implies that
y is drawn from the guassian distribution
with the meaning given by that
and since the noise is zero
i mean
when you add
noise gas in you just adding new effectively making that the mean of the distribution
writing constant function to zero mean gaussians which just means mean new thing is that
so we can also write i would write that that that this the sort of
very statistical notation this still the thing here means y is sampled from this
another way of writing that is that the probability of y given
w and sigma
is this calcium distributions so
my wife depend on these parameters
and its dependent the gaussians vision so i might interchange between those two styles but
basically identical sister wives missing of that
one of the things i think is quite confusing is is i i d assumptions
the way i think of i i assumptions
which you mention all the time
is this so if the noise is sampled independently for each data point from the
same density so this noise we this corrupting influence is independent every time we get
a data point and coming from the same density each time that's why i think
it was an idea assumptions i don't think of the model is being IID assumption
your body can help get it here it's kind of funny when you with these
things i want to give it away
that's all i know it's really it's actually when you build is very integrated models
kind of behaviors which might not necessarily anticipated
all right
and here's another example looking at the learning scenario
you know
just looking at integrating different sort of social building so this is map from the
i this is the possibility of this is big bird
so one year of age human children able to find the very effective appraisals of
novel objects environmentally socially reference
their parents people they trust
you're welcome big brother things that you don't have to themselves
if you look at the learning
learning ability of the of the matter is that the very interesting
early birds sharing attention about it you start to think that fact from his tone
of voice
getting are yellow
this is the reference to the interaction that happening around
this object
starting to pick up on that his own internal state
are starting to come into line with that is to learn essentially an effective tag
helio vocabularies in world characters actually the thing that you want so that's what he's
reaching out be a good thing i want i want to be
is i want to give it to the police are ineffective presumably the positive things
they might want to learn the next for about
this is showed basically that the you know the answer the interaction can happen as
was also a novel object can you find cookie monster introducing making sure that you
know this where it is
so we understand this cookie monster thing
nobody found in the world complete monsters appearing in the opposite
speaking up on that monsters very very
scary monster wants to disregard these
and that's OK you that you can share now
in this but surely actually has the memory now you can read about these subject
in prison
is that we still want to predict what
you want to do that you want to so
so people sometimes get very concerned about this video were teaching leo cookie monster
it's really not trying to show in the video
really want to make the point that know robots in the world you know most
about the encounter is going to be notable to the brain
and the way that the public and how have to learn about things that are
safe to explore that to explore the problem that to pick up from the people
around them so endowing about these social learning abilities imitation demonstration for thing all these
things that we do in nature i think are going to be very important for
the success so the idea is that by
communicating to things that are going to explore versus maybe not good might
o gauge how we choose to explore the weight of but isn't necessarily matching his
memory these forever going forever that we get to keep the bigger picture open mind
and why we're motivated to look at this is what learning
OK so so the next thing i want to talk about then is if we
can build machines that can elicit the set of social understanding from people can and
should be little sister elongation for social understanding what about relationship what about long-term interaction
relationship and why might that be interesting for robots
so we wanted to do a study exploring this in terms of long-term human robot
and the domain that we wanted to look at was weight management and we chose
that for a number of reasons the first of course is that this is this
is an african issue in the united states sixty five percent of the united states
are overweight or obese
and we know that as we get older many of chronic diseases are tied to
overweight and obesity so even just for human quality of life it's important for us
to think about how we can help people get this under control
it also turns out that from you know successful progress to achieve success is often
attributed to a number of things so
the first of course is long-term motivation
two your diet exercise program
social support is often found to be very positive interventions of friends family also trying
to do
you are encouraged to lose weight is also very important just logistics like accuracy of
collection of
in calories expended calories through exercise and perhaps if using adaptive using training being able
to share your progress with members of a social support network so
given these factors
it is intriguing to think about how a robot might introduce a new element a
new kind of technology to help people address this problem with the key ideas this
robot can not only kind of either the social support a long-term engagement between the
the person themselves
the patient so to speak
are to maintain a way that you can imagine the robot can also help manager
device network we have a bluetooth pedometer bluetooth scale just to help with the logistics
of keeping track of your calorie expenditure and so forth and also if you have
a little bit every day and keeping track of those interactions it can store the
information that you could print out and share with your training your doctor your family
so to empower your actual social network
as well
we find this structure
in profound way melts away
leaving the very
he symmetry behind which are symbolized by these grains of sand on this picture and
what this means i'll explain in the fourth lecture
but the general idea
of there being a profound symmetry in hot conditions
which freezes into structures and patterns in cold conditions
it's something which permeates all of science and is at the root of this desire
to find the higgs those on all that stuff the large hadron collider is about
hopefully by the end of these four lectures you'll have a sense
what this is
and here of course is a particular example of snowflakes
the freezing point of water show beautiful six-fold pattern
melt snowflake by raising the temperature that six-fold pattern disappears and you get a completely
uniform symmetry this is one of many examples of patterns disappearing and different symmetry is
emerging as you heat things up
and we will see in the universe as a whole
we believe exhibit this sort of phenomenon you go from
present temperatures extreme edges we'll measure the LHC
so that's how things began with nothing at all
and then out of it out of this big bang emerged
matter and antimatter in perfect balance
the best experiments we can do
and we all know from star trek and even experiment
the when matter and antimatter meet they annihilate one another
so that then raises the big question which we still don't know the answer to
why is it
the beginning a second later
the newly born matter and antimatter had mutually annihilate to one another and destroy the
so how is that fourteen billion years later
the universe appears to be made primarily of matter
and you have to invoke we find no evidence for it all
this asymmetry
is critical to us being here
the origin of it is one of the great unsolved problems which we hope will
get the answers to
the LHC but we'll talk about this again you'll hear more about this in other
so to give an idea of the scale of things that we can do in
science and what we know about the universe
i have been able to explore the universe over forty orders of magnitude distance scale
that the
observable universe about ten to twenty six metres
of course we build instruments to expand our senses beyond the immediate once we have
telescope shows the space
if you want to start looking
at the smaller structures of things you need to build microscopes
and if you want to study the very small structures of things that the levels
of ten to the minus fifteen meters or even smaller
you have very special microscopes which is what
particle accelerators are
what i do and it is actually show you how these numbers
things all merged together why is the particle accelerators microscopes why they probe distance scales
while you need energy you need
so the basic game that started many many years ago is what is matter made
and there are three broad ways that we know how to do that you can
look at it you can smash it up which is obviously more fun when you
can heat up and see what happens
as we will see all of these three are doing the same thing in different
ways but let's take the one at the time
looking at things will see me
because light is shining on me
and you see it in your archives
the light source and object in your eye
two international jargon of particle physics
this is a particular example of what we do all the time
in this case the light is a beam of radiation
you have been
which you
fire target
and then you detect the scattered beam
and from that you work out what the target is made of
so why don't we do it just by looking well there's a limit to what
you can see with your eyes the limits
of the
vision with
the rainbow
ten months for me to i bacteria are even smaller than that
after much smaller than atomic nucleus quarks electrons yet small still
so it's not a problem of you have the powerful enough the magnifying glass there's
an inherent problem
i'll show you know i mean it
what i mean by that and how we can't
so to look at things smaller than bacteria we need to have special instruments to
be able to withstand
our vision
and the problem is the fact that light at least the wavelength of light that
our eyes respond to
are very large on the scale
after a little over small things
five scale
ica wavelengths greenlight right there in the middle of the rainbow
compared size that and you see the atoms
incredibly small compared with
the light just passes by without being disturbed
in order
two c and at some level and resolve its internal structure
you need to have a wavelength which is comparable to or smaller than the object
you want to look at when those of you who go sailing you where the
fact if you've got a nice
rolling waves going along
a small fish small yachts will just pop up and down the waves without disturbing
is a large oil tanker will scatter the waves
and in principle you can imagine detecting the scattered waves and working out there was
an oil tanker there so the moment the wavelength is smaller than the object that
object will be resolved so we need to have waves that are smaller than atoms
one of the great things that was discovered in the nineteen twenties
is that not just like in the way that all particles have wavelike characteristics as
one of the basics of quantum mechanics
and the wavelength for example of an electron
the wavelength is inversely proportional to the momentum so
high speed the higher the energy the higher the momentum the smaller the wavelength
and hence the better the resolution you can receive
and rather than comparing walk walks into graphs they compare some three like patterns
in in two graphs what's up three like patterns
it's not exactly the same as up tree
of the graph
subtree that allows for repetitions of nodes so you start from one node in your
grasp you visit its neighbours
and then you visit the neighbours
one of these neighbors
which means that you might go back
two years starting note
and that's the difference between this up a tree like pattern
and the up tree
and the common works by first comparing
the starting notes to each other
in year two graphs so started to
nodes in u two graphs and then you compared to neighborhoods
because if you to each other
if you think about it it's quite related to this paper decomposition idea
these nodes from which is up three
like patterns are grown as the selectors
and the advantage here is that this gives you a richer representation of the graph
structure than the walk based approach but of course the runtime grows exponentially with the
depth of the subtree like patterns
so this gives you a richer representation but does not here neuron timbre
another approach was presented at KDD two thousand four
is the so-called cyclic pattern occurrence
i want to compare simple cycles
in two graphs and these are
pass through the start node equals and note
so cycles cycles in europe graph the problem is that the number of simple cycles
is exponential in the number n of vertices in the worst case
but still
in order to find a problem based on the simple cycles
palmer et
defined the canonical string representation of each simple cycles so that they be find an
ordering over the nodes in your graph and the canonical string representation of the cyclist
the one that is first in alphabetical order
according to one needs to be in a sabbatical order according to the
the order about is that they
defined in the first place
and that's an interesting alternative to walk based comments but it suffers from the problem
that in general the sickly pattern con is NP hard to compute
and so what i restrict attention
two scenarios but the number of simple cycle
in the graph dataset is bounded by a constant you then they can prove
that the runtime effort
it's only polynomial in the size of the graph otherwise is NP hard
to compute this suit cyclic pattern comes
a third approach
which is based on the idea to look
and subgraph
class sub graphs other than walks
the so-called graph can
here one counts subgraphs of of of limited size k into two input graph
and these subgraphs of limited size are referred to as graph it's because that's the
term that has been used in the bound for medical literature
as before
and you can't value is then
the number of isomorphic graphlets into graphs
however this
because of runtime problems the pairwise hasadvisorx morphism
for these graphlets
is expensive
and the number of graphlets lipschitz off into the so enumerating them is already very
expensive k
as k grows
as k increases
there are however two solutions
to speed up this kind of unlabelled graphs
two drinks the first one is precompute
the isomorphism relationships
between the graph let's here you exploited
the property the fact
that if you cross are unlabelled then there can be only a limited number of
graph of size k so you can precompute the isomorphisms
among these
subgraphs of size k
and then rather than enumerating all the
the graphlets in off into the k
you can sample graph from your graphs
to speed up your computer
this each here
there are obviously the same solutions do not hold
for labeled graphs
so far this only
on labeled unlabeled graph
these are the
graph of size four
you encounter
in and they would an undirected graphs
in ICML two thousand eight two new
i will start today was very interesting phenomenon
which is known as beat phenomenon
suppose you have two simple harmonic motions
with the same amplitude but with different frequencies
so we have x one
is a
times cosine
only got one t
and you have access to
which is a
i'm gonna go only got two and the two are different
same amplitude
if you some them
one class x two
you get to a
times the cosine of half the sun
omega one
but only get divided by two
times t
times the cosine
of half the difference
and when you look at this
you have
a frequency which is high compared to
this frequency you can best see that
you only get one look
it's very close to omega two
you could simply replaced by omega
then this is simply saying cosine omega t
and so if you
chains from the notation of omega in you had to
frequency in hertz which is a lot easier to think of
two quite
time frequency f
this is the words
this is in radians per second suppose you have
and f one
which is two two hundred and fifty six per
and you have an f two
which is two hundred and fifty four
you take these numbers now is working example
the period of this oscillation is one two hundred fifty six of the second
but the period of this oscillation is only one second
because it's the difference between the two divided by two
so what happens is
that if you
make a plot
of the
of x as a function of time
i will first sketch
this is very slow
so this
is very slow
compared to this one
which is very fast
i will first make a sketch of of the very
slow one
this is the slower
and i will make also
the line here
guide my hand when i'm going to make it a lot
so what you see now is that the
the first rule she
this flow on goes like this
and the net was old is this
this is the fast one
fast one
and so you see right here
is when the slow one is zero
so this long kills the amplitude you can think of this as an amplitude modulation
that he h
is multiplied by that
cosine function
we defined as just a matter of definition we define this as the beat
when the two are
in phase
and here they are again
in face
the two a hundred eighty degrees out of phase we define this as the bit
for the working example that we have on the blackboard and two fifty six per
cent to fifty four
from here to here
it would be one second
that's the time for this slow one
go three hundred sixty degrees and so the bit
here we would in that case
the harvest second
so if you want to see in your head what is happening
then if one oscillation
is like this
then when they are in face
we should
give evidence before
is this really is
almost optimal
let me
right down the theorem forty
the length of the binary string
but i just mentioned a few minutes ago the one that we send the length about binary string
this article is the length of the encoding
if x one to x and its lesser equal to
the shannon information content
which is what shannon says ought to be
but absolutely perfect compression is less than or equal to the last two
so the entire length of the whole compressed file is only two bit longer and the optimal
length that shannon would like you have
and something to really emphasise there is when you compare that with what we could
do with simple codes for symbol codes
the length that you've got
character was with in one of the entropy
and so that means the possible overhead on a file with an characters in it
could be as big as an
and overhead event
which could be enormous
this is an overhead only two bits the entire file so it's a factory end
smaller than the overhead you get with simple codes
why is this the case what why is it that we end up with three
of length well if you just think about
the subdivision process that we're going through
the first
interval has size equal to the probability of the first character
given your model
then you subdivided in proportion to
the probability of the second character
given the first character
so his
the alphabet of possibilities
and the product of those two
is equal to the joint probability of x one and x two just by trivial
probability theory you
and then when you subdivided and you take the important size
is x one
and next to sell off its hair
you subdivide
and you say this is the probability of
divided in proportion to the probability vector given x one x two
if you multiply this length by that's fraction you get
the probability of x one x two x three
and so forth so these signs of the interval that you get on the left-hand side in the alphabet world
exactly the probability of the string
now when you find a binary interval that lines up with at interval and that
fits snugly inside it fitted perfectly snugly
then how many bits need for the binary
strength on each time you start with one and a half then a quarter and
so forth so the number of halving you go through is the log base two
of the size of the binary interval you end up with so if it fits exactly snugly
the length of the binary string will be it be exactly equal to
the number factors are to
but this
number here is small
which is log base two or whatever peak
first not fit
you will end up with a binary string and exactly the optimal length
in practice you won't quite have a snug fit
but it's an exercise in the book you can do the exercise and prove that
in the worst case the worst norms not fit you can end up with will
be that he
binary string is a factor of four
the alphabet string so you only need an extra two bits
to be guaranteed that you've found
a binary string lifts inside
so that's fact one
which is brilliant
andy node number two
the other thing i want you to know is how much work is it to do all this
what did we need to do did we need to think about all conceivable strings
the hub scores
for over here gets translated into authority scores over here and then is propagated back
so that for instance the hub score of that node has changed
and they have squad that no had some impact on what the hub score that
and that node will be as we do the propagation can in this back and
forth over the links
OK and we can also write it again in matrix notation just by
this time the matrix that we're looking at remembering the in the pagerank we really
had a markov chain so we had a markovian matrix is the hostage matrix here
we just use the adjacency matrix
it's a it's just the adjacency matrix and so on what we then can see
is that
the authority scores if multiply by the adjacency matrix we get something that should be
proportional to the hub scores and if we take perhaps causing multiply with the transpose
right because we are reversing the direction of the of the links is just taking
the transpose of the adjacency matrix we have that relationship
and now what we what we can do is
basically eliminate to analyse this further we can instance now eliminate
the hub scores in that scheme
and condense it in a single equation
which means right we take the authority score time step t minus one multiplied by
a that gives us the hub score we take the hub score multiplied by transpose
that gives us the new authorities
so we have the two steps in one
and this is now
almost and i can vector equation only that is just the proportionality we don't actually
know what the what i can value is and whether it's the same for for
every time step t we haven't really specified
OK but
what we can do for instance if we can ask ourselves well if we would
somehow normalise
let's say these scores so that the norm
it is always equal to one
you know does this scheme then converge toward some
the score vector for the authorities
for instance if we would start with
all the hub scores being initialize to one
OK and
so here's a little example
i don't know how much that helps but it's you know small graph with six
you see them over here is the adjacency matrix but you already see that in
that picture this is how a transpose and a transport a looks like and if
you don't do the
the perhaps another thirty computation
until convergence
you get for instance the scores for the authorities so you see that page one
and two
because you know page two
then we will
here web page to actually happens to get a zero hub scores well so it
doesn't inherit anything here and this is the only incoming edges both but actually end
up with an authority of zero the highest authority is page five here
we see this here in the second highest age three
and in terms of the authority scores on these are the authority scores page one
has the highest
you know it's kind of consistent with that because three and five have the highest
authority scores and one points to both of them right so one in that case
is good hop note although it has zero authority weight
OK let's just like two
maybe just skip over that so basically you can show that this that indeed
this makes infinity vector defined by these
by this recurrence relation is ultimately concerned giving converging and it's converging towards the dominant
i can vector of this matrix transpose a
under the assumption that basically the dominant igon value has the multiplicity of one
OK but
if we just move on here
and talk a little bit about how you know actually going to use that in
the in the context of of web search
OK now you could just
you could just say well why that's just use this perhaps an authority on them
on the web as a whole
but that was not really
the idea that time work was pursuing because he was interested remember we had initially
we're interested in this brought
and then we might be able to find a result set for these broad queries
and the results it is just you know very large
a lot of pages and we would like to find a way to rank these
pages so the idea that the strategy that he was suggesting is that we first
determine a subgraph of the web
and then run the hopson authority propagation algorithm on that subgraph
how's this subgraph determined well the way that determine is based on a specific query
OK so let me talk about just one more thing we did on this spoken
dialogue task
another challenge that we had is
o which comes up in a lot of applications
is that we have a huge source of unlabelled examples that getting the labels is
very expensive so in a single day might be able to gather thousands even tens
of thousands of
telephone calls
which are unlabelled examples
but then you have to have humans actually annotate those examples so getting those examples
getting those labels throughout rather is very expensive you can only afford to do a
few hundred every day
so the question is how to get the most information from the human how can
we make the best use
the human annotators that we have how can we choose
that are most informative for labeling
this is the problem often called active learning which comes up in a lot of
and we use the very standard technique here we use something called selective sampling which
means that two to select examples
in particular what we did is we focused on the least confident examples
but we need to do is we
we need to find the unlabelled examples
on which are classifier which we built is least confident and ask for the labels
on those examples
and this is the technique that goes back to lewis and gail
and so for how do you measure confidence while for boosting we already have a
way of measuring confidence we can just use the margins around the absolute value of
the margin
as the natural confidence measure
so here's the type of experiment that we did so we started out with a
pool of unlabeled examples
and then we choose maybe five hundred examples at ran for labeling just get the
whole thing started
and then we what we do is we run boosting
and all of the labelled examples
to get the combined classifier as and then we pick
maybe two hundred fifty additional examples from the pool
for labeling
and the way we choose the messages the examples that were least confident about the
ones with minimum
this turns out to be the margin
and then we repeat which is another
two hundred fifty examples
we train and so on
so here's the kind of performance they get doing that
so this is plotting the error rate the test error rate
as a function of the number of labelled examples that we have
and the red curve is showing what happens if you just use those examples random
and the blue curve is showing what happens the beaches those examples for labeling
using this kind of active technique that i talk about
so again you see this
huge speedups this huge improvement in terms of number of examples that you actually need
so for instance to get
narrator twenty six percent
if you just using examples are random you need about twenty two thousand examples
with boosting you only need about ninety five hundred examples so it's like a two
to one speed up
what's also interesting about this curve
is the fact that this blue curve is active curves
goes down and then comes back up again
you would never expect to see this with random examples with random examples more data
is always better
but this is showing that more data
it's actually worse than last data
that somehow these examples that were added out here
are actually
destructive there actually dis informative and you actually do better by ignoring those examples
OK and this is just another dataset
OK so let me just talk about one final application o o you question
you try to get to the point that we saw
oh i see
so so you need to know something about the experiment that was actually done here
which is that we had
for this experiment we were starting with a fixed pool of forty thousand
so but you could do something similar to what you're talking about so we could
do is you could
try to predict somehow
where this minimum point is
and then you could just stop at that point
you could just stop at that point and people calling conan so and had a
paper using support vector machines rather than boosting but they observed this exact same thing
with active learning you can actually do better with less examples and they try to
use techniques to
try to predict where the lowest point was if i'm remembering correctly
where the lowest point wasn't stopping at that point
so if you have an
infinite amount of data and presumably would not
see this type of phenomenon even with active learning you would see things just dropping
dropping dropping but
i can't do the experiment because i don't have an infinite amount of data
this is out of sample this is tester
this is all tester
i don't completely know i wouldn't call it overfitting
it's not really overfitting because
so each of these is the different run
a boosting every two hundred fifty examples getting differ run boosting
what's being plotted here is the number of examples