this i would like to represent with my neural nets some probability
distribution over all the classes on conditional distribution
of my input x belonging to one of the
capital c different classes so i'm noting that
mathematically as the probability the of y my label why
be equal to some small c which is a choice between
zero and c minus one or actually x from one to capital c
here so one way to get these probabilities is essentially have
an output layer that is always positive
and whose activations some to one
and there's a very simple way of achieving this with the what is
known as the softmax activation function
all that does is that it takes the pre-activation vector
at output layer so these are the case of the output layer
and then i'm going to take the exponential
on each dimension and finally i'm going to divide each dimension
by the sum of the exponentiator pre-activation
so you can see that writing it this way
all my dimensions is going to be normalized that is if i was to
some over all the values in that vector
because i explicitly the divided each dimension by that some
i'm going to get a sum that is equal to one
so because of this i can interpret the output as a multinomial
distribution over my put x belonging to one out of the sea different
classes and if i wanted to actually perform classification with
a model that the softmax output i just look at which unit has the
highest activation that is according to my neural net
what is the class has the highest probability given my input
x and that's what
so we can go from one hidden layer to multiple hidden layers some
just extending my notation here were now using k s some arbitrary
hidden layer within my neural net use capital l as the number i
hidden layers so in this case pre-activation and some layer case
is just going to be a linear transformation of my
previous layer so in annotation to make this equation work i'm and
assume that h zero x is actually the input
so the layer below the first hidden layer is the input
and another pre-activation is just this linear transformation
taking my weight matrix multiplying it by the activation
layer below some bias and finally i'm going to get hidden layer
activation by apply my activation function
and i do the same thing for the output but typically put the output
layer i'm going to use a different activation function as
i've described i'm performing multi-class classification i'm going
to use the softmax for the activation function at the output
for the hidden layers might use a sigmoid in my user tanh h
quite frequently will actually use the realm of the rectified or
linear activation function
ok any questions so far than this so yeah
yeah so point so my assumption what i'm writing vectors is that
they are column vectors and so because if i read it this way suggests
that it's a row vector the transpose here is to
emphasize i'm taking a row vector transposing
so by default if you see a vector notation i've
that's a good point you mention this i don't really
emphasize that so whenever i use a bold type
it's to refer and lower case it's usually refer to a vector
i'm using bold but for a capital letter to going to be matrix
and if it's a it's like instead of like this one here instead a bold
that's going to be a scalar ok some try to hopefully help understand
what we're referring to scalar of
vector going to try to stay true to that convention
great point yes
so the rule of thumb is used the relative ok
that tensor work really well but i've seen examples where turns
out that the sigmoid for some reason is better
tanh h i think that i so yes where as like their own rule of thumb
but typically i start with the relevant and maybe i will try to
sigmoid and tanh h if i for some reason not satisfied with the
results that that would be my rule of thumb but
f yeah yes
i mean i can't say i've seen a lot of yes thank you so you will
have to tell you that often so the question issue we used different
activations at different layers different you know positions and
there are different hidden layers of the network
i haven't seen whole lot of success in actually
you know type kind of fine-tuning the type of activation
and in this case the state space is continuous and in particular has two components
the position of the core of the car and the velocity of the car
and so the value function is defined over the state space as you know
and this is the way it develops
so the the thing to notice here is that this is a recurring theme in
reinforcement learning
is that the value function could be
not so small
so in this example it won't be smaller because
well the car could be really close to here
but if its velocity is not high enough
i think one fish to go
so it's the proper course of reaching the goal would be very high in that
case the velocity is not enough
but in the very city limit the larger
then it will be able to reach the goal so the course will be small
and over the discontinuity in the value function
on the other hand if the problem would be noisy then this discontinuity is most
of the right because lawyers can have to use your work on this
being other party
so the
thing is that well the the math or the works well
again you can ask questions about value of lambda is going to give you the
best answer and it turns out that in this case it's not long london was
it was not long there was one
so lake was one gives you a ridiculously bad
estimates in this example islam because to point nine
problem though is this target
is so hard to
how to make it work is the so-called off policy situation enough policies situation
what you want to do is you want to
estimate of a some policy by following some other policy what you want to do
if you want to do you want to implement let's see policy iteration
you want to compute an action value functions
you have your friend policy
you want to compute its action value function
but in order to be able to do that you have to try some other
it's not only the actions
the policy
prescribed that that you want to try
because you not learn about all these other actions if you want to improve your
policy you should learn about the other actions well so you want to explore
the question is if these arguments are working in that situation on that solicitation is
following some some and you want to have with some other policy
so know policy iteration gives you want to have current policy but you're following different
policy because you're are exploring and
and the bad news is that you can come up with some pretty simple examples
that show that these are getting just doesn't work
so this graph shows the number of iterations and this is sort of logarithmic scale
and this is the weight of a changing if you use
he zero in the previous example
and you can also show that this has nothing to do
he zero if you want to do
some of these other organs that that should that
you can exactly
computer about one of the
the ones that look at updates but then you do some
least squares fitting
then you can show that are those organs won't work
that's bad news but on the other hand people are
using these are gardens is quite a bit of success with some care
and so that's good
i have still some
twenty five or so
and probably won't have time to cover all
of those
maybe as
it's a conclusion i just want to mention that
very recent work
we have to go to quite a few are that working off policy situation
in an increment of a on the batch for when you have this singer trajectory
and just want to learn a good policy that seems to be
possibilities some your guidance and
but if you're interested and you should talk to
so the questions
you can ask how does this work
so OK so
if the environment is changing in a very advanced way
you cannot do anything right so
one thing that you can always then you should always do is that if you
have a chance
you dont became the learning this two zero too fast so you want to keep
on learning
because the environment might change
so in a non stationary environment so in the mind is changing fast then you
suffered bitter alliance loss at the time when the change happens right so
you won't even have said the change may be
it's already too late then you're about the
so that's a very very serious situation so you don't want
i mean there's no
value in in thinking about that
maybe you want to think about the
the niceties spending one hundred changing but it's not changing in a very very survey
on the other hand
it's not the environment that changing but if features are not sufficient
you're one
in you know one
have no
is called
the diffusion coefficient of carbon as a function of the concentration of carbon in life
it turns out that as more and more carbon goes in the higher the diffusion
coefficient changes you'd expect that because now some of the sites are occupied so which
is it do you think that the diffusion coefficient as you get more and more
carbon into Alliance starts to fall like this
or do you think the diffusion coefficient arises like this so that at higher concentrations
it becomes more difficult to diffuse
well this might sound appealing because the sites what makes sense right there's fewer empty
sites that body factor the diffusion coefficient actually rises
well I've told you that the carbon atom is larger than the interstitial site so
the carbons go into the interstitial sites the actors wedges and they actually wedge open
and make it easier for the succeeding Adams to
diffuse through
so in point of fact this is what this could be either so let's imagine
suppose we have a case number 1 where the diffusion coefficient full of false concentration
rises and I've got a steady state a concentration profile of C 1 constant on
the left C to constant on the right is the equation we have to look
at minus the DC by next but this is now a function of concentration
so when concentration if I have case number 1 when I have the highest concentration
on here
if this is the remain constant if the concentration dependence of the diffusion coefficients as
D but is low when you see is higher than that suggests that to keep
a constant
reflects the CVX must be high but when see is high so that means instead
of a straight line we're going to see something that looks like this so this
is case number 1
case number 2 where the concentration dependence of diffusivity is indicated with rise all that
means at high concentration diffusion coefficients to be higher than it is at low concentrations
of this number is higher than high concentration and this number has to be lower
so that the product will remain constant proclamation class
so this is case number 2 I
these are all variants of steady state
of the steady state j but is not a function of time J is not
a function of time
independent of time
so now I ask what happens in that initial moment when we 1st pressurize the
system let's say we start off in there's nothing inside the
membrane and just to keep things simple and make up for the equals 0 on
the right hand side
website is p 1 at at time 0 initially pressurized swim concentration C 1 instantly
at surface what's the set of events that occurs leading up to the establishment of
the steady state profile would expect after a short time we see concentration profile shown
like this
and then after a
longer period of time like this and after a longer period of time like this
and then finally of course we establish so this is time is increasing
load so this could be a T 1 and T 2 T 3 and so
we can then say let's Park ourselves at some value of X 1
on 0 l look at what's happening initially if I take the Slobodan a low
number but take the slope at a later time it's a higher number fighting the
slope at a later time it's even higher number and ultimately it's going to be
multiply that probability
by the total number of ways of ordering small and successes out of large n
bernoulli trials
it's not some sort of standard
the problem of combinatorics that you can work out and that happens to be the
answer so the answer is the number of permutations that you have
it is large and factorial divided by small and factorial
began my small in factorial
so so that gives me then the desired probability
and i write that in the following way so this is important to introduce my
i will write for the probability or probability density
s four p or some letter like that and then the first letter there is
the random variable in question
and then i have a semicolon
after that i list whatever parameters or constants characterize the probability law so here the
total number of
bernoulli trials and the probability of success per trial
and that that is the answer but this is a POV and one minus p
to minus and and then this comment factor
now for each of these
probability distributions i will give the expectation value and variance don't actually derives them to
sort of written down so in this case you could probably guess what is the
expected number of successes what you've got
large in total trials you got probability for success
p per trial so clearly large and times p that that's probably the expected number
of successes and if you work out that some you find indeed that's correct
and similarly you can work out the variance of n
and you get the expression here
OK so that's the the binomial distribution
that's what it looks like
for several values of the parameters so here's for large n equals five
so five trials
success probability of o point five and the similarly here
n equals ten equals twenty
so a bernoulli trial with the success probability of
o point five that would be like tossing a coin right to a fair coin
and asking for what is the number of heads out of
o five ten or twenty
of the coin
so that's what the probability law looks like here for example are for twenty trials
in each case but for different values of the success probability as you can see
there the distribution can look slightly asymmetric
this comes up in particle physics all the time for example in
considering the case of a particular particle suppose you observe large and decays of the
w boson and you want to know what's the probability that are small and have
them will go to a particular final state say
the w goes to a new one in neutrino
and you'd like to do somehow the error analysis to know what is the probability
of getting different outcomes so in that case the number of decays to
at final state that that would be regarded as success and so that number would
follow a binomial distribution and in that case we would call the success probability p
that corresponds to the branching ratio
of the particle decaying to that final state
OK so having said down quite a bit about the binomial distribution i'm going to
skip the details on the ones that come the multinomial distribution only read on your
own that simply generalizes the binomial distribution to the case where you have not only
two possible outcomes but some larger numbers a possible outcomes
but now here's an important extension of the binomial distribution
consider the case where the number of bernoulli trials gets very very large
but the number that the probability of success per trial gets vanishingly small
so in that limiting case
i want to consider that
such that the product of those two numbers which is the expected number of successes
i want that to stay equal to some finite constant which i'll call new
that's the greek letter new
in that limits the binomial distribution becomes what's called the plus some distribution
and that's the formula so here now so previously and had to go from zero
large and but now i'm considering large and becoming infinite so
and can go from zero to two infinity
here's sort of by construction
the parameter nu corresponds to
the exp expectation value of n
and also importantly the variance
of of this process on variable is also equal to the parameter name
and that's the important formula and began memorizing formulas
we have a long tsuda dalzell than other other acts that
we've discussed free oscillations harmonic oscillators
without damping
and then we introduce damping
but in each of those cases
we let the simple also later do its own thing
we did not interfere with it
that's going to change
they were going to
impose are real
o two
the simple harmonic oscillator
and we can impose i will on to it
driving it
was a force
and then c
what the net result is
let's start with a simple example
that i have here
spring was spring constant k
and object
mass and
this equilibrium position
x equals zero
really damping
i will introduce again be over m equals gamma
and omega zero squared equals k over and we've seen this before it is the
shorthand notation
so now in addition to the fact that when the object
it is away from equilibrium
that there is here a spring force
i'm not going to apply on the object of force may not be easy to
do will get back to that how we do that
but i can apply a force on that
maybe through magnetic field may be through electric fields
and i'm going to this force
it's not going to have the character of zero
times cosine
omega t
i impose on that system now
that frequency omega
i can choose that anything i want to
so now we can write down
differential equations of motion and newton's second law
x double got
equals minus kx nothing new
it's the spring force
a minus b x got nothing new that's the damping
external force
omega t
what i'm going to do not going to move this to the complex plane not
that it is absolutely necessary but i'm so used to that
i'm going to write is now in terms of physique
and then we take the real part of the later that this was back goes
back to
two x
so i'm going to write is now in terms of
xe double doctor i divide and not
you get plus
see dots
omega zero squared
times e
and that now
becomes zero divided by n
remember i divided them out
and then we get cosine omega t
for which i will right
you could apology omega t
because i work now in the complex plane
and through all alone
i can always convert the back to cosine
trial function for c
which is a complex notation
is some amplitude
times e to the apology
minus delta
crucial is
you understand
why this omega
and this omega and the same
this is the only gun
one of my
driving the system that is my will that i impose on that system
clearly given enough time in the beginning the system may be unhappy and it may
do all kinds of nasty things
which we will discuss next lecture but ultimately i will come out to be the
winner and ultimately that system is bound to start oscillating with the frequency that i
impose on it
if i start shaking you in the beginning you may not like that then you
oppose that but ultimately i will be the winner and i'll make you shake was
that frequency omega
so clearly
the ultimate solution must have the same omega
the driver
what is the meaning of these delta
it is not at all obvious
the object will be in the same face as the driver it is possible that
when the forces supporting in this direction that the object may be going in your
direction and you will see that that indeed can happen
and so this delta is the phase angle which takes into account
the possibility
that the driver
and the object
in the motion and not exactly
in phase
we call this solution a steady state solution study states that you must wait long
forty system not to fight any longer that will be part of my next lecture
the fighting issue
this is when i ultimately
why because in summing over all dividing the smaller than that
and an expression that i only have articles
two n
so the resulting expression is a function of ten
but this goes from one to n minus one
but here i have and i was one so
i have
this year that connects exercise
in minus one
with x and years
then summing over all these body within them
if x and likewise in the right hand side
summing over all the bottom was about allowed end
in the expression that has all the while in addition to n itself so the
result is a function of n
xn u u of x
just have just that
where every entry is depends on every venue possible
position accept
essentially what is called is that if you have a change
the marginal probability
given the
is the problem
functional in that comes from the last time the function and come to the right
call that both functions
because this a nice way to to have a toilet understanding of the situation
like your best messages using it here is that
every message is nothing else
the summation
one of the few
over two five
for me the problem
we can understand this SMS
computing this as
i put my eighty s
the complexity is of course linear on n
linear one
and quadratic on the state space
the same way as we saw
fourteen international
think about something
we haven't specified which we have right
this can be any of his body
so the marginal in any of these by is the product of the incoming messages
the desired
now assume that
i want to
we use let's assume that they want provide
they create
what do you suggest me to the
the messages
compute the messages
so what
compute these messages
and store
message up to
was one will be just as see from these expressions here
you need to search over x and
the messages
the problem the most common extensions can just
equations so
what you have to do just precompute whole minimis
two n minus two
when were two times in one
change or the three in the change in the three with an old
you have
how many edges
n minus one add
for every edge in need to compute messages one you the way
each way
two and minus two
message is just because you all things
and then you put them on the the table and whenever you have created OK
that's x y one
just call
the message from x forty five the message from x six to x four
multiply them together and you get
the normalized
what is called belief propagation
just put example change because seen
but if you have three it's exactly the same thing is just that
you're going to multiply these
always said
belief propagation three
saying in
and in the tree
in this case i just showed example
because of the tree
you have
like this
let's assume that these are and
x and we want to compute so
we compute
all the messages
going to xn
also don't their actions
that suffices
compute the marginal effects
but if i want to make it arbitrated and if i want to make agreeable
any of those
i need to compute messages
the other way
and i for one to create is no then multiply these messages by his message
and here's general equation based the message that they sent from j to i
i sum over all the values of j
of the potential
potentially this
c o x gnx i find all the proper folding come messages to j
we can use that information to identify would one profile
we're all profiles industrial profiles and so on
you can
but it even now
this means
but political
the volume of
for a given time
and this is a very important
the problem is that the economic downturn
the problem is that
the companies
the cell and by eleven
depending on the money
and for example important role
by or sell in machine
and if they
it can
but i think
the next week that is because mind
so they can buy now
electricity to make
at a much lower price
if they must decide
that they need it
by in
for the next problem
the price
most of the decision
to buy and sell
on may
but as soon as possible
and they are based on these
we can do much more things
take a chance
the tech trends in favor of
the text failed
but the normal activities
the x to involve
anomalies because some months before
this is not
a new problem
it has been stopped
long time ago
and most
of the process
out of this fact
strategy is
something like
select few need some
of x
the a static model
in the lead to can find
a lot of different types of models
types of plastic
different types of neurons were kalman filters wavelets polynomials and so on
he said the more
they have
that's a good performance
for the next month
after they have been
four seconds amount
the that performance that
the that
in six months late
they need to retrain everything
what this problem
the problem is that
to work
it's not for
seems sensible
the data that is
so in that light sensors and what we call it the first
and data stream
my can have take
that is
we have
much more data that can be
seven years ago
nowadays what we have is that computers
the same information
two articles
e there are a lot of cases where you have these sorts of things
most of these data
will never to be be seen by a human
we need
real time and all
real time
of the two these days
a lot of
learning that that can be
required for
these types of data
the stream is continue
the flow of data generated at high speed
by changing
he so the
is used
is continuous flow
i speak
nine and ten times changing
so what is the problem
this type of thing
the problem is
most of machine learning
adding them to
as in the data flow from
the station now
strip was
in practice
what we do in machine learning
assume that all data fit in memory
you will
training set
this is problematic
when lot slammed take
lessons from the stream
many thanks
at scission model in real time
and decision model
must be
able to
incorporating a new information
and this is
we need to
be able
two days
you probably say take the new treatments
yes can see the
seven hundred male standard
three hundred million OK good question so the question is how come there is only
a hundred miles taking the standard m three hundred taking the new
one is the other way around for women and this is the key to
what's going on
was there is a quite likely that i cannot add up they should probably be
two hundred ten
james that
i don't know
OK work it out
thank you
there's a mistake there is always a mistake
they should be the imagine and that's the story
two yes two
over two hundred ten
so is exactly the k this was an observational study in which there was no
particular pattern to how the
drugs were assigned to different patients although of the doctor may have had his reasons
but we don't know what they were ended up signing the new drug to a
lot of the men
seventy five percent of the men got the new drug and only twenty five percent
of the men the
OK try and it was the other way round with the women
so the new so the men mostly new drug takers
and the women are mostly old truck standard drug takers and we can see that
irrespective what get men recover much
better than women
round sixteen seventy percent against twenty to thirty percent so if you've got group known
mostly men
and irrespective of what they get the likely to return high recovery rate
whereas the women are likely to show
a group of mostly women also allow recovery rate so
what we've done here is
the new drug is given given mostly to the men who show high recovery rate
so it one even if they will the identical drugs
the problem and if you look to those who about the new drugs were mostly
manual c
high recovery rates and if you look to those who mostly the new old rival
mostly women you see lower company so got nothing to do
with the drug
it could do with the sexual pleasure so here so sex is a very large
confounding factor
in this particular trail so
that's all very well but is OK so which which of these numbers should we
believe that which can recall causal
you can say well it makes more sense to desegregate by
six this way use these numbers
but then when you start because there well maybe is a very young patients and
all patients in all sorts of other factors you bring it you can be positive
divided you can make a big cases like this where you subdivide more and more
and his level the message change
when you stop
it's tricky
for the same data what's going on the drug good for you about four
OK so
now i will talk about
so that's what we active population drift and you've seen is seen some numbers now
let's look at a couple of examples my first example is chip-and-pin
in the UK in
february last year
the banks rolled out a new
the way new fraud prevention strategy called should be you know many of you must
be perhaps will be familiar with the electronic microchip on the card and the PIN
it was predicted
instead of magnetic stripe and signature
it was replacement for that
the credit card
it was predicted would essentially end card for this what all publicity said
roll down then fourteen to february and as predicted credit card fraud in the UK
did decline
one of the questions you might ask this point though is how much of the
decline was due to the publicity
if all the banks more papers and everybody saying once we've got this system in
four the stop they won't be able to do it
and as i said at the beginning
with that sort of publicity people will back off control from certain kinds of fraud
so that's the question you might ask but anyway
continuing from the decline after this rule that fraud in the UK
but the water benefit
it was predicted to lead to an increase in identity theft
and here's an interesting thing
lloyds TSB which is a UK bank observe an increased use of force UK cards
in europe which didn't have time
or in those countries which didn't have the champion system in place
they were still relying on magnetic stripe and swiping and signature
so the cards
card details are being stolen
in the UK
ported across to countries which didn't have chip-and-pin and used to perpetrate fraud that this
was observed this happen
there was also
an increase in ATM cash machine
fraud and cardholder not present fraud we we saw
and his is an interesting thing sometimes you can go back use old technology some
crooks installed data schemas which take the numerical information from the next right and so
on in shipping terminals you combine these data schemas for less than a hundred pounds
it's not expensive
and very rapidly they sold over a million pounds from
petrol stations from gas stations
my second example
passwords of reactive population drift is password will familiar with passwords
but the password
are not perfect
no fraud prevention strategies perfect this is sort of like holy grail will never find
anything which stopped fraud
passwords are perfect because people tell them to others
they write them down
sending many email
remote servers logged onto and eavesdropped and often passwords are easy to get
hollywood movies there always easy to get to get them on the third get in
normal is a bit more difficult but sometimes they are easy to guess
people invented one time passwords
password which is only used once not is terribly complicated because you have to remember
passwords and then forget it and then returned the next day doesn't work like that
they have algorithms which generate a new password for each user and there's some sort
of synchronization there are various ways can be done
between the purchase
and the bank's computer so that they recognise each other and recognise that it's legitimate
so the various ways that it can be done so each time you make a
purchase you have a unique password which refers only to that task
the bank also known as what password is what's the purchases made once the transaction
is made
that password no longer works so if the password is stolen
that's OK it's not going to work anymore
so i test for you
if you were forced to how would you find your way round how would you
rate a one
time password system
we can come back to that in
those are two examples of reactive population drift
i want to focus down on
some of our project
the particular fraud project people highlighted in red beginning dave weston who here
tradition that chris whitrow and gordon blunt
myself working on the before project and some other things myself and david going to
we have four major
international banks providing us with data that feeling is given
large fraud
and on four datasets
evolving altogether hundreds of millions of transactions
we've got the projects divided into three phases one was OK at the beginning of
something like this you need to work out how you can tell whether it succeeded
or not
is there
system you feel any good
so the first phase of the project was to develop appropriate criteria for measuring performance
of detector of detection algorithms and we've done that
then we're in phase two reaching interface to developing evaluating refining new
new approaches to detection algorithms
i mean
as you know the banks already have systems in place our aim was to try
to that
new approaches
and then in the future implement these in collaboration with the banks
phase one how do we know whether we've got a good system
OK well
a good system
it's obvious what good system is that it classifies fraudulent transactions as fraudulent and different
ones as legitimate
nothing tough in that
the problem is a course that no method is perfect
it's gonna make misclassifications
if only because of the subtleties of been talking about
we do need criteria can't decided to get more right or didn't we need criteria
assessing relative to degrees of accuracy
very important
timeliness is important
it's no good discovering the credit card transactions fraudulent three months after the transaction you
really want to discover at the point being made and stop it
is it something we
it's not something we
taste or touch
or here we don't directly observe souls with our five senses
i wonder why don't i sort of directly observe it in myself that i ever
i guess have been people who who have made that sort of claim it seems
false to to me i can only ask to view to sort of introspective berserker
also turn your mind's eye in word and asked do you see a soul inside
i don't think so i i i c
things outside me i feel certain sensations in my body but that seems so i
observed a solar i believe in a soul
i don't see it
how do we prove the existence of things we can't see or hear taste and
so forth
that the usual method maybe not the only method but the usual method is something
like this
we posit
the existence of something that we cannot see
so as to explain something else
that we all agree takes place
why do i believe in the existence of atoms
i don't see individual atoms
why do i believe in the existence of atoms so small that i can see
them because
atomic theory explains things
when i posit the existence of atoms with certain structures
in certain sort of ways of interacting and combining building up when i posit
adams suddenly i can explain all sorts of things about the physical world
and so on
i infer
the existence
based on the fact that doing that allows me
to explain things that need explaining
this is that kind of argument that we use
all the time
how do i posit know why do i believe in x-rays even though i don't
see them because doing that allows me to explain certain things why do i believe
in no certain planets
not too far away to be observed directly through a telescope because positing them allow
you to explain certain things about the rotation of the star the gravitational fluctuations what
have you
we make inferences
to the existence of things we can see
when doing that helps us to explain something we can't otherwise explained
this pattern of argument which is ubiquitous
called inference
to the best
now i want to emphasise this bit about the best explanation
what we are justified in believing
are those things that we need not simply when they would offer us some kind
of explanation
but when they offer us
the best
explanation that we can think of so looked
why am i justified in believing in germs various kinds of viruses that i can
see because the bacteria would have because doing that allows me to explain
why people get sick
but there's another that would allow me to explain that is well how about demons
i could believe in demons and say i know why the person get sick and
die i you know the demonic possession
why can't i justified in believing in the existence of demons
it's possible explanations
but what we seem to be justified in believing is not just any old explanation
but the best explanation
so we've got to rival explanations we've got roughly germ theory and we've got demon
theory and we have to ask ourselves which of these does a better job of
explaining the facts about disease and who gets what kind of of diseases how diseases
spread how they can be treated or cured when they kill somebody
and there are
in fact of the matter is demon theory doesn't do a very good job of
explaining disease where while germ theory does do a good job if the better explanation
and so we are justified in believing in germs but not demons so it's a
matter of inference not just any old explanation
but inference to the best explanation so
we need to ask ourselves then is
what about the soul
observe souls but here is a possible way of arguing for them
are there things that need to be explained
so that we could explain
if we posit the existence of the soul
and a material object above and beyond the body
either things that the existence of the soul could explain
explain better
then the explanation that we would have if we had to limit ourselves to body
and put it this way sort of the easiest version of this kind of argument
for our purposes are there things about us that the physical list
i can not explained
either mysteries or puzzles about people
the physical is just draws a blank
but if we become do this
we can explain these features
suppose there was a feature like that feature f
then we say look although we can't see the soul
we have reason to believe in the soul
because positing the existence of the soul helps us to explain the existence of feature
which we all agree we've got
suppose it was true that you couldn't explain love
from the physical is perspective but we all know that people do fall in love
but sold what allows to explain that will bloom we have an argument for the
existence of a soul would be an example of inference to the best explanation
now there are the
question of course is
now to give you an indication of
what that distribution actually me trying to that
because we have the additional problem
that that we can actually write down a function because the function has infinitely many
but let's just try to through look at what what value function has
at a certain set of x fourteen
and i'm going to look at instead of looking at the whole function
i just look at the function value at some particular choices of the vehicle i
have just now x n
locations and i want to know well
what about what the function value looked like at the next so both boldface x
now if not that
which has the function value at some particular locations
and now because of the marginalisation property
i can be
i can be so the the the
the distribution over the of the function was as infinite dimensional gaussians when i say
OK i'm only interested in in particular
subset of those variables
and i just marginalize out the one just integrate them out
not interested in those
and then by the by the marginalisation property i can get and i'll get a
finite dimensional
and actually get the gaussians which has the meaning of a
and the covariance matrix here
it's just the
the entries in the covariance matrix is just the
covariance function evaluated the arguments x i and x
those would be exactly the entries that you would be that you would need you
need to pick up
the entry that correspond to the
the variables that you're interested in
all right and then you you can simply
part the
the corresponding
the values of i've drawn
drawn values
from this joint girls distribution
the count joint concentration depends on
what x chose
and it depends on what the covariance function
this particular transaction have not drawn
but i have to like twenty point here
that i have twenty different input not
and i draw this single sample from the of the
variable which has twenty coordinates
and i just support
which corner i just put it as the function at the corresponding value x
you can sort of see that this has the same underlying structure here
and the underlying structure
reveals that there some
that it's reasonable to believe that this is actually a sample
from the distribution or
this is sample from a distribution functions then
the distribution of functions must right
i thought of hopefully made it possible to use that this this
o thing
define a distribution over functions in the second half problem
let's try and
there are different ways of
technical problems and notice the one thing that people have a problem with looking at
the smallest thing OK this function here but when the function come from
but because it's not it's not really
there is no explicit representation of the function
the question is what you would you repeatedly sample from this from the same x
right well you could do that here here's a couple examples of
very in nearby axis here i've only
only sample four four four different actors if do it joint sample
and you have the same x twice then you'll get the same for that value
because because because actually realizations of this underlying function
and since the function
it has to have a a unique value for
unique input later on when we apply this to noisy data
we can see how we can modify things
but you can have you know different realizations for the same point
OK but there
any other questions
yes because the process actually used for work for a lot of different enough from
context and there there
that's process can also define random walk this particular one that depends on what the
green function in this comment function actually needs to very smooth functions but all across
function that would lead to
the raw emotion vocab
i would also say that doesn't processes are often used in time series analysis where
the where the where index to the simple time
i'm not doing that here
OK my example
i also had time on the x axis but but it's not really time model
but the interesting thing here is that you you use the golf across the index
set got what are your input of your regression problem
and there's no there's no
necessarily no notion of time in here
OK so let's try to try to get a little bit closer to where where
the underlying function when it comes from to one thing that we can we can
try to two
we do is we can try to pull apart
this this the joint distribution by looking at variables one time
have done better
i look at the
the joint distribution that have ultimately going to be interested in the joint distribution of
a particular
a set of function values given the corresponding input factorize that
by simply writing it as the product of
terms where the first term is probably the first
given the corresponding input
times the second term which is the the probability of of the first of the
second variable
given the first one
and the corresponding input and so on so forth i always look at
so welcome to this session of our tutorial on reasoning for ontology engineering and usage
and we are continuing now so we have seen this morning
techniques so how reasoning can play a role in ontology design using different approaches top
down and bottom up design before so i started looking at how reasoning
plays a role in answering and accessing information to an ontology query answering
now we have
go on and analyse how techniques for moderate modularisation so how modularisation
you can play a role in ontology engineering
this is the first part of
the doctor that give the second part we look at
to explain the inference of how the user can get an understanding of what the
system is doing behind the scenes
and this is called is the third part of the story
and then the fourth part
we look into more detail
existing large amounts of information into the ontology but this is fully
so welcome
and this part of the tutorials hands-on on to some extent so if you want
to follow along this just remind
you can download this version approach to a and
installed on all you have to do is and they can run it a
this version is not publicly available it will be in the next release so if
you want to follow along comes on
and then if you've got any questions that crop up due to be quite nice
so i'm going to talk about modularisation and explanation
and to start going to have an introduction on modularisation by only
thank you
to be
in this
o thing
so the solution
the more
we all
the wrong
his home
all the rest
there are
let me know when k
and strangling myself
as we have
as i have claimed before this property of
i mean the following it is
on import so
we want
coverage is there to achieve the following goals
we want to impart every something from the external ontology that this ontology knows about
the topic
we are interested in in this topic is given by a set of terms whose
meaning we want to import
but again hopefully not the whole ontology
and so here is the
specification of what this means
on explicitly so we say that a module which is only simply a subset of
our external ontology so this you would be the module and
this module converts
this external ontology
a set of specified terms we are interested in if the following holds
for any two class expressions CND that i can build
over these terms
not only for any two class names but for any two class expressions that i
can build over these terms
if i would impart into
and then have the entailment that c is subclass of d
then i already
that's the type of
this theory must be in e
so if i import the whole ontology
and this would result in the entailment that c is subclass of d then
imparting the module gives me the same entailment
i'm tempted to correct so please note this here is the
the whole ontology yes please
coverage has something to do with preserving entailments or not losing entailment
and coverage means that you don't notice whether you import the whole ontology or
whether you import only
the little
hopefully little modules
thank you very much
that we have provided you with
so no difference apart from hopefully the fact that the reason there or any other
two will be fun to run it because the the result is and hopefully smaller
this clear
so now obviously
the little question
how can we guarantee coverage
how do we
make sure
then the module we can compute
guaranteed coverage
so in general the bad news is that we can't this is highly undecidable problem
it has been looked into
a while ago
it involves something which is called
conservative extensions and logic which is the term which has been looked into the index
if you take a one atmosphere dry air
at room temperature
then the
the electron on average
on average
we'll have to travel about one micron
which is
due to minors
six meters
between the collisions with the molecules that just to give
on average sometimes a little more sometimes to the last to surrender process support
two ionize
ionised oxygen takes energy
ionised oxygen
next twelve and a half
electoral votes
and two ionized nitrogen
takes about
fifty one electron volt
electoral vol
fifteen minutes the amount of energy
it's one point six times ten to d
minus nineteen jules
electron volt is actually a very nice
unit of energy
once you have an electron
and it moves over a potential difference of one volt
it changes in kinetic energy
that's the definition of an electron volt it gains one electron volt is the charge
of the electron
it is one point six times ten to the minus nineteen cool multiplied by one
and that gives you
energy one electron volt
and so
what it means then
let's assume that these numbers ten electronic four wheel you wanna back-of-the-envelope calculation
so we want the electron
to move over potential difference delta b
which is roughly ten holds
and we wanted to do that
o over a distance delta x
which is ten to the minus six means that you one micron
and if that happens
you get this
enough kinetic energy an electron cause
so one electric field is required for that
that built the potential difference
dividing by delta x
so that is
divided by ten to the minus six
so that's about ten to seven called
that's a very strong electric field
in reality when we measure the
electric fields near breakdown
it is more like
three million volt meter but it's still very close to it was only a back-of-the-envelope
so very roughly at
one atmosphere and when temperature when the air is dry
we get electric breakdown at about three million volts per meter
but the ions neutralize you see light white parts can be seen
the here
they produce little pressure wave
so we can also hear noise
if you had two parallel plates
and you will bring those plates
closely together and suppose they had the potential difference of three hundred volts
then you would reach an electric field of three million volts per meter
when the distance the
is about one tenth of a millimeter
so that's when you expect something he was discharged between these two plates
in practice however
it probably will happen
when the
plates are further apart than one one-tenth
of a
millimetre and the reason for that is
that there is no such thing as a perfect place
the plates have imperfections
that means they always areas on the plate which are not flat
a little bit like you see there
small radius
and that's of course where electric field and will be larger
and that's where the discharge will occur first
if you touch the door knob and you get this park
rufus part and you look
at this park you see that when you three millimeters away from the dawn of
the spark
you can see
pretty sure that the potential difference to be you in the door of the order
of ten thousand several thousand volts at least
over three millimeters
requires ten thousand poles get three million volts
i mean
when you come you here
when you take your shirt off
you get little spark you can hear them start you can see them
and you can be sure
that the sharp ends of this here
the fabric that you have developed electric fields of the order of three million volt
meter and then you get the
of course high voltage
alone doesn't necessarily
kill you
what what what matters is
not so much the voltage
get killed but it's
the current go through you
and current
these charts
unit time
so in as units
he calls per second
which we write the capital a
which stands for and here
the man with a tremendous amount
of research
in these areas friends
and so if you touch the doorknob
instantaneous currents may actually be quite high maybe
and nnp even but it may only last for one millisecond
and so
that's not going to
well known and when you come your hair
but you don't die also know that when you take your shirt off w sparks
that's not
maybe in the future lecture we can discuss in some more detail what it does
take to actually
execute someone electrically which is very unpleasant nevertheless
we would have to evaluate how long the current should last a strong the current
should be and then also
during which parts of the body
the current will cause
legal reactions
so i want to be a little bit more qualitative now
deepen our knowledge of the then the graph
slowly we're going to understand how the pentagram works
and today
i want to calculate with you
how much charge we can put on the then
about the maximum potential is at the surface
if we charge the vendor graph
with charge q
the potential
of the surface is an equipotential
is q
five by four quite
absolutely zero are
and the electric field right here at the surface
query q
divided by four
humans who are square
so in this case of spherical symmetry
we have that the potential v
he called the kinds art
but we know that economics is three million volts per meter
so that gives you know the on the potential that we can give
then the graph
so if you substitute in here
the million volt meter
you can calculate what potential you can maximally reach
for a given sphere
with the given radius
and if we have the radius
and we have the voltage
and if the radius of the sphere
or three millimeters
you could not exceed a voltage of ten can
you did you get this
automatic electric breakdown you get this sparql
if you have here
one of three centimetres
that would be hundred chemicals
and then the graph
which has a radius of thirty centimetres
it would therefore be
one million calls you could not exceed that in practice in fact this one doesn't
even make it to one million volts
the sphere is not perfect
it is the first actually historically the first one from one parent
it says that if you take two different algorithms
and if you take
all possible problems
which means all possible data distributions
so to speak about all possible data distribution in these cases he's looking at to
set who has at at finite domains so the input space is a finite set
and you are looking at the
finite output space as well so binary classification for example where your input is finite
so it's a bit restrictive but in that case
you can show that if you take the average of the sum over all possible
one of the loss that you obtain
on future instances
so on the instances that you have not used for training only the best instances
and you have to ensure that they are different from the training instances if you
do that
it will be the same quantity no matter which algorithm you consider so all categories
will on average behaving in the same way
or put another way
if an algorithm is good on some problem it will be bad on another problem
or if it's better than
so if
if you take as a reference here a stupid algorithm that always predict in the
same way if you have an algorithm which is better than this on some problem
that in then it will be worse than it on some of the problem
in a way
it means that you cannot say my algorithm is better than some other algorithm you
can only say
what my algorithm does or the prior implemented by my reason
but my algorithm is better in the specific class of problems for example
OK so that that's very important because in the way it tells that's
what we naturally would be
tempted to sing which is OK this algorithm support vector machines are better than neural
networks for example this has no meaning
you cannot even
give mathematical content to this sentence
so you can only see as are better than new networks for this kind of
and this kind of problem has to be is kind of limited class of problems
anyway so it's kind of trivial this serum if you if just think about it
the what it says essentially is that if you have no assumptions so if you
allow all possible distributions
then of course
there can be distribution like if if you observe the value
of the function at certain points
and you are asked the value of the function at that point
why should they be related in any way
because there can be
distributions for which
these are related but there can be the solution for which they are not related
if you
if you have a certain way of extrapolating from
the training instances to the best instances
then you can
take the
the the probability distribution that assigns exactly the opposite labels to years test intensive and
very large error for you i was in so you can always
kind of inverts the labels of the future instances
manages the you know we
one way to
go around this is to to introduce the
i idea assumptions
as i said before so you assume that your data is
i generated independently from some unknown but fixed distribution
and this already implies that there will be a relationship between what you observed and
what you may observing in the future right because they are sampled from the same
maybe ask this
you have think editing the slide but i i just want to get to the
point before the end of the this lecture
the good news is that and the other IID assumption because there is the relationship
between what you observe and what you will observe in the future
the term
so the term is either variable
a function symbol
i'll leave off the subscripts and superscripts for readability
followed by might as well parentheses them
the prime number to function symbol
where these things are terms
in virtue of this definition is recursive definition of what term
we allow the case and equals zero
in which case
f doesn't need any arguments in order to pick something out in that case f
is just nine
carol constant is sometimes called
just picks out the thing it refers to without needing any arguments
we also allow
unitary binary and true function
so all the
term so we can name things
we have predicate symbols
for which i use upper case
letter f
and again
for every
arity and we have
predicates or sometimes called relation symbols
with that number of arguments
the syntax here is that in the an argument places this predicate you plug the
and you get
atomic formula
an atomic formula atom
predicate symbol
followed by
my friend the size or not and whether i want to disambiguate
the right number of terms
from here
we build up compounds in the usual way
by throwing in these
hidden on the board underneath
and or not
error going both ways
if we want
boolean operations and we can throw in x or in any of those
i don't take
take this to be primitive
maybe i want a
with the expected syntactic condition that
these are all binary except for the negation
you plug in the appropriate number four million you get a formula
will also throw in true and false
OK these are
harry connectives
this this
false the
german does subsort
that's bad guy
the that than which nothing silly can be can deviate
constant false proposition
sometimes identified with a and AT
assertion like zero equals one
something like that
it turns out to be technically useful
and quantifiers
where x
the nine it's subscript is variable
and a is a formula
for all i say
and for some x a
so this a direct route to quantify for each variable
and occurrences of the variable
in the qualifier
or in a is said to be bound by this quantifier
if x occurs free that is not bound by any other qualifier in here and
it gets bound by this one
similarly here
otherwise if there's no quantifiers
in whose scope
x is x is said to be free so
if we take an atomic formula like
the variable x is free
if we binding by quantifier for all x fx
then in this
variable becomes bound
and if we take that formula
then in this whole formula
and this 1 comes up very of this is the way and doping of semiconductors
and comes up so often that but it's convenient to define another another function where
in many instances seen equals 0 right over doping pure silicon the initial concentration boron
or phosphorus and pure silicon is going to be 0 so for many of those
so for many of those cases you'll end up with something that go through the
math this is a 0 transposed you'll end up with this is the solution C
equals C S times the complementary error function birth complement over 2 routes of the
where the complementary error function
the complement of the z is simply one minus 1st so if you see that
the literature it's over all they're doing so another question as I told you that
the special conditions that validate the error function solutions what are the conditions when went
to use 20 user because that's not the only solution to fix 2nd where
these other conditions see of x at time 0 is a constant so this is
boundary condition number 1
boundary condition number 1 we throw away sometimes data so here's data at time equals
0 the initial condition this is called the initial condition initial conditions must be a
constant and that's OK there are many systems for which the initial value of the
material that's being diffuse is constant throughout the material as opposed to block on all
over the place or maybe already having some kind of gradient as long as you
can make this assumption you're on the road now we need to boundary conditions the
boundary conditions 2 and 3 over here because we got a double derivative right you
have some function plus constant when you do the by dx constant goes in the
trash bin we need to recover that information somehow so here's what I've got got
C for x equals 0 at all times is a constant the surface concentrations fixed
is a constant in
they resembled what else could it be like to have a slowly rising surface concentration
or I can have a surface concentration very ideas soil yourself those will work it
must be fixed at a constant value so that's 1 so this is boundary condition
this boundary condition number 1 this is the boundary condition boundary condition number 2 and
then I need the 3rd 1 and the 3rd again is this 1 I would
give you that looks funny moderator mathematically but you'll you'll understand what I mean and
standard of and infinity the concentration doesn't change will die but this really has to
this really has some meaning we know that are we know that the size of
of our own piece is not infinite but here's what we're assuming were assuming that
over the time scale of the process that for all intents and purposes the dimension
of the silicon wafer for example is so large in comparison to the depth of
the diffusion profile that assuming assuming that the wafer is semi infinite because we got
diffusing from both sides right let's just assume from 1 side that we can assume
that it's infinite because ultimately what happens if we wait long enough we start to
have a tail over here
because the system still thinks that the way exists but were saying no it's stops
but this value is so small during the time scale of the
process that we can neglected and by allowing ourselves to assume that the material is
semi infinite it simplifies the math if we have a finite sized piece
finite-size specimens we can use the simplified solution things get very very messy but there's
another way of expressing there's another way of expressing it you see this relationship it's
always birth x over 2 times the square root of the t look at something
would be infinite would mean it was it's very large
large dimensional it's a large length scale
large lengthscale
but that's a large physical dimensions
so that means the argument of this is very very large but there's another way
to get the same result
short timescale
so that means that every diffusion experiment initially is operating in a material that for
all intents and purposes is infinite because when 1st philosophers and start diffusing into the
silicon they don't know the silicon is only a millimetre stars they're concern infinitely thick
this solution is valid everywhere so as long as you've got concentration initial was Effect
concentration surface effects at short and the short time solutions valid
valid over short so that means it's got great utility great utility and now I
wanna show you something that takes everything we've learned and crashes into a simple rule
of thumb rule of thumb but these are the kinds of of rules that I
hope you'll retain long after wasn't afraid considered education is what remains when you've forgotten
all your schooling so this is what you remember
you see got C 1 and C F over see not going to and that's
equal to 1 over here over for effects over 2 routes and the travesti accurate
solutions so if I wanted to capture the whole diffusion process in 1 tiny little
what would be an average value this is the normalized ratio a goes from 0
1 so what's an average value between 0 and 1 5 public ahead
so suppose I just choose this as an average value for the whole diffusion process
everything you could ever happen diffusion
all I have is less than point 6 since a half is less than point
6 can approximate birth x over 2 routes of DT is simply access over 2
routes of DT so now I've got this equals sort cancelled the toulouse across multiplying
and that gives me x process to roots of unity as an overarching equation for
everything that happens in short-term diffusion
short-term diffusion I can't tell you how many times I didn't situations where I some
conference from a bunch of people sitting around trying to figure out what to do
in some ways get ready to do some you finite element calculations mathematically model this
whole process and I said that go she 1 over lengthscales on the order of
what we do what we do well let's do well let's put it let's put
the rest that with given told this thing about cathedral windows why the glass at
the bottom of the cathedral window is is thicker than it is at the top
and it has to do with the fact glasses is really a viscous liquid and
and over 500 years it trickles and it gets wider
it's not
I can show you very and we already know
that you know the average the average temperature cathedral in northern Europe 0 when story
agrees with summer let's pick at number 10 degrees C
right so 10 degrees C we think the diffusion coefficient of silicate glass at 10
subject there used to be an expression for this used to be called the british
museum algorithm the idea being that the british museum has these vast collections of things
most of them out of sight
right so so
so you just you another way to look at it is the notion of the
notion of putting a hundred monkeys two
to type
and if you wait to long time they're going to type all the works of
shakespeare while the amount of time is going to be very very large
but eventually the title of the works of shakespeare or the
you know all the italian with the literature you know the type everything all possible
sequences of
of letters
but but you have to be very very patient
so this is a similar idea i'm running through all possible sequences of characters you
know all possible text of approved
but the number of possible attacks of of proof of any given size is finite
may grow exponentially large
but in theory i could go through and systematically
looking at all the possible proofs and and getting all the consequences OK so i
think of the mathematical theory is formal mathematical the you know going back to euclid
this idea
but the model imprecise version of a formal theory mathematical using symbolic logic and finally
vaccines i think of it is just a computer program
the the producers the theorems it's the computation which never and which is the calculating
theorems mechanically
OK so i don't care what's going on inside
this computer program
in other words
i'm taking i'm flying at very high altitude you know in a jet plane very
high up and i don't really care familiar mathematical theories the black box formal theory
i don't really care what's going on inside the only thing that's important for me
is that it's a computer there's a computer programme which calculates one by one all
the theorems this program is very slow it goes on forever
but it does give you all the theorems and that's all that counts OK so
the next crucial thing
from this point of view you won't be surprised to here is to look at
the size in bits of this program
how big is it
so let's look at how many but this program has how much algorithmic information there
is in this mathematical theory now
in intuitive terms i would say that this is equivalent to sort of the complexity
of the axioms it's the number of bits of axioms really way
of your theory is how to think about that
but the technical formal definition is it's the number of
it's the size in bits of the computer program that produces all the theorems by
running through all possible programs
OK so
this will give us for any mathematical theory and what is an example of the
mathematical theory one good example is the mental frankel set for example
another example this panel arithmetic since
we're in italy
a piano was from the other end right from torino
separate panel
and he had a a formal mathematical theory for zero one two three four five
in addition multiplication is called arithmetic but there's a more general mathematical theory formal theory
which is called the zona franca set theory is an axiomatic version of set theory
people believe that most of contemporary mathematics can actually be formalised within that theory called
tomorrow frankel set theory there are questions like you will have trace or not
normally you do
and OK
so those are exactly examples of formal mathematical theories
in in fact there are no developed to develop modern symbolic logic
OK so let's say
let's say that i have so let me state my result now i have a
formal mathematical theory
which has a certain number of bits of axioms
you know i want to know what is the number n bits i want to
know what it is what is m
and that's the number of bits of axioms i have
in but but it more precisely it's exactly the size in bits of the computer
program that runs through the tree of all possible process
and outputs all the theorems all the
the consequences of the axioms OK
so i want to use this
from formal mathematical theory to prove the programs are elegant
this is the
this is the goal
if you do this carefully you i have to tell you what is my programming
language which i haven't bothered to say so we're just gonna skip
not get involved in the question
so let's forget about that but
but the idea is to use the formal mathematical theory that has a certain number
of bits of axioms
an attempt to use it to prove that the individual programmes are all other words
i want to exhibit examples i want to give individual examples of elegant programs
and i want to prove
but there are that there is no program that is more concise that produces the
same output OK
and they are an infinite number of programmes their own problems are arbitrarily large
with any number of bits but what if i want to
give you mathematical certainty prove that individual give you examples of individual programmes and prove
that a particular programme is elegant OK so the result the the could of the
metatheorem is essentially this
you know it and it's theory
to prove that the program is elegant
another way to put it is that any
fixed mathematical theory and normally they would take similar triangles that would be this theory
that theory has a certain number of bits of axioms and i don't know what
it is but i would guess that hundreds of thousands of that perhaps
the complexity of the mathematical theory is usually not very large because of the actions
are very complicated no one would believe in
you know
so i would argue that the complexity will not be that large
OK so
the one thing that we
where this
but how you go
from the triangulated graph
the junction tree
and the fact that the graph is strangulated
guarantees that you get a tree
if you don't have a triangulated graph
you can get them it's like this where you none the wiser from before
yes you can run loopy belief propagation on that these but
so what
now i haven't actually told you it
i can perform any inference in this case it
so if you remember
what we have before is we said well you some out all the variables
but the one
on which this snow depends on
many interesting the message on
and the game but you some out all the virus but we want to send
the message to
and you pass it on
now what could we do in this case
well let's just look at
this node one two three
if i want to send a message to the two three five
well all the functions here depend on the variables x one x two and x
and this one depends on two three and five
now this means that can somehow terrible one
may get
something that's slightly smaller than what they had here
and now only need to send out the message
which is as large
as well
if we had only binary random variables here two to the size of the separator
so what have to say not seen through four numbers
in order to send the message here
now i can do the same thing here
basic can eliminate the variable
from the graph
from this message
if they want to send on the message over there
well what happens
i did
i've got my potential function here which depends on the variables two three and five
i've got something here which depends on the road two in three
here on the variables three and five
i take the product question is which verbs can eliminate
they want to send the message over here
everything but the five
it means i can eliminate the two in the three
missing out the message which only depends on the value of the y
and then this note you can do the rest of the summation by just taking
this message was only depends on five
in take care of what they were six and seven to
now let's look at what this means for the rest of the models
he was verified this kind of
crucial role in here
because if i knew that one the rest of the graph with the decompose
so this is very
pivotal place
to help
and actually corresponds to a message which only depends on the value of the variable
he goes on the way
now the same parallelisation properties as as what they had before
to apply to this case
i could do things locally per node if as i had the tree
if i pretend that they have
that actually every clique as node
i can also again do everything locally
it's just that now
instead of having a node
click on which i need to do is the summation
in addition to that it also means that
i can't really some
through all the variables anymore but they may have to carry some forward
so for instance the variable five course in this clique
its influence is propagated through here
and then ported onto here
that makes a lot of sense because
these variables you depend on the value of y
sure enough
they typically this dependency needs to be preserved when i look at the play
two three five
about twenty minutes before from it
and of course it will also have a bearing on what level six and seven
so that's pretty closely related
so that's why i have to propagate the value of this variable
and its influence through the entire graph
and this also explains why
in some cases i can get rather nasty structures and they're going triangulated graph
one of the most horrible
situations is the following
this case triangulating it
well actually producer rather
pins object
so that means i have to transport a fairly big message through the entire graph
in this case
the top of
exact inference fails
so what you could do is something hacky
you could well below a little bit of a junction tree which might lead to
and and then do loopy belief propagation that
or what is actually much better
use certain sampling techniques
for instance the nice summit
sampling algorithm
those guys
you and one
so i think from nineteen ninety four when they talk about trouble acolytes estimators
the more recent description of that in the paper by
hunt and if writers
and that would have been UAI
two thousand and
use this page to look at the picture and get the reference
don't try to understand the as in it
it's worked but the idea is quite simple
if that's just go back for a few slides in order to explain
what's going on
OK i see
what is
by the summer school interactions that i did so you know
in the patient
it will be possible
and this
this is one of them i will always
before i start let me just get show as i mean if you are interested
in reinforcement i think of reinforcement learning just curious about possible
OK so he said that the the crash was
OK so as the missing at university of michigan point
material here perspectives here more perspective
the material
o special thanks to many many people in particular it's been great colleague and mentor
for many many years and and you'll see
his hand if you like indirectly in the much what i'll talk about
the course a lot of colleagues audience here are some of the ones that have
collaborated with or been influenced by fairly closely and i've been working in reinforcement learning
for about fifteen years now and i started my phd at the university of massachusetts
amherst with andy barker can both which sutton and i did phd with their about
maybe five people in the world in reinforcement learning when i started and finished about
ninety three now of course there are thousands of people
i think
all around the world in this area of research and so
i started fairly early on in the reinforcement learning days in
this area so
you get a perspective that somewhat different
on reinforcement learning then you get from some of my more recent colleagues in this
in this area so that the plus and minus but just be aware that you're
getting a particular perspective particular slice from someone who
has been in the field for
for a fairly long time so has has has a long view of these things
this the specific slides i'm going to talk about today are on this website as
well i know that you probably have them in your hand out just like values
and on head
OK so
i don't if you're trying to look for it will not find them but these
are available then the on the fly they use tomorrow also be available on some
website and
maybe even printed out
try and i apologize for not being my body max together giving them to dog
in time so that any blame for this is on on my shoulders and not
only the organizes so that you know where
who complain about say is an outline of the talk i'm going to begin by
giving you history in place of reinforcement learning just sort of the context based in
context of artificial intelligence and machine learning brought their the research that influence reinforcement learning
and then i'm fairly quickly dive into the the dominant
so the framework the most productive framework of reinforcement learning is used which is that
of markov decision processes and then once described that framework and we talk about planning
in mdps learning in mdps function approximation reinforcement and low reinforcement learning and outdoor that
i'm not talk very much about partially observable markov decision processes because michael littman to
talk about that when he comes next you but i'll i'll touch pressure on stuff
and then tomorrow i'll go
beyond mdps and pomdps and pompey's being partially observable markov decision processes and and perhaps
today and some tomorrow talk about some applications of forced that sort of the plan
i should say that this is a small enough group let's try to make this
as interactive as possible so feel free to ask me questions at any time
you want cry just let's try to make it as as possible OK so here's
obligatory sort of
very high level view of reinforcement learning so this is the thirty thousand ft view
of the reinforcement learning problem what's the reinforcement learning problem you have an agent of
some sort of interacting with some environment
the agent has sensors through to perceive
the environment
and then it takes action on the environment and has some sort of feedback or
or enforcement payoff all these terms are synonymous and the agent's task is to act
in the world so as to maximize some measure of reward it gets in the
right so that a very high level view is the reinforcement learning
of course
it's very abstract
at this level abstraction lots and lots of different problems can be formulated this when
i show examples of problems that can be formulated this way but
ran precise something out repeatedly do this to distinguish it from supervised and unsupervised learning
is that in some ways reinforcement learning is sort of the complete problems like
what's the complete problem it's really the problem of building agents that can interact successfully
in very rich environment
right so in that sense of course this is a
a large problems
a problem that that encompasses much of a i come to supervised and unsupervised learning
for example so certain things that distinguish reinforcement learning we complete agent it's temporally situated
that it's acting over time
is continually learning and planning its environment
and its object is to affect the environment right subjectivist affect environment and of course
we live statistical sort framework so the environment is stochastic and certain will
do things in a probabilistic in sort of stochastic sort of way
and you know one can argue of course about this but in some ways reinforcement
learning is like life right because what we are
just acting appearing in the world
so what you're doing sensing we're acting occasionally we get some sort of intrinsic or
extrinsic rewards and one could argue that
the agent's task our task is to choose actions so as to optimize toward or
i'd love to reinforcement learning problem very hard of here's another slice
of the reinforcement learning problem other way to view the reinforcement learning problem which is
that life for an agent is really a sequence of observations actions in towards the
subscript here denotes time is action always observation are reward
so here
they did is born the beginning of time
get an observation takes an action get toward option observation action for life sort of
proceeds linearly for like
along trajectory like this
and in any given point of time
given has history
of life