built and paranormal you set up a little just like before becoming an additional term
they just use some massif i'd actually all boils down to the addition to the
kernel parameter
but if there is an exercise you today
so selection right so
so the regression tasks of data classification including task what's the story when you have
a continuous valued output put OK i don't get bogged down in the details
because i just show you the story is very similar
now my function
doesn't have signed function is not classified by function
is continuous valued and is simply going to be w dot f x plus b
well i'm just going to say that regression
like with the sphere you try to minimize model w squares
did exactly for binary classification i have to tell there is now
because i have two times the training areas depending on which side of this functional
so if you like
i could be
documenting this or in commenting it sort of plaster
all stop there
added to this function here taking me away from the correct value i might one
point two here
and that's point one output
plus point one layer
what might be point three
o point four minus OK so two times areas
and that is accounted for
by these two types of articles slack variables very similar to the soft margin slack
variables and use are
now you just play through the mass OK
and what it all boils down to is i have a function which must minimize
which looks like the following this is very similar to the maximize the margin term
this is the to do the errors and system minimizing i want to minimize the
errors both ways domain name and this is the trade between these two
i just say if you start with that
you put in the constraints you have
which are indeed this things here these things here
if you like if this was zero
and this is zero then y i will be w w x plus
active function want to learn
and similarly with other time if it was zero and this is zero then i
have y equals wx speaking so in fact
if there is zero mean ECCV forcing this to equal y
now these two terms this is our you image possible about this epsilon
that is allow allowed
a bit errors
that typically got noise i don't want to have epsilon precisely zero because it only
fit to noise OK
so this is actually a equivalent to soft margin OK
but i don't have an enormous
number of errors
so these other areas
which i can have to take me away from my
the function quite functional mapping
i just want someone to
minimize that xi and so i have to
what all was down to is the objective function which have to do for regression
very similar
the the story for
what you'll notice previously alpha
now the square
one now it's the same sort of thing
linear in alpha and alpha had as a quadratic in alpha and alpha had so
it's convex top problem the quadratic problem just like before
one solution
and that makes it quite nice
one last point i should mention about this is that if you have encountered having
to solve the single one was the most of two user following don't define this
as alpha minus
and this is alpha plus and do the optimisation in terms of those we define
if it's a footballer
and it's about that
socrates is
is a footballer
as use it as in nine
and we can infer that soccer it is
is it like that
and we want some
to be able to
support and enable us to prove
the validity of inferences like that
and of course
many others
i'm going to say that of this again
OK so anybody wasn't bold yet
and i'm going to say a little bit more formal
so the
really good only so that we have a chance
being able to do so
mathematical proofs about this
there's a lot of nature that says anything you're of office what you want to
revert to next
so let's in nature
take this off
we have therefore
a formal language
in which we have variables
x one
x two
x three
and we take ourselves to have infinitely many of those
least there's always another one we can we can
is the
we have
for the two symbols
for which i use case
the function symbol has
some arity some disagee
some number of arguments places
zero or more
logic you get to use this wonderful for a zero more
nice so
if i in careful superscript
therefore with the number of arguments
for every
arity n
we have finitely many function symbols
of that
one f two f three
so we assume that we can
bill compounds these
in terms of that
we can construct
the things in the language the behave like names so
of the reflectivity function because it leads to sparse solutions plus a data fitting term
to be faithful to the data which it took also has an one penalty
a bit later centers and science suggested something very similar
where the proposed to minimize the l one norm of the reflectivity function as to
promote sparsity again but now the user defined by rise different data fitting term they
took the
l two distance
OK so that was happening in the in the mid eighties in geophysics and today
this minimisation
program this is very
well studied in statistics because it has been reintroduced in statistics as the lasso and
in signal processing as business process
which will talk about
OK since so lots of people were working in these things in the late seventies
early eighties and so what did
they find defined
that we want to put in l one norm
to quote centers and signed to effectively construct the solution with the least number of
nonzero components that is to recover sparse spike train and then we have this goodness
of fit criteria which you can take to be able to one depending on your
sensitivity to
all right so the empirical observation that these people did is that OK i have
been limited data
if i have been limited data
it is there missing out a lot of frequency components have don't have no use
in these the reflectivity function is actually sparse by train
then centers enzymes observed that the use of the minimum in one criterion produces under
many circumstances the correct solution
so this people's is committed geophysicist we're very happy because they could actually recovered
two reasons
some accuracy
the upper crust
of the year so by using
this kind of l one minimisation procedure from seismic
all right
now i'm going to move a little bit in time so now we can equate
geophysics and and signal processing and statistics were more recent uses of
in one norm have been you have been suggested in computational harmonic analysis under the
name of basis pursuit by chen donoho and saunders in nineteen six and statistics as
well as two by twos shaw nineteen ninety six and and what these things are
is there really is this kind of proposals except that has been exported in a
completely different context
i'm going to try to go quickly overseas
in computational harmonic analysis it to feel that is trying to
develop representations that are good at representing datasets for example images o o one needed
our three d data and so on
so it's an active field that aims to develop effective representation that is sparse representations
as this field has championed a lot of
interesting construction filters wavelets curvelets brush let's and so on and so forth and so
by the late nineties there was an emerging feeling that there is no universal representation
that is not possible
to find representation that is good for everything simultaneously in different representations are best four
different phenomena and then when i use the word best i mean that they lead
to sparse representations
for example
brush let's or sinusoids are very good at modelling oscillatory phenomena of course periodic phenomena
wavelets are very good for
representing scenes that are discontinuous around points curvelets are good for this representing things that
are discontinuous
long curves and so on and so forth locale cosines brush let's are good for
textures et cetera et cetera
so in the late nineties it was his view that we should try to combine
all this representation together to take
the advantage of the strengths of each representation
in paper in nineteen ninety three
my lines and proposed to kind of combined is these representations so let's say we
have basis that i'm going to call phi
so we have the first basis phi one we have the second fight to the search three
so for example this could be for users could be wavelengths could be currents could
be for and so on
and so now what they propose is now we're going to be we're going to
build a building dictionary by concatenating all these bases
by having all these representations together so we're going to create a uge data matrix
whose columns are the basis functions and because i have lots of basis have much
more columns and rows i want to create a uge
whose columns are basis functions phi i but because i have several representations
i'm going to have much more columns than world
OK because i have all good representation that are all good for different phenomena
the representation is not unique any more
so i can express any images signal is the superposition of basis functions but this
representation is not unique any more
or in it using notation from linear algebra i will just write is as ethical
site times of
five concerns for
the treatment
my estimate goes down
and even if some of those
estimate the
inputs to the treatment a redundant should be that useful but this is still a
better estimate if some of them are useful so what's happened here is that there
a lot
what be deducing from this is the
the first model
this model
which is what this one the state is about
this table
is that models
this table is about the model that
it was three pages but also
so so this is the one that's got the treatment
so this is saying
if this was the right models
when i go from this one to this one because
my estimate of sigma squared is changing from twenty three point nine thousand nine and
a half or not quite six
that's changed quite a lot of good and also indicating
this model here of that one
the sometimes missing from it because
this estimate is too high
because it was so easy for the inputs missing from the model
this estimate was too high relative to the square if i on the other hand
i mean this model i i would really think that if i've included so for
every single treatment
probably nice to get all the possible inputs i could have that
it is an estimate of were so look at least
this is telling me that i might put too many turns into model
but this should still be these estimates sigma square because that's what it said on
the slide before so if
if you have concerns in but i've got all the ones that can
s what is still the rest the square
so this making here is that by adding all those inputs
that i am actually going to
i might include some redundant all of the ones that should be there going to
be in there so
so my assumption is that this number
is that good estimates the square so that the rest
six were not point six
listen is it not not very good estimates work
so it's too high
i mean
the situation
so what does not include one or more inputs that it ought to so then
minus r-squared also square is too big
because it should be
OK so that that's the trick so looking at this kind of formal mechanism for
working out probabilistically how big they should be how big that should be sold
basically it boils down to this but
this holds this role here is measuring the difference between
was the robot treatment is measuring the difference between having just watson having terms what
some treatments so it's one of the treatment
effects treatment input
like this one
i'm not going to get into exactly where that number and so when the number
comes from but you're aware of the was come from all the supplies comes out
this last number here this is what we get that is this
we have a number of the same
the concept was that got to hold of is this
i can look at that and say
well that's not quite six months twenty three point nine to twenty four hours big
o point six i can say that
i'm no acceptable well how do i know that that's not just fly
i don't really
what's this number here
he says if the
what's the chance
of getting
the difference this difference twenty twenty three verses point six
what's the probability that happening
treatment inputs make no difference was the chance of getting a difference five field please
feel something fluctuations well it's not very likely is what it says
so it is unlikely that
this difference
is just random chance
then it's likely that was caused by including the inputs
that's the that's the reason is going on here
basically what you
that's the idea operationally what you do is this you go
right there is a row in this table about treatment
it is what what's called the p value the probability is less than five percent
is less than point zero five it's just the case which is the
then the to ready the model
are important
but puzzling so the mechanism for doing this with the basic
but this is that less than five percent of it is
so what if i said so
it was done
other so saying simply
but it seems like the difference where we might want someone to
well advantage
if you remember the treatments were made up of
so so variety was so in data and there was a density
so we might then go on to say if we think there's the difference caused
by the different treatments
what aspects of the treatments causing the the differences
this is
a table where we
basically it's an expanded version
of this
this this treatment there
o thing to it's to do with sowing data
so intensity on topics
so that's what i'm not
and basically
but the variety is
you start off with a
the plot terms and so starting off with the same basic model
what is this model
we've included inputs
is that
show here
and what does effectively is a in
OK b
in my opinion the difficulties of establishing a hilbert space
in practice many issues one has to make this into a finite approximation
one divided by problems
and also
this is positive and negative eigenvalues shown
down there
and in one of
bounds with particular i values support from negative to estimate the fact that this by
this is what i show you this what you will discover
symmetries of shapes information that is extensive that it is it is
the problem with this method
for symmetry in general you may not have
full data
you have to
and when they come from scotland it is often vital
so i think
hands up for having a complete fault we can compute decided that
not always applicable so we've got to look
what the it
following sections ideas namely that can diffusion point on the surface
one thing of placing a little
china p element the point ninety four
see how these diffuses the future of our time
characterizes somehow
one about the behaviour of point for example point of positive curvature diffuses slowly point
negative curvature diffuses faster
and this is here
diffusion script
it is for
the corresponding told of the drug
and the interesting thing is
after a short time
four four look the same could in fact or four legs look the the same
the future
question two
the large areas of the drug and then you can distinguish the back legs from
the front legs because the diffusion behave differently in the front leg area then the
battle against integer with
and of course from the graphical view interesting topic is to take a shape that's
semantic would like
the same applies to make it more human
it's interesting to the coupled optimisation problem because the four behaviours he
while expressing your objective you want opinion formation space basically what to make the clusters
have both now in the last show here an example of the these are the
i symmetrizing by
making clusters in
OK so i the
the space
in writing the article
the flow
the common theme of his work and what could come in the introduction of the
first places to express
this relation of the object so that a lot of structure discovery and also of
the operations dual happening by understanding the coupling between the three geometry
and what's going on in this task force space
you see you like got it all in the attractor
on the right
so the
the show you how
it's possible to capture
partial approximate any particular shape bias in mechanism
and that this is actually
i efficient discovery documentary
now about the problem
so the problem of what don't have all the data in the same place in
somehow still
discover the abstraction
so you have partial does not have you know what should have a clear
large common area
they want to compute only certain very compact footprints from the scales in the comparing
the fingerprints
i want to discover simulated
thank you for complete shapes using
come back to it
but classical problem the problem here is this is about looking back and looking forward
much the like i don't know much about how much
the point is the signature fingerprint compact
the independent and they have two shapes to compare
his fingerprints to compare the shape
and actually the idea here is an idea adopted from the domain
or duplicate web page
so how does it work
and you actually
break it up into
just a subset of points they can neighborhoods around this point
because of the large this it
and simply fission each objective it into the bag of back
i forget about the object
just like the fact
the question is if you want something
i mean have to have something they symmetrically
so what you have actually we can pull out it's possible to recover the object
by in the fact that this is very much how DNA structure
or you could happen but all
put them together
and no
what we do is we take this back to the conventional
compute descriptor
very much like about
again this
this overlapping
the space in the use of guns is large compared to ten times
this space examples
and so one this by taking all this it's good for every single
we map of shape
and the point cloud high dimensional space
the majority of this
so somehow now measuring similarity of shape
becomes given this kind of the point clouds how many points they should recall how
many of which have other
so compared is actually two bags of points
how space
it very classical music
they can be made it
the distance metric
so what line
and is it and there is an object or the subject or the verb of
the sentence so you can put everything here if you know how to use it
how to use this information
you can extract included into during the innovation
here in the in know our
OK so
we know
we can extract extract everything from the
basically we can stop all development because they have enough for search engine so what
we can do they can take polymerization
it is structure of our from documents
you can have a career
we can come compare this query to what we extracted
and simply return this result when you have image
and this
simply naive can't simply scanned the document
and i think the
you can say that it's not gordon brown but that but i can
object is very good friends
first of all
you have reason for knowledge
you know all the words from the document because this
constructed and there
what's in your
and one that is doing so much
so you can you can do very complex algorithm
you know it's very
good for the current hardware architecture
because you using only linear acts as the euro was one thing
all document by small plod through all infrastructure search engine
the last can be very easily parallelized
imagine that
we have
if you wish
library in alexandria in
two thousand years ago
and are going to
four of
and they don't have index on this particular work what they're going to do
the highlight of people who are literate and the reason this is
navy common one percent but otherwise
and it's much harder than for humans because humans good in reading but very
but in
jumping from one place to another
the good approach and sometimes you can use
because it is doing and if you have a small collection of have collection that
change so frequently
that building index is is not
think simply does doesn't have any sense for this collection because when we already have
in the have already new collection
maybe and in this collection is not so b
maybe it's better to than i can have pretty fast hardware
then to implement some something
but we are going to be faster and we are going to add even
and here unfortunately i want to say
my example this library and librarians doesn't work
librarian point-of-view
in the this is what we are
we are usually called taxonomy
because they extract the most important words from documents and they put this model into
some classes and the things that you
and seen in libraries the index
and for as for developers of computer programs
in the simplest
as special structure
the accelerate data access
it's not
some something that was created by human it's not connected to document it simply
some things that
to improve the speed of our application
and again i really
had such cases when i talk to librarians
and so that's what this system can implement
indexing this church
and she said no way
the can do it because indexing is a very complex task and you need to
understand about documents
is different but the difference in terminology is not different than what they actually are
because librarians indexes on also
sometimes physical structures drivers and car
that accelerates search
so now we are talking about
i recently has graduated
the question is how to accelerate church
and the usual answer is
OK have a special tool for storing
a lot of information charge this is databases and we have a lot of that
basis starting from
like a skylight like something small
and ending two such more of or
take from the shelf one of the
a very powerful tool
and use it as our search engine and we can do it and there is
nothing wrong
this is a construction we have
because we we assume that
i'm going to church and we are putting some set of words and want to
get all documents that
contains this work
we create the structure of the database
so we have a dictionary
you have
description of our documents
and you have ideas for them for normalisation and we have the main table
well being
put together formed
flags field
playstation the document
i'm not very good
database programmer
therefore in this structure is one
one you
every every specialist in relational databases so that it's not it's not right
what you don't like
i think that this is
if you because it
one to many and we need additional addiction
OK but
doesn't so
if are doing our simple search
this is selected for this not
and and everything is OK with this that
except for one small thing
if you are going to implement this
and if you are going to in this in this structure
war and peace by leo tolstoy
even if you're using or
you will be surprised
pretty law
and i will said OK i'm smart guy i read books about information retrieval
and it's not true because the information to your system
and then this lasky that i would like to solve
what are the same circle
but now
now now
the sources on the boundary like there
well that's the circle despite its
and inside
no sources
well the sources on the boundaries on this in this case i'm solving you plastic
qxx was you why
o zero
inside but now on the boundary
you is the delta function is that the boundary
you here
you on the boundary
is delta
so you see that i'm creating a sort of very special
problems and the reason is
as of a show in the next lecture
if i can solve problems with
with delta functions
either inside or on the boundary then i could solve them with
other things i could combine the answers calls are called the green's function as the
green's function for the source at the origin the answer here you will be the
green's function on a circle
for the source
inside point the solution new here once i find it is going to be the
green's function
for this problem on a circle
with the delta function at
the boundary
there are special problems but if we solve those we can use them to solve
a much more general problems because i can take any sources like some combination of
sources at different points
or any boundary conditions would be like some combination of delta's different boundary point
so those are the three
problems and the first one is all
that's where we stand now and now i would like to be able to solve
the other two
and then you would see sort of some of the key points of how to
deal with all possible great
the more much more could be said but the thing
this would give you the main points so let me
race this
and just write down some of the write down the answers
for those last two problems
OK and then
try to understand them let me take the last problem
you call delta
on the boundary
with the passing equation inside
i think the solution to that one is the solution
and this
consider it right
i think it's one minus are in polar
its natural we're dealing with circle so we better stay with four corners or one
class are square minus two are cos
i think that's the right guy
now i need to divide by two pi was these numbers
so how would we
and i actually will arrive at this answer using
fourier series
so let me know try to
anticipate that step of getting to this answer but just look at the answer
after we got it
can you see that satisfies the boundary condition in me reasonably so
so the boundary we're on the unit circle
why don't you come out zero at this point
is it's supposed to
because the sources
the delta function is there
because our is one
no problem
so all in all these other points are is one well why don't we get
a zero or
at that point
what's happening at that special points are is one but they do is
a zero at that point the denominator must be doing something to this point that
i think this is the zero of course
on this re
five i just look on this race they was there i can learn some stock
the state was zero i have one or two pi
one minus are square divided by what
let's see if fate is zero what's that
one was are squared minus two are
we just offline look at one plus one minus two are
because they are square and say what is that
it's one minus our times one minus stars
o five o one minus are times one minus are
and one of those all cancel out here
and give
one plus so it comes out quite nicely if i divided into that i'm left
with the one plus are
so i still have one of these guys below and out of one class are
above all that
that tells you
to science show it
how to decide to find out how what where
not science is shown
but this experiment for this effect as shown
right now
why do we quote fineman
because he's an expert
the literally
expert that the etymology of expertise it means someone who has done experiments
we called him because what he says makes sense
so logic is the fourth way of knowing things so the two ways that we
that we know things in chemistry or in science are experiment and logic and that
the lecture is a little bit more focused on logic layer is more focused on
experiment and you get an unbalanced view
if you do one without the other
OK so modern science got underway in the seventeenth century there's the seventeenth century sixteen
hundred seventeen
and sixteen thirty eight was when new haven
colony was founded
and seventeen one was when yale was founded so that's when everything got underway just
when this enterprise was beginning here
here we are
if you go back one hundred years you get to quantum
quantisation by plaque
and we'll talk about that
and if you go back another hundred years you get to love was the iron
and if you get another hundred years you get the new then gravitation and we'll
talk a little bit about that
and if you go back home or another hundred years you get hopper nickerson and
revolution other
heavenly bodies
and columbus and navigation
and luther and the reformation
and these things all have something in common
as robert hook road
in the seventeenth century his age was an age of all others the most inquisitive
all these things have to do with to do with people inquiring into how people
know things and finding out new things
and in particular an important figure was was francis bacon who were in his in-store
you may not know the inspiration so let's look at that here's francis bacon there's
years he
he was elizabethan and jacobean
he was almost exactly contemporary with shakespeare
and with galileo
he went to school
at the university of cambridge
and here's the cartoon
it shows a man
imagine to modern cartoon imagine in class
cambridge because he wrote of his tutors cambridge they were men of sharp wits
shut up in their cells of a few authors chiefly aristotle their dictator
all the philosophy of nature philosophy and that science in those days all the philosophy
of nature which has now received
it is either the philosophy of the regions
or that of the alchemists
the one is gathering
out of the few vulgar that means common of course observations
and the other out of the few experiments of the furnace
the one never failed to multiply words
and the other ever fail us
the multiplying gold
so here's the book he wrote the in-store asian that's the brothers piece for this
pictures from the binding library with them
that picture the book
notice that was published in sixty twenty what else happened
that's when the pilgrims came or
so the title of the book rather small under his name and the title was
lord chancellor of england is in store at model which means the great restoration
restoration of one of the way of knowing
this is the a bigger part of it is called the novum organon which is
then it develops the inductive scientific method based on experiment
to replace aristotelian deduction which is you may be did one experiment sometime in a
new reason everything from that
he says no you have to do more experiments now there's an interesting thing here
on the device on one of the devices on the title and this from piece
is two pillars
one of the world are they doing there
well the the same pillars
you see on this
that's a piece of a you know treasure island pieces of a
see it's a real is
and it came from the silver of mexico was minted in mexico city
and there you see the same pillars and on them says plus ultra
beyond what
what are the pillars
it's africa and spain
but it's
the pillars of hercules
which are the mouth of the mediterranean the old classical world
right so there is the mountain of moses in morocco and the mountain of tariq
which is the name of gibraltar
so here's the mediterranean the classical world of aristotle
and you can say out into the new world
and bring back silver for example
there's danger of course
but look at what it says at the bottom
what will be brought back
not just silver
multi paratransit want out gaby tour CNT
many will pass through
and knowledge will be increased
right so we go beyond aristotle and experimentally based science and knowledge will be increased
so here are some quotes from the instructs your model
that was the which we have derived principally from the greeks
no offense
it is a but like the boyhood of knowledge
and has the characteristic property of boys
it can talk
but it can not generate
it is but the device for exempting ignorance
from ignominy
that means it's a way of hiding your ignorance
and we'll see you can see examples of that will talk about in lecture eleven
about correlation energy
and we'll talk it lecture thirty two about strain energy
and you'll see that both of these are just words that are used to hide
our ignorance
the and which the science of mind proposes is the invention not of arguments
but of arts
ways of doing things
not so much by instruments
although new instruments report light microscopes and so on
as by experiments skillfully and artificially devised
for the express purpose of determining the point in question so artificial experiments designed to
decide the question
mean group
you picked up right
i was just
there are OK
so here we see a five membered ring created
so here's the thing is not free swing out in free space created a five
member group called the where the end of the site actually covalently linked to
and then also has implications for the structure of proteins because this particular amino acid
whenever it occurs within a polypeptide it doesn't have the flexibility of assuming certain configurations
and the other one was
those four citations are not so encumbered
none of them has total flexibility but this one is far more common in the
in the kind of three-dimensional structures that can assume
and with that in mind we begin to
questions about how
polypeptide chains soon three-dimensional structure
if we talk about polypeptide chain
in our minds
there's only
twenty combinations
i go to one of many
right so
look here and you see this is a typical polypeptide
here we have three thriller called true there's a single letter code which was introduced
around nineteen sixty five seventy
each of the twenty amino acids on single letter code
and to make friends
depressing admission
thirty five years forty years after the single amino acid code was instituted
i still have learn
but we can learn the three-letter code which fortunately
our presence here or in single article l is lucene and
these are is
alan is a
this is another example of not being able to teach old dogs
the tree and so
here we see
the late one way by which one might picked enemies of and keep the amino
acid chain polypeptides it keep in mind this can go on indefinitely
as we begin to wrestle with the three-dimensional structure of the chain we begin to
realise the full
and that is that the change is initially synthesized
initially chaotic and it extends increasingly begins to issue
a very specific
molecular three-dimensional molecular configuration which is indicated down here so the operate
will eventually result in a native configuration over here
which is in many respects often referred the lowest free energy state
since the last forty years people have been able to try to figure out if
you know the amino acid sequence of this primary polypeptide here if you know its
primary structure
when i say primary structure what i mean is the sequence of the amino acid
so if you know the primary structure and you should in principle
be able to develop a computer algorithm that would predict the three-dimensional configurations
which is shown university in that way
and which will discuss in much greater detail shortly
and the fact is
after forty years of trying one still is unable to do that
i mean if i were to give
these three the primary amino acid sequence of
polypeptide to the smartest biochemist in the world
there are some very smart ones
he or she could still not tell me what the three-dimensional structure of this protein
with us to certain it would be
why because there's
an almost infinite number of intramolecular interactions
that greatly complicates
how the protein structure
if we this information estimate the protein we can imagine that there's ways of disrupting
that because much of his native state is created by intramolecular hydrogen bond
remember the hyperbolic relatively weak
and if we need to be
the temperature
then we can break hydrogen bonds
and therefore every time
we we friday
for example we want to get down to earth
we within nature
we break the three-dimensional made the three-dimensional structure of albumin molecules that constitute life
so when everything turns white what we've done is taken a molecule like this
he up temperatures
the intramolecular bonds no longer applies notably higher and no longer stabilise three-dimensional configuration
and we put it into a a d nation-state
which might be all the way up here
and therefore
this acquisition of native configuration or native state
we represent the natural state
it is also reversible in many molecules simply by heating them up
there are to be sure you the molecules which are different from a quite from
the help human egg white working-class back down
well spontaneously we assume their native structure
many proteins most will not so
well how
OK let's go back to to the issue of the position of complex three-dimensional structure
and here we begin to see how
some of this
structures acquired stabilised
through these intramolecular hydrogen bond
and there are many opportunities for the intramolecular hydrogen bonds because here we see one
polypeptide chain here we see another
and we see
the NH group right here and so the nitrogen with
the proton side
and the carbonyl group here with the oxygen
are not encumber they are in principle available to form hydrogen bonds with polypeptide chain
somewhere else
now this other polypeptide chain could once again from another protein from another polypeptide
but more often than not were once again dealing with
but in this case the intramolecular crossings are not disulfide bonds are covalent or to
stabilize the iraq
in the absence of reducing agents here we're talking about much weaker bonds hydrogen bonds
which also
in between
different looks of the protein
and served once again to stabilise the three-dimensional structure of the native state proteins
you can see how the opportunities for for performing multiple hydrogen bonds to create an
enormous degree
of stability
and here are some examples of what we now call the secondary structure of the
i think this is the organisers for letting me to present this work we see
which is joined with michael jordan from UC berkeley kept concrete from the san diego
and as a nationally we from silicon valley
so my today
it's too
so that my go today's two
french you
recent class of techniques from machine learning
they only can methods and how they can be applied to computer vision
so we first have to show that many
vision tasks can be expressed as a machine learning problem
and i will present a kind of methods
essentially the opposite of that we show you how you can do kind of design
for simple vision experiment and then i will go quickly over links between economists methods
and sparsity inducing norms that have been talked about for the this morning
so i guess this is no surprise that there is more and more pictures the
world whether you are in the industry or in a research lab at home
and you can indicate millions of images of about of the pictures and from those
pictures you have a lot of tasks to be solved and we try to show
you in a few slides the next slides
it that each of them you should be given machine learning problem want to to
the task on images to imagine learning problem
and we all be of the same data images would be different different kind
the first one is image retrieval that we
what about in the previous talk
so he this is a sample of the query for good we are so
that's what new york and of good images and this is what you get
and they are all those images at the moment i created the system they were
retrieved only based on surrounding text OK and you can see that would get is
a diverse in terms of images we have pictures of new york
we have maps of new york city maps of the state of new york
you will have to be able to maybe go beyond the surrounding text and more
classification maybe i want to classify
real images from from pictures
you may also want to do outlier detection remove what's really not new york so
there's not so many of those that is the case for a new query paris
and then you can see maps of paris
you have to our right
maps of paris years again i think that this is a key players
and this is what this list is the task of
being able to look at the image it removes some of the players so these
could be an outlier detection problem
similarly you might want to do simple image annotation so you the bank of images
and want to annotate from the animals plain so all is
this is in fact my most changing to me is the set of personal photos
so i guess as baby get you take one megabyte
amounts for the first months in the indicates that of the like the babies but
don't get additional babies to go back to when you go back months and then
you get like many go back in your laptop on your new computer and you
want to organize that
it is organised by that time
you to be able to say all the pictures from kennedy
give me all the pictures on k two and all the pages and get three
so this is a change because of kids
OK to make it look like a lot so it's very hard to distinguish
so with
pictures photos
you have a lot of work to do in terms of working on images you
want to the classification can one can toolkits three wanted to to clustering
maybe discover new kid on the block
this something that some of these accusations
namely how i how can you look at this a few bytes of images
so what i presented is many
twenty task involved with images i want to classify them to them calling them in
some way
and all of those
are the common issues that work on images so the goal is not to deny
one image but to work on the images so immediately massive that data OK so
you have like millions of images which is an sense of millions of pixels so
you need to be careful what you do
the stats complex things that does not for example it's even hard for may hard
for humans and finally the data of very heterogeneous
even for images you have a lot of ways of looking at images you might
want to consider color texture shape and so on so even within one minute you
get a lot of heterogeneity
and of course if you want to consider all the images as well as well
as like text and in some you really have to be careful was also so
type of data so let me try to convince you of today that
kernel methods are well adapted to the task so every community it's all so my
q on
will be a positive definite kernel and we present in slides
before going to that
let me put into what machine learning about supervised machine learning you want to predict
we have some input x this this image
and why is your outputs that you want to predict let's say the identity of
the person in the image
o with basically know and most of machine learning and statistics and also some processing
is framed as an optimisation problem when you have an objective function which is the
sum of the that fitting term
jamaican data when you predict for exciting instead of why i'm so if is how
you predict from exile i
then you have the organisations are usually not so have two main issues in machine
learning which is which is hard to design a loss
for specific tasks of course what you know what the symbol whether you're trying to
clustering classification regression model that
the y
but then you have to decide which function space you want to consider how will
i predict from data
so it not just with into the first the of main two
mental tasks which is the regression classification
but you could design the for all possible
that described earlier
so far regression against everybody uses quite cast list
because between what you want to predict and your new output this is
very simple important for classification this i wanted to binary classification you want to predict
the labeling minus one one
of course if they belong to the space so how do you get from the
two the manifold wanted to sign
so you want to design a loss
which would be adapted to predicting the sign to be adapted to do the sign
of the of function of a function
so of course in the canal if only the sign this i disagree
because if you have the same sign you ought to get if you make a
lot of positive in the mail on sunday and you want to consider when you
y f one x have different signs so put away with the product by f
again has to do with parameter sharing
and the parameters of the mean time model can be trained that can be tuned using backpropagation algorithm
and the backdrop algorithm you know it's been it's been around for quite some time
so one question you might want to ask is is the you know top-down bottom-up
can we actually design algorithms that maybe have some kind of feedback connections
and is there more rigorous mathematical formulation
obviously a lot of these things are driven by empirical success and and yes there's
a lot of empirical success but the question is is there a little bit so
something more we can say about these models
so let me give you a little bit of introduction to graphical model just so
that we can get the notation right this as we go through the year
the rest of the tutorial
how many of you know about graphical models
what so so i can go i can go fairly quickly there
just primarily for setting up for setting up the notation forests
right so it's it's interesting if you look at the history of deep learning started with basically
looking at these models from graphical model perspective
right now there are a lot of different algorithms like sparse coding and auditing courses but
initial models were inspired by graphical models and doing inference and learning graphical models
so graphical models it's a very powerful framework for representing dependency structure between random variables
typically when we look at graphical models
the graph itself will contain a set of nodes vertices
that's will represent random variables
and we'll have links that
tell us something about dependencies between those random variables
in the joint distribution over those random variables can be decomposed into the product of factors
and each one of those factors is looking at a subset of all four of these
subset of the nodes
there are two types of models
there are directed graphical models something is called bayesian networks
and they've been around for quite some time
and there are also undirected graphical models and these known as markov random fields boltzmann machines
you know in this tutorial will be focusing on a bit more an undirected part
just because a lot of models a of these models come from undirected graphical models
but there are also hybrid graphical models
and we'll see some of goals and hybrid graphical models model that combined both directed and undirected models together
so for example you know deep belief networks for those of you who heard about deep belief networks
these actually hybrid graphical models they have both undirected and directed parts to it
ones like hierarchical deep models
and the idea behind
directed graphical models it's it's directed graphical models actually used a lot in the machine learning
and they useful for expressing causal relationship between random variables
so for example in this picture here
right the joint distribution that specifies this particular
as consistent with this particular graph is you can say well my joint distribution with
these random variables which is gonna be written as a product of
as the conditional distributions of nodes given the parents of the nodes
right so for example in this case if i look at the joint distribution
of these seven random variables then it factorises precisely this way
there is x one peel next appeal x three
if you look at x four r x four has parents x two x one and x three so that's
and all that i have here
end notice that the graphical model tells me something about how the distribution factorizes
and this is known as a directed acyclic graph with dark
and it you know graphical models in particular directed graphical models are very useful you been used a lot in
a lot of different domains but you know maybe one example
it is just a show you is you know how would you generate an image
well you might have
the latent variables like object position orientation
and then we all of these two random variables might have independent priors
and then the way you generating the image
is you say well if i know the object identity the position and orientation
then i'm gonna have a likelihood function here
that essentially tells me what's the probability of the image given these two
variables right
so given these two random variables i can generate the image
you know this is sort of a canonical way of how people
OK so the people are known more about segmentation in various different probabilities maybe they
chosen different
but can we go from that so
step up from segmentation spelling correction
in egypt were processor used to seeing this square little reliance on my colleague and
fellow which machine learning connoisseur of the arts army always gets upset
when he sees little red
o lines under his name
and in a common office product when he hits the OK button
he is that
which is probably not the most likely capability but you know given that you're going
from a dictionary and his name was in in the dictionary that's the best you
can do but if you work from a larger corpus and said maybe you can
do that
and so i want to compare get back to this idea of agile programming compare
this corpus based approach to a more traditional programming based approach
and so on
they went on the web and i search for that spelling correctors and i found
this one
you know so there's all this stuff in there under the case e
he said something effects is it's
CIA's in there were chr LCS is if in CIRC you see why it's dropped
most i
CRS USC y
quick can you verify that they got every case right there
can anybody did that OK well you know maybe you take you for a little
while to verify that every possible cases covered there but then that
trick is give a couple days to do that and that i give you know
the data say well just let's do simple one more thing and just bought this
to romanian
that can be too hard right just modify the total little bits does remain instead
being how hard could that be and you can see that that's the fragility
this can code approach as opposed to machine learning approach
so again
it's the same old model you fall back to this the probability probably the spelling
correction it could depends on the probability that the correction sees the word
and the probability that it's impossible typo for the original word
best correction is one with the highest probability
probability of the word we get again by counting just like we did before
the probability of the type of you some kind of model the a given these
two words how similar they to each other and how probable one b type of
for another
if you've been running a spelling correction service for a long time you've got lots
of examples of that you really good model of that if you don't you can
just do something simple like count the edit distance between them and that's what i
and then there's all program
it's a little bit longer but not too much again fits on one page
i i guess i get get something like that i forget the exact number but
something like eight percent correct with this and if you want to do more
you probably want to take more context into account and do
what is probably this word given that it appears before the facts were so
analysis of a little bit from there
and say can we do something that's more semantic oriented and this is one of
the first experiments we did that the google labs google sets them by some time
and the idea here is to use all the information you have available on the
to suggest a set of things that are related to each other so here i
put in our car so anonimity sic
and i get back matisse picasso and go monday because so
so it's concentrating on these impressionist artist first and then it has other kinds of
artists and
it veers off a little bit now science o atoms is in the bottom there
is slightly different medium that uses and so on but looks like a pretty good
if i give the lions and tigers and bears i get back
tigers lions elephants monkeys giraffes dogs cats snakes and so on looks like it's been
pretty good the couple things that italics there that are quite right it looks like
so there's cottonwood musical toddler
and you might want to think about how to sneak in there
and we'll see the answers but what you guys do one
so there are all kind of related animals so what if i gave it two
different kinds of an animal so what would come up with that
of course of course
and then you can see that you know this already from central to peripheral
so does it out that
man analysis CPU narayanmurthy
the typical unix commands and make node in the MIIA are more peripheral
so does seem to have some kind of understanding
so how would you do something like this why not show the whole code is
that doesn't fit on one page building and show you some of the data sources
so the first thing you can do is just go on the web look for
and say look like tigers bears curve close to each other maybe they're related and
that's pretty good clue
but then you also have to say well some men mostly in but also occur
in that does that mean they're related so maybe it's not that strong
but here's a case where they look stronger
we have HTML structure in the in the case of these list elements in case
of links and maybe that's a stronger clue that those are related
and this is example to the puzzler of why those weird things come in
because the web but does reflect reality and so it does talk about animals but
the web also reflects an awful lot of commerce and you can't really by lions
and tigers and bears but you can buy
stuffed animals and kottler animals and cotton plush toys and so on so those words
get confused
another thing you can do is look at your user logs and well somebody was
looking for a cheetah pics and then leopard pics soon afterwards maybe that's an indication
and then you can try to understand the structure of english and you can either
do that with a full parser that understands everything about sentences or you can do
it with the restricted approaches think marty first perfectly with the first one to suggest
using phrases that are highly indicative that are our
high precision but potentially low recall
and so if you want to find what things are like lions you could search
for the phrase such as lions and then anything that shows that there is very
likely that that's going to be in the same sentence lions of course there is
no countless numbers of different ways that you could say lions and tigers are similar
and you're gonna miss all the other ones with this but if the web is
large enough and there's enough examples you get
what you need
hey i'm just kidding the right to be indecisive or to have the thing with
this i haven't made up my mind whether really want to invest in options and
so by in stocks as well by an option
that gives me the right to buy
you know you could say that a lot of people think that way
like a company will think we're trying to decide whether
we want to
build the shopping centre so by an option on land
underlying what where we would build the shopping centre will think more about it and
decide whether it's a good idea to build the shopping center
well that you could do that
but this is something a little bit misleading about that reasoning
whether whether or not you decide to build the shopping centre if you buy an
option on the land
you will always exercise it
if it's in the money and exercised it whether you build the shopping centre now
not right
i suppose you you you couldn't decide whether to build the shopping centre newport and
option on land
and then
someone comes in and says well we have to make up her mind today
the land the options exercising is expiring if we don't exercise today is worthless
so what you discuss it you're meeting
you don't discuss whether we're going to build the shopping centre and not that's irrelevant
you discuss
what can we sell land for and we can sell for more than the exercise
price we will always exercise it
there is no
the assumption in finance is that all options that are in the money and on
the exercise date
are exercised
and there's no
choice award option might be misleading because you could choose to be dumb and not
exercise but that's not what it's about
on the other hand options really are central to our
i was thinking about a lot of things to i give you an example of
an option that you might not consider
an option
this is the option to marry some happy and so sometimes people complain that their
boyfriend or girlfriend cannot
we've been going on for three years it's time that we get married
but this person
the other counterparty cannot seem to decide
but actually
one view of of that situation could be that this person is just a better
schooled in finance than the other
one principal finance is that you should never exercise an american call early
and that this is article about relationships and i just tell you a story that
comes to mind
you never want to come back but you never want to exercise an american call
early so that's why there's an important distinction between
european and american
but just in the prince in the in the
it's in the case of relationships
suppose your girlfriend or boyfriend really wants to marry you
is is still giving you time
then you instinctively notion which
this law and so not really perhaps in terms of theory you should wait until
the last day when this other person
he says it's not our never
because there's always exercise hours option values are is the chance
maybe that will become clear and i feel like my knowledge and not cynical these
things have some people who are
this is a call option up here but
this is the call i'm gonna show you what it but go ahead
what our tries
so the price and come back to the price of the option will always be
above that line
so there is no evidence that we
there are possible it depends on if the price is wrong arbitrage when you come
back to that
i this is a put option
this is intrinsic value for a put option
it's the opposite of the call
if the strike price is twenty and the stock price signed for fifteen
then you can see that it in the money it
right because you can make five dollars by exercising
you have
you have the right to sell for twenty
but you can buy it in the market for fifteen so you buy for fifteen
cell twenty make five dollars
but on the other hand up here if have stock prices thirty dollars
you have the right to sell it for twenty one that's worth nothing right
i can sell it for thirty in the market
but then what
so do i have
make me jump to this isn't exactly what i wanted to do
this has to do with our trying using the
the price in the market
should always be greater
any intrinsic value
until the exercised it
the last
and american way even for american or european this this talk american
this pink line is my
the price of the option
now we will talk about how we get the line from theory but
if the
let's see if it's an american option got time to go and say the exercise
isn't for another year OK
and it out of the money the price of a share is only fifteen dollars
but the exercise price is twenty dollars
that option is still worth something to right
it's not worthless
it would be worthless if you exercise today
hey you're not going to exercise
the reason it has value
is that the prices might rise above twenty dollars sometime over the next year
and so it had the you have a chance of making money
we go to
integrated application ontology
integrating application ontology means developing one last thing
which is
we need to bridge ontology
as you will see in the next slide this bridge ontology is basically
a set of tripos but says
this time here is this guy here
an event here is an event here an artist here is an artist here
OK so
it connects the concept in that not more than to the concept in the
content models
it what it looks like
it says
whenever you find an artist in musicbrainz ontology well it is the next performer
do you remember this idea of the subsets
you seeing that perform
as a subset which are
the artist in musicbrainz
these one is maximal
and this one is musicbrainz
so whenever you have an instance here
your seven instance here
so you can query using these terms
even if the data where everything in these terms
this is that it's nothing more than that of course in reality is not that
you we said one-to-one mapping which basically calling for
why did you do that
i mean you should have adopted ontology and that was
in reality what happens quite often is that you have a one to many mapping
or you need the rule translate from these ontology to his ontology
so multiple data here are represented as a concept here
but in this tutorial and then we just use one-to-one mapping as a way to
develop this bridge ontology so the concept is useful they way it is done is
trivial but because this tutorial
here we use of this subproperty
so we are saying that the related artists
musicbrainz is a way
to be related performance in next i guess but you remember that i do
these things
so this was the relation related artists here what i'm saying is that there is
another property is one that really performance
and whenever you found two artists here but are related using the related artist in
musicbrainz you should also say
but there are two two performance-related by they relate to perform
property so this allows you to model concepts style events and properties
you read the performer performer style as when and as well
got it
any question
so this is the magic basically
this is where the reasoning comes soon
these machines started working because so far it was broken so far you have these
up you you can put query but noted data we come up because of the
data were presented down here and the only way to get the data was to
asking this more
now you put these bridge ontology and the bridge ontology allows to query from top
we've all really caring about these people down here
OK this is just an explanation of what i said
what to do
want to know the number of particles then we're doing model selection
this is an important
if we select for example the number of possible which is large so very probably
what will happen is that the fundamental frequency which would be for example four hundred
will be fitted on two hundred
and then you will have the first part of the four hundred
then another one
three hundred
and around four hundred so you have artificial waterfall between because you need to replace
all the possible
within the
and if you have too much or too many partial than possible so am not
be too large
but if the number of phosphorus too small
then you will not capture most of the energy we can begin to higher powerful
so again there is some compromise to do in this environment
so as possible
choice is to select the prior
western distribution
the fact that several when you run the lambda equal twenty
this favour solutions twenty powerful
and again as was the site parameters
i tried to this lambda parameter here
and we would like that to be too precise about it because we don't know
whether there would be five awful awful people
so a good solution is to keep
as an unknown parameter
and try to estimate
OK so
this is lake
to find a prior to find
it's about the violence of additive noise of the model
of course we could assume we know
but if we know it
then we don't know how to choose the balance between the noise and the company
we have to learn this from
if we want to capture most of the energy in the model
we tend to favor more value the sigma
so an example is to select an inverted gamma distribution
and which can that free trial
which would like to this paper very small values of sigma parameter and it's been
high for
and it does a good advantage to be
the conjugate prior we can write
very easy some posterior distribution and
we have to define
the likelihood
and we have defined
the prior now we can
right the posterior distribution of models
multiply these basis
we have we
and that was a very big expression with which supplied with prior
she won and what's very nice and this is because of the
prior was selected
we can integrate out some of the parameters
i can try to integrate
well where that if a right
with an integral in front of it
one thing left where
which includes
parameter theta
i can calculate it in closed form
can also the same with
and then you can have just above here of the frequencies the the number of
because i don't have to bother about
obama tools of amplitude and variance of the
i don't need
i can do
during the frequency
and it the like
and a just reward
to compute these quantities
we need to compute the metric here
which look like that
the important fact is that the universe
so if you want to
it would be very costly
nine inch
two times the total number of rules
and the number of amplitude and phase
it can be very large
so we integrate out
five of
and the amplitude but i think is that we can accomplish
i assume you know about the pregnancy
you can write
the posterior distribution of the variance of the night with respect to the frequency the
number of children the observation
you can also the same with the
and the violence
so we start with an application which is estimation of the music
we right to physical model
when that into a probabilistic model and we end up with equations which are the
posterior distributions of the parameters
if we want to estimate its parameters we need to explore this posterior distribution
the previous one
OK so the problem now
is that
to obtain an estimate of the frequency of the amplitude of the
we need either to maximize the two either to integrate
it's a serious about
so this can be very difficult
and a good way to do it is
bayesian computations
so you have the lecture six lectures on a bike store there
so i go very fast
how can we do that
OK now we have to where we defined model
we have this
the set of parameters
and we want to be able to explain
and the very difficult
so i recall a little basic insincere
so we want to know
estimated three estimated number of possible maybe
estimated value of z eighty nine
you can
as i mentioned earlier you can do it like an image
and maybe
both are going
but the important thing is that we need to explore this posterior distribution of the
parameters and we want to exploit around its maximum
for the main problems prior approach
OK so the MMSE estimate
looks like the posterior distribution
and it returns
the parameter that we have
OK which is the expectation with respect to the posterior distribution so we need to
compute this integral
and we also
identify the main focus
starting to five
on the column is that just to
refresh you
OK so i want to come
we want to
integrate out it
with respect to the parameters
in health the posterior distribution of the parameters just
so one element is very simple
same but
OK so before the
a monthly column
imagine a density p
is a uniform distribution
and it's very easy to calculate into
provided h can integrate
if it gaussian
you might be able to calculate it analytic right
the bad news is that it's never any of these cases
usually it's much more like that that you have
both should be very high peaks and very narrow peaks
local maxima
o thing
OK you
so that
you see
you know
well of the world
he told
it's not same on
you i of
the state is
we're going to be able to solve the problem
same thing
well and
of course
we need
we all know
and what you find
you know a
and you for
he said
it is
park you
there there's no
the problem is
how i
all the time
among are
so we
it has lot structure much like this
it's it's very hard to guess beta
the nature of
the data
it was the whole inputs that they
forward if the text
i would have some kind
there should
you don't have any
i was trying the best
i don't know
i would expect
here she
but i'm uncertain
there were ten speed of ten for large datasets
or not
you can also compare the speedup versus the number of
euclidean dimensions
this was in this
just about eight hundred features
this is that images dataset which is about four thousand features
it's also only has six hundred
data points we didn't really notice
so two explanations for what might be sort of a six hundred is about there
is this one
maybe what this says is that
the number of features is not too
related to the speed up to you see
in waiting speedups for presiding over the feature so i think these are
the above twenty understand actually very kd trees but i i think about twenty
they start to break down
they just require radial of competition time
this is
is like forty or fifty features
OK so the the expansion constant
so where you compute expansion constant
is this way
you take the point because distance to a point in each sort
and then you think about a radius
two that just before one of the sorted elements
the double that
you can number of points here which here
in the iterations needed the worst case several choices of
this is just before
you can prove that the worst case risk is one of the sort
so it's in square in time because for every point you can business point any
but then you would have the worst case
try to
it's a
actually probably be
that's more valid in some sense because what you see
the worst case value c
this is the the worst case expressed constant
is not strongly indicative of the speed that we have to
what you can do is you can take
every point you can compute some worst case of radius is
you can sort the points according to that
worst case this and so was his first cousin the point
and in the eightieth percentile
and that's what this is
the green
so some sort of average notion
one taking the very worst case for taking its present our case
if you do this operation of
o thing that the
worst case per point and sorting
we observe is curves like
maybe in this goes like this
maybe maybe it's this one here where you little speed up
and then
the ones we we get a large speed but still have large
its worst case let's just like these
you see things like this
so a few points had to be
we fly away from other points so they have a large expansion constant but that
doesn't matter much
the performance of the
this graph is just looking at sort of that point
it's going to be g
yes it is
so what would be interested in estimating there
the deal known the theta will be the probability of getting head
when we don't know the the coins there
it points for the obviously we know what the chances are half
i was saying here is we don't know that we try to find out what
the probability that is of course it's that's still known to try to find out
and then
saying that we've got six had so saying
the like because
so the likelihood say point one would be if the probability of getting heads point
well what's the chance of getting six heads
out of ten games
and then
you can change as a function of t c could be possible values this probability
you work through the what's offensive
the probability that heads point two what's the probability of getting
is the probability of getting a head is point two
what would be the probability of getting
six had given the image go
the chance of getting a head pointer
so this is what this this thing like is measuring so we very t
and what we try do so
and what we do
if we choose
our estimate of theta
so with the value of t that makes this function the biggest
so let's move on to you know there's a standard abusive is this abuse of
notation is commonly used with forget about calling it to put featuring because i see
on this side view of new this definition
so so and the reason is because this is just an unknown number so can't
really be varying t
this is very
so what we can do is we have as we work out the system and
the way work is
we choose the value
that maximizes the likelihood
which is the value of the in the in sample of talking about the
it was so now
that the best choice
would be to set our estimate for the probability that you had to be six
out of ten six ten point six
if you work out the likelihood function and differentiated maximize it you find that is
maximized the sequels point six for that situation so that's what we tried to try
again estimate
i was based on this assumption here
stand once we do that
we do very well because we know how the law of theory about this function
so we can work out always something properties was an alternative
which is
bayesian inference
on the situation
we've got the same thing with theta that's i found out about but
we use the subjective probability idea even though these are
numbers constants we just don't know there was also will have the chance that they
long term the
for this dataset is twenty seven point two or something so the probability of b
twenty seven point two is xy
say point four seven percent or something like that
what we do is we reflects believe
about what the value theta is
by giving a probability distribution
which is one of the subjective probabilities so so even though we don't believe
it's a random quantity
and actually belief about
its characteristics by using a probability distributions describe what we think
it is the text
so for example
if we thought that
if this might be really bad example course matter if we think of vehicles the
pressure is
the average the pressure say a hundred
we have no idea of what the ranges we might say that
what we think of as our belief about what is that
the belief about what
the average the pressure is to be characterized by a normal distribution with mean one
hundred a very big variance then the variance because we weren't really sure what the
so that there will be one example of capturing
belief about a constant
the constant being average blood pressure across
everybody in the world of
if the number of people
well that's that's the constant but we're trying to say what i think is what
i believe about it capturing that by probability distribution probability distribution is this thing here
p theta
so it's subjective probability and he's telling us what do we believe that the parameters
now the idea behind it is that if you do any data analysis the client
we also have to tell you things about the unknown quantities so rather than just
rely on data collection you can rely on asking you apply what they know about
so this is the way
including information from experts
and what we think of in this context is this is what i thought was
the case about theta before i started doing and experimentation
do for the last twenty years actually in a certain sense this string excitations sort
of energy trajectories are added headings you may say because the particles of the standard
model of definitely not arranged in marriages trajectories we are pretty sure about that they
are just corresponding to one trajectory particles so you know there are many trajectories if
string theory is correct there are particles in the standard model so the real idea
of the iraq beginning was not is not really what is driving unification on the
other hand it what has been
recognise is that one of these particles that it's always fair weather you want it
or not is the graviton on that these theories are consistent theories of quantum gravity
and this is really the main motivation for trying to think of string theory as
opposed to quantum field theory it when one thinks about unification of interactions
so this is the unification program how about the strong force well there as you
know in the seventies the beautiful theory has been developed and almost completed quantum chromodynamics
and furthermore there are other technical tools which are perturbation theory and lattice QCD calculations
which are adequate for many many context not for everything but for a lot of
context therefore if string theory is to play a role there it
really will play a role only as an analytical tool an analytical tool for accessing
the low energy strong coupling dynamics which are still hard
to calculate the this we don't have other techniques
indeed the fact
that we see these nice energy resonances in hadronic collisions at low energies is not
a mystery at all
if you think for instance if you look at lattice calculations of the quark antiquark
potentiality is here is one such calculation
it is not very obvious that just plane QCD
there are linear forces have large separation that's exactly as if there was a string
between the park and antiquark which was being stretched and because it has been shown
this creates energy proportional to length and therefore the more than understanding is that QCD
has strings these are some sort of flux tubes chromo magnetic flux tubes which like
the case of electrodynamics where they open up know
here they have a tendency to actually become not one thing when you stretched them
and this explains the qualitative successes of both the dual models from the beginning and
also more a more practical effective models like the one model
the modern reincarnation on the other hand dual mode this as you will see is
completely different from this world very different from his original ideas and it goes by
the name of the aviation safety correspondence out talking the last lecture about potential applications
of these mostly for the quark gluon plasma what there is some hope that one
will get new input from this approach but theorists are much more excited by the
idea CFT correspondence for very different reasons because they believe it so far-reaching correspondence which
allow us to understand quantum gravity and this is the hope and i would say
think about this
in the last lecture
so now today let's go back to very basic things let's try to first understand
the dynamics of one relativistic string that's where the story begins
now this is described by a lagrangian connection principle which in theory as you know
it is very nice way to basically summarize everything including the symmetry equations and the
quantisation of the thing in the case of relativistic string the simplest such action is
known as the number of got to action it is basically nothing else but the
area of the trajectory that string things energy extended object think of it as a
when it moves it
it leaves behind the two dimensional trajectory something like a cylinder deformed cylinder now the
area of these
it is basically the action the area has dimensions of length squared so there should
be a dimension for parameter and this parameter is known as the fundamental string tension
and it is also defined as one of our two pi
time some other parameter that edges slope parameter which is called alpha prime has dimensions
of length square
so x mu of sigma tau
here the coordinates in space and time of this extended the object as it moves
sigma tau are to parameters that you can
use on these what she thought trajectory to describe a at any given point the
position x mu of sigma tau
it and using here the lawrence symmetric namely exit the means minus time squared plus
space square
now what this is to say well this square root expression may look a bit
complicated it is really a very simple geometric expect pressure as i said namely it
is the element of area
on this trajectory it can be it also as mine is the determinant of something
about one called the induced metric namely if you have a surface embedded in some
i'm which has its own notion of distance you can of course measure distances on
the surface by just taking the same mistake me stick that you had in space
time and just moving around the except for say on the globe the surface of
the african of course measuring distances in exactly the same way as outer space except
you have to stay on the surface of the earth and the induced metric is
simply this reduced
a notion of distance on this two-dimensional surface
now this is the start of the story now when you think about these would
be if you realize that
there's nothing totally unique about this action actually if one simply
but requires the symmetries that are here namely lawrence invariance and re parametrisation invariance it
shouldn't matter how you choose to label the points shown this trajectory there are many
more than one can write down however what is unique about this action and that's
vector machines and you almost certainly going to hear about this and can lectures coming
red curve
is a log probability law for logistic loss
cook from a method called logistic regression which is really common classifier so one we're
talking about
you will get very lost if you really clearly predict the right answer but
instead of just having
a lot of one if you get the wrong answer
if you're
very confident wrong
then you're going to experience a very big loss and the loss will go up
to infinity
maybe that's bad if you're making the financial prediction your very confidently saying the wrong
just regression can be seen in a couple of different ways and
it's again going to be an example of ideas that we'll see all over the
instead of just saying i'm going to come up with the decision boundary logistic regression
does something a bit more it says i'm going to actually
try to come up with an explanation for
all of the labels
and i'm going to say that
it's not actually the case that if i have a decision boundary
and whenever i make observations on this side
you're always going to see a plus one it's actually possible for there to be
noise people might enter the wrong number in the computer or the world more complicated
than the plain so i should always allow for other possibilities
this defines a probability distribution over what the label might be
it can sometimes the same w transpose x the same activation
and if the activation is really large
then the probability of getting a plus one label is basically one
so if you are very very far from the decision boundary it does the same
thing is
other methods we've seen it says well you're going to be one on this site
and if you're a long way on the other side then you're going to be
zero probability of being one which means or minus one
what's different is that
near the decision boundary itself
it explicitly says the probability of getting plus one labelled is the high
and if you're a little bit on one side or the other
i'm not sure exactly
it's more probable that you're going to be one if you're on the positive side
of the decision boundary but it's also possible that could be a negative one
that's a richer description of the classification problem than just a single plane is describing
the whole dataset including sort of outliers and noise
and it's also possible to fit the w in this description
so we can make a objective function
out of
this model of the labels
so one objective which is sensible is what's the probability of
the whole vector my observations of this whole lecture pluses and minuses ones in my
my training set what was the probability of seeing that
given the particular matrix of input that i had
and the weight vector that i've currently got in my hand so given your model
with this weight vector how probable is that you see the labels that you actually
did c
and that's equal to
the product of the probabilities of all the individual labels if we assume that
the label during small independent given
the weight vector
so now we could maximize this thing
which is called the likelihood of w
with respect to w
so that i'd like to emphasise the pedantic point this thing is called the the
likelihood of w it is not the likelihood of the data set
that's what this is sort of the long-established tradition in statistics is called the likelihood
of the parameters
so i want to write computer code that will optimize this thing
you'll quickly realise when you write code
a bit of a pain to deal with directly in and in computers because they
tend to be incredibly small
if you imagine that i flip the coin
a thousand times
and i wrote down head tail had had told hotel and i wrote down the
and i said what's the probability of the data set
but answer is half the probability of each event
raise the thousand the number of events half times after high
a thousand times now half to the thousand is an incredibly small number and
that under floating if you try to represent it
you can't deal with probability that small instead you take the lovely so what's the
log probability and that would be a number of floating point can deal with
it will also be numerically more stable and
that night for a variety of reasons
one reason is nice is now the the log probability of the whole dataset can
be written over some
each of the items so the log this term
is given here
now we can interpret this as optimizing the loss because we've got a sum of
independent terms for each individual case in the training set and it looks as though
we doing something
like the least squares optimisation we did before we're looking at each
items the training set and saying what's the little term here that we want to
that we want to be good
and so the loss we pay for each example is the log of one class
e to the minus y transactivation
that's what
this red couple sharing
the loss we pay
the log probability
for predicting label exactly correctly is there
and that makes sense so
if i'm a long way from the decision boundary
then the probability assigned to the label is one
i'm not completely sure that this is going to be a plus one
so the log of one is around
if i'm going to be very wrong if i say i'm completely sure that this
is one
and i'm sure with probability one and it turns out to be a minus one
then i'm going to take the logs very
which is minus infinity
it's a
the negative of that which is infinite
we've got an objective function we can optimize the classification instead of this procedural description
of the perceptron
i've got a weight vector and i'm going to
spend less around according to some arbitrary rule
i've now got
an objective function i can say i'm going to spend more around this weight vector
it's a really good explanation of my labels