in the first part of this lecture
ten minutes ago this test
results showed that the essentially
we have those
i dimensional point distribution will approximate
others is we need to find a way to do it
there's a lot of an antiquated do it
i don't like that
i'm gonna go for basically it tried to
basically do this using mccallum
because i don't have a clue how many of you are familiar with monte carlo
methods i'm just going to start
simple introduction to multicolour column that very few essentially the main idea
b by the monte carlo mean something
actually we cannot use the
when we get to the bottom of the column in all cases
so we this the method which is very
all admit that was in the fifties known as the importance sampling
i go from some but on their we and
hopefully by this afternoon we will have discussed offers
sequential monte carlo algorithm that build on
in france in
nineteen no longer ocean model OK
for the time being
i'm going to say that all only
the posterior distribution of x amount when you know what i want to end
where the time index for the time being is fixed
so remember that
eventually what i want to do is i won't
basically it to be able with me
these distribution for an increasing including value of i
but for the time being and we just assume that n is fixed
so i would like quality distribution where i noticed the abortion or the joint distribution
on the question is known exactly
because it is highly unlikely with all i know exactly
the thing i don't know
the marginal likelihood
in most practical cases of in five unable to compute this
what is monte carlo
o thing actually when you never seen that is a bit strange idea
but it's going to the saying
well if you want to approximate to very high dimensional solutions
what you should do
you should try to obtain
that people and
and being a large numbers one of the
capital and on the volleyball
x one n
i will discuss this quite
it's basically i going on one two
one thousand it is the
to the index of the sample
you can apply to obtain capital and one themselves or
the posterior distribution of inputs so i assume for the
you know
this will be an entrepreneur distribution
and i'm telling you assume
you our more
i think that people in one sample
from this distribution i'm not telling you are
you just assuming it we know
in this case the monte carlo approximation
is very simple approximation
you say that what going to do
that you can approximate
the posterior distribution having
by the empirical
of the simulated values
approximate the guy
by one another so i call one n
then you like mass located
in x one and i that's what you're doing
OK so in remember
the property of the dark matter
i'm sure you're all familiar with that kind of controversial version kronecker
OK so this is the only thing notable are based on
so it's a bit
when you think of the monte carlo is very confident my believe
what you're doing
is that
even if i give you
the functional form
the distribution of interest
what you're doing
so i tend to go show
is that
your sampling from it
you can on you completely forget
about the functional form of it
the sampling from it on your approximated by this empirical measure bits find so why
do need find so
assuming i give using four
normal density
i mean all find one
get the colour of estimation of distribution what you're doing you're gonna sampled say mind
escape fifteen
the gaussian distribution
only approximate this
by some of them are located
the realization
on the model
this can be find the big
it seems to be a bit we
we start thinking that maybe it's weird but using numerical economic sense because
well you have this kind of into gaul
this dysfunctional from it integration respect the target distribution interest now you replace all this
complex gordon
by respect with some better than that
integrating with the from them at this point
it might be actually
might make sense
let's have a look in order to kind of more
complex problem is assuming you are like
that i
none of the quality function is non gaussian beam strike action is an example taken
from the real life examples in econometrics
so you've got to
five i pointed the function of a bit trying to the big muddy here over
the minor mode in there
you want to approximate
basically do monte carlo methods are going to get on arrival on this and i'm
not kidding you are
basically if you look at i don't know why that applies here just to get
the plot the point think and here and see what he does not the column
already funny actually because
he's going to put
that deploy automatically is going to put basically point
in our ears that matters
we could be more than one got some of these guys here
correspond to the retailer
so we we manage essentially what he does multicolour methods that
automatically you can discretize the space
but you do it in a clever way we can automatically
you put the points
in regions where it doesn't matter
for example
here you will never put anything because you appointed function is zero
so you will never sampled point is on here
when you sample points well most likely to be here because this is where most
of the matter is that you get because you've got that we're going to get
how to you know we can do sort of optimizing the cost function that's not
the big problem you go to
to the people in in combinatorial optimization they give you a cutting plane algorithm and
then you you just get the solution but it's not so clear how you would
actually transfers such as solution to two inuit
new image
so the factorial nature of these cost functions makes it particularly simple tool to talk
about the generalisation problem
we just take the statistics and we use the the nearest neighbour rule with the
new cost function and then we get the labelling about one
what you want to be could look is minister government so
why can't you
say that you you have to learn the individual cited statistics that basically distributions bunch
well even one image but then you should learn some markov random field interactions from
a say
a few images and colleges just run something like the book of common of you
know this is insufficient
many ways of finding MEP solutions to markov random fields conditional on the data so
can continue then
maybe that will come in and support well
what do i know that know i think i think on on our way here
to grenoble we had a discussion in the train and let me let me sort
tell you a little bit about what the problem i think is and that makes
it clear when when you use k means all these distribution clustering cost function
and you you've trained young you attribute training you have explore exploit the information in
your training image and you have now your centroids
basically what this then the scenario actually is you get step-by-step pixel by pixel
the new information from the test image and you have to make a decision
after i give you a particular list local statistics
what what what do you really want to do if i tell you i give
you is in some all the
the pixels of the new image that you have you copied model
and although
no but if you you but but the true the true
challenges to define the generalisation problem and you have no generalization problem if i give
you the full image
and if you are only tested if you are judged on the on the on
the empirical error on the test cases
then nobody can prevent you from basically doing the best what combinatorial optimization gives you
now i'm not saying that there is no such that is when you sure sure
sure you you you you have but you have to think about a little bit
like the how you would actually use the smoothness constraint which is in your in
your statistical model built into which let to some
two changes to the game that i had in mind is that you have an
ensemble of images maybe i have a lot of
the things i want to you know landsat images and i keep some back just
like we play
you know in
in classification in the whole the games now not on on individual image but on
a whole bunch of images by some to learn about the rest that all of
that is the
well then you are in the game that you say well you have asymptotically many
approach from statistics and was co-inventor earlier in the engineering literature to the amount
and that allows us to treat learning with latent variables using the only
he served
estimation of these forests are sometimes something to tell you a way of taking this
problem essentially doing calculation which for something about these values probably are and then take
the difference is just like me to go to school
so the
here is just a guess the values that you
and use them to create a synthetic fully
problem solved the only problem and then go back and we
and it's very specific way you can execute a triple guarantees that
and the basic matthias use of simple that are still around the
now everything talking about here is a very simple context
charles and the earth
larger models the difference between the naive approach these approaches which was in the first
are sent to you
the most basic application of latent variable is
when you have single discrete values variables
four in
and that was traditionally called mixture
so one discretely variable
different submodels sometimes called experts to contribute either the conditional density into the
for example the right side user
the density modeling and
so here's the request for example and you can imagine when one goes here one
down here and here and the really
variable which design with these were samples from the conditional
got it
mixture called similarly to think that the only way to find fault in general is
clustering is that since overlap each other just three manifold a lot it has irregular
shape by this time
now this picture is very easy to draw two dimensions is expected to start thinking
about how many
you need to know i mentioned above
generic looks like
this this is also very
here's a one-dimensional example or
you can see here and then add following to show that they can get
here is the final remarks
with many many mixtures number is not itself
here's what you
here by the way to
on the left is the conditional models so now
you have some input x
some variables and this
so we're going to generate y
so here's the situation is the one-dimensional but this is one-dimensional
well i
it is
four is used to model this spaces linear model here is based on the right
in this year
and the lines
which is the conditional probability of being model
one of zero right
in this
can have
you can have a conditional density for
i actually is and
which is you know so very best you're either going to generalise around here and
here think this is function are very
the idea is to model this is a very common idea conquer parts to build
complex models for multi densities are piecewise linear regressions so now we can extend the
universe seems from union model distributions linear models two
mixture distributions and piecewise linear models
and for any more but
rest matching standing literals
OK so let's write down a simple piece of
the mathematics here and show you what the core calculation will be focus on issues
which she inference so this is the marginal density
this is the
observations as
and this density is
some of the conditional density functions give
the well variables and we by prior probabilities is simple
marginalisation and then you can
prior probabilities just constantly or
so you can think of this is a simple mixture density function keys keys keys
or the some density functions and blending together
that is
and what is it
show you an observation x
so if i tell you this model here i put it right there and as
component do you think can
it probably came from the one closest to
there is some chance came from the southern which is
so far
and there is a finite very small chance that
so the point here is that tends to do in the next scene one standard
deviation event on this site
five so some probability for all that time
during the posterior probability
given the
the point
that's the team from any particular clusters and that's just a simple application of these
it can also be smaller
just dumb numbers
there's another way
that you can define you can call this
method number one if if you
three for that
there's another way that you can
find the dot product would give you exactly the same result
if you have a vector
and you have the vector b
and the angle between them
if a down
then you can project be on a
or a and b for that matter it makes no difference
and the projection
the length of this projection
is that of course b
cosine theta
so a dog
and that's exactly the same you may want to go
through the proof of that
it is the length of a
times the length of the
and cosine
if a
and that will give you precisely the same result
what is interesting about this formulation which this
lacks that you can immediately see
if the
two at ninety degree angles or two hundred seventy degrees for that matter
then the dot product is zero
but that's a inside you get through this one
which are like
so that
let's take a
down to earth
over dot product
suppose a
three x
two axes
was to y
and i'm asking you what is the dot product
well you could use method number one which
this case is by far the fastest believe me
if x is three
bx is due to the history six
there is no
a y
there is no easy it's there just six
that's the dot product
you could have done it that way
it's a little bit more complicated but i certainly want to show you
that it works
this is the x direction
this is the y direction we don't have to look into easy direction because there
is no easy component
then this would be
factor eight
and this point
it would be at three
this will be too
this would be too
so this would be vector b
and it's immediately clear now this angle
forty five degrees
follows from
two in two
so if we now apply
method number two
a b
first the length of a three
times the length of b
that is too
times the square root of two
this is to do this is to this is to square two times the cosine
of forty five degrees
which is one half
it's clear to any answer six note that
this square root of two in discriminative to
this two and you get six
get the same answer of course
but would be done things
to do it since it can be done
so much
on cross products
i don't want to go through the formalism of cross product
the way we did that with the determinant
i just want to
i remind you that you you have
cross product
two vectors that is minus
the cross
and that the
the magnitude
of c
it is the length of a
times the length of the
times the size of the angle
between them
the vector c
the dot product and cross product is always perpendicular
both a
and perpendicular to be
in other words it's perpendicular to the plane
of the two vectors
now it is perpendicular to the plane in in that case is perpendicular to
like what you have two choices either coming at you perpendicular or to coming right
straight into the blackboard
everyone has always own way of doing it
i can't you what's called the right corkscrew
you take the first one that is mentioned in this case a
you rotated
over the shortest angle to be
when you do that
you rotate your corkscrew seen from where you sit in counterclockwise then the courts will
come to you and so
the direction of the vector is such that you will see the tip of the
vector coming straight
out of the blackboard and so that gives you that
the direction
now i will give you
the position
x often
as a function of
and then we're going to ask ourselves a lot of questions
about velocities
sort of everything you can
i think of everything we covered speeds
i will cover here four seconds of time this is the time axis
in seconds
and we will cover four seconds
so let's see one
and that the object
b at position
this is my
x axis this is where the object is actually moving
this is three
right so i we were really exciting point in the story
why i want to go rec
this is the sample
data covariance
why how white had transpose is the centred inner product matrix
but it also has an interpretation as a covariance matrix i'm not sure what material
single orgasm processes you'll see a little bit in the bit
the gas process for example expressed that
it expresses correlation and anti correlation between data points rather than between data features
so it's like a covariance in the opposite direction look at i mean i just
transpose my design matrix
that way
then it just becomes the covariance matrix but it's the covariance across data points run
across data dimensions
consider a vector sampled from a zero mean gaussian distribution
z is just as vectors
what i want to ask what is the expected squared distance between two elements of
this vector
if i just say
z i minus zj j
and this is an expectation which is across
so this infinite times doing this as an infinite sum of these brackets represent expectation
i can just multiply that out
and what i get is the expectation is that i squared plus the expectations adjacent
minus two times that i z j
expectation of
now under zero mean gaussians with the covariance given by k
we can immediately say what those expectations and that is the variance which is the
i th diagonal element
that's another another variant the j th diagonal element and this is the cross variance
the k i j so this is the standard result from gauss city squared i
it is equal to k i first j
minus two k i j
we can take the distance to be the square root of this that the squared
distance but if we want
distance we can just take the square root of the suspected distance what does this
mean physically what we saying physical was saying
i've got two correlated points from gauss distribution
there are indexed by the data point number as it were
so on sampling these two separate correlated points and that's doing it a million times
on average what is the distance between those points is the question
now if strongly correlated if the correlation is so strong that the cross correlation is
basically the same as the variance of the cross correlation is one and each of
these variances one the distance between them is one plus one minus two
so that if it is the same data point five is equal to j this
is k i i plus kjj minus two k two k i i k i
minus two k i if i is equal to j and then the distance is
zero or if the point is strongly correlated expected distance are very small
if the points are uncorrelated
let's say that the variance of the i th point was one
the variance of the j th point was also one and there was no correlation
between so cross covariance is zero
then the squared distance will be
and it is in between them on average to be square root of two
so that's basically saying so what i'm saying is that if
you have a gas in distribution
o two thousand distributions with unit variance and you sample two different points
to those on average the distance between them will be
square root of two
now there will be a lot of variance between the average distance between them is
so this is the transformation i'm going to suggest between
the similarity matrix
and the distance matrix if we interpret the similarity matrix is a covariance
we substitute in this form of what we see is
which is the euclidean distance
so on the covariance matrix the expected distance
between those two points is equal to the euclidean distance now
be careful because
when the wise are being sampled there
generating the covariance matrix and not the sample from the covariance matrix the covariance matrix
of function of y another sample from it is a function of one so is
then relationship between if we set k equal to that
this functional form and then we sample data points from it on average
those points will be the same distance apart as the euclidean distance between those two
now for other distance matrices over the euclidean distance we knew we were starting from
euclidean distance in the first place if we wrote down the euclidean distances this wouldn't
be a problem
we would be off scot-free in the first place
but that's not what's going on
we have this distance matrix in some cases and this is going to give us
an approach to reforming classical multidimensional scaling
a classical example redraw a map from the road distances between the city
in order to figure out the weather
the office bearers are just a cheap way of doing the computation
the important thing to understand from the math point of view i is just we
have lots of possible ways of explaining
the ice cream
and we're interested in which of those explanations involved data
did well
cold and a thirteen called
so how many of the what the total probability of explanations that go across that
OK so
let's look now at
the picture that we actually got of the second order probabilities it's kind of any
picture actually
if i can manage to get
the spreadsheet go over to good
OK so there are four kinds of by
four kinds of days
there's days where
thursday's which are hard to hide
and we're pretty sure we have those during hot spells
and pretty sure that we don't have them during the cold spell
and there are days which are the yellow ones which are called the cold
so either the
so i the
the problem
dark purple one start from stars which are called called pretty sure we have those
only during the cold spells but look at these other ones hot to cold cold
so over here when the cold spell starts we're pretty sure that day fourteen
what they called the heart with hot to cold a
and we're pretty sure that either day twenty seven order twenty eight
it was a cold-hearted but we're not sure which each one individually has probability less
than less than point five what's really going on here is that we think we
either had this the two ice-cream day
we think we either have cold cold hot or cold hot hot and we don't
know which
so if we're looking at a third order probabilities
which you could do
then we see that cold cold hot and cold heart were both likely to rule
is showing second order
but that doesn't show the correlation between these two but basically if one if this
is a cold hot then this one probably is
i and vice versa
i guess they couldn't both be coulthard
OK so let's see no um
let's go back to our flat picture again
so here we have inertia show
and no information
what do you think will happen if we change the probability of starting on hot
data point seven
so this point five point five will turn to point three point seven
what do you think will happen to this graph
we started on what we started to i spend a
so i decided
yeah OK
so you think we're going to be point seven likely to make the first i
from the right
since we get no information from here anymore
and then what will happen after that one i guess
so i
OK so you think it also because of inertia also a point seven
so we think that the rest of the summer is likely to be high
OK so let's see what happens
it's always nice to be able to do experiments
OK you're right about the first thing but not the second
the reason is that the universe is perfect you write it would start point seven
everhart a one hundred percent likely to be followed by heart
but it's not so what happens here is but that's not actually the second autograph
because i think that'll shed some light
so here
we're saying this day is
remember that this was likely to be a hot day but it's also
more likely to be hot to cold than cold
how can be called the hard probably not called
so if you're more likely to be high
remember that you whatever you are you have a you have a ten percent chance
of switching to the other whether
whatever whether you are
the switches are more likely to be if are more likely to be hard the
switches are more likely to be in the cold direction
and that's why the weather tends to get colder
over time so this is the current whether the long-term behaviour
of this kind of system with some kind of inertia or anti inertia the long-term
behavior is called the climate
and any set of transition probabilities will eventually also lisa will eventually stabilize like this
to some overall weather so we see here that
in the long term
we were about fifty percent likely to be
to be high even though we happen to have a particular you know we're seventy
percent likely on the first day
in the long run were only fifty percent because that's what the long-term climate is
the reason that we don't get this behavior when we actually see the ice creams
is we've got some data about that correlated with the actual weather so we can
reconstruct but what this is showing is what would happen if we started a system
like this and we generated it using a right when the latter died so what
the press which does now generating hot cold cold
according to the point one point and if you try doing it by flipping coins
you'll discover that eventually you will
get about half higher and have called
OK so now
i have an interesting question for you
so we've done this picture here
the old friends
so is
in fact
from about
the channel
the first term
like the last
o point
o point o
but just
what can i do that
the structure
so far
in fact
for before
one of them
one of the
one of the best of the rest
so what
one of
are all
the fact that terms
i want to solve
one of the
one of the material
so just
one of the start
algorithm just given you one way to design an algorithm which turns out to be
useful but it's certainly not the only way
here are some papers where some of these topics are discussed and some other extensions
and i mentioned if you want to look at
francis slides from last year that's only a source for a lot more information about
this includes in particular really long bibliography
OK for topic this is one that i just touched on five to ten minutes
ago and that's trying to identify the optimal manifold which is solution lies
this is an issue if you're trying to do the regularized problem and i just
talked about it's also an issue when you trying to minimize over constraints applicable in
and issues as far as follows often the study of the lies in the low
dimensional subsets of the set that you're interested in the space you're interested in
so in particular the regularizer one norm what you really would like to know is
which components of x zero and which are not zero
and so you can you can sort of define if you know
if you were to know what the solution x tau was you can define a
consisting of basically the the
the vectors z
that have no zeros in the same place as the nonzeros next style
and has zero whenever the next hours
that defines the reduced manifold that can be parameterized with a as a number of
parameters is significantly less than n
a few nonzeros
in the case of the save box constraint if you try to minimize f over
some polyhedron
if you're interested to know what faces of the polyhedron does x style so in
the case of three dimensions here suppose x dawood alliance edge the appropriate manifold that
would be interested to know would be
this said we'd like to know that
you know if we knew the next allied to lie on the stage
we could just focused on minimizing f along the said we could just ditch two
of the three unknowns and just solve a problem in one dimension
so if we were to know
this manifold in which the solution lies we can often vastly simplify the optimisation problem
but why is that useful because we don't know text are is right so if
you know next why do we think we can identify the manifold on which lies
well it turns out that you can sometimes OK
even without knowing next
if close enough to extend often you can get a pretty good read on what
the optimal manifold
so let me try to describe how that is this is a little bit thorny
this like throwing in some
very elementary convex analysis here
but is the idea so let's let's take the setting that i had on the
previous slide where we're minimizing over constraints
and i'm assuming that x is that makers closed convex sets
the optimality condition for x
start to be a stationary point
for this constrained optimisation problem here
is that the negative gradient
of f at x to
it lies in the normal current two my your next what's in normal kind
normal cone is the set of all vectors make an angle of more than pi
over two
with all the feasible vectors emanating from next OK so if you take all the
possible directions you can move into america
from ext r
and then look look at the vectors that make an angle of more than five
two with all those directions you get the normal set his the picture
so to the extent that i had on the previous slide the normal says basically
this plane
o this quarter of the plane
that is anchored here next and you can see that any vector my drawing is
not very good but any vector in this shaded area
it makes angle of leaves pi over two
with all the feasible directions coming out of x to all the directions move into
the box
gonna make an angle of least prior two
with these vectors here
so basically you want to know that negative gradient lies somewhere in the shaded region
OK that's what this condition is
and i'm just shifting both
left and right hand side by next
OK now what i'm going to do with this set
this set x topless in a major effects that this is just a piece of
the plane as i mentioned
but if i take x starring and moved up and down the the optimal manifold
and dragged the normal current
up and down as well
i get said that actually has full has an interior r three
OK then it has a non-zero measuring the full space in so you can imagine
i take the set
and just move up and down the optimal manifold i get an entire when she
because it has nonempty interior in r three
so another given that some notation of called set are the major and
now here's the thing provided x is close enough to the text
and it turns out that x minus
great effort x
it lies inside the set provided you got appropriate nondegeneracy condition
OK the x minus graphics lies inside the set is the set of i got
by taking the normal current moving up and down the manifold
and so therefore if that's true then if i take this
vector and projected back onto the optimal onto the constraints my guess actually land on
the optimal manifold
so what this is saying is that if i got an appropriate nondegeneracy conditions
you know things are relatively nice then i can identify the optimal manifold from any
point x that's close enough to next i don't have to know text are is
i just have to be
you have to be using an algorithm has converting text down eventually by doing something
like this whole identify the right manifold
OK so that's the idea now this nondegeneracy condition i'm kind skating of that but
actually did come up in
and bill months tutorial this morning you know i can't describe the all the statistical
details for you but he had a condition in this somewhere that said that the
would get the set of nonzeros in by to correct
he's using baited using x provided that the minimum of the the true non-zero axis
was above some threshold
in other words he need clean distinction between the elements abated that really were nonzero
and the ones who is zero
so that's something like this relative interior condition and i'm talking about here
so you do need condition like
OK so what can we use this algorithm so if we got away of
eventually getting a good estimate of the correct manifold then we've got away of just
being able to do and do an exploration of much reduced space we can just
explore the space and
by using some other kinds of methods like reduce newton's method or quasi newton methods
or whatever
and it can often be much cheaper than trying to do things in the full
space because for example if i'm just playing it if i'm just decided to stick
to and i might only know a piece of the gradient my mother need to
know piece of the gradient might not have to evaluate the whole grain anymore just
to peace
and the relation is exactly what we had there
it is w
that's the
that's the that's the step we have to take those matrix w that gives a
change of basis
i what i want to do is
think about matrix transformations and matrices
so here's here's the question that could to complete this lecture
suppose i have
a linear transformation t
so it's it's it's it's we would think of it as an eight as an
n by n matrix
and it's computed with respect to
a certain basis
so t
so not a sudden
i got the transformation t periods
that's taking eight dimensional space for eight dimensional space
let's get matrices in there
so with respect to
with respect to
of the first places say we want to be a
it has
a matrix
i'm just setting up letters here
with respect to
the second basis a are making you one up two
or w one and w w
w one up two
w eight
it has
a matrix b
and my question is
what's the connection between a and b
as the matrix transformation t is settled
we could say
it's a rotation
for example
so that would be one transformation of a dimensional space just spinel
or projected
or whatever
whatever linear transformation we've got
now we have to remember
so i so for my first step is to remind you how you create that
then my second step is
we will use the same method to really be
but because it came from the same transformation there's gotta be a relation between a
and b
what's the what's the relation between a and b
and let me jump to the
answer on that one
that if i have if i have the same transformation
and i'm
computer it's matrix in one basis and then computed in another basis
those two matrices are similar
so these two matrices are similar now do you remember what similar matrices meant
similar a is similar to the two matrices are similar
and what i mean by that
i mean that i take the matrix b
and i can compute it
from the matrix a
using a or using some similarities of matrix and
on one side and an inverse on the other
and this and will be the change of basis vectors
i'm having to this this part of the lecture is admittedly compressed
what i wanted to know what it's really about
the conclusion that i want you to
now i have to go back and say what does it mean
four eight to be the matrix of this transformation t
and so i have to remind you what that meant that was in the last
then this is the conclusion that if i change to a different basis
we now know
i think linearly polarized radiation
this is my easy direction going to make it a traveling wave
this is my x direction
and this is my wide election
good linearly polarized with the asian
only has x component
i'm going to make it move in this direction
so at this very moment in time
if it is traveling wave would i don't need any more but i just want
to remind you
so to be factor
i would be in this direction
so to e crosby
is in the direction of propagation
so i have an incident wave
so i write down
your phi
so the church
and then it is travelling wave so i get the cosine and sine if you
prefer that
mine is only getting
so propagating in this direction
this is the key factor
and that the incident wave
x the action so their plane waves
perpendicular to see infinite in all directions
the vector is everywhere in those planes
this value changes was
c and the changes with time
now i'm going to do
i'm going to put here
perfect conductor
and so he vectorized there
there is no normal component to the vector so i don't worry about your friend
there's no normal component only have t
that you've t must be
comes zero
at the conductor
so this reminds you
the string that we had
when we were recording the string at one side
and we fix that side of the story
then in order to make sure that there was no motion of the end of
the spring
the reflectivity was minus one came back the valley to make sure that this point
never will
so exactly the same thing is happening now
we must make sure that right the electric vector is always at all moments in
time zero
so if i just call this
for convenience single zero this location
then the
reflective wave
must be minus is zero
it is the mountain becomes valley
and then it
moves in the opposite direction so you get kc
plus omega t
in the x direction
you will see that the sum of these two at any moment in time
will make the vector right here in this entire plane which is infinitely large
that's the boundary condition that we have to me
the total electric field
which is the sum of the two one moving in this direction
and this one moving backwards
it is of course the factorial some
so i have the cosine of of
call that of
mine is the cosine of data
i schooldays tell you that that is
twice the sine of half the sum
sign of half the difference
although i always have to look that up because i forget that just as well
as you do
so when i had that then
then i get that the total electric field
which is the sum of the two
it's going to be
two is zero i
and then i get the sign
of cases
and i got the sign of getting
and that is the standing wave
all the spatial information is in here
and all the time information is there
and indeed if you substitute in this equals zero
the field is always zero this by the way
it is in the x direction
and so we have standing wave now
and what that means is
that there are surfaces
the direction of c
where the vector is always zero and the entire surface
we have no not all surface like this
they are separated
by distance one have lab
so this is a notable surface
this is also notable surface i'm trying to
draw the curve of the effect
sinusoidal curves only vector may be up here
and then
the factor
the down here
but it's all in the plane perpendicular to the blackwater same
so this is a notable surface this is notable so this is a notable surface
this is the wavelength and the vectors go like this
nothing is moving anymore in this direction it goes like this
standing wave
it was notable surfaces
so this spending electromagnetic wave
has an electric field which is standing
so there there is an associated magnetic field with this which is spending magnetic field
and i would like you to work that out and may even have put it
in one of my my problem sets
and what you find out much to use surprise certainly much to my surprise when
i saw his first
that the magnetic field is now ninety degrees out of phase with the electric field
both in space and in time
so that means where you have the nodal services in e
you have the entire notable services in b
and really feel free to the maximum you have that the magnetic field is zero
unlike travelling wave where the
magnetic fields and electric field in phase both in space and in time
now ninety degrees out of phase
when you think about that that is perhaps not so weird
because there cannot be any energy transport any net energy transport in one direction with
standing waves
and so the mean value of the poynting vector must be zero
and if you make a and b
ninety degrees out of phase
and there's always met so the mean vector of the point vector becomes any case
if you use maxwell's equations you'll see
that the magnetic field
he feels are ninety degrees out of phase ninety degrees in space and in time
i have here are famous
eighty eight
many problems and we have pf with everything
and we can see it and it
so the first thing was sleep SVM wants to reproduce the phenomena
and as you mentioned c is only parameter of linear SVM so we we try
to bury it
so what's happening
for some c settings has been we show
a performance dip when the civic feature vector size varies so with the figures on
the left
so we reproduce everything was labour's
and and then you have
hi c values here
which really much affected by the performance
and then a smaller c values here
which are almost not affected by the performance dip
no no
OK can you can you repeat this this is this is clearly which is
coming out of this
first is
this is
we can discuss it and so on
and i go on and then we can discuss it features
the next step is to relate this phenomena together with the number of features and
the number of training documents
so i we show the performance here include also you have look at films in
dark and high performance
in white and and then you also have
the relative performance you about sixty five percent
about seventy five eighty and then you get better performance
so as you may expect with nice log shaped as performance
learning curve then
as more training to commence you have the better is the performance as what you
the mall features you have the better business you get that's
quite quite regularly so was expectation
i do this
four sequence points are one here and and quite one hundred
and and then here
we see appeasers which is
much more complex and that results as the characterization of all the performance dip
and in the same way we see the correlation between the number of features the
number of documents and the performances which is quite clear here
so there is a relation ship between both
so for large c we have the performance the president is affected by the performance
before the next step we define bounded and bounded support because it starts to be
really technical
four non been people it would be a bit technical
and the solution is flat five where you give to each feature vector each
document weight
which which is between
zero and c
actually you just give the weight to to each feature vector line of your metrics
and then you we have some of as wage which would be equal to zero
because you don't care about those source feature vectors
we call them inactive
for those which are active active documents then that's the way it is strictly positive
but then because we don't want to give a weight which is too important to
some some of the feature vectors we bound is by and
which is
what's what's called a soft margin support vector machines
so then we will have two kinds of active support tools are active feature vectors
unbounded ones unbounded ones
i'm especially interested in cells which are bounded because that quite
if i was giving a higher c value bound then they will run away
so we just limit
and then we reach is is about sources
those the feature vector of a bit problematic
you might expect that good been solution should have as it little bounded support vectors
because that's clearly not the settings you like from the an SVM solution
two steps
o to characterize the performance dip there is the size of the feature vector
and very tracking
we study the nature of the SVM solution
what i
i mean by nature is listed in the bounded the proportion of bounded support vector
energy momentum dependence of the
effective charge the part the probability of radiation as a function of how violent the
disturbance in the energy momentum flow
the radiation makes
and by that kind of experiments and by many many other kinds of experiments you
can see
this property of asymptotic freedom as the sole
actually is correct and the car the
predicted form of the variation is correct quantity
that's the body and that's
the story directly in the phenomenon
how you establish
the underlying theory
we want the underlying theory to explain
not only these jets but also the whole variety we want to make sure it's
complete that describes everything about the strong interaction
it is sort of all the non because it's a consistent theory that is so
tight that you can change very much
that's an aspect of its symmetry
but perhaps there are things you could edit without changing the central core
perhaps it's not
entirely complete as the theory of the strong interactions
to test that we wanted
due to look at it and other applications
and in any case we would like to understand the origin of mass that's not
a bad thing
so let's see if these ideas lead to an understanding of where mass comes from
where the bulk of mass comes from and in particular as we reduce to two
where the mass of protons and neutrons comes from
because studying the masses of protons and neutrons intrinsically involves only small transfers of energy
and momentum the protons and neutrons are built up from quarks that are moving around
in conf
in circles so the constantly being deflected by small amounts
there are very difficult to calculate their cope their copy the they are not
in the regime of weak coupling and low
momentum here
let me
the same word about the scale
the scale is GV so the proton mass
not accidentally
is with the coupling is getting very large
i will come back to that
but in any case it indicates
the approach
trying to add up
individual radiation events and see them one by one won't be sufficient to
build up the structure of the proton you have
infinitely many radiation events going on all
to build up that structure
to address that kind of question requires a much more elaborate kind of calculation
and in fact these kinds of calculations have
and continue to this day
the frontiers of computer technology
back in nineteen ninety three
the frontiers of can computer technology
displayed in the name of the bigger flop eleven
computer g eleven
which was something of the locker room size with gigantic fans in the basement of
IBM yorktown heights
now of course it's the sort of thing you could easily put on your desktop
but g eleven was built specifically to try to get an estimate
of what QCD predicts for the masses of particles
and although we now realize that the estimates of the errors on these measurements were
quite optimistic
the pattern certainly was
essentially correct
closer to the state of the art in nineteen ninety eight is this machine which
does terra flops
calculations that is trillions of floating point multiplications per second
and runs for years
with that you build up
calculation that has one parameter or i guess two parameters
and overall coupling and the mass of the strange quark
that builds up the mass of the observed particles this is the normalisation
and then the rest are fit
and you see that the result of the calculation compared with experiment
are quite remarkably good
even even though one is using terra flops
is an approximation about that's why it is quenched QCD
and it's believed and further exploration
is very out that the residual errors are due to that approximation
so one really does account for the mass
the strongly interacting particles on the basis of the same fundamental theory that you see
directly in the laboratory
in the jet lap
notice one of the entries here is
that can't that stands for nucleon that stands for protons and neutrons
the origin of mass is this
the fact that
you get the nucleon mass from this fundamental theory
so let's see what went into it to get that mass
at a fundamental level
and see if it really does explain the origin of mass starting
from no mass at all
the ingredients of QCD that went into that calculations are
massless gluons
mass was up and down quarks
and nothing else
so i hope you'll agree that all these things are massless and so to get
have explained that you've got a massive particle that the number of them out of
particles with no mass at all
but you notice there's an asterisk here
because this isn't really
this is QCD light
a little joke there
so to be honest
and i'm always honest
and then this thing here we go to zero we already know that this was
i argue that we have sufficient consistency condition for
so often you the tony because a few years the writing of the persistence is
actually necessary and sufficient
i worry about the city has the important thing here is that
this is a condition
which takes into account the whole set of functions that can be implemented by the
learning machine because here we have
the supremum over the whole function class
and of course it's
it's difficult to take this work on learning machines if you are given some
class of functions and you say OK now i'm going to empirical risk minimization on
this path functions
it will be hard to cheque for this kind of uniform convergence will take place
so one would really like to have some further elaboration of some further conditions which
will then in turn imply
that this convergence would take place
so the question is are there properties of learning machines
all properties of set of functions
which ensure that this kind of uniform convergence will take place
because now we learned that if this in the uniform convergence takes place
we have consistency will find so if this takes place that we know
but as we see infinitely many training examples
we will be able to generalize will be will be able to do arbitrarily well
so the difference between the training error
tests are get arbitrarily small
so therefore
by minimizing the training error we would really be minimizing the test which is what
we are interested in
so now we have translated this problem
into the problem of
the convergence of the empirical risk to an actual risk
on function classes
these things are studied in model theory statistics called empirical processes
OK so now
let's take a little bit closer look
the second is a closer look at this quantity
this is that
o thing that we want to go to zero
and the second of is how do we prove that this
we're going to use the telephone
OK first of all
if i class
contains only one function
then we can directly apply the general because if we have only one function in
this class f
and this isn't really is supremo
we can just
drop that part here
so then we are only interested in the probability that
the difference between
training error and test error
larger than epsilon
already shown you before the channel also of the problem we can directly plug in
and we get this nice and fast exponential decay
of the difference
so that's my
and the way we work now is
if we have more than one function but only finitely many functions
we can do a little modification of his argument
and and we get
something which is almost as good will not
if we have n functions we just get the factor in which appears here
and this doesn't cost as much because it appears here
and we still that the exponential decay and whatever this number in
the exponential decay will win against it so we want to get the
so we get the convergence
in the next case will be if we have infinitely many
such functions
then the main idea would be that
on any finite sample of observations that we might see
but even if we have interested many functions they will appear as if they were
financially many
because there only two possible outputs of the functions
if you have only finitely many points on which we test those functions
and effectively of function class is finite
and then we will be able to use the term of bond in the second
life that's
roughly speaking the outline for the next
ten minutes hopefully
so let's first look at this case of
finally many functions in fact i won't the case initially of two functions
so if we have one function we can plug in china directly what happens if
we have two functions
of functions as the phase these two functions
we are interested in this quantity here
so let's just rewrite it
we can rewrite this the probability that
this thing happens at the probability of two sets
remember this was the probability of all
samples of n samples
so this was the probability that i'm drawing pairs of observations
with the property that test error and training artist something different
so when
with the supremum over the function class
at least
epsilon different in this case you will be
the case
i vote for the first function
or the second function or both of them
we have at the different of these epsilon
so here
this event
i epsilon denotes the case
for the function i we have different of what is the size of the business
the case that we are drawing through a sample of points
with the property that training error
test error different please sign on this country by
the union of these two
the function one for the function to
well then give us exactly this event here that the supremum of the a function
class of this two
this function cos theta functions
would be used
some different
OK so maybe
if you don't get it completely could afterwards but it's actually
number difficult thing
so we can rewrite this as the probability of this event
just a little aside
it's not important if you have noticed it and just ignore it but
i use the convention that i have said over here
i use round brackets for the probability of that set
and if i have like a logical formula here
use these curly brackets
it is going to say i can only have stable equilibrium
the sum of all forces equals zero
and if the sum of all works
relative to
and want
equal zero
and nature knows how to do that
always will happen
if the
in the centre of mass are
along the vertical line
because if that's the case
then there will be here
force and g
and then will be a force mg upwards
this object is hanging on that
the action equals minus reaction
push upwards
so to sum of all forces is zero
and there is no talk
take any point you want to this point that point at this point that point
that point
there is no talk anymore so now
there is complete equilibrium
so if you had an object for instance that look like this
thin rod
a very massive object here centre of mass
almost there
then in this situation
will be stable
or you might say
this situation
because now
we have the centre of mass
so also here
we have now
g down
so we have the pin and you
sum of all forces is zero
some of the talks is zero
but there's a big difference between this situation the situation which you really feel your
stomach of course
and that is the this is highly unstable
if you
just below this a little
it will swing over it will
start to rotate residents stable
if i move this to decide
welcome back
to that position
but the basic idea is that the centre of mass
will always stable configuration
line itself out below
the point of
i have here
the triangle
and i have no clue where the centre of mass is
somewhere here
it may even be an open space i don't know
what i can do now i can suspend it like this
and i know that the centre of mass
must be below my finger
if you notice
it's actually rotate it
sort of the centre of mass aligned itself precisely below my finger so i can
now take
and so and draw a line here
or i can a little
and i can change my finger to here
and i can again draw this line and where the two intersect is the centre
of mass
the centre of mass will always find itself
the point of suspension
now i think piece of body
and i put piece of body here
and clearly i changed the location of the centre of mass quite substantially
must have shifted enormously in this direction
whereas the centre of mass
i have no clue
but look
balance it here
centre of mass must now be
somewhere here
i balance it here
centre of mass
must be somewhere here
where the two lines intersect
could be
in his opening
that's where
the centre of mass is located
so it's easy experimentally
to find the centre of mass early in the course we calculate it
where the centre of mass was perhaps you remember that when we had very special
geometrical configurations i mentioned to you then already
that the highways
you can experimentally determine it
and that
can be done very easily way i just showed you
i want to show you some examples of static equilibrium
which are not so intuitive
you may have seen some of you may actually have
if i take a pencil
i think my pocket knife
he was a pencil
i'll show it to you shortly
just regular pencil
my pocket knife and i put the knife jazmine i've
this is the knife
and this
is now
like so
this arrangement can easily be made such that the centre of mass is below
this point
so if now i
one my finger
i can balance
the fluctuation downward one of about twenty five percent worldwide in every market it exceeds
what you will ever find with gaussian random walk exceeded simply because
to take this many steps this many successive scales in the drugs quite has exponentially
low probability of ten to the minus three hundred forty seven
number one ever like to say never
i think ten to the minus three hundred forty seven is about as close to
numbers you can ever get
and and this is another way simply will not happen
most of the time this does very well in many of you know
that this
by showing the work of over one hundred years ago it forms the basis used
trading models and all the markets of the world and i and even if we
don't care about the money of other people we may forget that our own pensions
are tied up in this money and we may forget that even if we don't
have any money or care of everyone else's money that we're going to lose our
this model in short is very very good but not good for rare events so
there already is a little bifurcations economies could be as economists prefer theory
and this is a few rare events and they use words like salami
to describe them
the first such a theory than to worry about the real data especially when the
rare events are exceedingly rare one in fifty years but we didn't actually it's a
little more than one hundred fifty years because if we simply subtract
the price
at one time interval from the price
ten minutes earlier
we have a quantity that usually called returns
is return on your investment ten minutes later
and this galaxy and of course is all those e to the minus x squared
and e to the minus twenty five is already so small that you don't see
returns that are more than five standard deviations one minus five standard deviations everyone is
sandwiched in this region for the time intervals but now it's not forty years thirteen
in contrast the real data display not only the very rare event
black monday october nineteen eighty seven
but also quite a number of other events
and in fact
if we use a piece of experimental equipment there
our mothers gave to all of us which is two eyeballs
you can actually just use one eyeball
you can see a power law
for these fluctuations and how can you do that you can count how many
fluctuations larger than twenty standard deviation there is only one black monday
and you can count how many are larger than ten standard deviations and believe it
or not you get exactly eight
ten is happening twenty
and h is true
the power three
so already we see a cubic power law
and if we want to check it we can count how many are more than
five standard deviations again lo and behold we get exactly sixty four sixty four is
a time state
and so once again we have the standard deviations we get two q as many
so you can already see a power law with the i and q one in
principle could stop right now
but you would convince anybody know that's not even a physicist or gullible but certainly
not a mathematician
who's love to make fun of the
methods that physicists use
two major discoveries
before we leave this slide and look at something a little more complicated let's continue
to use our mothers present
among those present was the idea and with the eye you can see some things
that actually were known by economists toward by kind of as they discover the first
but they've been pushed a bit further by physicists the first is that the returns
are not going every economist knows this
the question is how important think it is but they definitely know this is no
sense in which physicists discovered that these returns and i guess you
and the second thing that economists knew full well is that the large events cluster
such as by monday around like money there are quite a few other very volatile
days and there is a period of calm in the budget volatility that a long
period of volatility
and so forth and this so-called volatility clustering
it is not qualitatively for a long time
what physicists have added and i will discuss this later so just say now
is that for every one of these big shocks
there little aftershocks just as in the earthquake blackwell last month after the earthquake we
all know they were aftershocks in these aftershocks
i have a mathematical properties were first studied hundred years ago by more
and and and a graduate student in palermo fabrizio below working with his advisor professor
maintain you applied to this
the same mathematics maury that all more had applied
to the
problem of real earthquakes and found the same sorts of laws
quite interesting is that if the markets have these
a quantitative features in common with earthquakes and very recently professor have in this room
working with three of my students
the possibility that the aftershocks themselves have aftershocks and those internet more aftershocks sort of
the way that
the poetry goes for turbulence that began eastbourne ladies and lindisfarne
ladies and so on information and and this is a picture of a sort of
self similarity is a qualitative picture that makes one immediately think scale free phenomena in
economics and here is where the biggest bone of contention probably exists with a really
genuine hard-core economists that there should be or even could be
scale free
properties in economics they are reluctant to accept that because the evidence is not of
the calibre
they would consider acceptable because they hardcore mathematicians who do do not accept the sort
of thing
plot for the show
type of
i suppose i want to redraw this because this has been
drawn at right angles its colloquial we know this thing zigzagging one
so i want to redraw the two beauty
and so began by putting double bond
and then
that means i have to have a hundred twenty degree angles
and what turns out here is that the double bond goes to
carbon which has a hydrogen on one side
and on the other side has
the manifold group
and the same thing here so now i have a choice what i can do
is i can click the manifold group
up here
and hydraulic redraw this
well it does read rather
the the two beauty
and i think you can see that i can put a
a symmetry plane here
thank you for symmetry plane
and what wife what do i have i've got all my
i got both of my
methyl groups above the carbon carbon double bond and all the hydrogens below
the carbon carbon double bond but another way i could have
set up the structure again there's the carbon carbon double bond let's put the a
hundred twenty three degree angles will put
the groups above the carbon carbon bond on the left side but below the carbon
carbon bond on the right side and then we'll do the complementary
positioning with the hydrogen
so in the case on the right which is also a two beauty
it's also to butane
we can see as real time warner's we look at structure structure is really important
to us and we say OK same constituent groups but
what you can tell
the electron distribution is going to be different and the one on the left from
the one on the right
so you start thinking well
what about their properties guess what they have different melting points they have different boiling
points they have different as you can see the impact differently
so all this and yet they have the same chemical formula
we have to distinguish these two they're not differ by
their constitution but they are different by their spatial layout and the time that we
use to talk about i some that are different in their spatial layout spatial arrangement
is stereo isomers stereo ice
they are constitutionally identical but
structurally different
constitutionally identical
identical constitution different spatial
so we got labels on this the the one on the right
to indicate that
the various groups are on opposite sides of the double bond is called trans
trans so the structure on the right is trans two team
we're one on the left is
two beauty
so now we met
stereo isomers and
we know what the
this one of the things we can have more than one double bond as well
we can have more than one double bond
in now king
more than one
o double bond in
l here
and we'll need a few these as well we talk about palmer's if we have
this is called a die mean
and if we have three it's called a
look at these so so for example we could do something like this was i
gave image you don't mind i'm going to put the age and the inside you
forgive me this OK right
you know the ages are on board which is going see
what else
OK so what we do with this one i'm not going to give you this
to ten name i just want to see how it works in all
make sure that we focus on the chemistry but just for the record one two
three four five five so it's got to be and
is something pants
got to be in e e because there's atleast one double bond here
and there are two
this is going to be up
died in
and to die and furthermore we can say this is
this is
carbon number one carbon number two number three
four number five in the double bonds issued from carbon number one and carbon number
three so we can call this one three
to die
so now you see how
how all of this
works and it's not so bad
radicals what happens if we want to use just the piece of one of these
so the only one that the comes up that well there's two actually one of
them comes from
from philly graphically
going put the hydrogen is to indicate when i don't have one summer break his
born throw away the hydrogen and use this so this is the radical that comes
well you might say well what we call the since the formal name and when
use the u pacman fifteen
well we can't say apple because apple is already taken
as well as the
so that's helpful just to know
because sometimes i get questions later on word people will say
we showed it was like the big show was log v
like to point out that
the various ways of representing graphs
i'm going to cover a couple of the important ones is actually more we'll see
some more
so the simplest one is what's called an adjacency matrix
and jason
j a
the adjacency matrix
after all the
for simplicity i'll let t be the set of
majors from one
up to and
it is the
and by an
matrix a
given by
the i j entry
it's simply one if the edge i j
is in the edge set
one zero
if i j
it is not in the edge set
OK so simply the matrix where you say
the idea that entry is one if it's in the matrix is in some sense
giving you
the predicate for is there an edge from i to j
OK predicate memories of boolean formula
is either zero or one and
and in this case you're saying it's one if there's no
edge from i to j
and zero otherwise
in our sometimes you have weighted graphs
edge weighted graphs and then sometimes what people do is replace this by edge weights
OK to be the weight of the edge from i to j
so let's just do a an example of that
just to make sure that our intuition corresponds
two are mathematical definitions here's an example graph
say that's are
so i was just across the
adjacency matrix
so this is an edge from
the from one to one
the answer is no
from one to two
i learned from one to three
and h from one to four
image from
two to one
two to two
two to three
two to four
no edges going out of three
ge from four two
three and that's it that's the adjacency matrix
for this particular graph
so i can represent graph as this adjacency matrix
what are represented in this way
how much storage do i need
OK and squared error
for the square because
the size is the same thing
scored storage
and that's what we call a dance
OK it works well when the graph is dense so the graph is dense if
the number of edges
is close to
all the edges possible
then this is a good representation but for many types of graphs the number of
edges is much less
then the number the possible number of edges
in which case we see the graph is parts can somebody give me an example
of a sparse graphs
l class of graphs solomon class of graphs that is n grows
the number of edges
in the graph doesn't grow is the square but grows rather
as the
it has some things in a much smaller
linked list so the chain
so what i want to talk to you today about is actually something
something completely different something different in terms of what it is
probably the most
focused upon a dimensional aspect of statistical machine learning
it's really not what i'm talking about today
that is
a lot of statistical machine learning is about
are induction inference over
attribute space
in structural pattern recognition that's not the case that is we
i have a very rich structures that we have to deal with in images
and and senses
and we have to
work on our that can learn to summarise generalized and optimal inference
over data structures that are much richer
and simply vector spaces
so i want to give you some
insight into this wrong literature
on what's called structural pattern recognition sometimes called syntactic pattern recognition
and that really is the interface between statistics
logic programming and a sort of areas
so it's a symbolic
and numerical
and that's needed is i hope to convince you to solve many many many problems
in complex signal processing
and that's what i want to get over today and tomorrow and over some of
the techniques that have been developed over the last fifty years
to solve these types of problems
so some of you come for example from logic programming background to be metaphors to
what's called inductive logic programming
the second is to come from city background that we could be
uses of bayesian network inference
and this is how to bring these things together in usable systems is the theme
of these these lectures
not to overemphasize
structural pattern making structures are defined by attributed part and relationships
so contrary to what you think
ninety percent of papers
published in the
in many the computer vision journals don't trade
patterns all structures as a groups of of pixels
i already
extract features
and from two thousand images you have all other attributes
there are indexed
so for example in describing upon the lillies
you want a system that can actually insane states that english phrase
well that is what the distribu headlines juxtaposed to each other have about the leaves
and flowers and all those things not simply i thirty two by thirty two arriving
of RGB values that's pretty useless
may be useful for initial preprocessed
but to generate or structural description
i need features attributes labels
so that structural pattern recognition
so where does it come in my goodness
just about everywhere every every aspect of for example computer vision
component description of objects content based queries in the sense real content
correspondence so often in in in in binocular vision
computer vision systems you have to solve the correspondence between disparity parts to infer that
first example of matching now two two sets of features
often for example in medical image processing in photogrammetric you have to align images by
learning parts by learning features fetching and doing various types of morphological not find transformation
based on the correspondences of features
motion tracking where correspondence is not
you probably heard when a talk about motion correspondence you probably saw a few days
ago that we probably so in order to work on the assumption is you've solve
this thing is a product guassian process is independent across features
with a linear kernel
so what that's saying is well when viewing piece e eight is if you've got
a bunch of bayesian linear regressions over
some outputs
you don't know the inputs but piece ieee is finding the best inputs for predicting those outputs
this is what this model is say fine i've got a bunch of outputs
ants i want to know what input generated those outputs and i'm going look for
the best ones on the likes likelihood given that my mapping is a bayesian linear
regression that's the dual piece yet so
how do we make it linear
non linear kernel there
so that's actually the exact same trick is going on and can appreciate
but i can appreciate
the igon value problem
why why transpose is replaced by a kernel
hear x x transpose
latent variables
mappings going in the opposite direction
can appreciate
has a unique solution
up to a rotation
this does not
it has a very nasty nonlinear optimization so you replace the kernel with the nonlinear
kernel no longer have an i can value problem but because the probabilistic interpretation what
you have is to have a kernel with a shedload parameters
those parameters are the inputs
you've got all the end
q parameters plus any other parameters you chose you kernel actually
lengthscale inactive redundant parameter in the grammar article
grammar grammar are
because they appeared together yeah
but actually i find in practice i often using both just a so the alking scale right
this point
i i have like a choose your own adventure i guess you guys you're the
playstation generation so you never read choose your own adventure books
there were these dumb box and you need the page and it says if you
do this code page forty seven and if you do not go to page fifty
anything you wanted and trying to invert it together
because life is what would say you die horribly even by the monster
that's what we had to do before we had powerful computers
just think they had the machine learning the goal that statistics
also it turned out
okay so
by the time i some demos
okay so uh this
so you know you've already seen i love that's man so he's gonna come up again
okay so the stick man data let's have a look at it again
there's a stigma running
nineteen ninety are
get there
o is they
head daejeon
on the data
it's quite nice actually disappointingly good this
when i read it
okay so
something slightly confusing is this gonna be to defend
is computing a background grayscale
o it doesn't come out very well
them okay so
that's annoying
what you see in the latent space is the gritting had a massive grading together
nicely as the blue line that does this circle here
is a jump actually a big jump
so the circles right there then jumps across there
because outlines coming in there so it's not a fully formed circle so it's difficult to see
the background grayscale is is actually trying to indicate
jacobian manifold is trying to indicate when the manifolds being walked quickly and actually it's
pretty constant across here it's not being bent too much better way of trying to
visualize when there's a lot of strong bending the manifold that they call magnification factors
i'm gonna be different from the gray scale used the end
but what we can do with these models in this
as we can make our little man
always had gone
otherwise it's not looking more like a visit
we can make a run
and we can even get angle that's the thing i loved about when i first
in the jubilee and i'm unfortunately showing it to with the duty and first
so the angle yeah
that's why
these lines should not be on top of each other
you can make and dance
raise okay
it doesn't know anything about constraints on the man so looking back is is legs his feet got too big
he can take into unusual positions
but if you say because the data you don't quite know where the data is
so thanks to jim guess he's he's gone
so good morning i'm showing back off from university of manchester
so what i'm going to talk about over the next i guess what forty forty
five minutes is going to be much more
so what's the big o and things the germans just kind of introduced and taught
one of the giant is is give you an overview of some of the ideas
behind OWL
OK i'll be in the an ontology language designed from the start the semantic web
in the time available clearly one can kind of give all the details such language
know forty minutes is not is not enough time to do that what i'm going
to try and do is give you a feel for some of the motivation behind
the choices that are in there
and also a little bit of the details of the language so that you can
go and chase them yourselves
this is probably too much material in this slide valve get through but tends to
some of the things that you can look at kind of offline but the idea
with this is to give you some of the motivation behind OWL and some details
of the language so some of the things i'll say what kind of resonate with
what was just introduced and hopefully will encounter things that people talk about later on
during the day
so some of this is going to not for this is kind of
to a certain extent motherhood and apple pie for people who are kind of involved
in the semantic web world we've got this notion that the original kind of first
generation web is very much enabled by the use of standard some standard infrastructure that
might people to build applications on top of it so we have to understand the
mechanisms to transport standard mechanism for representation things like HTML TCP IP and so on
and this made it easier for people to build some applications on top the would
inter operate OK
but the
the first generation so i kind of early web pages were essentially handwritten HTML OK
handcrafted we've moved on to things being generated but the page is largely are intended
for human consumption
it is that these pages to be looked at and to be read rather than
targeted at a machine processing so what kind of moving towards this is more
making no web sources accessible to to automated processes
and the problem OK again this should hopefully be kind of fairly obvious is that
a typical web pages have rendering information about markup and so on
the content of this page is is accessible to me OK i can read this
page and i know that it's about the w three c
but the kind of the underlying content is not really particularly accessible to computers OK
if we're going to going to do this we made across natural language understanding and
so on which fabio against me talk a little bit later on
but essentially this this
information here is targeted at me is that as a person
so the idea is that is to move towards the semantic web we can provide
resources which are more amenable to machine processing and do this by some some markup
or some additional information describing the content and function of these particular resources
and this is where the notion of the ontology comes in to provide some vocabulary
for the annotations and the and the the the the ontologies to ensures that we
have some kind of standard language that we're all talking so the annotations that we
make we can understand and we can share
OK and the kind of prerequisite for this kind of approach is that we have
some standardized language to do this representation so we have to have a common syntax
is that we can agree to share this same the semantic web passing around
in order to do this
OK we have notions of metadata so we're mucking up our resources or describing resources
with descriptions of their content that's all very well
but it's no good unless everyone speaking the same language OK so we have to
ensure that kind of speaking the same language terminologies can help us to do this
terminologies controlled vocabularies and so on so they can kind of limit the the language
that we use to describe things
provide some shared common vocabulary
even sharing a terminology isn't sufficient OK because we can we can now use the
same terms we could use the same language but we could actually have different underlying
interpretations of those terms because maybe terms that have have different meanings in different contexts
so the idea that the ontology is that we move on from the kind of
just just sharing the terms and actually have some explicit representation of the
the kind of understanding of the meaning of those terms and this again will help
us in sharing interoperating and moving information around
the activities that we need to go through in order to build a semantic web
including things like annotation is we need to associate metadata with our resources
we need to integrate things so james talking very much but it's all kind of
white notion that the
semantic web is distributed the information from many different places that we need to bring
and then we might perform some inference over information about when i say inference i
just mean kind of fairly general
machine processing to try and kind of either understand or gets more out of the
to the the information that we have
so this this doesn't necessarily have to be heavy weight logic style inference can be
quite lightweight OK we could be using some kind of taxonomic reasoning for example just
so the idea of inferences we just kind of captain the notion that once we
pulled all this information and to get together we may need to do something with
and again the key goals here are to to try and interoperation and sharing information
so a lot of the work that we've seen in the kind of semantic web
has focused on the definition of a collection or stack of languages so there's a
kind of on this slide here on
the aside on the left hand side there's this kind of idealised notion of the
stack don't want to go into too many details of this this is just trying
to show that there are
a variety of languages some of which are all talk about what about the next
half-hour so
they provide some basic machinery that we can use to kind of represent information and
these then facilitate the notion of using annotation integration inferences we cannot move all of
this the
the stack and i'll say a little bit clear about kind of RDF and RDF
schema and so on
so one general point
i think this this sort of relates back little to to one of the points
that you made when he was talking about
kind of kids building wars models and so on is a lot of the the
representation languages have this kind of common approach to the use what one might call
an object oriented model i don't we kind of object oriented in terms of an
object oriented programming job and so on but the idea that
we we can think of the world where we think about domain in terms of
things like objects or instances are individuals is an element of the domain are going
to describe and then we can group together into classes or we may use the
word types of concepts and so on which are generally collections of sets of objects
that share some common characteristics
and then we have relationships of properties kind of
sets of pairs of two of things the relationship between things
and in general
this kind of language is we that when we when we approach to modeling using
this this kind of paradigm we can get languages which were kind of well understood
we can formally specify them they're kind of relatively easy to use this there those
a very dangerous turned to
and using relatively easy to use subjective decision but they and their amenable to machine
processing so we'll see that kind of language is i'm going to talk about adopt
this kind of approach where we have objects are going to talk about we group