one thing i should point out before you forget is that if you're interested in
using this software looking at restricted boltzmann machines deep belief nets convolutional nets and such
if you go deep learning don't see is that all the data u on the source code
you know you'll see a lot of different energy be implementation of convolutional nets
there is deep learning models
there's something that i'm gonna talk about the multimodal neural language models you know if
you're interested in doing face recognition facial expression recognition
with deep belief networks you'll find a lot of different
tools and codes
coding over there if if if you're interested
so now we're gonna we're gonna talk a little bit more about more advanced models
just give you a flavor so this is more about what's been happening in the
deep learning community in the last you know a few years
what i'm gonna do is
i'm gonna give you a little
a brief introduction into
something is called deep boltzmann machines
these are very similar models the deep belief networks but they are have
so differences
and then got show you how we can start looking at learning more structured models
or more robust models
as well as getting in the problem and the interesting problem of transfer learning one shot learning
and we'll see some of
and now then i'm going conclude by looking at multimodal learning so this is where
we're gonna look at language images and trying to combine different modalities
together it's been very exciting topic in the deep learning community in particular looking at
you know images speech text or a or a
jointly together
which is what we
talk a little bit about people's machines is sort of
i different classes of models
if you look at the two models
you know structurally they almost look the same but there are some subtle differences
in particular deep boltzmann machines are undirected graphical models so you see there no causal links there
in terms of the deep belief networks inference probably inference in these deep belief networks
is problematic due to explaining away
by the way before i forget i should also point out that i'm gonna put my slides on the web
this evening so you can basically have access
these slides as well
um so deep belief networks inference deep belief networks the proper inference is quite problematic
due to something called explaining away so people basically do some approximation to it
there is also greedy pre-training so if you want training deep belief networks typically you
just go to the trail is bilayers
there is no joint optimization of all the layers right that's that's that's a drawback
of these models and then if you look at the approximate inference algorithm for deep
belief networks there's no bottom-up top-down
so these are sort of
kind of differences that both missions were designed to to address
and i'm gonna show you some of them
so what is it both machine it's basically markov random fields um
u half dependencies between hidden variables
right but all connections undirected
so what's the difference between
restricted both machines and enables machines well
if you look at deep boltzmann machines you basically have these two additional terms in the definition of the model
and these traditional terms these actually modeling correlations between each one managed to manage to energy
very much similar to what deep belief nets are trying to do
there's one particular
structure in these models is that's you can combine bottom-up and top-down so if you
look at the probability of a particular variable he knew being wrong it depends on
what's coming from above
and what's coming from below
and this is unlike many other existing models if you look convolutional neural nets models
or if you look deep belief networks so if you look at age max
the nodes
the next lecture hall at all
by that come
when they are not
any of the you compute dissimilarity function which is based on the feature vector
at their value school could
which is operated on children that
so this request functional is a lie
until the complete
if you could
can you
so far
support vector
the next step is nice
this is a popular model
my mother
it's simple to implement and it is also
there is
well one of the reasons quite popular in that
simple computations
but here
full text classification and i will give examples
i think it
i would give an example would used
such an
the classifier with music for motion detection sex
it can
not that
in if the at
it's quite useful
the posterior probability that a new previously unseen objects belong to a certain class
given the features
of the object
is computed the the problem is that individual features are related to the class
it could be clear you need more people so compute x
the probability
so given
object representation
according to the feature vector or individual words
we compute the probability
class of a given configuration of
this a generative model we use these rules
translate into the probability that would give us
which we can easily
so it's broken at some prior probabilities
and by the rules these
by the probability that this configuration certain of course
it is if we do ranking
well actually
we compute the most likely
it is defined to be that of course
we can
it's all in the way
two weeks this equation
but still the probability that does that
of word
of these words p
let's see people
given a certain cluster
there is very difficult to compute it
well we assume
independent of the features
which language is not
always valid
so we can add to more
the probability of the certain
class g
what w i put in the sky classification
author of the
today is going to be 1 of the more difficult lectures so
but on your thinking caps as they say elementary school the topic is going be
what's called a convolution
the convolution something very peculiar that you functions together 3rd function but has its own
special symbol
effort to asterisk is the universal symbols used for that
so that's the dual function of t which bears very little resemblance to the ones
effort distorted where are
I'm going to give you the formula for it right 1st that there are 2
ways of motivating and both the important
there is a formal motivation which is why it's talked into this section on plus
transform and the formal motivation is the following suppose we start with all plus transform
2 different from those 2 functions
now the most natural question to ask is plus transform a really a pain to
calculate is from
old will plus transforms is it easy to get new ones and the 1st thing
1 would cost something functions as easy I give you some transforms but a more
natural question would be suppose I wanna multiply effort ingenuity is this sum hopefully some
neat formula by multiply the productivity take a product of these 2 is that some
neat formula for all plus transform of that product that would simplify life greater
and the answer is there is no such formula and then it will be
well we will not give up entirely suppose we ask the other questions
I instead I multiply that will plus transform could that be related to something I
cook up out of Africa ingenuity could it be the something about fugitive and that's
what the convolution is for the answer is that this time this G of X
turns out to be the water transform of convolution the convolutions and that's 1 way
of defining it is the thing that you should functionality but you should put in
there in order that it's will plus transform turned out to be the product of
that event types you
I'll give you the moment the formula for it but I think I will
1 of the quarter minutes of wealth through the of motivation as to why this
should be such a formula
now I will calculate this out to the end because I don't have time but
here's the reason why they should be such a formula and you might suspect and
therefore will be worth looking for
it's because remember I told you with all plus transform came from the plus transform
was a continuous analog overpowers areas so that when you ask a general question like
that place to look for is if you know what analogous ideas state doesn't work
something like that were there so here I have a power series summation A x
to the end
remember you can write this in computer notation is a then to make it look
like effort FFT
and the analog is between and is turned into T when you turn a power
series into plus transform and X gets turned into the negative that's 1 formula distance
the other
OK so there's a formula for f of x this is the analogue of plus
transport and similarly G of X here is summation b and x to the end
now again the naive question would be well suppose I multiply the 2 coefficient corresponding
coefficients together
and add up that power series summation a and B n times x to be
is that somehow at some related to f and g and of course everybody knows
the answer to that is the the relation with
but suppose instead I multiply these 2 guys well in that case I'll get a
new power series I don't know what it's coefficients let's write them down was just
call them and
so what I'm asking is that this corresponds to the product of the 2 will
plus transform and what I want to know is is there a formula
which says that CNN is equal to something that can be calculated calculated out of
the AI and clear
know the answer to that is yes there is
and the formulas is called the convolution but now
you could figure out this formula yourself you figure
anyone smart enough to be interested in the question in the 1st place is smart
enough to figure out what the formula is and will give you great pleasure to
see that it's just like the formula for the convolution that I'm going to give
you that
so what is the formula for the convolutions OK hang on right there you not
going to like it
but you didn't like the formula plus transforming the are usual wiser grown up getting
it but it's a mouthful to swallow is something you get used to slowly and
you'll get used to the convolution equally
so what is the convolution of and it's a function calculated according to the corresponding
it's a function of T
it's the integral from 0 to 3 all
half of you you is a dummy variable because I know it's going to be
integrated out when I do the great G of the might the think
that's it I didn't make it up and just very bad news
40 do when you see a formula that seems to you
well courses try calculating just just to get some feeling for what kind of guy
you know
what was that was let's try some examples of what it was calculated
what would be a modest beginning
was calculated convolution of RTD with itself
0 barrier let's calculate the convolution just so that you can tell the difference of
the with the square
a t squared retrieved articles
but the convolution is symmetric F star G is the same thing as she start
with but that that explicitly I forgot to last period so tell the guys who
came to 1 o'clock lecture you know something that they
well that's a theory it's community this operation is computed other words now
with latent semantic analysis this mmr reranker since performed
consistently better than the other two
and then things another
feature way
explore a little bit is that because IMF staff reports was written in such a
way that
each section contains different paragraphs and in
each paragraph since
relatively independent and the first sentence of each paragraph is kind of seems to be
kind of
condensed content in in that sentence to represent the whole paragraph so we explore a
little bit this paragraph lead based method and the result is
better than
previous methods
but this this is
this is even if we sum up with some will try to summarize the report
paragraph by paragraph if the position feature is only giving a we to one where
that which means the centroid method plays a more significant role in that case
the result is not so much better but only one u
he is
he much higher rates to the position feature the results even improves much better
and so
i don't have some much time but i think we can now report
sure some of the insights
we can see through these experiments
so all the change of the parameters of the summarisation methods in the ranking
the reranker has an evident effect on summary of those
and compare rate has much more significant effort on the summary content sometimes it is
not so obvious
well just from this to this kind of evaluation is this kind of quantitative evaluations
but when you look at
when you really look at the out food
o yourself you can see that the ten percent summary much much more better than
the five percent summary but these these these you can you cannot show is it's
not showing this kind of quantitative evaluation methods
and then different IDF database seems that's not have a significant effect
on the evaluation results
however this is also related to what kind of compression rate you you take
the problem is that in the end comparing with the baseline methods the MEAD methods
is not evidently better
so there might be a problem with the summarisation methods are there might be a
problem with the evaluation methods and i don't know what is exactly the problem and
and here
to hear about your opinions about it
and and the with the semantic analysis evaluation we know there is there is a
limitation it has to do with what kind of semantic spaces available for to use
because the results can change
can change dramatically depends on the sixth semantics space you use
and then these lexical overlapping methods they are designed only for comparing
system extracts to human extract means
the the one that the
the model summary hard appears summary compared to
our extracts themselves they take origin of sentences from the document they are not like
written by stuff
and stuff not that kind of summary
so so it is not
well it tries to
you know actually that is quite remarkable in the sense that
just because some of the people who are involved in that really famous it's making
bayesian nonparametrics very fashionable suddenly with people who were not interested in what
but there are some really neat results here
i just would like to
to know roughly
what what questions are being asked in this area
and what kind of results you know what
it's kind of involved in formulating these results
okay so
well if drawn here is a cartoon
of the set of probability measures
in this case this would be actually is a set of probability measures over three possible events and so on
like a
say a coin was
three sites are like say coin with two sides and it can land on the edge right this
this is heads tails this is no
now you can imagine that if you have like if you have a forty went
then you would get something like guitar trader
right this is the simplex
this is the domain of cherokee distribution if you will
and if you may if you view
at more and more events in the general case
of of probability distributions is usually infinite
then you really get something that's
i mean that the
description is really something like that
trying only in in a very high dimensional space
okay so this
these these every single point in the set here is
the probability distribution
and the corner points
the extreme points of probabilities on a single event which place all the mass on a single event can
now what is
what is the model
statistical model statistical model is a family of probability distributions
like the family of all gasses
so you can imagine this you to be
the set of probability
represent a set of probability distributions on the real line
and then the set of all guassian distributions would be some subset of the and i've i've
i've i've drawn that here and include
so there is some subset of the set of probability distributions
and then if we have a particular
some particular model is a single point here
all right now
let's say not
the distribution that actually has generated our data
we don't know which was which distribution that is but there are some true distribution
which is actually generated our data
and now we try to find this distribution
positing a model
and then estimates the model parameter from the data
and if if we have chosen the right model and are estimators good then as
we see more and more data we would get close to the estimate that we
get we get closer and closer to the true distribution
very basic idea of of statistical inference
all right now so what can happen
if we
if we choose a model then that's an assumption right it's a modeling assumption
one thing that could happen is that we get lucky an hour the true distribution is actually inside the model
that's good
and then there's another case which is
the true distribution is
outside the model and in statistics is this case is called misspecification now so we
say that the model is misspecified
if the true distribution of the data is not inside the model
you know you can ask
in that case we can ask if we if we see more and more data
how quickly do that's our estimate converge to the true model how much data do
we need to get a good estimate of what the
the real distribution is
and in this case we can additionally ask what
since the true distribution is not in there
policy estimator going to be and so i would certainly like to see in this case is
our estimate the estimate you get something that's over here that's as close as possible
to this rather than something over here because we have to define what close means
in this space but
and this is in
one of the year all the more theoreti from a theoretical point you one of
the motivations for using nonparametric models
because essentially if you use
and humans
are able to understand
single plants
hundred milliseconds this by the number of objects with different pose scale ends up instead
are within the scene
we distinguish in computer vision three main tasks for recognition
we call categorisation within cluster
classification for reasons why we want to distinguish between
faces versus faces
or identification
two five within class classification
and parameter estimation we have some although and one of the parameters
first all is for instance of
or when one is banned the degree of
at this
fashion inspiration and so on
and here here we are going to look for categorisation task
we are going to discuss
about categorization specifically
turning an image in two thousand visual words
categorisation possible
and focusing on categorisation
image representation although i'm going to discuss
originating from this community
where the back of
one more than
i've been used as a tool to describe the commons
histogram of the frequency
of some words within
the documents
every word
wasn't in it and set of topics
is use it more often than others
and for instance
the were brain
optikom are more users in
it is in government
business commenced
and the point is that that if i give you
people like these
that's like these
there are many things to read if you want understand
what is the topic of the document
but if i give you some
he works
light rain
the brain and so on
probably you can guess
which is that category
of the documents by looking just
thank you
this means that
even without syntactic
we can guess
by looking
so more within the government
the idea is that you and i said to works
by looking at which words
the vocabulary correspond to which topics
a system is trained to look at the histogram
of the frequency of the words
to understand
which is the cost of the document
and in representing
we can two problems
the first one is that
comments have different lengths
and the second one
is that
there are some
works that are not
realising you've got to discriminate between documents
first and or themes and so on
text mining community
they introduced
they TF IDF
two normally
histogram with respect to the number of the words
within a document
the idea
is use it too
caps two and going out
not significant words
for discrimination
and in computer vision
recently we have using this similarity
to build representation for images
we want to look for
so we we should
look for some markets in the image
and we should describe this marking the image
and and then we should be able to
regional vocabulary
and then we can build an histogram over the visual vocabulary to represent the images
so you know that the bag words model in a very intuitive way
what we're doing is
we have an image
and we're using
a collection of building blocks
and here the building blocks are simple
just to
o point out that
most of the bag of visual words model
you know take into account the geometric information
of the image
and here are the basic representations
you have a different class of of the image
you somehow find a dictionary of the building blocks
and you are presented your class
as an histogram over the visual vocabulary so the problem is in finding a way
these are works
defending the and when we have a vocabulary which should be in the vocabulary
four images
you could say this slide summarise the framework
one of the framework is used in computer vision for
categorisation task
this is composed by two park the landing party
and the initial part
and deleting parts
what he wanted to
to learn visual vocabulary
that often
useful to describe the image
and that the visual vocabulary
we chose struck some features from the image
we should represent
this feature
after that
we can
by using
the previously learned representation
and when a new part
we can represent
by the previous learning vocabulary and then we can use
the models
for categorisation
we look at the representation issue first and they are forced steps in representing images
and it's also clear that heartbeat signal something very complicated so it's some some three-dimensional
preceding vector
so it should be a subspace
and there some
mother components here
and some some for things so with this you can see that that these would
willing to trust
the other is not
and if you actually compared to these up in this case then the matrix is
rather grey and black which means that there's no real stable projection that can be
you can use any other algorithm says well OK so
so we have used this as well with any g
and in energy often you have
the modern images have three hundred channels so you do an ICA
it's very hard to actually show three hundred channels tour
two and d
because it doesn't have the time to look at all these things and after looking
at twenty channels anyway it's
you see always the same thing
the question is can we reduce the number of interesting channels such that
then these have to look at less
and this is a particular experiment that i don't want to
go into very much but it's measures somebody in the electric field magnetic fields in
OK so
this is the
and MEGA it so she you don't have the slide in the new
the note
so it's
shielded room
and this is the shielded room PTB in berlin
and you see that plane are
m g
that so this is the door
which contains all these squid electrodes and it's about forty something i think forty nine
and the d c
imaging measures
other than the image e four d actually but seen here tries to find the
senior currents in your brain somewhere here in the auditory cortex
OK so
an image is very expensive because about two or three million depends on the type
in the room like that also another half million
so so so this is the reason why we wouldn't be using this for BCI
experiments it's something that you cannot put into the home somebody
so here's the separability matrices
and if you look at them
i mean
in this case for example jade you see you see this there's no structure and
it all looks very bad
in this case you see that there some structure
and there's a big
the noise subspace
and it's now interesting to i mean you will remove this one
and you try to get these one-dimensional subspaces or towards a low dimensional subspaces and
look at them
OK so
in fact i showed show here too
three one-dimensional
so this is the drift
of the energy which is normal
it's very strong signals to some
particularly noise
fifty hertz
because it's measured in germany and here is the
the third component
which is the signal of interest
if you look at it
so so what did we do
and actually i will not discuss very much about the the medical content but what
what did we do is we did and i see a decomposition of these
forty of old channels
we found the separability matrices there were grey and for some algorithms
which means unreliable
and structured father algorithms to means
quite reliable
and then we looked at the most reliable components and the most reliable components turn
out to be addressed artefact
fifty hertz artefact
and the signal of interest and it makes perfect sense that the artifact is something
very stable the plugs always on the road in the same place
and just to get you an idea of this this is a dipole
in the auditory cortex
the paradigm was that they were
thirty seconds thirty seconds of music but in fact it was but not
not to the
for example
we use
beta one four dead
bid for home my beats eight four TV
and for watching and affordable all-cash function i don't know what function was used by
by the smart guy maybe you simply
court of all characters in this war
and then
divided by module a all this all the time
and for this
beta in place
you saying OK we're using
fair enough long binary strings and this is that all these
and what we can do
we can incorporate all documents simply stating b because the took using back towards the
interesting thing about words in the document
so what you are doing
again this example
that is
reading a book so we
thirteen two one
that belongs to daddy
said setting to one
the to do that belongs to
he is if not skipping stop words
retaining one what is going to ring et cetera et cetera so
if all matrix cells flowers
if selected
pretty long binary stream
and if you
selected good test functions with is not that
uniformly distributed this one
what we do
it will compress
are also you know matrix so and all columns semantic
became much smaller
number of call a number of roles in this matter be simply a number of
these here
OK so it seems like
she a lot the information we work with this
we put them all together in one of them is that some words in our
the same the same crash called how we can search and the structure and doesn't
have any sense
but actually can
so if you have query monday
which again from this example
so what we can do we can things that this is a document
and create a binary string for this
then you can our compressed metrics
and if you look for
we're all in this
in this new compress matrix
well we have to be set
you know that in the target documents this these should be why because the documents
that contain this work
of course of course you have some number of documents because we have this correlation
because different kinds
i have this one b
that's not really in this world but what we can do that
what we can do that
we can look
through this metric
we can
we can select only documents that
are supposed to have a lot of work that we're looking for
then we can a lot of these documents and naive scan over the documents and
that its
again our search engine
now can judge and in war and peace and all russian literature on these cheap
and this can be done in
ten seconds
you have a small structure if you have if you like this all this has
functions and is selected for long
binary stream
and that's it
we created the structure compress and extraction
the fun
this signature file
i saw
articles about signature files maybe
and we are talking about signature in this application because there are other signature file
hosting service
but in this application last time i saw
six articles about signature file maybe ten years ago
i tried to implement signature first member thirty years ago
and they held
a lot of helpful during this period of time
right now it's not so important because you will see that
this is a good combination by this my this money guy
actually combine
three technologies
that we do
learned later except scan
user has
will filter and can
we already talked about can and will talk about passion littlefield on the next lecture
signature file like
jumping ahead
you know that you can compress and you don't know how to do this well
but we press
more than they did not seem to compress into the
a lot of the compression because he lost some information about you managed to fix
this you know that even if you
losing some information you can you can manage to a
search for
signature file is very good structure from this point of view but this description that
there's a naive implementation of all this stuff it's a bit outdated and now people
are thinking
from this point of view
o thing about
in the
if your extremely smart guy
i think that at this moment say OK
it's enough
i tried this stuff i tried this
you've brought me many new collection that is going to be indexed by
by my signature flower because
we have seen
our characterization in terms of continuous optimisation
and we have seen how great going hold to find dominance
now we are shown application of dominant set which is not our first application whether
many different ones actually
we applied
the dominant set framework to image segmentation
the problem is very
easy to state image segmentation is the classical
clustering problem actually are given an image
the objects to be clustered pixels
and then you want to segment
image into
maximally coherent
this is one of the
basic problems in computer vision
this is the first step for several other albums like
object recognition and many other more sophisticated so it's very important basic problem
this in this application the objects to be clustered are just because
the graph we create is just a graph where
it's always about it
this graph
and we have an edge weights which reflect the similarity between the
we have defined the notion of
the dominant set but we don't talk about how
i can partition
set of objects into the
so there are several ways to do that but probably
the simplest one
what we call which was called the of strategy
it's very simple actually i just fine
the first dominant set which is usually quite large in terms of numbers of objects
i just wrote
the dominant set the way we apply the argument over the remaining part of the
graph and so on and so forth
until a cluster of objects made there's almost
this is actually
very in a simple strategy that we actually used in this
image segmentation experiments
we found segment for the weights so
there are several
alternatives to this actually the end of the talk will also describe
the more sophisticated way
to find
maybe overlapping
some applications it's important to have overlapping class
OK so
in order to apply this framework we have to define a notion of similarity of
course you are just in the last year of pixels
so what we did actually was to
to do exactly the very same experiments that
i a group from berkeley did a few years ago
you can dramatic example she was overtly they introduced what they call the normalized cut
four aways classes
which is based on the idea of
trying to find the best possible way of captain graph into pieces
you know two or more pieces in order to
i have a coherent regions and this leads to a spectral class
the nice thing about this approach is that it starts from a graph theoretic problems
how can i
divide the graph into two max career regions and it ends up with the characterisation
in terms of i eigenspectrum
OK so in that paper was apparently people i'm is the leading journal in computer
vision and pattern recognition is that police transactions machine in that paper which actually was
published in the conference years before
they did this some experiments
to see whether they normalized gap approach were not only missing station
so the proposal
is similarity measure which is quite common actually
are we distinguish they distinguish actually we
we we put ourselves in exactly the same setting and there's just
let us compare with the results
so for example they
use of graylevel images so this means that each pixel
it is characterized by a single number
between say zero and one he says we're actually sees the degree level of that
or we might have
color images in this case each pixel is characterized by three numbers and depending on
the space color on the color is that you're using a different tribal
they use what is called the age as we tried
and so
associated which big so there is a fact three numbers
this two similarity measures work really well
in cases where you have
a texture image
c is the role whatever they don't work because if you apply either of these
similarity measures the zebra will be segmented into black and white striped
the similarity between pixels in this case we need something more sophisticated instead of missions
similar direct similarity between two weeks we try to measure the similarity
all the windows of excel centre on that it's
so what they did was to use
a bank of filters
filters and that scales and this ends up with the vector
associated to each
the article itself which gives information about
OK so text information around the particular pixel
case we have two vectors coming the back of filters and just measure the similarity
between the field the
the vectors using the very same for actually
we take the exponential minds
the quadratic distance euclidean distance between
the the feature vector and then we divide this parameter which is given
this is the way
white standard way to transform it distance interesting
these are some results this is typically used by
berkeley grew
this is the whole image
this is what we get is in dominant sets
this is what they got using normalized cut
one you can see is
the qualitative results results much better
all the types of
of measurements error rate is false negative plus false positive over total number of examples
instead of using here you can use the couple
so rate false alarm rate or hit rate precision or hit rate fraction of selected
to people depending on the domain people use different different things you can use balanced
error rate which is the average of the errors of the positive class and other
than ever the negative class and in you know text processing people use the f
measure which i'm writing you hear from memory and you can then also vary the
threshold as i said before and if you the special you can plot the ROC
curve you can plot the rate lift curve or you can plot the precision recall
curves this gives you know
an idea
what is a risk functional
so risk functional is is the function of the parameters of the learning machine assessing
how much it is expected to fail
on the given task
and giving examples already right focused mutation problem and the error rate is going to
be a functional one minus the area under the rocker so whatever
measurement or objective you set yourself about the performance of your learning machine that is
going to define for you a risk functional for regression people use most of you
mean square
so in that case you taking the output of your learning machine and the desired
output making the different squaring and averaging so it's the average discrepancy
between the target we want to achieve and what you obtain from your learning machine
what do you irresponsible well that's
that's used for training writer once you've defined how you're going to be measuring how
are you going to be performing
then you want to optimise its and so you're going to
very the weights of your learning machine
such that you're going to be optimizing the risk functional you want to minimise the
risk and that can be done with a variety of methods including gradient descent mathematical
programming assimilated milling genetic algorithms all means of going down
in the beaks you know
surface of the that the risk functional defines in parameter space so this is a
very simple drawing in which you know considering the there is only one parameter in
your learning machine
your risk functional defines know peaks and valleys and what you want is to find
the minimum which is the w star your weight your optimal weight in reality you
have occasional spanners space we have very complex high dimensional surface which trying to the
and so we're going to be continuing that in the next lectures so will be
defining risk functional and defining ways of optimizing it typically gradient descent
in summary for you know this introduction lecture with linear threshold units that are analogous
to neurons we can build many different kinds of learning machines including linear discrimination it's
functions which are you know this which is special case in the naive bayes algorithm
the kernel methods and that they're all methods that are linear in the parameters not
necessarily in the input components and neural networks which are non-linear both in the parameters
and the not in the input components decision trees that have also elementary nodes that
to make a simple linear decisions don't just thresholds in that case and the architecture
of the learning machines have hypercritical hyper parameters of which we are going to be
talking in the next lectures and those may include the choice of the basis functions
so which phi functions you're using in the perception which kernel using in the kernel
machine the number of units and how arranged in the case of the neural network
and learning meets it means fitting the parameters of the weights and also the hyper
parameters and one has to be aware of the fit versus robustness trade-off from so
it's not necessarily best to obtain a decision boundary that learns exactly well the training
examples what needs to care which we need to care about is how well we're
going to be doing on our future examples that we haven't seen training data and
in that respect using a linear decision boundary sometimes better than using a more complex
non-linear decision boundary and if you want you know to learn more about machine learning
there are a lot of good sources which include the well-known textbook of duda hart
installed one pattern classification the book of to show any interest freedman the elements of
statistical learning
days chapter that covers some of the material i've presented to you here in the
the perspective of you know going from percent crimes two kernel methods and vice versa
presenting some simple algorithm could have algorithm that presented today and some other ones and
then there is the this book i mentioned before that using four and for the
lectures that i'll be talking about this week and that includes also the city was
the data of the of the challenge on
the features section
and so thanks very much for your attention and you will see
what are you should know was talking too fast know looking at the clock in
the morning
anybody wants hold
this problem
that's question of
you want that
what about you know about
that's actually that's good question first that because you don't know very much in the
audience yet but so should have started is that we were thought that you have
it so the whole asking you know we were euphoric which so who who in
this class is still it's preparing a phd degree
for each
data point which tells us which clusters belong to
now consists of setting the latent variables of these data cases to be equal to
each other so when we think grouping we mean all of these might have the
latent variables z equal to one of these might have the latent variables z equal
to two and all these might have latent variables and equal to three that's what
clustering really means in the latent variable settings and you can think of it just
like classification with missing targets k and the same problem here
in terms of dimensionality reduction factor model so another very common unsupervised learning problem is
i show you some data
the data normally lives in the two dimensional space here in this picture but you
believe that the data has fewer degrees of freedom in two here we think it
only has one degree of freedom plus noise and you'd like to find a low
degree of freedom model
it captures the data you actually saw
so that's the kind of dimensionality reduction or
factor model kind of problem and that's exactly like regression with missing targets
so you can think of it as if i really knew this continuous
underlying cause as the generated each data point in this would just be a regression
problem right would just be trying to fit a straight line here but because i
don't know that i have to do something a little bit more clever and n
that involves the kinds of things that apple mentioned principal component analysis and factor analysis
which we'll talk about the intellectual so both of these problems have this graphical model
and unobserved latent variable and the observed data variable if this variable is discrete multinomial
that it looks like clustering and this variable is continuous and it looks like dimensionality
let's now see a little bit more about why
the the learning problem is hard
so as i said before
we're going to focus on the case where some variables are always unobserved is going
to be these edges so we have some joint distribution over x and z this
is the data in the latent variable which we don't observe
and we can rewrite it of course as a prior distribution on z
so this might be your prior on you know
each cluster how often you think it's used to populate it and then this is
a conditional distribution what does the data look like if it's from cluster one if
its own cluster two and so on
OK now what we want to maximize is the law
probability p of x right and to get that we have to sum over z
and then when we take the we get this log of the sun OK and
so when i try
estimate these variables x invaders and there are no longer independent estimation problems
in the first case i could just estimate pz this parameter theta z by just
observing the Z's and fitting the distribution and could estimate all these parameters theta x
by conditioning on z taking all the data cases where z equals one and fitting
the data for those taking technology the data cases where z equals two and fitting
the data for those and so on
i can do that here these variables are now coupled
what are we going to do well there's two
approaches and actually
although this slide is sort of making fun of
naive approach the naive approach is actually sometimes just as good as the fancy algorithm
approach to talk but when me pretend that we don't know that and let's let's
make fun of the naive approach so
we wanted do is we could say
oh well
like you know
who cares
so we have this gives some but you know
we have seen complicated likelihood functions in the past it doesn't really bother us let's
just take the gradient of the likelihood function and whatever the gradient is that's what
the gradient is the eldest followed in maximum likelihood learning using gradient optimizers just like
we always
and that's fine you can actually compute the gradient of these models by taking the
gradient of the log and you get a term which is one over the marginal
probability and you can compute the gradient and attack it directly with the gradient optimizer
of two things
and the what starts boiling and is so
that's when water and steam coexist
what i'm saying
certain conditions of pressure and temperature and volume
so that
water ice and steam will coexist
that is a unique situation you cannot get to that for any other mean
and that temperature we will call
plus two seven three point one six
in this absolute units
so basically what you have done by going to absolute units is you shifted the
zero to more natural point that all graphs meet
then you define one degree
to be so that two seven point one six of calvin brings you to the
triple point of water
if you find that confusing i'm just saying the boiling point of water is not
a fixed number you go to the mountains changes
but only under one condition can water and ice
and steam coexist
that cannot be you cannot get that any other way to everybody will agree on
that particular situation that will be called to seven point one six killed
now that's the rule
you can see degrees centigrade
not supposed to degree kelvin
that's a big deal made in a lot of books
i keep forgetting so in fact i forgot again
and nothing terrible has happened to me so i don't think
you should pay too much attention to whether you can call something degree kelvin or
simply count
i think the purpose of languages to have no ambiguities when is degree kelvin and
i find that you guys don't get confused i don't think that's the big find
video i person will never
great degree help
but having said that i don't hold me to the standards i just don't feel
any affiliation to this particular
completely are artificial and in the convention
but you have supposedly member if you take the GRE or something is not called
the become
OK so as far as we are concerned
the kelvin scale is like the centigrade scale except zero is shifted
two here
that's it
the temperature scale
we will use
the absolute temperature men i t from now on
i'm talking about health
sending a
now that's all about to eat
i mean all about temperature and i'm going to talk about he
he is denoted by the symbol q
you don't ask yourself
what are we talking about when we talk about heat
again let's use your intuitive sense what of what he is
you say a bucket of water i want heated up
and how do you do that you put the bucket on top of something else
which i think is hard
and when the two are brought together somehow
the water begins to feel hard to
so we say we the water
and we say we are transferred heat
people were not sure what really was being transferred
what is the best going from the store
the water
why is it that the store
it was not plugged in is getting cooler than the what is getting hot
there is this edit to call it the calorific fluid
they imagined
this is fluid
which is abundant in hot things
and not stubborn called things when you put hard called together this magical fluid
flows from optical
and in the process heaps of the call
and they decided to measured in calories
so you have to define what the calendar years the what you want to ask
how much he does it take to heat this back
so what
and the rule they made up was to find something called calorie
where the number of calories
you need
it's equal mass of water
and the change in temperature
that's going to be calories
the words if i had a container with ten grams of water
and the temperature went up i'm sorry this same as the water ingress
one gram of water
and you did something to within the temperature went the by seven degrees will have
by definition pumped in seven calories
if this was a kilogram of water
this would be called a
q locality
sometimes they use grams and calories sometimes use kilograms calories but
the definitions are consistently for particular on the ground particularly in the county
now suppose you say
i don't want to just talk about water
i want to talk what he thinks something else
maybe i one
he diagram of copper
so then you write down
the following rule
and one that he takes
he the anything
i think your own favourite material go
and now what he i think we can all appreciate
must be proportional the amount of stuff you're trying to heat up
that's our intuitive notion because i want to go gold
that takes some number calendars of second second identical chunk
by definition that predict the same number of calories
put them together
it is clear that whatever this gallery fluid is need double that
so it's got to be proportional
the mass of the substance
and it's got proportional to what you're aiming for namely an increase in temperature
but this is true for any substance
but it copper wood
i wonder what your heating it's true the heat needed is proportional to mass and
the temperature
so what is it that distinguishes one material from another
you put a number here
and that number is called the specific heat
specific is the property
of anything
we don't understand certain formulas will depend on
certain parameters in the genetic way and some things that depend on the activity
in fact this a similar quantity i mean maybe i'll take a second
if you go to liquid that i said with expanding you can do the same
take a ride
and start eating it
and ask which will expect
if i heated by someone built fifty
what will be proportional to anybody think of what it may be proportional to
depends on the original length of the right the ways that
when we think it's going to be proportional to the length of the right
yeah based on what it had before yes
it's kind i think the way you one way to say that it's taken me
to stay
expand some amount
put another major stick next to it that expand the same amount by definition of
identical things
for the two meters thick will expand by places much
so we put the length of that
so no matter what your heating block of wood block of steve this is true
but then the fact that he
has different effects on copper versus would
is so pain is indicated by putting in number here
alpha is called the coefficient of
linear expansion
and that depends on the material
these are true no matter what your heating
so the specific numbers this corporations this out is the coming going to come in
that those days when you're just making use of the
relations between the different genes you can improve by
what is currently going on in robotics is this collective inference if you want to
do semantic labeling
so you get a point plots and you would like to know if the tree
is the wall in the ground floor can i rather than there are
and then definitely you know that at least locally you should have something like the
smoothness assumption that one pixel voxel in terms of the class label is not so
much different from the neighbouring one right you
walk out of the building you're not expecting that there
road is all of a sudden
stopping and then for the next millimetres the tree and this again i wrote on
the wall in this tree and that we expect somehow because there is a kind
of manifold that locally everything rather than within are changing radical
so again to make use saying my neighboring pixels road i'm more likely to be
a road segment
right so
they also interesting because we may view here relations as constraints so it's not like
you just use the relation to propagate the emails theater
or another one where we
it can work with a whole new options for example web search so definitely if
i do a very good certain
documents that
and you can think about preference relations but definitely you also have to
reference relation between documents here and you know that one is relevant than similar ones
should be relevant well you may also use the similarity relations two
are completely different interesting questions like if you want to have a diversification
you know if i pretend that document should not present that one
so people are using relations all the time or even though they don't give it
in a statistical relational learning but somehow they do it already and we would just
want to go one step had make it more
and of course you can show that relational approach was really outperform standard approach of
course you have to pay the price that may be learning and outer inference is
taking a little bit more complex sometimes but it really pains doing
we skip that one
i think we can also skip that once topic model there
a lot of relational extension for that but you may also use these kinds of
the techniques developed within statistical relational learning with another
so for example if you look at how least my students spend their spare time
they really what youtube what i said well actually not only this but also while
they but also youtube is facing the problem of information broadcasts right so you want
to have the latest movie
the question is where can i don't know what is the best policy to download
if one of my friends already having some parts of the longer movie may be
downloaded there and download the other part from somebody else
many of these big companies nowadays really facing the problem of having complex networks trying
to broadcast information there or i think in the last tory we solve this one
problem as well with the the microsoft the called service update
system the same problem right from microsoft doesn't want to send everybody now because this
is really putting a lot of traffic
since then he would like to have more in a peer-to-peer network like to use
username to one computer they tend to the next one
so to keep the
for the traffic quite low
so here
petrol talk a little bit more about lifted inference to say that we were able
to show that lifted inference techniques so far the belief propagation c right so you
can really show that even in task where belief propagation algorithm already quite fast and
really use you can make use of redundancies and their to speed up computation
yet another one recent applications
we wish we were able to show with relational techniques you can better predict heart
diseases than any of the propositional systems and here we are not talking really about
money because
cardiovascular disease is really cost already the EU
several millions in the year so if we can somehow get that down that's good
but you see something else which is important for relational systems if they are sometimes
more declarative better to understand so what you see here is the
and of local
conditional probability table which is now making use of abstractions
the variables the lower part variables so you test whether a person is female or
and what you see is what you can't see here but you have to trust
may the female subtree
it's much smaller
then the male tree
and that's actually what many medical doctors no but they never had the chance to
validate that using the propositional case so it's known that females
females are women have a much lower risk for heart attacks and may bite and
so on and so on and so it's very easy to sit down with the
expert medical expert that's what we did here and here and the shear
right so
we were even able
the mission to to get new insights or
well trying to illustrate
interesting applications
i think it already popped up then we should ask the question what our relation
i will start
when i come to a halt here
there we go
you can
this but
i don't
thank you
ten two was one of the lower
forty five
o o point six one minus o point one seconds physics works i'm telling you
he was the
period of a pendulum
this is the mass of provided that you can ignore
the mass of the tree itself which is the case
with the band
many pendulums and some we'll see in a three
complex more complicated
simply a mass history
was an object
those pendulums
the physical plant
for instance i could have this compasses
just let it also like this
it's not just simple
or i could have a rule like this would hold true here have been
have but also like
but i can also have also played here
different here
i also like right middle
and does oscillate
now comes the question is how do we deal with that most of you
must have seen that
in the one that i want to address that quite some detail
so physical pendulum and
looks like this
this is an object
and i really a whole year
that will depend on the wall
and it can
without friction can oscillate back and forth
and that the centre of mass this year
precision o
this separation between the
p and all
is the always the centre of mass
you can choose to be any way you want it is no restriction
so you see that this
pendulum is offset
over angle theta and it will start to oscillate back and forth
and the question is what is the
so clearly
we make
but you find gravitational force at point always the centre of mass this is
the force acting
that points
now comes the question and any other forces acting on this
four is is the only
when study
all forces
always happy that we have all forces into account
raise your hand
also known as to be at least one of four
which forces that
english queries that where does it act
so there must be somehow force at p
to hold otherwise it would just start to accelerate down and i'm not even sure
that straight up i doubt that
it may simply be an direction i don't want to think about that
but surely there has to be forced out
every because i mean
when you deal with rotation of objects
this is going to be irrotational
then this equation changes into
paul talk
its moment of inertia
times of far
by all five
is thing that double dot
the angular acceleration
so if i pick
the as my point of origin
then the talk
due to this force does not contribute
my talk equation because
the talk is
i cross as the cross product between the position vector
and the fourth
and this is the action vector two
the centre of
and the position vector from p two p zero
so if we deal with the poor relative to point b
that force
is of no consequence
so i'm going to take is my origin
so now is the question what is the talk relative to
o point p
it's ok across f
or is this this and which is b
f is
but i have a cross product so i have to take the sign of this
angle into account
that is the magnitude of the talk
and the magnitude of that talk them according to my
visual equivalent of vehicles may
he calls the moment of inertia
rotation about that point p
times that double dot
it a restoring torque
the talk
you can do that with your
right hand where you have to learn how to do that the talk is in
the blackboard perpendicular to the blackboard in the blackboard are cross efforts in the back
i have rotated counterclockwise
which is
vector out of the blackboard
OK so i'll talk about algorithms for
solving these problems in different settings for still talk about the stochastic setting where
accessing the words are generated from some distribution and we talk about an adversarial setting
where no assumptions are made about how access and they were to generate
and then i'll talk about solutions for
we use unsupervised learning algorithms to
to solve these problems in both online and batch settings where you have
exploration the line around that you want to use
but you don't have control over which actions
were chosen to
and john we'll talk about
and a number of practical extensions
on the setting
it was a bunch of interesting observations and descriptions
so here's the simplest way
the simplest algorithm that you can think about
and this abstract how any supervised learning algorithm
can be used to
approach these problems but will see that it's not a great solution OK so
let's say that you are in some time step t and you have accumulated
the don't this form so you have an axe
an action taken in the reward for that action and now you want to know
what to do
in the next time step
so you can for each policy pi
you can look at the examples where the policy agrees
was the action taken
and you can somebody words
over those rounds and use it as
some estimate of the value
of the policy and then go the best policy
in the set
so far
right so you choose to policy
maximize the sum of rewards
the previous rounds
where the policy agreed with the action taken because that's the data you can use
for everybody then that policy
it protects the same action
if the policy protects the same action then you can use the word
some indicator of how good that policy is because if it doesn't agree with the
action you don't know what to them is that example
you don't know how to use that example
two very few policy
right if your policy protects take action
and in that example
action to mistake you have no idea of how to use
that example
to tell how good your policy is
because you know your feedback is only partially only know the reward of action to
any policy predict section one so
how the use that
so that's
and the flow of
solving this problem
in india your so you choose
the best that the their so far
based on the examples you have accumulated
you observe
and you predict the same way the leader predicts on that acts
so you choose the action
predicted by the lead and the observe the would you have that example
the you set so that you can
do the same
on next rounds
and this is
basically worked any supervised learning algorithm tries to do is to find an empirical
on the day that you have so far
the problem is that even in the stochastic setting even have access accessing the words
are drawn from the distribution
you can do very well where you started you can be very badly
and substitute kernel for these products and thereby
carry out these algorithms in the representation induced by five
so for instance in the space spanned by all products of all the way could
the could be any natural number
so if you want you can
draw this final decision function as some kind of neural networks this is the
the decision function what it doesn't it compares a test point x
two days
twenty point x i which are the support vectors
so for instance if you did something like digit recognition the support vectors would be
simply did it
so they can comp
input from test point of these digits gives you some values which we set up
characterizes all the notion of similarity
and then these values are linearly combined by some weights
which we follow these with the product of the levels
multiplying the class labels and then there are fed into this
decision function so that's one the architecture
maybe i'll show you a a little
example of little demo for support vector machines
with matlab
so again i will be using a gaussian kernel that you already saw yesterday
only yesterday when i showed you the table you didn't know yet what the kernel
is now u
you know all the details
you even know how to construct the feature space associated with the kernel i think
you know more about kernels that
maybe the majority of people applying it seems nowadays
which is actually this is true
maximizing people applying ESPN's didn't even know that occur in an SVM has to satisfy
some conditions for the whole thing to make sense
but again start with a simple problem
separate this problem so what we see here is the separating hyperplane
actually that is not even simple so here i have parameter sigma
which is the width of the gaussian kernel
you might remember
mister the costs incurred
looks like this so we have the parameter
it's a completely opposite from sigma here
and the are lots of this proud sigma the less non-linear the the kernel you
can actually
in some sense argue that sigma goes to infinity this will
in some sense converge
two was a linear kernel
this kernel here
which is the product so in this case we will be
in this case we would just be computing the hyperplane directly in the input space
to make the signal very large i would expect to find a separation which is
almost a straight line here and you can see that it is almost
so this is the separation is dotted lines are the lines on which they
are there
argument the decision function this function w dot x
plus b
this takes the value plus one minus one
this line and this line and on these lines you can see the support vectors
so now we have three support vectors in this case and all these points back
here i could delete and that would get the same solution so
the case it's pretty obvious for me to delete some of them
trying again and now
not coming
problem more difficult
and then you might wonder what's going to happen because so far the only told
you how to deal with problems that are linearly separable
but actually here i have an implementation that also
can deal with non separable problems although it turns out this probably still separable but
let me make it a bit worse
i don't think this would be linear separation
OK so here we have some points which are on the wrong side of the
so far you don't know how to deal with them but i'll tell you the
but what also you know is that i can still
this is that this is there and the second lecture
in linear algebra
and the i've
but below
my main topics for today
that i put right there a system of equations it's going to be
our example to work with
but let me what are we going to do with
we're going to solve it
and the method of solution will not be determinant
determinants are something that will come later the method will use is called elimination
it's the way every
software package solve the equation
and an elimination
well if it succeeds it gets the answer
and normally it does succeed if the matrix a that's coming into that system is
good matrix and i think this one is
elimination will work will get the answer
in an efficient way
but why don't we as long as we're seeing how elimination work
it's always good to ask how could it fail
so at the same time we'll see
we'll see how elimination decides whether the matrix is a good one or has
has problems
then to complete the answer there is
obvious that back substitution
in fact
the idea of elimination is
you would have thought of it
i mean gaussians
i thought of it before
we did but only because he was
born earlier it's is natural idea
and died earlier two
OK so
but then
and you've seen the idea
but now
the part that i want to show you is elimination expressed in matrix language because
the whole course
all the key ideas get expressed as matrix operations
not as a word
and one of the operations of course that will meet is how do we multiply
matrices a and y
there is a system of equations
three equations in three unknowns
and there's the matrix the three by three matrix that that so this is the
x equal be this is this is our system to solve a x equal
on the right hand side is the vector
two twelve two
well i describe elimination it gets to be a pain to keep writing the equal
signs and the pluses and so on it's it's matrix that the totally matters
everything is in the matrix
but behind is those equations
so what is elimination do
what's the first step of elimination
we we accept the first equation it's OK
i'm going to multiply that equation by the right number the right multiplayer
and i'm going to subtracted
from the second equation
with what purpose what what what that will decide what the multiplier should be
our purpose is to knock out
the x
part of the equation two
so our purpose is to reduce
to eliminate act
so what do i multiply
and again i would do it with this matrix because i can do it short
what what's the multiplayer here what do i multiply
equation one and subtract notice i'm saying that words subtract i like to stick to
that conventional do subtraction
so what
first of all
this is
the key number right
that i'm starting with
and that's called the pivot
put a box around it and write named
that's the first ever
the first ever
OK so i'm going to use
that's sort like the key number in that equation and now what's the multiplier so
i'm going to
my first row won't change
but i mean that the pivot role
but i'm going to use it
now finally let me ask you what the multiplayer
three times in the first equation will not count that three
and because the probability is zero point five we know that t one that does
not satisfy the requirements
so this is the problem is to search for the carry on uncertain categorical data
and how to build a factory next to help in such kind of qualities
we use a probabilistic in british inverted index
so for a list of all the elements in the answer to attributes we have
a list of them and the associated with each list of couples having their possible
value of of the article
and in the show we are those couples in the probability decreasing order
we have acquiring they are here this is
example we have
possible values in the query q
and with their associated the probability for each
and we want to find is
temple t will come at the query q
with probability had and there were twenty three
so in order to do the inquiry we don't
so because we don't want to exact each sample of one want to avoid something
we can do two things the first is called the column pruning
that means if we have a couple of t
and for each element in t
the probability of this element is already smaller than a threshold
that means that each component of this quarrying fallen it's more
of course this you cannot be
match the to q with high probability that the we can prove this temple
the second column pruning means we call it vertically
and the the second of putting technology is called technique is called a rule pruning
so if t only contains two element
and the probability of this element in the query
in the query q is smaller than top say here there are one other point
one to point to the
it's more than ten
because they cannot be matched to two do so you can only matter to this
elements that means
the here this i this component is zero and for the last two components it
can never be higher than the point three
so what the topology only contains p six and p a d six and d
eight we from the property is that all the row pruning we can prove that
the way i element
so this is the idea of how to have probabilistic says well carry on certain
categorical data
next i will introduce a few ranking queries answered data because the data is uncertain
so the semantics of running because of uncertainty we have a few different proposals of
the iraq inquiries
first of all if we can look at this problem is to table and the
first of all we we ignore the confidence column so we have temperature and we
want to rank of data according to the temperature and select the couples with the
highest top too high temperature
and the answer is
r one and r two
but if the data is uncertain
there are a few things we need to pay attention to first of all i
one or two
there may not exist together in one possible world
the returning these two temples may not make sense
in the second missing is in different possible worlds the answer to this query different
so we don't know which one to return
so this is industry the challenges of ranking carries the data we want to first
of all figure out to the semantic of currently rocking curve mean unpublished data
and the second thing is would in order to acquire we know that the semantic
concept surely we need to forward all the possible world by too costly went on
to do that we want to find more efficient algorithms
that's the second challenge
in literature there are different proposals concurrently and they can be categorized into
two classes
the first class is the extension of the traditional ranking is you have it it's
ranking based on optimal objective functions
so we have three different curries
and the the second car ranking based on out the probabilities
the output probability means the probability that
the temple satisfy the query
of course the the two are not disjoint we can do ranking but both based
on objective functions and then i'll put probability the global top cookery is in this
introduce this carries one by one
first of all ranking based on objective functions
so we have a scoring function here for example we want to rank all the
objects according to their temperature
now we have a total order over all the titles here
if we want to find the top two
then the different inquiry only difference in how to select the top two answers
first of all it is called that you topic inquiry
if we unfold all possible worlds we can find top to list of each possible
world there might be different
and they can here we consider each one as that to the mean the order
between the two answers really matters
so we compute the probability of those answers each
in all possible worlds we list them here
and you talk inquiry tried to return
most probable
answer possible world
here are the list are five and three has the highest probability so we were
to five and also as a
this is one proposal
but in some applications we'd we really want to look at those positions pop up
one and the second position separately so here we consider the others separately in all
possible worlds
and computers that probability
we want to return the highest that we want to return the most probable answer
each position
so in position while we find that are five has has the highest probability for
it return
and also in a position to five also has the highest probability so it's also
returned either one
so this is different from the first query because depending on the application we want
to use
and proposal is that in some situations we do not really need to distinguish the
order or the opposition we only care who the top two
one of the best right so we did we do not distinguish of them and
then we compute the probability that one temple lies in the top two all possible
it's a combination of the probability and pollution one and the probability in position to
so we compute them and because in some situations although it's the most probable one
the probability might be very small say zero point zero point five
beyond the rules so that this particular statement you
cannot be proven using rules the way in which is inscribed constructed tells you that nevertheless believe it's true
so people usually state there and around the negative way
so there are certain things you can't prove
but what that means you can't prove using a very specific set of rules
but if you trust those rules and then you can see the statement is true
and this is
very striking thing about the goal state
clearly during was very much aware of this
and that is when i talked about the ordinals ordinal
logic systems that he was trying all the ordinal extension
of these
let's was called
there are logical systems which depend on these things called almost out of a little
bit about what was later but not very much
these things and they wanted to
i have a sort of hierarchy statements used to have your rules are
and then you construct stuever and make you add that's the thing had before and
then you do that again and again and again and again
and you can get more and more and more powerful
methods proof that's the idea so he was
during the studying how far you can go with that kind of thing
i should say
the phrase this is more or less during the
goes which in many respects
is was more general
and it's easy to prove to
describe interesting
this is stating intensive these
aspect of it is not
terms phrased in terms of logical systems and formal systems and so on
which i have to spend the rest of the lecture explaining them
but if you know what a mechanical bull
the system is know a computer is if you know what a general-purpose computers that's
all we need for the state
okay i'll give you an example
here's an example of the sort rules you might be talking about well i
there's a logical statements might be involved to but the basic piece mathematics
is what's called mathematical induction again i'm just talking about the natural numbers
suppose you have some
statement he then which holds for all
the question is doesn't hold for all these natural numbers one two three four and
you're trying to prove that us
that's an infinite number things you have to prove you prove that for one then
for two and three and four
and then i would take an infinite length time well of course that's no good
so use this very well established in very familiar
established appeared zero
if you think that's just one thing to establish so know it's okay for zero
and then you show that if it's true for ten
and it's true friend plus one
and these two things to establish
enable to say is true for all numbers
and that's a very unusual
general procedure
for proving things in mathematics is things we use in schools approval sorts of things
it is well known as technical terms as first-order peano arithmetic
questions of computational rules such as those provided by ordinary mathematical induction induction sufficient
for establishing
he perceivable truths arithmetic those
that we can actually see true
and goes theorem says no
i'm gonna give you an example
all something which cannot be proved using
mathematical induction
there are lots of such examples
people used to say well okay maybe there are things like that's also incredibly complicated and uninteresting that who cares
well give you one is
this is the
a nice example
is due to
kirby in paris
nineteen eighty two
achilles and the hydra
so here we have
particularly is
yesterday and i hope is is incredibly strong he can keep on going
for as long as you like
he just never gives up okay
there is also a bit stupid
okay well the stupidity doesn't matter actions using them in
when he doesn't see
cuts of one of the heads of the hydra
each time he swings his sword cuts ahead of
this is
but each time because the head of l
it grows more heads
and the procedure is like this i this is i don't scan schematically here
if he cuts the head of which is the one is just about job of
what happens when you go back to work throughout
go down one more
you see what else lies above just here and then you repeat what's underneath
so he's going to my head he's got one of it's got to more not much good is it
next time
this is so stalkers you go back to this is the origin of it
okay this time it size to cut one of
so you go back to the beginning down here and it goes to more next time
next time you cut these cuts this over the goes three more formal five more
and you can see the number heads is growing and growing and growing and growing
and growing we're gonna win or not
the head going to keep on going and you just be chopping forever
whether theorem hockey and hydra theorem says that no matter how stupid he is
he always wins
it doesn't matter whether he's clever some
chopping some heads of will win faster than others
but probably it will take much much longer than the age of the universe
in the second term you have
the second hypothesis namely that you don't have the disease
OK so from the previous overhead you can plug in all the numbers
before you look at the results probably already have to think about it it's a
pretty reliable test right ninety seven percent reliable are ninety percent reliable however you want
to say it and you took the thing and you got a positive outcome should
you be really worried
right but if you put in the numbers
you're probability that you have the disease
it's only three point two percent c probably OK
that's kind of surprising results
think about why intuitively
is that right
intuitively it makes sense
because the prior probabilities
to have the disease the probability that anybody in the population has the disease is
so small
and notice that this probability is to have the disease given that you've got a
positive outcome is proportional not only to this probability which is ninety percent but also
proportional to the
what's called the prior probability to have the disease which in this case is very
so that's what the results than in this relatively small numbers surprisingly small number that
you have
the disease
so on the other hand think about it this way before you took the test
your probability was was ten to the minus three
after having taken the test and getting positive outcome it's jumped from ten to the
minus three of the three point two percent so maybe you want to take another
test or something
now one of the interesting things about this this particular example
is that
it can actually make sense regardless of whether you interpret the probability as the degree
of belief or some sort of limiting frequency
and so for example if you're the person taking the test you might want to
know what is my
the degree of belief that i have the disease
so that's subjective degree of belief can now be three point two percent
on the other hand your doctor use user statistics of lots and lots of people
and he would say in the limit that i see a large number of patients
three point two percent of them we have that result will have the disease
so bayes theorem just because you're using bayes theorem doesn't mean you're you're doing bayesian
statistics right you can you can use bayes theorem in problems with both frequentist probability
and with subjective probability
all right so if you go to the web site of the university of london
course i have some some homework problems actually applying this in particle physics standpoint i
think will will even come back to one of these examples later in the week
right so now
i don't want you gone too long about sort of foundational issues in philosophy but
i do want to just give to overheads on the basic philosophy people behind frequentist
statistics and bayesian statistics and that'll be it then for the rest of the week
i think mainly talk about frequentist methods
but here in then is the the general philosophy of frequentist statistics
so the thing to keep in mind is that in frequentist probability
in frequentist statistics probabilities are associated only with the data
only with the outcomes of these
observations that are in principle repeatable and very often i use some sort of shorthand
that like x or x may be the vector symbol over it to indicate the
the probability is the
the fraction of times that you would see such an outcome in the limit you
repeat the observation that many a large number of times and so therefore things like
the probability that some constant of nature like alpha s lies between two fixed values
like point one seven point one c one
well is is either in general or not no repetition of any experiment is going
to change that so that the probabilities either zero or one
but i don't know which necessarily
so that seems to say the tools of frequentist statistics are not allowing you to
answer the questions that you really like to know i really want to know what's
the what's my
is office in that interval or not and i would like to quantify how confident
i am of such a statement
so what the tools of frequentist statistics tell you is i tell you what to
expect expect about these these hypothetical repeated observations and so
the the
the use of such a statistical framework is it says that the preferred theories
are those for which our observations would be regarded as usual
so in other words if if i
if the model or theory is correct then it probably predicts a very high probability
for data that you've got
and low probability for data that's very different from what you've got
there seems to be sort of a convoluted way of talking about it and then
it does actually get a little bit complicated times
that's one of the reasons why people prefer
sometimes bayesian statistics
general philosophy
bayesian statistics is that you extend the interpretation of probability to include subjective probability for
when a hypothesis can mean
that is the nature is governed by the standard model only or
supersymmetry or the the higgs boson exists or does not exist
and what we would like to work out what is the probability of those hypotheses
given that we got a certain set of outcomes in our measurement so that's what
we want the probability of the hypothesis given the data
that's what is called the posterior probability because that's what comes after having seen the
so how do you get that you get that using bayes theorem which is why
this is then called bayesian statistics
and so what bayes theorem says is that the probability of the hypothesis given the
it is equal to the probability of the data given the hypotheses
times the probability of the hypothesis
and then in the numerator here what we have is it's what corresponded to p
of be a couple of transparency to go and what you have here is that
what is in the in the denominator here service serves to simply normalize
this probability to unity if you're too