i mean this is what you would get
if you do then
and it's clear that if you test distribution is different from the training distribution then
the estimator is biased
there's no way wrong
and so so we would like to
reduce the bias
one way of doing that is was proposed version with
in fact the idea here is that you get yourself density estimates
i mean they don't need to be very precise
but you know it so every data point that you use for learning
is actually weighted by the ratio of the densities of the training and test distributions
so this is very similar to importance something although importance sampling also assumes that the
distribution c
so the idea
here would be
that all the data points that are close to the test distribution which is here
would be weighted much higher
this is what the ratio is about
so essentially
all the data points here in this area
the training data
only this will be used
for training and the rest is ignored
this would give you a prediction like that
or or
the distribution of the same name
very close to the
well if it has the simple
and the problem is with that before
you can prove this is an unbiased asymptotically
which is very nice
still has a large variance
we should be trading
the bias of a little bit
with the very with reducing the variance which means that we basically
put the land up here
and this this
allows us to balance and then the whole story becomes the model selection problem
OK anyway so we can do that in the context of weighted linear regression are
also linear discriminant analysis
and basically introduce some weighting
and some some regularisation we have anyway
so this is just the updated
in LDA equation on the weighted regression equation that we using now to to adapt
to this change of distribution so
there is some
so we have some
something that test give
it doesn't exist i mean
with the believe
we to against
estimate one i mean we we actually in this experiment showing you don't
since suppose you don't have to see you assuming that you
i mean this is
but i mean in the papers and so on
it's not
it's not like this
i mean i talked about clearly hear alex and this
i mean
OK i think it's philosophical issues
very happy to discuss about because i think it's
he really
paid enough attention
if we look at the
the difference between the distribution
the training and the feedback session c four was some imagination
then we see that there's a difference mostly in the in the visual cortex which
makes some sense
in the alpha activity
and which makes some sense because it's just
much more exciting to play
OK so
i will not go into this but
in principle one could ask the question why just
you know
correct this one's only from training to test what is it
that's the other of this region
so if you want to make predictions small you put down
next year
and you see all
from this curve design this one this one
is also
one theory holds that
here and then given to the right of you sample from the conditional distribution which
is again
this means that
in terms of the slide here is the input space
here's the
the variables that which depends on the input from the conditional distributions of this thing
here is the outline
and then z y depends on the x axis here
any questions about the simple idea to make sure that seems
while this makes you in your efforts
now it time is
four a
i'm going to try
i promise you we will see the algorithm but before we get there i just
want to write down the gradient of the line
small because it very interesting for me and
and i think it helps to understand what is really happening when we define so
let's say that you
you were interested in the sense the amount algorithm you just want to optimize the
likelihood and you can see here is just
despite the director
first wrote down this like it's a lot of the probability mass
the probability of accidents so
you take the derivative
because has a lot to get one billion
the mixture green one gradient for each expert k
OK and if you must cite this for a little bit
way you start with marginal density inside here in one iteration
what you find is the gradient is
the responsibility weighted sum of the individual breeds
so the overall gradient
is a weighted sum of the gradient but each expert
weighted by
the posterior probability that experts is
so when we think about it is
if learning in the small i shall appoint
all of the experts decide between who will most likely be responsible for that data
point an expert who will most likely does not need to be likely to be
if something happens to your problem you really have just parameters something happens in your
backyard your data from the office three
so great is weighted by
the posterior probability that it was our fault
that's not the way
OK so just quick recap related variables the probability contains some
so the log probability the likelihood function as the greatest
it's the variables were observed
then we can do define the
and what is just ignore this fact
go back to this compute the gradient to do this
three whatever
here's another idea
and the idea is to use the current parameters so some parameter optimisation you could
get the parameters to estimate the values of the latent variables
the estimates standing circuits the real values and do fully observed
and this back-and-forth you might make optimisation in some sense make it easy
that's exactly what
so this general strategy is known as the expectation maximisation algorithm
it is most often credited as to their
from the late seventies
journal of the royal statistical society
although this idea was developed much earlier by parliament through the people working in statistics
not to mention
the canonical citation details so we have here is two steps in the east village
values variables using this here
and instead of going to parameters
in some sense taking advantage of its
so he's involved is crucial
it would tend to decrease and then at some point would start to swing up
and why is it swing up well that's exactly
due to this variance that variance term that i just derived in the two cases
is exactly what's pushing this up because the overall risk is bounded below by the
so that various
it's what's pushing the true risk up and so what we like to do somehow
minimize empirical risk up to a point in the point where we probably want stop
is where this variance term starts to exceed the value of the empirical risk because
at that point of the empirical risk is really are are sort of guideline our
surrogate for the risk we know the true risk can be less than the variance
we should never try to push empirical risk down below that level
and in this region here we can think of this is where we started to
this suggests
following procedure to guard against overfitting
we would select a tree not just based on minimizing empirical risk which is here
but also
as you add to that the variance so what this does exactly when empirical risk
is lower than the variance for the variance starts to dominate and that pushes away
from over fitting to the data because
at some point this guy starts to increase in among the larger value here
four four very large and complicated trees
that's the basic idea of variances proportional to the complexity of the partition of the
number of cells in a dish so this is often called complexity regularisation
and the basic idea is that in principle this can help us avoid overfitting and
give a very accurate model
the empirical risk we can calculate very easily from the training data which is the
sum of squared errors the sum of absolute errors that's easy to do the variance
is something that again they these expected values of f had myself square f myself
in absolute value in order to compute those expectations in principle we need to have
access to this underlying probability law p
we don't have that but it turns out we can get
good bounds for the variance
and rather than using various itself we could use the bound on the variance and
so that's what i want to describe next all
first of all i at bounding the variance and purcell basis and then once i
have various bounds for cells of pulled us together again variance found for an overall
so here's
per cell variance bounds in regression
alice according to denote only for selling the tree this grey when they have indicated
for example
as well is the number of training examples that landed in that cell
i have had in regression is the empirical mean is the true mean
the variance is equal to the expected squared error between
and in this situation already doing is fitting
of single parameter mean two to data was just one dimensional
parameter estimation problem you should know from your undergraduate statistics that air will decay like
one of the number of samples we have one over and help
and about the minus one so this is
i'm assuming everybody is comfortable with that idea that the variance of
of the parameter estimates decays like one over here
in the classification case is very similar same set up except that had is the
empirical medium
f is the true medium
and the variance in this case is behaving like the absolute error of mine
i have an expectation
and because we're looking at absolute error rather than swear here
it's a very
fairly easy way calculation to see that this should decay like one over the square
root of n rather than one over and as it did in the regression case
so we get this
and the
and for the minus one half
decay of this this parameter estimates of the median to the sample
everybody by that because is kind of important little pointed to by two interesting
OK right
now we can convert those purcell balanced overall violence for a full tree and to
do this you use it will be that have
maybe will lose here but let's just think about this for the first of all
and civil the number of training samples that fall to sell l
will be approximately like and the total number of training samples
times the probability that any sample what happened fall in
the leaf for self-help that's the problem x one to l
and l denote the probability by piece about
so and about the number of samples and leaf l
should be about like and so there are n times piece about
so by looking at the overall variance for the regression case
i can write that is the sum of the purcell variances
times the probability falling into each cell
these purcell variances behave like one over and times pl
so the peels cancel each other and just left with
the number of leaves in the tree divided by
so that's the variance
bound for tree in regression
and this should also look familiar it's essentially like the degrees of freedom in your
model which is the number of leaves in the tree
divided by the number of samples
yes but
so we didn't get it right and so i'm assuming right now fixed to give
an idea for a fixed rate how does
that the
fitting of sample means are medians affect the variability of that that the resulting
we can use markov chain monte carlo method is to try to sample from both
data and x
we can use variational bayesian methods and i'll try to talk about that
in the next lecture little bit
these are just different ways of dealing with intractability
so let me just talk about a summary of the parameter learning
i talked about maximum likelihood and bayesian methods for both complete other words fully observed
data incomplete data with hidden or missing variables
for complete data bayesian learning procedure is not any more costly than the maximum likelihood
procedure just involves treating the council differently
for incomplete data all talk about this a bit later
we have yes an algorithm but there's this variational bayesian the EM algorithm that is
about the same time complexity is
it has some nice properties
other parameter priors are possible but there's laser pretty flexible and intuitive distribution for these
conditional probability tables
for binary data other very well known parametrizations have been used
these include the sigmoid
where you have a whole bunch of parents the probability that your notice on given
its parents is one over one plus e to the minus some linear function of
the parents
this is very analogous to
the way we
i have neural networks with sigmoid units but just the generalization of that too
the discrete
graphical models with binary variables
there is also very nice noisy or parametrisation that makes sense for situations where you
have a whole bunch of parents and you want to include the idea that the
child is going to be on if any of the parents is on
but you want to have some noise in that in that or function so this
makes sense for modeling things like diseases where you have
diseases and you have a symptom and the symptom is on if any of those
diseases that could cause the symptoms are all roughly speaking
OK for non discrete data we can use similar ideas but generally is harder to
do inference and learning
so now let's talk about structure learning
given a dataset with observations of
so these variables a b c d and e can we learn the structure of
the graphical model
by that i mean let let m land the graph structure by that i mean
the set of edges in the graph can we learn whether this is a good
model where nothing is connected or this is a good model we have lots of
connections et cetera
so there are two general classes of structure learning problem algorithms
one class of algorithms is called constraint based algorithms
and the idea of these algorithms is to use statistical tests of marginal and conditional
independence c take
pairs of variables are sets of variables and you say
can i do
statistical test for whether these variables are independent or not
condition these variables in my observed data
and the standard of frequencies test that you can use like for example kai square
base test for assessing whether something is independent or not
then what you get is a whole bunch of conditional independence statements
and what you do with the same as you try to find a DAG or
set of directed acyclic graphs whose d separation relations match the results of those conditional
independence tests and in general the answer to that procedure will not be a single
DAG will be a family of dags with equivalent conditional independence properties
so i won't talk a lot more about that the algorithm for example like the
PC algorithm is the classical way of doing constraint based learning
these graphical models
the other family of methods are score based methods and what these methods do is
they compute a global score
of the particular graph given the data on that score could be something like the
bayesian information criterion score
the bayesian marginal likelihood and they try to find the structure or structures that maximize
this score
how do we know when we're doing well is the question that's a great question
is it depends on your application domain
there might be ground truth in that we might be able to go collect more
data to do some experiments
for example to evaluate a particular structure or another but is the same as any
other learning problem another way to test that is to leave out some test data
and evaluate performance on the test data
but in general it's a good question difficult to know
the ground truth of course
it's just another formula that we e we associate
maybe i want to name for that school that BI
so the formula
we assume that we've chosen the constant c is so that for example
caesar by doesn't occur anywhere in this previously also
like that so it's it's far in its new with his best known possibility of
special pleading for it
and then we can let gamma double prime
gamma prime
this debate
OK with throwing all of those
gamma prime
the brain is
taking here because
there's there's some slippage i think
these guys must be
yet more constance
they can't be the same things as we used to get rid of the free
we have to throwing yet more but we can always throwing yet more i mean
there's always yet more
through in this is throwing the days and the
what we want is that absolutely none of this stuff interferes with anything else they'll
just they're all just one off
and now we can appeal to this stuff look
there's a theorem
of the logic
that's a is
there is an x satisfying this
this implication
all right
so here's the left hand side of it
there is some x satisfying this
thing is a theorem of logic
by the rule of choice
we can pick one and we can call it seems by
right whatever follows from that
followed anyway
from the existential
from the existential fact which was a theorem of the logic
for that reason
if gamma double prime or inconsistent
so would
gamma prime being consistent and so would gamma being
gamma double prime is still consistent
all right
we can use linden baum's lemma
it's this big theory
that we apply the a
the linden down hankin
we're gonna blow that
to a maximal consistent theory
right so let delta
the maximal consistent theory
maximum the and extension
of that big
by the same construction is this morning
or if you want to be quick
by zorn's lemma
because this is a consistent set
so the set of consistent sets of it is nonempty it's got a gamma double
prime interest
partially ordered by inclusion
and every chain
in that sense
is bounded about its union
OK because of the chain of sets is consistent
if you have a chain of consistent sets the union
is also consistent set by the same arguement we had before if there were direct
derivation of a contradiction from the union it would have to be a derivation would
have to be finite and therefore derivation from something in the chain
we can use on islam and get linden
in one hit
static i through the construction of delta zero delta one delta two delta three all
we can do it we could do about constructions
i'm going to us i get away my hands and assume that does
so we have the maximal consistent extension
of gamma
double prime now
it's a maximal consistent sets has nice properties of maximal consistent sets like being closed
and consequence
for every x extensional
in the language it contains
a formula of this sort of witness formula
and so in particular for any existential formulas in delta
the analogous thing on the right hand side of this conditional is also going to
be in delta
and that's great because that means whenever delta contains an existential it contains eyewitness
we just
constructed it to be like that
a theory that has that property is called a henkin theory
after another logician anking
so the theory saturated something about sort
explanation of why things keep getting better
now the question how many layers should you actually use
there is no simple answer
yoshua bengio's group has done a lot of careful experiments showing that more layers helps up to about
if you try messing with this stuff
changing the number of units in a layer by fifty percent doesn't seem to make much difference
it's very robust to that
there are theorems that say if you make the net deep enough it can learn anything any distribution
over binary vectors even if it's narrow
but this is basically empirical.
you just mess around
this is just related to the first paper which we talked about all this
kind of learning
when i learn those weights in higher layers, the inference that i'm doing at the bottom level is
no longer correct
if i use the transpose of these weights to do inference
that's the correct way to do inference
if these weights are all the same as these weights.
as soon as i start changing these
the prior up here no longer exactly cancels the likelihood term here
but at least i started from the right way of doing inference,
as opposed to something that's hopelessly wrong like variational inference
and now as i change these weights
they're actually going to be very unhappy if they make this be doing inference wrong
so this'll stay pretty good
and it turns out that what you win by changing these weights
to get a better model of this
is always going to be more than you lose by the fact that this isn't
doing correct inference anymore
i'm not gonna to go into that any more
in the last couple of minutes i want to talk about
how to improve contrastive divergence
basically by doing something else instead. but we'll still call it contrastive divergence.
where contrastive divergence goes wrong,
is if i have say an energy landscape like this
so work
i have my data on some manifold like this
here's the whole space
and this is what i want to be low energy
and so what we do in contrastive divergence is, we pick a data point
we start the model there,
we say, where would you like to go? it says i'd like to go here
and we say,
don't go there, go here. so make this higher, make this lower,
and that's going to create a ravine along the data
but suppose that when we do this, we say make this higher and make this lower,
we accidentally make some point over here lower,
because these parameters are used for all sorts of things
and suppose that when we learned here we also make this lower.
we could end up with a big hole here that we never see
so we don't realize that actually we haven't got a very good model because the model
really believes in this stuff
we have to run the markov chain for a long time to see that
so is there any way we can run the markov chain for longer to see
this kind of thing?
well that's what this is about
what we're going to do is
we're gonna take the data
we're gonna activate the hidden units, and we're going to measure the statistics
and that's only one term in the learning algorithm
but in addition
we can have a whole bunch of particles, i call them fantasy particles,
that are sort of wandering around
in the data space
and each time you update the weights, you move all these fantasy particles by one step
of the markov chain
but you don't reinitialize them at the data
and that initially sounds like a bad idea
here's a concrete example you take
a hundred examples of data. you activate the hidden
units, you estimate the gradient, the first term.
you estimate the first term of the gradient
you also take a hundred fantasies
and use those to estimate the second term
but that's very tricky because the second term
should sort of model what's going on in the whole space
and these particles
can't find all the modes in the space, you'd have thought.
so it's very strange that with just one hundred twenty particles you can model this
whole partition function
and the issue is why does, why are these fantasy particles able
to find all the modes and model the partition function accurately?
i'm going quite fast here, but you'll get the slides
i'll put all this on the web
and the answer is that the learning makes the fantasy particles move around
so i have an analogy here. suppose i want to get 3d shape from images
and i said well i'm gonna study single images and figure out how to get
the three d shape
and a friend says, you know, it might be better to think about video sequences, 'cause that sort of
might be easy--easier problem. i say, no, no, no, i don't even want to think about video sequences
until i can get shape from single images
well it's obvious that's a mistake, right?
the equivalent mistake here is to say
i'm gonna get the gradient and i'm gonna do some learning.
and i really want get the gradient before do the learning
well it's going to turn out that because your gradient is the difference of statistics
actually the learning is very helpful in getting the gradient
and the reason the learning is helpful is
if you think about it
if you have an energy landscape
that looks like this
suppose on the energy landscape actually
i've got some fantasy particles
and my fantasy particles are sort of sitting here
i'll draw those in red for fantasy particles
my data
is sitting over here
a markov chain has a hell of a job getting these guys out of there and into here
what the data is going to do is it's going to pull down there. it's
gonna say, make this deeper, because i want to be have more belief in the data
but the learning is also going to say, because fantasy particles outnumber data here
it's going to make this go up
so rather than getting the particles to jump out of the minimum,
in parallel
and then have the computation
follow the data that's how paralyzed competition so the basic idea is to partition your data logically
using the mapping function that is
well the partitioning key is
you take the partitions
i do
but partition processing on then there is the so-called reduced at
and in between the my spilled it at a local this
and this is all the network and a very expensive shuffle step
the set things up for the reduced
the reduce tasks work on this
andy leave their results in a local flight that's mapreduce
thank you things i would like you to
think about here
this factor of implementation
this early june four scans it's early june four r appends sequential writes
can see
the scaling as i said is true partitioning data partitioning
on the scale these systems work
tens of thousands of machines
this is orders of magnitude more than your typical power database systems right
forwards are given
and while the unique aspects of these systems is in architect for
this turns out to be non trivial in terms of cost
i don't have to be one of the reasons why
mapreduce paradigm doesn't lend itself with things like iterative computation graph complications machine learning
and then there is no concept of iteration as a first class
the first generation of signal
there were implemented in a straightforward way
by translating programs into my previous statements why
implementing large-scale distributed systems is not something you start
you know like
and given that you had
that occur value system scaling issues
the first generation sequel concentrate on functionality
today story is what happens beyond this
what happens next
is this
that people
are going to insist
on storing all the data in a place where
they can bring all the analytic tools to bear on
and so i call this the social box you when the next data management war
by building a sequel system that's twenty percent faster than the previous generation
or by system that's twenty percent faster
i think we're gonna win
the most flawed experience in terms of having more data owner diverse data in one
place and being able to create composite workflows
i that stitch together all these different kinds of data over the appropriate kinds of analysis
everyone applications agave you earlier
has this characteristic you stock for example
with blogs and web pages
through a process of extraction
you may end up with tables along the way
you do everything from machine learning
from clustering
role on
visualization kinds of
conventional analytics
but the point is you want to be able to do all of it on
one surface you don't wanna be moving your data across different platforms
so this ubiquitous store
i called the shoebox style
has data is
captured from different sources typically want to be able to do complex event processing on it
and persist the results at all
store today doesn't mean simply desk
on windows azure
that is a separate data storage
i on which the machines don't allow you to run any computation
well if you look at amazon history is like back
there you will be giving this is specialized storage systems
andy intron dataset center networks are getting fast enough that the distance between local and remote discuss different
on the local machines yes you have local disks
which is what age actually first managers four year
four main memories are getting to be significantly large
for many many interactive applications
if you don't have to staged in main memory
you simply can't make the performance criteria
if you looked at work like i
it's essentially
trying to be clever about what the cache in main memory and how
i have
touched up and some of them already
we'll do diagnostics
we've done some
i spotting of plot already
we will study residual structures
we will talk about
how to
specify the model
modelling problems
here we can draw a line
say if you know this
you are
already pretty
experienced regression analyst
after this
we go into topics
and i suggest to study
two topics
that are
quite important in political science
we talk about categorical variables
think about voting decisions
this is a categorical variable
think about gender
at least to the extent that we needed is a categorical variable
so study
different sorts of variables
and then we'll talk about
specific ordering of the data
namely data that this water it
in the sequence
time series
and then we'll put everything together
and we'll combine
cross sectional data like the european social survey
with time series data like presidential approval
which over time is changing
if you combine the two
we get something
we call a panel data set
panel data sets data that
across units
and within the units over time
depending on
the number of questions that you will be asking how fast you were que
distribution of
topics of the base will be different and
i might add small modules or
about the small modules depending on
your interests
but the starting a year
is the following
the first two days will talk about the model
and the assumptions underlying
the mall
the basic assumption is linearity
we will talk about linear models
and you will see
was this example here was the square root in the log
i have given you hints
it's possibilities to linear lies variables
if you have an idea why you might be generalised
so that you can stick in the linear world
which is the simplest of all worlds
studying data clouds that are nonlinear in nature
this is a different approach from
the more sophisticated approach that has been discussed quite a bit in mythological
the basic conferences namely non-linear estimation techniques
technique immediately
estimates such a function
without first being ualizing it all the right
you can do that
i have hesitations
to what extent
you should do that
my idea is that before embarking on nonlinear estimation techniques
it might make sense
the first
possibilities still in their lives
because the linear model is so simple
so powerful
and well
research well developed
and there are lots of
bells and whistles you can attach to the linear model
it's a very straightforward interpretation
it has a very straightforward
a way of dealing with residuals
so there's a lot of
that gnostics you can do in linear models the much much more difficult to do
in the non linear context
for that reason
my suggestion is generally to first check all the options you
fourteen ualizing association
don't forget this is what natural scientists are doing all the time the first develops
a theoretical model
that's where the economists got the idea from
and then
and this theoretical model tells
the association between variables but they do that by
employing a mathematical transformation of the data
i will give you exactly
set up of the data set in order
to find
nonlinear associations
linear estimation techniques
you will see if you do
the course
the second problem i will discuss is identifiability
i will be able
to distinguish
between different
if two variables
are conceptually too close
let's say
and a number of years
a student has studied
the age of students and the number of years student studies
these two variables
this is most students start their
student career at the age of about eighteen nineteen twenty
there will be some variations
the number of years someone has study
i will
closely connected to the age student
there will be some outliers there always people start late
some countries to people start very very young
but these
two variables
cope very much
to be able
to distinguish effects
this is what we call identifiability
if we add
the errors that are conceptually very close and empirically highly correlated
o to one
regression model
then you will get quite odd results
we get exactly of past winners estimator back
the question
depending on how you cities just like variables
not exactly because
you using would actually try to push points out of the margin on both sides
so it wouldn't be exactly the same hyperplane but
i presume it will be extremely similar
because here for novelty detection you're not making any assumption of separability
they just saying what i want to ensure that points
by and large lie on the right side of the hyperplane rather than the wrong
for a large margin separator you actually want to have a large margin
any other questions
let's move on
is a simple online algorithm for it
what you do is here
director function
the squared
so the best possible the y
so all i am doing is just replacing this
average by some
that are single sample drawn from it plus one half the square
and i can just to those updates
three just like the perceptron algorithm essentially when the point lies on the wrong side
of the boundary
you just update the weight vector otherwise example anything
with thresholds just make the will be part of if the point was normal
otherwise you
you relax
hi implement things
of course
you don't really want to do this explicit multiplication all the way through
you want to pull it and then multiplying being that's much faster
that's the training ground
and these are points that are considered notable as we go through and you can
well it's fairly common digits
as we go down here will see that it actually starts to focus on
kelly pathological looking ones
i think they all have slightly from those that stand here
but basically
what you can see is that
initially it it it considers pretty much everything or even typical beach just because i
haven't seen that in many of them yet
but as it gets more and more data it will start picking up fairly unusual
this the first training examples
after looking at the same time gain
now it's from the first
least pathological
and that's on it is that started it's never seen before and you would agree
that there free of
that's just one after other
so let others and can only be good
what we did so far
we looked at
novelty detection by this information
we first
look the parzen windows and then we realized that it's maybe not so effective
then we looked at this and
in the end we just
the fourth places the founding
well basically
on one side the dots on the other side no points
and we discussed the brief stochastic gradient descent version
in the practical sessions of fishing
you actually get to implement the stochastic gradient descent algorithm
this very simple
it will be very useful for you
any questions before we move on
OK good
i don't understand british sorry
let's say
and some statistician at the australian bureau of statistics or some other boring place
i hope we don't have anybody from the here to be
now good
so and let's say i'm just recording the weight and the height of people
and maybe these are really tall people anyway
and knots
the reason is can in any case
what you will get is if you like get the plot like this i don't
know whether that's true have just made it up and i just use the normal
distribution and generated something like this
what would be nice
be able to say well
let's assume somebody
is one way to ninety centimeters tall well what reasonable distribution of his life
given that is that all
maybe you know given all those possible situations can i think therefore making the prediction
of how to the guy might be
i'm going to tell you that this distribution here was a normal distribution
so that appeared in city
so what i could do is i could simply as well the probability of the
weight given the height
of course is the bayes rule p of five white to have appeared five
this this is fixed
just proportional to that of course also gained gaussians
it's actually the really nice thing about constancy conditional software variable to get the calcium
back to his
if i go in slice
this density here on this line
we get some but like this
if i sliced over here to get the public this and so on
so these are all gaussians
and what you could could actually see if you were to draw straight line through
this is i could draw straight line through all the maximum
well what's happened here
i've basically done in linear regression
what i've done is
well given the height
i can estimate the mean of the white they can also estimate the variance of
and all else is well hey this is a linear dependency between
the means of weight height
this is inside debate
let's get some divisional one why fronts otherwise
trained on what promised to start
of those locations
and so i could just go in the world
what prime
one of them so
i can just
look at this one here as long as they get the proper normalisation everything's fine
so i cannot integrate out there i can use nine districts and just sample
i'm going to be lazy here so i'm going to look at only cases where
i can integrate out
now let's assume that the normal distribution david agus has seen one before his life
this is a multivariate normal distribution
the random variable x
the mean
cause you can see it's maximized for that this is inverse covariance matrix not just
some normalization
well forget about that very much
but this will be interesting lecture on
obviously this sigma has only non negative like
i mean
the that's random variables in a negative thinking combination of random variables also can only
have a negative i
people are interested in
you know radiation in
a particular feature value for example
they tend to be univariate
you know the main reason is for efficiency reasons
finding when changes occur for example if you have a stationary stream if something
then you want to know it could be and normally event and you have to
detect that
and also you're interested in finding the magnitude of the change for example not just
to change
but it has to be
sufficiently significant
for us to be worried about
in which case
you wanted to see the magnitude
so for example it could be used for
you know detecting some binding event so for example it's a there is a huge
in the in the distribution of something
then that could be construed as a critical events so for example it's a
you know somebody watching internet traffic
there is huge variation took place
and that could be a signal of something so for example
let's say if the packet rate on it could be somebody attacking the network or
if the traffic drop substantially
you know one of the line being cut
you know one of the
communications we just might have broken down
so it is very important to detect these kinds of events
so what are we going to
measure these
changes for example
can we use
you know some kind of measure
to say that
there is a i
it's interesting is in the in the in the medical
the main
they continue to use these things like for example
if you look at any typical medical papers
that that have some
i don't to look at
unsurprisingly most cases
they have some data to the
and the reason i say surprising is like medical work is experimentally nature always the
case studies
i'm and sometimes the case studies are very small populations like
ten twenty
and the reason is that it's very difficult to have large large scale test for
and also some of these cases
run for twenty years
and they want to study
so it's not non-trivial is a real problem in certain domains
so the language they try to use in in understanding
these kinds of patterns
they use the notions of our iteration risk ratios and i'll talk about little over
for those things
generally they useful binary data the mean many medical cases
the situation is generally of
binary you have the disease or doesn't have the disease
can also be used for quality evaluation
for multivariate contrasts and we see that a simple example is given x
suppose let's say we have collective small datasets
i and we're looking at
but the gender
it is a an indication of you know exposed to some kind of
so we collect this data and and then we wanted to
ask questions suppose let's say in our population
we have one hundred men and women
and and we found that seventy of of men were exposed
and ten women
are not exposed
so now we want to give some kind of measures to show
how this particular feature
the gender value can determine
these kinds of patterns
so for example on this dataset we found
the odds of exposure for male he's
o point seven two point three so
two twenty three
and for female is point one one
then in the in the medical domain they
we use this notion of odds ratio is the ratio of these exposure or
which is twenty one two
so males have twenty one point two times the odds of exposure than females this
is how
the terminology used
so it indicates the exposure is much more likely for males
then for female
and there's also a notion of relative risk
which is a bit more probabilistic model
so in this case
what we do is that
the relative risk of exposure for male is basically seventy percent
and for females is ten percent
and then we say
relative risk ratio e seven
which which means that the men had seven times more likely
to be exposed than so this kind of measures we try to do so
the question here is that these numbers indicate whether it's significant or not
if the ratio is
which means
there is a
good indication
this particular feature has something to say
conclusions what
we're going to make
so this is a typically
what medical people continues to use and you will see that this could be applied
in contrast patterns as well
in the case of pattern and rule based contrasts we're going to look at
overview of relational contrast practice mining
especially we're going to look at the notions of emerging patterns
and then i'll talk about the mining issues
this particular type of patterns we call them jumping emerging patterns
what it means is that you know this somehow
a special kind of patterns that make it appear
in one
group and never appeared
so this could be
quite a strong
contrast patterns
and we'll talk about computational complexity and not going to mathematics but just giving you
and you haven't got a model modification and you haven't got additional covariates are all
information that has allowed you to anticipate the change
correlation pattern changes
that suggests that different
pattern zeros in the precision matrix
zero suddenly pops into life and takes non-zero time varying value
or something that was important practically
try not to use the term significant that appeared in the model and the data
like that that was relevant influence predictions
suddenly becomes irrelevant
this is the notion of time variation in sparsity and this is the picture
so he weekly management aggression parameters are precision matrix
wear different periods of time we want different patterns of zeros
and we want some
formal model time series model that allows those things to to to actually appears so
you can think about switching mechanisms and various kinds but as the dimension gets higher
the typical methodologies and switching mechanisms are really challenged
to represent this this notion
that's one topical area
into my earlier slides i had
pictures this particular are vignettes
cartoon very similar to this
this is another area where we are
seeing more and more interest in dynamic modelling
gene network cellular networks looking at networks genes within cells and also
networks themselves cause
other kind not just genes but other molecules
well we have to start with
at least notional class mathematical models of biochemical models
and then of course quickly abstract the statistical level
because everything is in discrete time anyway in terms of data
and one is interested in and fitting a highly non linear model which has
and overlay that were interested in the question of understanding sparsity patterns
because network
biological network models like this are drawn
very often with some of the edges and thee arrows in their well understood to be
to be real by chemically and potentially functionally
very often also
it's a hypothesis
the network structure itself
is also of interest
so the same general questions are looking at time series data
where things are very and time parameters that represents strength of association
on arrows and dioxin in pictures like this and other features
that will be very in time typically because these
context in which the cells are growing and all the other things we don't have in the model
but we are also interested in sparsity structure to
there's lots of other interesting questions here there are spatial aspects
i'll talk a little more about latent states missing data and in when one discretizes differentially
most from the continuous-to-discrete to discrete time
typically these models will be but built on a very fine discrete time scale
and data is on a much cruder scale so this turns and missing data
terms of latent variables translating states that become part of a these state variable that
when dealing with in the analysis
imaging is important
to get data that's a whole other story
let me say what about computation
this is a foundation issue
until i fast-forwarded always you know still back in the nineteen eighties
a lot of these
story was analytic computation to enter the nineteen eighties
since then as we all know
life has changed
we use simulation i got this synthetic futures i use the term synthetic rubber and simulated a lot
i it particularly in time series another process modeling contexts
don't look at prediction
by computing means and variances and other things just simulate and and ask questions how
do those synthetic futures compare with
the real data just subjectively
so we had twenty years event one twenty years them ciency and some of you
will know that this really had a big impact on
bayesian dynamic modelling as it did on online areas for
bayesian statistics
some of you will know about
perturbed style algorithms forward filtering backward sampling methods for simulating in linear gaps in state space models extensions event
to mixture models are various kinds are the two kinds i alluded to
mixtures in the models in parallel and models that get mixed up in different ways and each time point
of course it's been revolutionary
we've had more than twenty years sequential monte carlo
the foundational concept learning in time sequentially
we may care about the past for analysis retrospection to understand
and adapt a model for the future
you the second one was how to train an HMM and as i said there
the third one which is hard to find the most likely path of an HMM
you have that is train and you'd like to know i give you sequence and
that to no which sequence of states
this HMM followed to a to generate the sequence
and there's a very efficient algorithm called the viterbi algorithm
that does exactly that in the
the idea behind the viterbi algorithm is
is the following
if you know that you have you have the best let's suppose someone gives you
the best buy so this graph is the time
and the values of the state k and basically are searching for the best
the viterbi algorithm is based on the following simple concept
if you knew
if you knew the best
and let's suppose that you know that the best path
goes by this but at this time so you know that you just don't know
what's going on here and what's going on here but you know about this time
he has to go through that state
someone give you that his
in that case you know that the best
the best path to move from the beginning that
the best path is going to be the best off of this the best part
of that is going to be the communication there's no other way to that of
the best path if you know that that's true that needs to be the best
back here in the best
there's no other best but it's going to be the sum of these two so
that means that
i cannot simply compute the best part here
and decided that the
that now if i were to pass through that i think it would have to
be on the
the one coming from here are the ones coming from here or the one coming
from here on one of them
and that's not i can forget about all the other ones so that's the way
to break the complexity of the
one of the the problem into
that's marching chunk and there is no great
that's exactly this is here
and i will not explain it but basically
it decides to two
to break so you're searching for the best sequence of by that maximize joint likelihood
of the data and which state you back
breaks down
two searching
the recursive solution again so you have these variable that we define we're going to
have to do it recursively as we did for the i five variables and in
fact searching at each time step for the best
partial plan
for a given that that so if we knew the partial path the given types
that we can compute the partial path of the next and the one on the
what the when and we're going to do that recursively seen in the similar recursion
as the i found liable is in fact the same equations where we replace sums
by max
that's all so it's the same complexity the difference
and that gives you do
the best for sequence of states that
basically all
there is to it
so because
it remains are mainly used in very efficiently used in speech recognition i want to
british he explained how we use them for speech recognition because this this knowledge can
be extended to many other tasks that are very related to multimodal interactions
so the the IDE so there are several task in speech recognition i want to
talk about one of the most complex one which is continuous speech recognition so you
you have a sequence of acoustic frames
you'd like to transform that into a sequence of words or
forty let's
let's see the difference first between words and phrases in the given language
you may have hundreds of thousands of words
and that might be difficult to model on the other hand you have in general
you can decompose what can be said in that language into a set of a
much simpler objects which are called phonemes
and most languages have between twenty and fifty
changes such phonemes but on the other hand nobody is ready to say the exact
number definitive member and everyone has its own way to define what is the fourteen
but on average you have about thirty
forty four nine per language
and with these
chunks of phonemes you can create words by simply concatenating phonemes so we have a
very small number of phonemes you can create a very large number of words
so the idea now is that we're going to create an HMM for each of
these phonemes
all words if we have a very small language
working code everything it on this page is guaranteed to be working code
there were the least runs from subversion because that's how they were generated so if
you see figure that you want to make
like this annotation here for example if you click on it
it takes you to a higher resolution image of that
and syntax highlighted source code that you can just download and run so that's great
that's really great leeway when you're trying to learn
it's a great resource
the documentation is
you know i think i pdf at this point seven hundred pages and i don't
know maybe half of it is documented as opposed to a lot of work
left to be done
so we're using this tool called
sphinx which is applied on the documentation generating tool
and you basically right restructured text
and will generate output in HTML
or in
using later
so i'm just going to become part of our users guide working with text
since we're just looking in mathematical expressions we can look at contemporary writing mathematical expressions
so this is kind of our guide to writing method about expressions we actually use
our own math rendering engine
and in creating a user's guide to generate the output so again here's what you
see is what you get
and basically all the different kinds of math expressions different fonts and you can choose
the symbol tables
here there's also another new little thing in this rest one of developers wrote this
mode called plant and you can just say
in your best documentary structured text document you just say plug this file so
for example that the cold degenerate what we're looking at here
mpl examples
user's guide
at the bottom there just these two lines of code here they say a
this is an doctoring plot this file so points an external file calls matplotlib on
it brings the filing documentation so it's kind regression testing you know your code examples
are generating your fingers run because they run away documentation build time and we do
the same thing in our API documents
so for example if you have a pipeline which is one of the larger we've
been looking at
the autocorrelation function the doc strings around here
we have this sort of snippets which show you graphs and for really nice
i think it's a really nice
the rest is very nice tool for making
these kinds of
these documents because you can incorporate math
figures in the syntax
it's fairly simple to plain text is not is the mark of has the latex
document is
cross-platform cetera
so for those of you who are interested in the math the source tree we
actually have a template called things template that we wrote that has all basically create
some document that has all of these things to do documentation and to make lots
math text when you first start with the template and just use the project so
that's a great tool
for doing documentation
OK so
i told you i was going to talk about interactive use and some going
focus on that now for the
the rest of my demo time
and how much do insert
after quickly
so had this little demo here called
class starts
leon glass was professor at the center of nonlinear dynamics and mcgill
he was doing this experiment
three in the sixties when people are interested in systems
where he was
taking a piece of blank paper putting it in the xerox machine and copying a
piece of blank paper to the output from the xerox machine
but in the copy
then copied it again so he was iteratively copying this by piece of paper over
and over again and and noticed over time that these some random dot started to
form just dust other things that would accumulate grow
this is a very simple but we tell everything you have to be able to
look at all directions
since coordinate descent does not
it may not be convergent is global minimum
and funny story got on tree trying to optimize such a function at four am
before the of the line in the country does not converge
in august so
and in terms of confidence rated through the glass gradient
it's the same as gradient descent with no assumptions consider this
keep in mind that coordinate descent is not always convergent with those same two slide
is that positive so it is convergent OK so is not always converge on BT's
in some some settings and for the last week
so before i go on this is
good so the last point i think quite important for sparse methods is that so
true as the objective function for sparse problem is not differentiable
but it's not any
nondifferentiable functions so if you assume the differential
you get an objective function which is of the form LFW which is differentiable plus
lambda times norm which may not be differentiable
or if you the constrained version you get the minimizer you want to minimize
convex differentiable function with the constraint and if you assume that any smoothness and if
on top of each assume that you know
two projects on the ball the ball defined by the nom
all the body farm and one of its so if you don't know
but i do know is simply the one of the one norm is the infinity
OK and the he should be enough for the moment so if you know how
to project on the ball defined the non in these again for the l one
ball is again do for the infinity ward
then you may use similar techniques than smooth optimisation which i won't go into this
new statoil for because i don't have time to talk about algorithms and simple ones
are projected gradient descent
and so proximal methods
which i will talk about it just for reference if you want to look at
and the good thing is that with those types of methods to get the same
comment as weights than for smooth optimisation namely it will depend a lot on the
condition number
of the loss function k so if the loss function is well conditioned it will
converge quickly exponential rate and if it's not any coverage it will convert slowly
at the rate of one one or two
OK so this is very important in the field of communication
now let's look at the source and consider simple algorithms for that
the first one is coordinate descent so i told you i told you that you
should not use it
but in fact you can is sitting on the main reason is that the optimality
conditions of c problems so if you go back here
in this setting
you know that if you optimize only one viable you want that to be true
and you see that for all j is the condition for the available j is
independent from the condition from the other visibles and this is one of the reasons
coordinate descent is convergent
is convergent was
i was the only
OK so we have another
simple proof later businesses so the good thing is that if you optimize with respect
to one viable this is exactly iterative thresholding
because you can not get
two million case square loss
in fact so the you know what i mean you know if you have
i don't see your question
sure OK but if you not operational you're not convex anymore
and then i don't exactly
if it is not to believe it will not converge
it might be some in some settings in fact the same so is guilty indeed
on some simple UCI datasets but you take another set it doesn't converge so it's
sometimes it doesn't it doesn't
and you would want method which may not be convergence
this is very important because it may get stuck and you don't notice it which
is the problem
so so def arg one so good good thing about coordinate descent is that this
is a very simple to implement because you can optimize is one if you have
one viable you have to optimize acquired function of one variable plays an absolute value
this can be done in closed form and this is just iterative thresholding and ask
for example in
and if slides because very simple methods here you have to keep in mind that
this is a first order method so if
eg if your comments matrix is as local coalitions it we would be quite fast
but if you have a high correlation between between your valuables it means that you
have the load condition number
it means that it may get very small
a second type of technique like called that it that take
because this is how we refer to it in the group
and it is simply a method that will do it that iteratively squares to use
if you take the one on that and you can see again you can see
it as the minimum of any of the of the vector it up to it
thousand time of p
despite is so here if you have team at with respect to it down here
the optimal it is exactly the value is the square root of w j
i know
all right
i don't
our mission
now have
they are
during had
are o
now there
thank you very much
good morning everyone
first like to thank all the organizers
for over to the
here in this pursuit
the first kind
this is joint work we have right here on the left gobbledygook right from the
so far
and talking to the consistency of random forests and other averaging algorithms
thanks to
that right
OK so
actually many of the ideas and greenwich to explain to is
been inspired by the work of children so that
it was
so a three years ago one's for
what do you get your
brown triviality
as for his work
that's the biggest the classification regression trees
and actually the keywords of my talk today classification regression trees inspired by the work
of brain
so just before we start
anyway my advisor of classification and the different classification regression you're
so interesting observations during for
any you other which is white or one year
and what do they want to do of course is to pretty much
yes lot of the observation want to know what this is that
or reasons why
this is just strange type of regression
the difference is that we should why
just take some good
what i'm going to explain today
can be transposed from classification regression of ideas which
let me for classification of
all politicians in manchester
you can for the two
so at the end of his life to run promoted from the first four years
in this occasion and regression
the idea behind forces
simple idea is to use averaging as the sort of thing
that is instead of using one the classification just many independent small ones
which are
which is very simple to my
and just because of the first try to obtain some which is from one
and brown left some very interesting question unanswered regarding the consistency in the way they
and in this world which is kind of a different from the top
we're going to try to the first answers
on the question why do run for preventing everything just
start the first stones on
actually random forests are part of a larger project
national community just go and some of the project
and some of its ontology learning algorithm which was set of many individual classifiers
and this is the largest combined due to justify that
it is now well known which means that some methods are often much more accurate
the first for example to
was to be the reason for that
contraction forwards
application of
i guess you would have us some other
and of course
run for which we to pick up to
so what is known about the first especially now that for the first mentioned excellent
performance on a number of practical problems
in fact according to remember
the most accurate general i propose classifiers the market
it's quite difficult
but first just because different forest just for how
a round is introduced in the tree building process so around first is just a
collection of three which are independent and which
the way introduced around the tree
which for one reason two
what is sure that we can behind
the first is
difficult to analyse and remains largely unknown
so they are
some papers about
first i could
everything that just keep differences of the reference around themselves
two thousand four and interesting referenced by you could see
who have established very interesting connection between the first at
and i would come back to this paper is nature and of course if you're
interested in the software
you can download it consists of because OK
you can download the software on the web page of
all right
before we start theory that some example of what wrong for very to example which
is here
version two
classification of observation one
one the decision
what can we do to around tree
we just
the second we choose the cornet
once you have chosen according to go from a completely different form
so we get
you get yourself
which is also true
i once you have to decide according to the one chosen according to the UK
can think
three which is just partition of square
and this
there are some pretty easy for number of cells it's all a
in the one
are interested for ones come over
just take rich this we're going to test
decide one
so this is the result of one
random tree
this one
this one stands for example so
this could be the result of another random trees
exactly the same
because you take about
what decisions will take
you take one sequence of two one two one one two one we get our
results make
decision on this is an example of random forest which is completely of course
right now this is called bird for summer of tree ring tones of the
this is some of these researchers there was a lot of the best way you
can read
well this is the main
further education you know better
the really really good i study
it's obviously reading research quarterly which is one of the top meeting journal
we want to find out
which of four
techniques was best
so to the best evidence synthesis
and essentially
just on the title of the problem with the best evidence because
by their own admission
OK they left out called the qualitative studies and services
i'm not sure how you could be confident about saying you found the best evidence
just based on quality
that was in a town called the best because there are some out there who
believe that on experimental research is the
you know it's there a park is really really big
so only only really
very type of research
and so we just have to look at all the experiments data and we can
find the best evidence and i would disagree that strongly not-so-great talk to decide that
there really powerful
spam which is one of them
the thing about
seven research
is that they tend to focus on two types nificant
and practical
statistical being p values about say this was this significant
particle beam things like effect sizes
but this
two other types
i don't get much focus
one type is
clinical significance
o times economics significance
OK significance is
those often oftentimes the quality
experience quality of life
so for example in the medical field
you may have intervention you have the drug medication
it doesn't cure or does it doesn't improve them in terms of
attacking the actual
you know attacking the actual
cause of the whatever when they have
we improve the quality of life in some way
if that's the case that might be really important
you know years yes is gonna die from this disease but the quality of life
while you're die is better than if you had taken
i'm educational
well intervention
so that's not the idea behind clinical significance
you have economic significance
OK something that
it's huge surely huge political science because of politics is
do we money
in closed session time
that's really important so
a lot of studies i see
we don't incorporate often local political economic significance
into our interpretations
and economics is part of my
background so maybe what kind of media latched onto that so at cost effectiveness
cost benefit cost utility cost you feasibility and cost sensitivity
one of those combinations
might be really useful
first four
when you come to talk at the policy level
because politicians have cell bodies like anybody else
and they have to make decisions and after tries to make something work
have to give something else
so if you want to convince them is important to spend money on
you know to address global warming
therefore becoming thinking
o that means i have to give something else i i want to give
so in this part of our
discussion in articles argues that we make we have to find ways to short to
you know
by by using this technique
we can improve
so educated for example
well often say that this intervention works because it increases
and scores by harvest and aviation
OK that's useful to
but for politicians what does that mean mean
so what we can do is better than that we can say OK we could
find out
what your probability is
giving you have some education
avoiding going to jail was probably don't have that of going to jail
you can look at how many cos decided to go for a person to go
to jail
so ten seven cells are made for every ten to seven cells are die
if you have an excess of new cells compared with dying cells you're in bad
because that's really the disease cancer and that implies even without knowing any without knowing
anything else about cancer
that they have to be very careful controls over the decision on the part of
the cell
to whether as to whether can grow and divide it was not it should grow
and divide
now what does that mean well part of the decisions
come from the following situation let's imagine here growing
we're talking about human tissue each one of these things is cells
and as usual my art is not that splendid
but one of the things i want to impress on you
is that the body cannot give license
two this l
order this sell order the cell
to make the decision
about growing and dividing on its own
i still cannot go going say
i think i feel like dividing i'm going to go do it that's no no
wiser no no
because the moment one grants autonomy to such as cell ones in a very dangerous
instead what has to happen what must happen is that cells talk to one another
and cells reach a consensus
for instance maybe there's so that's missing right over here
in this tissue
and keep in mind architecturally complex issue has a precise number of cells in an
organised in a very precise pattern
and the way that
is maintained is that the cells are constantly looking around and seeing is their gap
year do we need to make and sell or not
it's not as if this cell says well i'm happy here and on my neighbours
are happy but still on the ground by because it seems like a nice thing
to do it again that's an invitation to disaster
and i'm saying that if only to impress upon you the fact that cells only
will make the decision to grow and divide and going to the cell cycle on
the basis of consultations with their neighbours they're constantly talking to one another
these signals the intracellular signals within living tissue represent constant ceaseless chatter
it's like everybody's on the cell phone talking with six or eight or ten
his are neighbours all the time
and if you can hear it it would be a real
so that raises the question cells with one another what messages to the exchange one
with the other so that they can establish some kind of consensus as to whether
or not it's inappropriate for one of their number to grow and divide
all right this is an unauthorized and you can
interpret the way you want anyhow so
how do they do that well what they do one of the most important ways
they communicate is the exchange proteins one another called
growth factors
and the growth factor goes from one cell
here's the cell releases the growth factor goes
two seconds so induces the second cell to begin to divide that's a mechanism of
transferring the signal or conveying the signal
and growth factor itself is the relatively low molecular weight proteins which travels through intercellular
inter stellar inter cellular spaces
it moves from one cell to the other
so it secreted by oneself
it moves here and then it goes over here the second self in fact if
we want to blow up the second self the second cell has on its surface
a specific protein which is known as a receptor or
or in this case we can see growth factor receptor
which represents a means
by which
that's still senses the presence of a growth factor in the extracellular space
as is suggested in this very crude and poorly drawn
this receptor is a transmembrane protein
it has an extracellular domain is an intracellular domain and it moves through
it protrudes through the lipid bilayer of the plasma membrane we talk very briefly about
these at the beginning of the semester
and what happens is these receptors are so configured that in the event the growth
so i would say it's legitimate criticism to say for this model the only reason
why this model
i found a taxonomy of clustering is because
of the features that are there there's more of them that supported taxonomic organisation and
right whereas here the whole point is to say give it as many features as
you want and it will discover all of the clusterings that are supported in that
feature set so i'm not going to talk about here but we apply this to
other datasets that are bigger like for example
data sets of how people vote in the US senate where the features might be
all the bills that are considered over a period of two or four years so
there might be like
you know hundreds or even thousands of features and the model might get ten
in the case of the senate voting picks out about ten different ways of clustering
senators of which eight we found politically meaningful and there's two others that are very
small and not very meaningful dislike here some of the features i mean i i
didn't talk about this
partition but basically it finds a lot of the features are in some sense just
sparse noise these are features which might be meaningful in some context but as far
as this data set is concerned they don't coherently recovery very with anything else so
it just says i'm going put all the animals together and and have have basically
it's you is going to use just
a single coin weight for each of these columns saying other probably mostly not present
right and ages vary in the degree of sparsity but there isn't any interesting structure
except for frogs which get carbon on their own and that's because basically frogs have
an unusually high number in this data set of idiosyncratic features so i would say
it's kind of an accident of this dataset that frogs
it's partly an active status frogs get placed on their own
although not complete accident because frogs are a little bit weird maybe compare two weeks
but for the most part you know what this is saying is as far as
this data set is concerned this is all this mostly junk whereas this is not
junk although it was treated by as junk under a conventional mixture model
that makes sense
i mean i think the the bottom line is a the kind of concerns arising
are important ones there but there the sort of things which affect any kind of
approach to unsupervised learning and exactly why we want models like this are ways of
actually trying to to to go beyond those kinds of concerns
by by recognizing that the that the
not just the
you know the whole motivation for nonparametric bayes in general is that the amount of
structure in the world is effectively infinite and certainly any finite the right finite approximation
is unknown and this is taking that to you know it to another level or
another dimensions and even the number of kinds of structures might not be something we
can commit to advance if we're going to be willing to give our system all
the features we can measure
yes so not in this and not in this model
but that would be an interesting extension
we thought it was challenging enough if you count the combinatorics of this model like
the height the effective hypothesis space is
you already for anyone nonparametric mixture
the effective hypothesis space of you know is all possible partitions of the number of
objects bell numbers or something and here we've got all possible partitions of the number
of objects and for each of those partitions it's one of every one of those
but i mean it's huge about space and
we were a little bit shocked we got anything meaningful and actually the kotchman singer
for those of you who know him might take a little bit differently but he
he he didn't really believe these results although he obtained himself he has very high
standards for for appropriate
you know
mixing and MCMC and all those sorts of things and so he spent several years
and and has started a company and has acquired over a million dollars in venture
capital funding and mostly what they seem to be doing with that is trying to
come up with
with inference algorithms for which he actually trust in this huge hypothesis space it's actually
mixing in genuinely sampling from the posterior for the model
they have this they will suppose we have a product soon you can draw samples
over the web for this and pay them by the
by the bit
that that's what you want or if you're academic you can use it for free
right so so i'll show also something later which is kind of more local clustering
but the main difference between this just quickly for those of you who know CO
clustering is is that here
and co clustering you cluster the rows and the columns kind independently right so co
clustering shops of the matrix like
this way and then like that way
right whereas here were clustering rows inside columns and you can you could imitate this
with the co clustering model but the co clustering model will be over parameterized because
you have to basically have all of these different
shops and actually i take that back you can even really do that because these
cuts here like it looks a little bit like because of the way of drawing
it looks like you could just extend this line over here but in fact these
are ordered in a different way so these cuts orthogonal to those cuts mean basically
you could you could kind of capture the structure with the co clustering model but
it would be it would it would it would look like a complete mess so
basically this model has to do it similar to
co clustering clustering both rows and columns but it has a different and much more
structured inductive bias that comes from first clustering the features
which represent since different different aspects of the data and then for each of those
it's trying to say OK i'm going to find a simple
the single simple view of the aspect which is just a single list a single
way of clustering to just explain those features
and the question about
OK this just says we have lots of evidence that people
i can do this sort of thing and i will tell you about the experiments
that would that would take forever but basically what we do is we give people
this sort of task where we have them sort of a whole bunch of objects
like we had sort exactly these things and then we look at how the different
sorts they come up with
it just depends upon the difference in the pixels
and what you get
this is g
x i
minus xj
listen equal to
exciting ones alpha
alpha minus xj
absolute value
it's x i
one of
xj myself turns out
without going into this race that this is exactly the opposite condition from what the
chicago our
if the function is convex
concave rather
like this
this condition holds
right so if your function g
is concave
you can use
concave in positive region
then you can use what what cos alpha expansion of if
it has the opposite
o thing
you can use your housing get an exact solution in this case you can't get
the exact solution
this one can
this one preferable summons this one nice of positive linear
you can use either you can use either one
and why would you use one rather than the other one would use
for expansion rather in chicago with the chicago gives you the optimal solutions of expansion
well the answer is
because of expansion is much more
economical in terms cost
lots and lots of pages
she chicago
OK that's all i can say about after expansion take these things more
multiple labels
also something about
about higher order cliques in the remaining twenty five minutes
that i have
and that is
one of the
perhaps problems with
using a clique size two is you are looking very local information about the image
to see how the constraint you if you look at
more complex
cost functions
being presumably get better results
now one of the things
about this is
it really depends on what the cost function is made you can't say that i
for instance
with with size to right size to cliques depending on the cost function
you choose your emphasizing the smoothness or abrupt change in
whether you
it depends on the particular cost function
if you can make your
cost function
cause large
changes or not was
sometimes people will sometimes wear
i'm going to
rather than try to go back to slide with this is which is likely to
have a good look cubic
we can turn
not just here on the board this slide in the
in my slides much more mathematical ones
which tells you how this works
so supposing you have
look look at just
we could just you know who was binary problems
again we looked at the
case where the cost linear plus
i j
x i x j
what if we have
that's why
i j k
x i x j
so i got QB once you get to court you can't even tell what function
submodular but in this case we can
we can work out with the function is submodular in this particular case and hence
would be solved
you can you can see
i want to
make the following observations
the function can always be written
in the following form with this is either
OK i j k
x i
xj by
xk by or x i x j or xk in which
OK i j k
this list are equal to zero
any function
right which is cubic
another how do you do that well
it's quite simple you take too well if it's the former i think it's this
form already been done supposing you've got you've got this where i j k is
greater zero what do you do that
i suppose you got to got to
x i x j
positive i don't want positive and one negative
well it's quite simple you just change them all
use this will two times one minus excited by
one minus exchanged by
one minus xk but
that equals minus two
plus quadratic
similarly if you had to like excited by our xjxk
to change
things that one change you always get
in this form
with that
isn't it
and sometimes you with new stuff down in the quadratic
so what about the quadratic parts
we also want
well once you've done that the important thing about the quadratic part of this AIJ
it also has to be less than a year
got rid excites j phi rho x sidebar
xj then changed sign here
and then what's left get swept out into the
the thing is that the theorem is if you have it in this form
where i j is greater than zero
and all you i j is alison zero
but when you cannot be sure if that happens
the function is
submodular and can be solved the let's just see how this can be solved
my graph cut
the question is how to deal with skewed to how we deal with human terms
well what we do
it is
we introduce new variable
we introduce new variable we look at this
look at x aybar
xj bar
plus xk by
class one
we introduce why
a new variable y
three should be why i j k like