we can do the same thing with an omission evoked potential which is just exchange
the target for break so
one two three four nothing
and people adapt to break as well as they do two target is just to
the trick that europe is also to be stimulus induced but you can also make
a silent gap stimulus
so that you don't have stimulus related potentials but just everything that is top down
if you will
well you don't have much of an an two or p three you see something
you what i think it doesn't hold the statistic but you do see is in
so people adapt to break in sequence as well as they do two two different
and across
repetitions of these cycles so what i this this trend of having earlier learning curves
are introduced to before this also happens on the on the scene he pretty clearly
it doesn't is not so clear with p three in two but it's still significant
this one we don't know why the way that's there but
you still have
the trend that the learning curve has the transient that is really an early across
right so people learn they learn faster the longer you do the same thing with
now what we want to know is OK we know that
at number of electrodes at different latencies
we have these effects
where do they come from
it's a bit tricky to make to make a spatial inference from easy so that's
what we wanted to do
after right
but then we already have the functional modulation we
we we had the signal that we wanted to look at in the easy so
what we wanted to individuals not
and my study with some other e they wanted to do the same thing at
the same time right so i wanted to do easy inside the scanner and get
the same effect in the EEG
and predict the fmri
with that signal
so that you have this learning effect on the same subjects in both
so what we did is that these amplifiers which you can put close to the
scanner keep the subject inside the scanner
there's not much that you do technically that's difficult you can just by these amplifiers
you keep the something happy new this paradigm while record from my and easy
simultaneously and afterwards he begin processing the whole thing starting with the artifact removal
the gradient artefacts impacting on the signal quality in an EEG you'd have quite interesting
artifacts all kinds of evil things
which you can control for
right to have the ECG so we can control for about this recording an artifact
and the gradient artefacts in the goods cannot tends to be very text so you
can subtract it with template based correction
after that we tend to unmix EEG with ICA
in our application we just did that for getting rid of artifacts
i movement
residual current things
are picked up pretty nicely by c and then we just back protected the residual
and use that forcing for estimation in the different
version that came out by by seventy even though they picked out one component that
they could reliably identify and related to one component
what you're p components
and then we did something like quantification where we
i took a signal
this and wavelet denoising so this country constrained time frequency content to whatever we thought
was relevant and then convolve that within the canonical ref
and predicted the atom activation
in this way
you basically do
you can do
timepoint by timepoint correlations between e
and the from
you get to a resolution of the my response as long as signal
represents different time points in different voxels
that's the only
that's how it works here
this will be just to standard from my analysis so define the onset times of
our targets
and correlated with the human activation you get
the usual suspects of of processing
here temporal lobes parietal lobes
you from the data
these medial the midline areas here some a precarious
and so forth and to force is just basically there's nice paper by can kill
neuroimage image from two years ago when you have enough subjects
you basically light up the whole range
because the ball is so simple that basically the whole
the whole conglomerate of brain areas that don't have anything to do with the task
would activate after a while
that's that's pretty nice idea
then we had basically what happened to slides before
we have these amplitude modulations this learning function for example
which is not expressed
in the same way across timepoints right then it will be a single are
representation this this learning function occurs at different time points and to change its shape
it changes
basically how it represented in the areas that my generated so you'd have a sinusoidal
or sigmoid they might be pretty correlated but still the shape is different related to
different types of functions
and reducing the fires can localize localize these guys
at different time points basically is just in this
this figure here
you get a bit tricky in the in the in the techniques but bear with
me so so what we do is a single trial denoising where we started off
after artefact correction with independent component analysis we think that while this component look like
in europe even even for data this component doesn't look like in european we take
it out of of the data
this is as much as we use ICA here right
and then
take for just two
you can do it very much better so here's our mark zero
we call this
originally the concept we can we call the two camps
and this one however is made of two large cameras glued together so we call
this one the glue can
and we use this one for quite a while but it's not very satisfactory because
USB cameras and USB is not temporary synchronized you cannot get USB do temporal synchronization
clearly the stereo the whole point is that the images a synchronized so actually if
you use firewire cameras firewire happens does happen in the
the middle where synchronization you can do that but that's sort of more expensive route
various reasons so we've now built
had a local company called cambridge signal processing build as a problem
camera which they call the hydra can
in which is a USB camera
but proper secret synchronized because it synchronized the level of hardware
and so having a lot of fun
playing with this work because things can you do with it well
he is my colleague
holly williams
chatting away on the on the camera
and you know it is rather distant we set the camera rather distant and you
know i'd like to see him a little bit more
a little bit more close-up
so we get more emotional
the collection and one of the things we are very interested in microsoft is trying
to see how teleconferencing is going to work
because you know we you just blew your carbon budget line here for this conference
so the next time you want to collaborate with someone really trying to home
and you know be sitting in front of your workstation
and this even of their workstation you're working on a paper or something that would
be civilized
anyway in order to see
you're the bigger your collaborating with i recommend all these very
you know but here it is move that the brain that's a bit messy
so you know that's why we have to zoom out the camera in the first
place because although would have liked more emotional contact
you dangerous to get it so
is something which is using stereo cameras automatically to estimate where the
the object of interest is and the sort of log onto that target
and here is a little bit later in the conversation
is you know moving out of the frame
temporarily but the camera soon catches up with that and frames him out
sort of imitating the rules of reasonably good can work to given the picture of
you can do this with the monocular camera probably you know you'd say well you
should be using an SVM in the face detector but you know it doesn't always
work i mean
you know sometimes it doesn't work at all
i mean and you know what i want to
show you the
which you i both the shop like we could well if you may not just
the two faces
you can try to do this monocular using motion and color and so on but
and because that works to some extent but stereo is incredibly reliable and robust really
is the method of choice as i say there is no real reason not to
use it
actually what we could do it sold before
stereo problem
and i'm just going to
keep going for a few minutes then you get your natural break
so you know why not go directly to the jugular and ask the right question
you this is a good principle in information processing is sorry you know make this
principle in many forms yourself that you know the curse of modularity i called my
friend ollie williams called it that you know why define intermediate representations if you don't
need to say exactly what it was when computing computer computing variables whose values he
didn't want know so we ask the question OK tell me what is in the
foreground and what is in the background so
to do this we take the
here's the stereo problems we last saw what the one in shape the dynamic programming
and we repeat the likelihood term out of that
is the likelihood term
actually the purpose of convenience
if you remember i said that xk in this formulation the problem was the coordinate
two world let's say
equivalently i could make it
according to to repair the corner to
coupled with the disparity
so i'm going to propose that representations of thinking and then as i'm going to
take an and the disparity of its equivalent pretty much
so now
this likelihood here can be re expressed as the likelihood for a particular pixel in
the right image
is a disease involving the destruction of motor control and loss of motor control difficulty
moving in one factor in parkinson's is too little of the neurotransmitter
known as dopamine
the drug delta
increases the supply of dopamine
and so does something to alleviate at least temporarily the symptoms of parkinson's
so you have neurons and clustered together
and if i only communicate to one another
so how does this all works
to give rise to creatures who could do interesting things like talk think
well again it used to be believed that the brain is wired up like a
like the PC or mac or something like that
but we know this can be true
it can be true
because there's two ways in which the brain is better than here
for one thing
the brain is highly resistant to damage
if you have a laptop
and i persuaded open that
for me
and i take the players
and just about anywhere
your laptop will be destroyed
but the brain is actually more resilient
you can take a lot of brain damage
and still
preserve some mental functioning to some interesting sensor some sort of damage resistance built into
the brain
that allows different parts of the brain to take over if some parts are damaged
a second consideration is
the brain is extremely fast
your computer works on
wires electricity
but your brain
uses tissues
and tissue is extremely slow
the paradox then is how do you create such a fast computer with such low
you can what if if if the brain was wired about the personal computer it
would take you four hours to recognise face
but in fact we could do things extremely quickly
so the question then is how is the brain wired
and the answer is
unlike many component like
commercially generating computers the brain works parallel
processing massively parallel distributed processing
there's a whole lot of research and this is research some of which takes place
outside psychology departments in engineering department of computer science department
trying to figure out
a computer can do the same things brains can
and one way people do this is they take a hint from nature
and they try to construct a massively distributed networks to do aspects of reasoning
is a very simple
computational network
that is interesting because it kind of looks to some extent like the way neurons
and this is often known as neural networks
and people who study this often claim to be studying neural network models
to try to build smart machines by modeling them after the brains and in the
last twenty years or so
this has been used in vibrant area of study
where people are trying to wire machines they can do brain like things from components
that look a lot like neurons and are wired together as neurons are
consideration all of this
is it this is very young field and nobody knows how to do it
is no machine yet
that can recognise faces
understand sentences
at the level of the two-year-old human
there's no machine and they can do just about anything people can do
in an interesting way and this is in part
because the human brain is wired up in extraordinarily more complicated way
then any sort of simple neural network
this is where the schematic diagram you're not responsible for this
parts of the visual cortex
and the thing to realize about this is is extraordinarily simplified
so the brain is a complicated system
so we've talked a little bit
about it
the basic building blocks of the brain neurons
we then talk about how neurons can communicate to one another then turned to how
neurons are are wired up together
now let's talk a little bit about different parts of the brain
there's some things you don't actually need your brain to do
the study what you don't need your brain to do has often drawn upon this
weird methodology where this was actually done in france alive we would decapitate people
and when they decapitated people psychologists would rush to the body
the headless person inserted chess tests reflexes
and stuff like that is kind of gruesome but we know
there are some things you don't need to reign
you know new brain for newborns active
lim flex asian and withdraw from paint
you're little pull back even if you had is gone
erection of the penis can be done about the brain
vomiting also the photograph i and you volunteer
very simple there's a lot of of all any of excellent any of the above
can you stand up just
this is an insurance i want to stay away from now is is if you
hold your hand
and one can flash
sceptic long time
but is is probably the heart that is the question so
this is what i get if i actually take
what are you looking for the posterior x
seven the civil is noisy data as to have it is good have it is
not you want to estimate the posterior distribution x
that the question
OK so what i was writing there was
how how complex the the posterior distribution tracks get complex is this function you get
if i have two data points
based on that that's the case here
and basically phi phi just substitute in those form the top into that
what i find is that some weighted sum of four terms
each of which is constant
so that's that's how the complexity grows
but here's the thing if you actually take a data set of one hundred points
actually compute this posterior part of this is what you get
suppose for
so yes that is it is a mixture of two to one hundred gaussians
what it ends up having a very simple
shape effectively even though the algebraic form is very complex the actual shape is quite
simple and this happens a lot in bayesian inference problems mainly because you have a
sort of central limit theorem facts more data more data you have affecting certain parameter
essentially makes the distribution of question the gas even though each individual likely could be
very nongaussian
so this gives us some hope that probably we could do some sort of approximation
and get a good representation of the posterior very simple compact representation the this posterior
and compute with that thing going to do the one hundred mixture of gaussians
so i'm going to talk about is how can we be computed represent the posterior
distribution compactly OK so it this point is sort of a fork in the road
what type of approximate inference technique you want to use now you've just seen a
whole bunch of lectures on sampling and something is certainly one way you could approach
this problem
i would say that something is particularly good for cases where the posterior distribution has
a very complicated shape that's not something you could easily summarize with some sort of
analytic form
so for example if you have a shape on the left which has lots of
modes in it
using for example a particle filter a bunch of samples to represent the distribution would
be a good idea
i know and if you have a nice smooth posterior distribution like the one i
showed you you can actually do something much cheaper and much simpler which is just
to approximate it with some parametric family such as calcium
you have the trade-off here so the nice thing about sampling is that
is that it allows you to wait
OK is that use enough samples you going to get a good representation of the
posterior even if you don't know what it looks like it's long enough samples to
get something that captures the most the posterior is on and sample that letters
the thing about deterministic approximations is that you don't really know in advance how accurate
is going to be honest you actually examine their posterior distribution see that doesn't match
the former fitting to see how does it is adjusted if you don't do that
you will really know how accurate results are so that's so sort of this unpredictability
the other hand it is very fast
within deterministic approximations there's still a whole bunch of things you could do so one
of the original methods people use was called method
and what happens there is you essentially find the mode of the posterior distribution finding
the derivatives that mode and you choose the gas which is the same mode in
the same there's your posterior
so essentially you're features the girls in which matches are posterior one point very well
and this has been used for various problems sometimes it's very effective so applied for
example to do bayesian PCA where it works very well for the problem
another method you can use
it's called variational bounds
so in this case we'll be finding
i can see in that
doesn't just imagine one point but it is the sort of the lower bound to
my poster distribution
and one of the reasons that people like using lower bounds is you get certain
guarantees about approximation you get a nice convergence properties of the island and so on
but today i'm not for either of those and the third approach
which is called moment matching
and i'll talk about racial bounds tomorrow
today i'm going to focus on this one and the reason i like this one
is because for certain problems where you're posterior distribution does not share assumptions very well
and get very good accuracy with this method
and i'm going to be talking about the medical expectation propagation which is basically a
method for finding a gaussian approximation to posterior
which was assert with essentially a combination rose the combination of two previous albums one
is called assumed density filtering which came out of the common filtering literature
and the belief propagation which came out of the machine learning literature essentially it's it
subsumes both of them
so since the both special cases of the elements two but a OK so today
what we focus on more matching tomorrow talk about variational
OK so
first of all let's come back to our problem is there any hope of finding
a gas and the posterior well what i'm i'm showing you i'm showing again that
same exact posterior distribution x and i'm showing the best gas fact and by gas
and i just mean the one that has the same moment the same mean and
as the posterior distribution and we see that the reason because there was not a
perfect fit and that's because our posterior wasn't exactly as it was it has heavier
tails and calcium
as a result i think perfect but it does a reasonable job OK so so
essentially our target is going to be define that purple curve as fast as possible
and the and the area between the purple curve and the green curve will never
be able to recover using gas approximation
what is the basic strategy
so recall that we had this factor graph
four x
which had among defectors get some wise
and the reason that the posterior distribution tracks
wasn't was because
some of the factors in this moment because i think there were some of the
gaussians well what if we were so lucky as all the factors in our model
augustine more than we would end up with the gas in fairfax that we want
so one way of getting that
girls in approximate gaussian posterior on x is to take each of the factors in
our model and approximate each one of them with the gaussians
and if we approximate each one of these factors one by one of the gaussians
will ensure that are approximate posterior because which is multiplying together we get approximate posterior
that essentially what i'm going to do
so works in a very different way than than for example the past the plasma
deform the whole posterior defines mode and so on going to do it in very
distributed way i'm going to take each factor one of the time approximated and eventually
but not together
OK so
mathematically i'm going to take that some weighted sum of gaussians and i'm going to
and that guess in some free proud going to call my in and those the
numbers that and you find my out
at first this might sound a bit fishy so what i'm going to do take
something which is the sum of the gaussians roughly one thousand how can i possibly
is exactly what our eyes are doing we're trying to study face
how many people
i have seen this study before
feel OK so here's the goal is fixed as the a video let's see if
i can get to work so
what i want to do with the two teams shares there's team with white shirts
team with black shirts
and the team both teams are going be passing a ball back and forth to
each other and the goal here is to you're supposed to pay attention to the
people in white the white team and count how many times the balls passed through
this video sequence
so that's what you're supposed to do to try to do that we'll see how
this goes
it's the thing
OK so how many times
four teams OK and how many people saw the dancing girl
a lot of people i heard laughing but the maybe it's just a matter of
how far you are from the screen and so forth but what the study was
as they had subjects washes video and told them to count the number of times
the white team passes the ball and a fairly significant portion of the subjects miss
the dancing girl altogether and this is an example of how
active learning is
a blessing and a curse in the way
you can if you're trying to figure out how many times suppose passed you might
miss something that is arguably very salient and an important about this video sequence namely
the mountain gorilla and so that's a great example of how
once you start decide to focus once you try to be active in very selective
and how you collect information you can overlook things and this is the greedy or
myopic nature of active learning in action
what's another reason that
i'm interested in active learning understanding complex systems
in problems
for example studying the internet or other social networks and things like that often it's
very expensive and difficult to get
lots and lots of labeled ground truth data and so
we apply to for example in the internet mapping
context be able to selectively decide where to probe the internet which routes to make
in order to help resolve our understanding of the structure topology of the internet
another great example is this neon network which is the national ecological of observation network
this consists of you who knows how many different sensing systems wireless sensor networks aerial
sensing satellite sensors on and so forth and you could say well it's just put
all this information
and store it somewhere and then analyse somewhere and so on and so forth and
that really becomes an impossible task what would like to do something a bit more
selective go out and collect information in some selective fashion
in order to learn something about the environment and ecology and a more efficient manner
so this is kind of like learning by queries wireless sensor networks where we're which
sensors should you query so this is an oil spill maybe would like to try
to determine its extent seaward selectively sensors in order to figure that out you can
as i mentioned network monitoring and also
and trying to discover it apologies clusters and so forth and social networks and other
networks active sensing an active data collection can be very effective
the basic idea is when where and how to collect information
so and then
it may be that the
grandest through the motivation of all is to automate science and this is something that
people are seriously interested in and we can just walk through it so the ideas
how to science work today we we have a scientist has background knowledge he makes
some hypothesis he designs an experiment he collects information
data from the experiment he analyses it and it goes back to the scientist and
the scientists either finds that the data supports hypothesis or they there's something wrong with
this hypothesis of the scientists up to him to go back to find that
hypothesis come up with a new experiment and so on and so forth and so
the the the the point here is that there's a person in the world which
is a good thing but it's also potentially bottle and we know that there are
lots of problems in learning in statistical inference where human intuition is quite limited especially
given to high dimensional situations and so
the idea of automating science is to try to
i reduce the burden of the human in the loop
take advantage of the fact that
computers and machines may actually
be better suited to finding patterns in high dimensional spaces
and so this is this idea of autonomous experimentation automating science and there's an need
sort of
article reviews that was put together by
a panel of scientists microsoft the cambridge put this together a few years was called
toward towards twenty twenty
science and the idea there was this whole automation process so here's how
how why we might want to do it
in traditional set suppose we're trying to
OK computer based classifier to classify microarrays to do something like that what you might
have a lot of data collected unlabelled you give it to an expert scientists that
expert labels statuses this is cancer this is in cancer something like that and then
passive learner produces some sort of classifiers the machine
in active learning it will work a little bit differently what would happen if the
data we go
the unlabelled they will go straight to the machine the machine would start asking for
to try to get a sense of what's going on to maybe ask for the
but they correspond to symbols of level one level
so what is this give you well
so the green line here but the black dots are
increasing rounds of just kind of flat training training with two categories four categories a
category and so on the green around the green is kind of doing this hierarchical
training and the first thing to note is were a lot higher than the baseline
so we actually start in this game lower than the baseline because we started with
an extremely simple grammars
and we end up with a basically reasonable results it's now up to about eighty
eight percent and just to give you a sense of the range in which people
report can state-of-the-art parsing numbers is kind of in the high eighties to kind of
very very low nineties range
OK and you can see that the the kind of the
the further you split the better it is to train things hierarchical
so it turns out this is the problem
because this graph doesn't keep going it doesn't look like it's asymptote right you think
we can keep winning in one are activities all hit like three hundred percent right
but it doesn't work as it does it doesn't work because you run out of
kind of computational resources this gets this ramsgate big the number of of rules grows
and grows cubicle in the number of states
and it turns out that were really wasting alot splitting everything everywhere and maybe this
should be obvious but it took us a while to realize this and in particular
those a part of speech called com
the words in the part of speech comma are
the common
so we split this into many many clusters each of which contains the comma
so this is clearly a waste so we don't want to be doing this
but you know even beyond that what if you're just putting determiners again and here
is kind of further down the terminus poetry and if you look over there on
the left you can see that we've got two categories that really answer different
so are these two similar
to keep the split or do we want to kind of stop splitting at this
point i don't know this is why i kind of
the computer sort this out and so i have to have some kind of test
the test we use as we look at the likelihood with and without the split
and if the gain in likelihood isn't enough then we reverse the split and we
get these kind of ragged trees that only split where where it is
so now essentially we're splitting of the categories but then we take half of half
of the splits their least useful and we merge them back together
what does this do
it kind of shrinks the rate at which our grammars grow substantially and suddenly all
of these points that we are achieving with very big grammars they'll shift over to
the left we get similar accuracy is much smaller grammars the actresses actually got to
and we let us do more rounds of this without blowing up the grammar size
and now we can get a lot further so now if we do some kind
of merging as well so that we're not allocating primers everywhere but only where they're
needed then we gain not only in size but also in accuracy and her up
to eighty nine point five percent
and this is already starting to be state
so i so we're allocating complexity where it needed
return to this later but for now we might kind of look and see what
kinds of what kinds of things we make complex and it turns out noun phrase
and verb phrases prepositional phrases and other things that you've heard of are in fact
very common and they are also very complex and we captured that by kind of
allocating a lot of parameters to them
but then things that you have heard about any trust me really don't know about
like the not a category and the next symbol with the service remained very simple
both because they are very frequent and because they're not very complex
same thing if you look at parts of speech so nouns and adjectives these kinds
of things are very complicated
they get split a lot whereas are from the common
and the part of speech to which also only contains one word don't get split
off because there's never any like again from
OK so we can allocate income parameters in an incremental way
so that we learn reasonable things and we also stop when there's one this can
no more support for the split
all kinds of things we learned
there are some candy
there are some of the proper nouns so it's it remember in the treebank there's
just one kind of proper noun but it turns out months are very different from
people in their syntactic distribution
the system is learned that appropriately so
months in particular abbreviated months because they happen to be used in the stylistically particular
get one category first name middle names last names or get their own category you
can see the first word of a place in the second world of place are
syntactically different distributions they get their own categories
in terms of pronouns there's only one pronoun but it turns out that according to
the statistics there are there are three kinds of case
in english there's nominative case there's accusative case and there's upper case
and the system is when this generalisation which never would have come
from a top down kind of linguistic
the notion where uppercase is not the case
the joke too
here's another split so you can see adverbs have been split i personally would have
had trouble figuring out how to put the adverbs but it turns out that there's
various kinds of degree adverbs in a pattern differently syntactically
numbers there's a very big difference between numbers that mean years and numbers that means
stock prices
so they get different categories because they they kind of occur in different places in
the tree
and so on
OK so this is a case where what we've learned
we kind of this is an incremental learning regime
we're starting with only the coarsest observation of the course is kind of syntax and
then using generalized policy iteration this was the optimal policy that there is this much
because this multicolored controller
the club which in the end
so i see it says
more or less around eighteen or nineteen
or above stick
and below him if you use ways and then you more complex only if you
no boys
at the bottom
and then i
right OK
so let me lately discovered something of exploration well
briefly the more
so what you can start in every possible state action OK you actually had like
that table
so then what you should do is
you the policy
chooses OK now you actually need to use a stochastic policy
OK because you want to follow what you think is the best action but occasionally
have to explore
OK so in this case you choose the greedy best action
with one minus epsilon classifier number of action that you have not state
without probability
OK for every other nine reaction
you choose it with absolute over number action OK you can see that this would
sum to one
the probability distribution OK so
most time to the reaction with some probability choose a
no not all actions OK and now blackjack table then you can start exploring randomly
as long as every state can reach every other state under some action they're guaranteed
for all states and actions
OK so the summary
OK so this is a very that their images of monte carlo methods over
dynamic programming solutions that we saw earlier
our policy iteration
you are direct interaction with environment you don't need to know
OK this makes your problem to specify model is supported only by model
OK now
what happens if you model your problem has a markovian process
but you didn't really productive fishing years and your state actually make work markovian
it turns out the monte carlo
control methods are actually
two markovian violations
which actually means that if your model is not a good model
and then may be better off actually settling in the world
the other two we can more clear as i as i move on to the
next lecture
OK let me start into that
so what
we discovered monte carlo methods
this is one extreme there we were recovered a
OK effectively
monte carlo methods sample
the entire trajectory
so can anyone think of
so advantages as some some imagine that you could use
then occurring methods
monte carlo methods
can you think of one disadvantage of the monte carlo sampling
approach or in general what the problem is simply
thank you
o memory and time course right
so i said if the state space sorry if if
it can often take a large number of samples to get a good
value estimate
unfortunately the monte carlo method you have to wait
so you see here some kind of knowledge idea this one
just that there is no one's again instead of being again it's a equivalent to
one be more
you see some some changes in the same so in this particular case
the only thing nineteen will be given by this newfound which is the maximum between
put on what you get
nine thousand hundred ninety so it's again in light of the two states that the
least significant bits of the smallest ones
value should be
constant of the full range but in fact it's not and you will see things
like that so find it is this
these beaches is a bit longer than what it should be it's
half moon and you will get at another place you get another one which is
smallest so you can get a very good for instance in the idea with this
missing but then if you look at the data it you will see some
some films
and again the world to see this effect
to to see the effect it in the new world
move very slowly you are going to this in looking which is the output are
you put some fully on the that
like for the kids and you should get some simple blood flow completely flat and
if it's not
it will tell you what are the nonlinearity
in terms of also quite often some missing code so as to give them time
to really get code which is easy to navigate uses could because something inside
or you can get all sorts of movement something which is not monotone which is
you go you from the to the on the background to sense
can you
a very important things to keep in mind is the effective number of bits because
when you when you get to that is you know it's an n bit ADC
and indeed see we introduce you
a quantization of which is assigned to be divided by twelve to to twenty
just because
you it is in between plus and minus
if it is been should continue the i find
square would of twelve
so now if you could if you are to see that which is pure sinusoids
with this opportunity with a being the full of a full-scale
then you will get to know i end
which is given by
but like this
formula which is
the islands and of wonderful
and if you do find similar to the i shall always be with that you
in indeed as then load this
the value of this thing and all of this is village
the signal and the only way you will find something like that which is nicely
in the ability to do so and then BBC will give you a signal to
noise ratio which is six times the number of bits plus one point eight db
they were and then you want
and you find that doesn't fit and so what
what we call the effective number of bits is what the end behind that we
have to put in this formula so that find
quite signal to noise ratio so i take an example
that's the BBC from another device which is given full twenty seven learning from twenty
to sixty five million and five if we just put inside this nice new so
it and then you make a fast fourier transform of the output you will get
a signal you your sincerity which is there
no then you look at where is the flow of the knowledge and you find
that in this case you get seventy db
between the nineteenth of your and and to get seventy b
here in this formula it will give you an equal to eleven point four so
that's not the twenty BBC this at this particular frequency would the point four and
that's a good one could be that you
and it is used for the song forty three twenty two
eight to fifteen
number of bits and then that's what calls for you for your measurement this is
something you should see in general is well documented
that i should
but it's always good to measure i
so we have this was a different type of ABC's
so this is the simplest one is is the flat simplex one instruction because it
is just that if you want to have
then did
you just put two
to the poor and minus one combined to
but we will
what you need to be
you you
would be
this is
general motors even use
and then he
he was that
this is it's
so just write your need
this is this
you know
so there's is no
it is used to do
brown and this
in vision
you you
it is
he was born
this be used
you seem to be
the reason why
you know you can do it
he was
so what
from the
six that
if you can
two rules
i mean
the to
i want to give
well you
you rules
if you want to give
you need to
the next two years
this is a
roberts c
you can do it
in this one
may also
this is of
to get
you are do
the ricci flow
so far
one of the main who is
this year one
so i
then you can start the question really going for
the all noise
when we can
we had market
and one thing we can use these feature
well at least for in the classification
so from the party
we might extract more features
which means that
we could extract for instance the park
between two work
in the past
so expect to complete on
and i mean going one which was in the water going down the far
so you can write here
taking off his car
this of course is that there information
if you use the features of the text
it might be
now all we only have a few of the kind of girl you come be
usually we don't you complete parts
but we could pull it
this could be split out silly because
living in a small
in the small
and he
the feature in classification
we we can use
like semantic
if we had like the some people use more than
you can find me anymore
maybe also hyperbole
more generally a certain for which we could also in
so for like four
we could use HTML
in the
on the web
these features
to describe information which want to classify
or to describe the context in which you
two o
a second topic it's all in that
the concept
in the rest of the chapter
so what
in information extraction well the only one in four
because we have be a very well already quite a lot out
pattern recognition in which all used for
information extraction
so what actually what we want to do is i think system
and classified
you you might
i don't know
very much about your background
some of you might know that i'm very quickly all about that in the a
support of supervised learning unsupervised learning and weakly supervised learning
so what
in the
which may
if we had a
for example they are
we can learn from
with within the y
and it all the information we have
the newspaper texts
and what would be able first me in the next four location that
we believe the person to take be a look it then you can
so the system act
the classification impact so the correlation of of patterns
after ten
we're going to maybe
part of of speech other information and the class y
we can learn from the training set
the classification function for prediction or classification
and then you can apply to move on and that's that
you encounter a new sentence putting new that
in which you will recognise the
he has
so that name
i might not have been
in your training that it might be a completely new names because the names of
the first names of companies
which is why we can can become and can be there are many new
but the context if you take into account the context of the feature
so we
well the other words in the name for
then you might
these for a new example apply
this is the class
o point five
learning so you have unsupervised
who had already labelled training
information extraction and text classification in general
we can the problem two class learning problem
so you
you classified information objects certain words for instance
belongs to a particular class or not
o or one
and the problem
we can learn from
but you might then
and the world belongs to class
you know we have
we compute the probability
of course not to class
we will
it was being closed in its own context because in greek mythology people have not
just one i are they have some blue hat and so on and this is
completely valid in greek mythology context while in the rest of this normal common sense
it's not so that's why you need this
concept of
context is one simple example which actually but you need the smallest on every step
on top you have the concept think
and every everything else is in turn inherited from this think let's say here we
have human beings is all mean that we can encode it
different aspects of human life
what's the structure of this ontology and so on the upper part we have this
upper ontology which are very abstract concepts about the life of me to make the
concepts and relationships between them below this we have courtier is which already know about
the space time and causality and so on then here we have
specific domains and on the bottom you effects which actually have
now what would be an example
of upper ontology would be that i think individual temporal think you've and so these
are really abstract things which
need to be represented courtier would be something like this for all events a and
b if a causes b
this implies a precedes b we all know this but
despite being written somewhere and this is what is written in this first order logic
in on this level domain specific theory would be
some like this for any mammal m and any
anthrax bacteria a
if m is being exposed to a then this causes m to be infected by
a a and is that you can also apply this rule then we know already
that bit
more that's
this exposure must have happened before because of the rule of law
and effects
this is an example affected by the following john is a person infected by anthrax
now since
you know in the knowledge base the john is a person and first person we
a lot of this kind of animal and human like the
type of animal and so on you know a lot about what the person is
you know what is the fact that we know what is and and we can
infer out of this a lot of new facts this is
the point of this
a short already disliked how certain claims
sentences that from news articles or somewhere else are translated into first order logic so
all the examples are from this there is the main because
the company had
projects from this area
so these are the kind of rules and these are the actual effects which
you can extract by let's say this text mining techniques which i was showing before
from the
text documents and
so this is located is based in afghanistan so this is encoded in this simple
fact which blocked into this such knowledge
this is an example how
looks like
concept cycle psychoanalyst
so just to show you how the knowledge can be structured so psychoanalysts
a couple of lexical representations
and his position of medical care professionals position of health professionals professional does professional this
one line of
sports innovations the psychologist scientist researcher person medical patient person homo sapiens logical spaces so
we can come from this biological space down to psychoanalyst and back necessary and reasoning
engines is using this so
we know for a person
a lot of things and since psychoanalyst just personalisation of the person
then you know that this holds also for cycle that but this is just taxonomic
relationship of what we have fifteen thousand relationships more in knowledge base
here is just one nice example how
reaches vocabulary in this cyc knowledge base see here this is vocabulary of the relationship
if something is in its
inside something else
so this is relationship for in
among so this is inside well in such a way that is in contain completely
this if this object is contained completely in something else or is in contain partially
because it's not contain completely version in contain closed
it's close all
in the spring and go in content open so it can fall out then they
would use this so this is just
this simple relationship in
would have such
so many specializations
but a further on connectedtoinside would have another one sticksinto screwedin and so on so
if they
try to describe describe one situation in mechanical physical world and they would use this
kind of vocabulary to describe it in proper way
and so this is just one last example
the whole cycle work so this is six from tents called cyc analytic environment here
i don't know if you can see so here's the question which you can type
being in a natural language question is the following never maybe two years ago it
was this that because the prime minister of lebannon got killed
and the question was
who has a motive for the dissemination of in africa
two non-trivial question
with that being the question
the cyc translate this into first order theory then you can correct this very little
bit more or edit for but most likely to get translated into proper form automatically
and the press
but in here and then we get the list of answers
let's start to the UK the united states israel so this would be candidates
and then we show here is you
the name
speculation speculation level so
how much
how difficult are what is the type of reasoning which site performs resnick engine for
performance on the other side it and
can be speculation well my mind mildly
mainly of moderates and these are sources
from the news stories which are encoded in the cyc knowledge base which support this
particular place now if e
but in further on then we would get justification for such a claim
it's a question here would be the following so why would have a motive to
they are perfect
but then we sort of in between e to close
plus four new two the plus one
they had this very funny shape
reminds we
the shape of this blue a little bit
sort of like this
o think
and there's one surface
which is most unusual
people potential surface
which here
has the point where the electric field is zero sort of like
twisting the neck of course you get something like this
so you have here surface
which has a point here is exactly at that point
the electric field is zero
that does not mean
that the potential is zero of course not
potential is positive here
if you come
with the positive charge from the lobby seventy you have to march up to that
point you have to do positive work you have to overcome both the repelling force
from the plus four and the repelling force from the plus one
but finally when you reach that point you can rest
because is no force on you at that point that's what it means that the
electric field is zero it does not mean that you haven't done any work
never confuse electric fields
i want to draw your attention to the fact
that the green lines the field lines are everywhere perpendicular to the people tentials i'll
get back to that during my next lectures that is not an accident that is
the case
next well
shows you something that is a little bit more complicated
calculated for us
the equipotential surface into the red ones and surfaces again you have to rotate them
about the vertical
to make it three-dimensional
now we have a minus one charge
on the plus four
so whenever it is read the surface the potential is positive
whenever i have drawn in blue
the potential
first if we were very far away from both the plus four and the minus
you expect
to be looking at the charge which is effectively plus three
so if you go very far away for sure the potential is everywhere positive and
you expect it to be spherical
if you look here
very far away from the plus four the minus one indeed this has already
the shape
of a
so that's clear that the plus for the minus one far away behave like plus
if you very close to the plus four
you get nice spheres around the plus four
potential if very close to the minus one
notice that the blue surfaces so almost my spheres
but now
all negative
very close to the minus one
negative potential
there is
he won surface
we now has zero potential
has to be
because if you
the negative potential closer to minus one
and you have positive potential very far out
you got to go through service words here
so does he was surface i still have put it in blue
which is actually everywhere on the surface
the potential
is zero
is the electric field zero order
absolutely not
electric field should not be confused
what it means is that if you take a test charge in your pocket you
come from infinity
and you walk through that surface
by the time average that surface you've done zero work that's what it means
is zero
there is view one point
which we discussed earlier
in my lectures where the electric field is zero
the potential is not zero there
potential is definitely positive here
because he was zero
surface using already positive surface and this is the positive surface sort of potential is
if you reach that point
there's no force on the chart
that means electric fields
zero not so easy of course to calculate
these surfaces maxwell was capable of doing that kind of ten years ago
and nowadays we can do that very easily
the key potential surfaces which have different values
can never intersect
plus five vols surface can never intersect with the plus three or minus one you
think about why that is why is it will be total violation
conservation of energy
so equipotential surfaces
different values can never
all right
so you've seen that for the various charge configurations
the equipotential surfaces
a very complicated shapes
can always be calculated it's very easy way
now comes the question
why do we introduce electric potentials leads them
and leeds
people tential surfaces
isn't it true that if we know the electric field vector is everywhere in space
that determines uniquely
how charges will move
what acceleration with they will
that means how to kinetic energy will change the answer is yes if you know
electric field everywhere in space sure
you can predict everything that happens
it was a charge in that field but there are examples
twenty electric fields as are so incredibly complicated
that it is easier to work
with the equipotentials
because the change in kinetic energy is
discussed now
really depends only on the change
in the potential
you go from one point to another
so you will see very shortly that sometimes if you're only interested in change of
kinetic energy
not necessarily interested in the details of the trajectory
the key potentials come in very handy
never confuse
which is
electrostatic potential energy
with v
which is
has unit
and this has to reduce book call vol
so for example i mean we can generalize search
just check this log
so the search procedure is you start at the top left let's say we're looking
for seventy two
you start the top left fourteen is smaller than seventy two so i try to
go right seventy nine it's too big
so i i followed this area
but ourselves that's too much so instead i go down
fourteen still i go to the right of fifty that that's still small and seventy
two OK
try to go right again all seventy nine that's too big
it's good so i down so i get fifty
ah good try the same thing over and over try to go the right sixty
six it's OK to go right or something and it's too big so i go
down and i got the right of seventy two
otherwise go too far in trying to go down ourselves
element must not be there
very simple search on
the same is here
except just remove l one and l two
go right until that would go too far then go down think around it so
that we could finding good and might have this login times
in each level including only walking a couple of steps
because the ratio between these two size is only two
so this will cost to log
so i mean that was to check because we're using intuition over here
a little bit shaky
so this is an ideal skip list
we have to support assertions and deletions as soon as we do need to delete
so now we're going to maintain the structure of the two
two special there's only one of these
where you were the you know everything is perfectly spaced out and everything is
you full
so we can do that
we're going to maintain roughly this structure
as best we can
if any one of you knows
someone in
new york city some planning can tell us
so asking
so this is the real this is basically a data structure could use this is
the starting point but then start using skip lists
and we need to somehow
insertions and deletions
and maintain roughly the structure well enough
the search
still cost or log n time
so let's focus on insertions
we do insertions has that deletions are
really trivial
and again this is all from first principles are not allowed to say anything
but it would be nice we could talk
so suppose you want to insert an element x we is set out to search
for element so how do we inserted
well the first thing we should do is figure out where to go so research
because search access to find somewhere
in the bottomless just anywhere
pretty easy to find a replacement topless that takes constant time
we want to know
because of has constant length
we want to know where x goes in the bottomless so we're search let's say
we want to insert eighty
we search for eighty we get a bit of a social seventy five
will find seventy five it's three here between seventy to seventy nine using the same
OK if it's there already we complain because i'm going to assume all keys are
distinct are now
west you start with a convex function you subtract off
the linear approximation
and then
the gap
in the approximation is the divergence
really understand this
it always has this formula
convex function minus the linear approximation
it has various properties defenses property
the saccharine theorem
which says
that the if you project onto convex set
this inequality always holds
no matter what the bregman divergences
this is opposite from the triangle inequality so that's why we use the term divergence
i gave a bunch of examples
right euclidean distance squared
and then he algorithms that interpolates between the two families
auc entropy
then i gave the matrix versions of them
and now i talked about how i motivate these updates in general
trade between divergence
and loss
this holds you back this makes you lost small
OK this is the general form of the update
general form of the update
you always apply to link function to the weight vector
you subtract the gradient and then you go back
these days are various
analysis that we have done in the simple analysis to the
the learning rate is constant in some of the fancy analysis we have learning rates
one or
this very deep problem in this context the problem is
i would like to have the trade-off
parameter vector which is also
over here as the parameters not just as the weight vector but also in
and eta
and then i would need a more complicated expression in here which also would have
involved the divergence
of the current learning rate to deal with learning rate
plus something additional
and we haven't quite piece this together they some kind of phd thesis looking out
that brings design very carefully the also derives an update
for the learning rate
we seen inklings of it
but it's not perfect yet
it's kind of frustrating
so beautiful
OK it's kind of going later on we going to motivate bregman divergences and exponential
families is going from
sort of the
this generalisation of exponentials
families that have the temperature in exponent street in that case
OK here i showed you pictorially what the trade of does
some going over this because it's important
this is the last
here's an example
divergence terms and here's the trade-off
between the two
tension between staying where you are verses updating and greedily going to minimizing loss
OK then i'll give you an example
i of sort of a general outline for how to improve bounds
use these convexity of the loss and use properties of
the divergence you get some kind of telescoping
i just want to get the flavour of how it's done
at the end you arrive at the bound of this type
total loss of the output
so moses biggest loss of the compared to
plus some divergence the beginning
notice bounds hold for arbitrary sequences of examples OK
here's some examples found for linear regression
these bounds are done for the worst case
for arbitrary sequence of examples sometimes called the worst-case relative loss bounds
worst-case regret bounds
it turns out if you pick any of these problems like a and and analyse
the out and out to analysis you do the worst case analysis union converted to
an average case analysis you be to beat the best bounds
the around for the average case for the case where the instances are generated by
some distribution
this is kind of
new level of power the documents similarly when you take into account titles and five
those kinds of information all really open up new possibilities for
richard better search
so what unexploited aspect the document is next
you know it's actually the linguistic structure document irony here is the most is actually
made of linguistic structure
and currently is mostly discarded and ignored
this is you know largely unaddressed the document side due to historically to computational cost
and complexity and most previous work in the natural language community trying to apply natural
language search has really focused on the query only and their user enters a query
and the system tries to understand the query and translate that into a keyword advanced
or you know you were critically through the search engines
that can go some of the way
but ultimately
it's just that there are things you would like to try to do the impossible
it's fundamentally limited because then your system while translated queries it still faced with an
old keyword is style interface into the documents themselves
so this structurally has immense value and is where the document's intent is action coding
so i powerset semantic index are indexer cracks linguistic structure these documents to extract meaning
the applies deep natural in which the entire corpus to build the right representation
this actually becomes a new kind of index creates a platform for innovation
that allows for greatly expanding capabilities we think we're really just at the start of
this and that together as a community world all going to be discovering the possibilities
that this enables
now natural language for consumer search especially the processing of the content on the index
inside was really not possible
that this kind of the scale that we're looking even five years ago
several things happened
in terms of economics the cost came down more has just
driven to make you know making many
orders of magnitude more computing available then when people were really trying to do and
natural language processing
even now benefiting from four corps and core processes among other things the cost is
going down really fast in addition to the technology is natural language technologies have sped
up in recent times
on the other side economics revenue came up so
all quite awhile ago people were looking at search there was almost no money to
be made it was something we might get some users but no and no one
knew how to make money that's all changed now the
advertising revenue from search is you massive and you can actually afford with this kind
of economics to do a lot of computing on the back end
it's also the case that the user experience can be transformed even with the current
NL capabilities in natural language has come along way but it's not perfect but the
good news about search is that keyword search is not perfect either so perfection is
not required here
but you know and we now the existence of robust broad coverage integrated systems
in addition there is a challenge to work across multiple languages and several of these
systems including the one power cities using are based on multilingual core platform
and you can then plug ins essentially plug in new languages to make the system
you know there there's an issue here about changing user behavior because users used entering
keywords i think in this research community we all look towards the future in any
case and this is the kind of change that should be a change to something
easier because you don't need to its were used to keyword search down but it
still is something artificial there's it it's the gap between what we really think of
our and we have to do so
kind of like when you're shifting from going from driving a car with a manual
transmission to an automatic transmission
you have to change the behavior but it's the change is something that's easier at
least for some of us
these kind of things are actually already happening we're nothing more voice interfaces in mobile
contexts we want to use language and get more precise results and already with careers
naver and yahoo answers and an increasing trend towards giving users shortcuts an instant answers
directly on on web search there's more and more opportunities to be using language to
get a better result in search
and even just using keywords these kinds of system by having more information coming out
of the documents can actually give better results without any changes we have
so the language technology
has really evolved a lot there are now on large scale grammars that can practically
employed there's also an increasing amount of lexical ontological knowledge resources things like wordnet verbnet
so know
the things many people here work on
in addition there's been a lot of improvement in data driven acquisition methods to acquire
new ontological natural resources and to bridge different kinds of ontologies so the work of
this community is really directly feeding into these you know enabling these kinds of applications
or discuss more
another big trend is open source software
these are big areas for most smaller efforts including start-ups and research organisations to create
things in large scale but the open source community is actually now working to
let me know the demonstration relatively small circuit
and measures of voltages for you
and show you that
the voltage is indeed add up to zero
so you my those circuits
so i'm going to show you a simple circuit that looks like this and let's
go ahead and
measure some voltages and currents
in terminology remember
this is called a loop
so if i take place far from the points c
and travel through the water source
come to denote a dancefloor one and all the way down throughout the back seat
that's loop
so the only this point eight is the node where
resistor r one
what source we zero and are four connected
just make sure your terminology is correct
it's all of those let me make some quick measurements for you and show you
that are these KVL and KCL are indeed in the truth
so it's up there could have a
grammar volunteer
and you want
well you have to do the right things the work one
OK so
let me take some measurements and wanted to write down what i measure on the
what i do is one of his talk here
but although in
focus on
this peer
and focus on
this node and makes some measurements
all right
you see the circuit up there
OK so i get few more
for the voltage from CQA
so in two i don't labels
OK so the next one is
minus one point six
and so that the and doing up a b b a b
OK and then let me do
the last one and
it is minus one point three seven
i could be the measurements ideas made have been this way so it's
it was written is busy but that's it's OK for about it so
so then number thank you
i appreciate your help here
OK so
within bonds of experimental error
notice that if i am out of this we will produce they the nicely sum
up to zero
OK next let me focus on this note here
and add this node let me go ahead and measure some currents
what i do know is changed to
james to an AC
AC voltage so that i can go ahead and measure the current without breaking my
again this time around you'll get to see the measurements that i'm taking as well
so we have here
i guess you can see this for what i have here is three wires
that pulled out from the
and this is the node
OK so three wires
coming into the node is to make it a little easier for me to measure
OK so i everybody keep your fingers crossed
so i don't look like a fool
i hope this works out OK
so you don't forget
this is the same so i it will give you
however the different rows or columns related to one another but i'm not going to
going over all the same masses of dry dung the last sort of half thing
but basically identical and the cells are still all in the book and how is
identical is all the book and the final picture is that
more dimensional scaling is
this is certainly where
instead of having
a set of experts labels that tell you
if you think of the axes given coordinates in space and in the course world
suppose that we have got is
the distance
between each pair
of objects in space so we might have
so what i mean that situation
what i think of two citizen travelling between them and how much does it cost
you might have
for example we can look at minute which is
places in the
britain and you got distances you want to draw a map that
and that's the objective is to draw a map that represents those distances that you
so much where the distance between the sexes is telling you about the price of
the tickets
so it's not the geographical distance they actually
and in this case
not the geographical distance but how far you actually have to go
in terms of driving rather than
flying in a helicopter all crow flies if you go by road
and the really classical example was man
i was told this egyptologist copy petri
what is the
it was each of these two things incidents of different types of classes
i would list which tunes the vases appeared in all which types of those work
coefficient measures how similar or different things from ones who were compared to another so
so this is how these sorts of things arise you a classic common standard method
of doing this is
one of largest arises things like taste testing when you ask people to stop eight
or does
so it's a small similar to chocolate and chocolate see those and things like that
so you rankings
but not
so you have a question about differences but not
the actual cases you know this is just a question how similar things are not
about their absolute properties
so we try do is we have the pairwise
coefficients measure how similar one justice to another or
o different
with local distances i have some examples as to
we're trying to construct is
the corresponding inputs the axes that would have given that space or map
o corresponds to distances
and various types one is classical scaling classical scaling because it was the first one
people came up with
so psychometric scaling because mathematically there's an assumption that the distances between places are actually
metric which if you don't know what i'm talking about that don't worry me normal
president for this article principal components analysis because it has a relationship to principal components
analysis paul not interrupts right OK
and it's been a long time
to show you itself
the is
taken in britain we have something called the automobile association they publish a little table
of distances between cities
by road
they're not the shortest distance is that
the fastest distances
the short journey time distance into the time not in terms of
miles it is about
right so taking
and applied classical principal component
now we are experts so we are starting to
the standard to combine things coming from different perspectives so we learn to learn something
about dynamic systems theory
and we can easily see
that if we we are modelling
we did using bayesian networks a situation like this one
in which we have
output measurements only of one of the state variables so which reflects the state variable
we may have a situation of partial observability
so we have the dynamical system which is is punishable partially observable states
and we can use it also
bayesian networks and so this kind of modelling to represent the systems which are dynamic
which instead of being a deterministic stochastic systems in which the state is not fully
observable so
i need
to put some knowledge around here or to use a particular optimisation goal is to
try to derive
the knowledge about the
transition of the state x x one
OK so you survive the for
around one hour and a half cylinder last the meaning of the of the
talk i have to
tell you something about one of the main topics of
the chapter of the book which was written by elizabeth bradley
one of the topic itself is called delay coordinate embedding
why have left this topic at the end of the story because i think that
we do have understood the let's say the basic components of the problem so we
have dynamical system this dynamical system can be typically described using the state space
which is a fundamental concept that tells you what's going on really inside of the
system when we are modelling we can if we are able make can model the
using the state variable sometimes we can't because we don't have enough knowledge to do
we are using input output systems input output systems can be deterministic or stochastic they
can be represented in different ways so now
the interesting question is if i just have all the variables m i
the arrival the presentation
of the output variable in the state space
so it's something which is missing in our discussion of the
and this idea of the coordinate embedding is exactly trying
to answer these questions
so if i'm able
to reconstruct the space the state space representation from a uni dimensional time series and
being available set of sample data
so it has been shown that it is possible to have the representation with there's
some properties some good properties in the main good properties that the qualitative behavior of
the face portrayed the which able to derive using this technique of the coordinate embedding
is the same of the real world
what does it mean this means that what they are doing using this technique is
not exactly this the state space in terms of
the same quantities so the scale for example is not preserved but what is certain
is that if i found if a able to find it equilibrium point in the
states space right using this technique then this equilibrium point will exist also in the
real world and in the true
OK so this so-called invari ants preserved the moving it is representing the evolution of
the state space in this using this technique with respect to the the real ones
so what is the idea well the idea is extremely simple when i started this
technique i far as well
it's so simple and by forces you're insured is through data is to add a
certain number of state variables using the same values of y which is time which
observing over time delay the all certain things to so using their also an example
of before example is better than
hundreds of the theorem so let's start with the an example
so let's study is example which is performed on a linear system
he has a very popular
probabilistic model for solving collaborative filtering
the idea is the following so we're gonna assume that every user is gonna
have some
some features which are unobserved
and this is a
a vector in the Euclidean space which basically describes what sort of movies does the
user like
corresponding to every movie we're also gonna assume that there's a probability vector which describes
what type of movie that movie is
and we
postulate that the rating that user i gives to movie j
is gonna be Gaussian distributed with a mean given by the dot product between
the user feature and the movie feature
so that
if the two feature vectors count lineup together so what that says is that the sort of
movies that the user likes is very similar to the sort of movie that that
movie is
and of course we'r gonna assume that there's some variants around this mean okay
so that we can handle
all the randomness in the ratings of the of the of the users okay
yeah r i j is gonna be Gaussian distribution over the mean given by this dog products
and the variants given by sigma square and
you can now
I forgot to to descr
to tell you what is the prior of these features and the prior of sigma square but
you can imagine that you know these features might be given priors which are
Gaussian and this feature's also Gaussian while
for sigma square you might use a gamma or it or inverse gamma a prior
and given our ratings we can now again compute the com the posterior distribution over user
features and movie features and that basically
kind of solves the problem for us okay
because with the user features and product features we can we can estimate
how much does each user likes each movie
according to this model of course one thing to note about this is
we are not just
kind of a
the dimensional vector right so we're all kind of complex beings we like certain movies for
some reason we don't like certain movies for some reason and really this is
simply a very simp very this is simply a model which makes very strong simplifying
assumptions about the generative process that jet that gave us the movie ratings okay
but still is a very useful model
and you can kind of test this model on by
entering this into the Netflix competition and so forth right so you could kind of test it by looking how well
it predicts ratings which which it it doesn't which it hasn't
observed and this does really well okay
so yeah so I'd like to kind of emphasize that of course all models are wrong
but some models are useful okay so this is a phrase by
a famous statistician that I forgot any more right so so that's
Bayesian machine learning of course today and tomorrow I'd like to talk
about a particular
class of
Bayesian models called Bayesian nonoarametric models and if you're interested in this there's a book
on Bayesian nonparametrics edited by Hjort et al that just came out last
so let's start off by kind of telling by saying what is a nonparametric model okay so
basically I can tell you what it is not it's basically not a parametric model okay
so what is a parametric model a parametric model is basically a model with a
certain fixed number of parameters so for example a Gaussian is a parametric model because it has
a mean and a variance it has two parameters and that's it okay
so basically a nonparametric model is not a parametric model
not in the sense that it doesn't have any parameters but rather in the sense
that it has either an infinite number of parameters of a number of parameters
changes with the amount of data that is observed okay and is in that sense
that is not a parametric model a somewhat different way of doing what
is a nonparametric model is that is a family of distributions that's dense in some large
space okay I'll come back to this a bit later so the idea yeah I'll come back to this a bit later
so why are we interested in doing Bayesian nonparametrics
so let's imagine the following so
imagine that you're trying to do a classification okay
so in classification you have some inputs and you have some outputs
and you may have a space of hy very large space of hypothesis which basically corres
corresponds to the space of all smooth functions from input space to output space okay
so your output could be if it's binary then it just consists of either zero or one but your
input could say an Euclidean
space so this is the space of all possible smooth functions from your input space
to your output space and there might be some true underlying function which
you like to learn about so this function is a function that actually
tells you for every input what should be the true output okay
if you do something like in your own networks or linear regression or something then
basically you're assuming a parametric model
of this space okay
and what is a model a model's basically a very
tiny subset of this space that can be parameterized by your model
and if you're bayes Bayesian about this you might put a prior on
on this very small space
and it's very unlikely that the true function will actually be in the space it's very
unlikely that your true function is say a linear function because you know
in many exa in many revolt
CSSP projection so you you
so what may be just to explain this more probably so
you see of
this is a way to
get features
right so for every c p
projector you get
quantity it every time and so this is a time series
and you can classify
so see you have six of the CSP filters so this means that you can
involve one hundred twenty eight dimensional time signal
with six filters so this means that you
you know you project down this one hundred twenty eight times serious to six times
here and then you can you know
classify every actor and this time series and
to the left or right OK
and you can do the same for these cssps of course you the classifier and
and see what comes out of it and you do some model selection
now you see that
in many cases CSSP can actually give a large improvement so
so where's here for this data point for example CSP gives you
fifty percent fifteen percent error is less than five percent here
there are some cases words about the same there is no significant difference
and this some
points which doesn't work
this is
it's all actually a very interesting to look at these cases doesn't work and see
what is the physiology behind so
but maybe the bottom line of this idea is that we should not only focus
on the spatial distribution of the
the brain signals but we should also look at that time temporal structure at the
same time
now there's more there is a parameter to select which is the tower which is
the delay that i take into account the time scale
and this needs to be
chosen appropriately
there is even another and for those of you at NIPS we had in NIPS
paper on on this this is just adding some more s is here
and it's two to give don he can in basically the bottom line is that
you don't want to specify pre specified this this
delay of the filter but you what actually want to learn it
from the data because in the way this is always something if you if you
do an experiment then you have to look at the spectrum of the individual and
then you know where to put the band filter and so on so forth so
it it takes some some knowledge or some some feeling for the physiology
and it would be nice to have this more automatic OK
if you
look at this these are
this is just the motivation for CSSP and there were not for the talk about
it because you can just download the paper from the NIPS pages it's also quite
technical but just to get the idea
the the
here the here the idea of this plot was to show that
of the spectrum that you see here
a quite
discriminative so you see these these little
the gray boxes down here they're very good for discriminating between between two classes
and you see that there are two bombs in the spectrum so you could in
principle use both of these pumps so there's a lot of fun higher
peak but which one should use
and it could be that that for example
you know
that one peak is very good for the discrimination and the other one is not
but the point in common spatial pattern as this CSS SP is that it automatically
finds the most discriminative so you don't need is a prespecified this
on that band
but you just get it automatically to the point
actually very convenient
i will slightly change gears
let's look at this motorhome and colours
if we look at the motor cortex than
this is the place where the mouse is represented
the hand these individual digits
the arm
and so on
so so the question now is so we've
address the issue of multiclass
the the the question for us was was how far can we actually get
can we discriminate between fingers c
because if we could be
discriminate between fingers and joints and things like that then in principle we could is
we could
o controller robot i'm saying
because we have all these
so to say primitive
on the other side EEG has limited resolution so so it's actually quite open whether
we can do it or not
in real time
because we don't want to make an averaging over many trials with averaging etc it's
much easier to distinguish say between gauges
we just
show you
i i show i showed these plots
before this this was
o point in time before
the movement takes place