marginal as the voice of art may be it attempted to remind us that despite the
optimism of certain metaphysicians there is something implacably and sadly
malignant about this world
my book concludes with the text by italo calvino
a short story that
springs from real experience
the cottolengo in turin is a Catholic institution full of incurably ill
people persons who cannot even feed themselves without assistance many of them born as monster
like many of those we have talked about here
not legendary monsters but monsters who live
ignored alongside us
the main character of the story is a scutratore man sent by a political
party to control the elections
the election because there is a polling station even in that hospital
because those monsters are citizens too
and according to the law they have the right to vote
shocked by the side of these subhumanity
the scutratore realizes that
very many of the patient do not realize what they are going to do
and that they will vote according to the will of their religious helpers
belonging as it does to a leftist party would like to oppose what strikes him as
a fraud
but in the end
against all his political convictions
he concludes
that those who have the courage to devote their life to those unfortunates
have acquired the right to speak for them I would like to conclude even
my speech in the same vein
I have presented images that oblige us to recognize that ugliness can provoke either fear
and disgust or amusement making us to laugh of many human miseries
but after having witnessed of how unpleasant ugliness can be
when it doesn't concern ourselves
I think is wise to end with an appeal for compassion
thank you
so thank you very much that was really nice we are now ready for discussion
a mamo kakšno vprašanje kakšen komentar
but here with the microphone otherwise I miss half
of the words
if not important because I have prepared the answers so I can answer you are not that lucky
and you want to be able to associate the best people
if anybody tells you
that phd doesn't and why you with news equals
to explore a rusty
to think level
you could go to before so
i think
ok you're ok i'd like to point out something where in his fashion
i think he ignored the data
none of us here said they should not do a phd
advice was get experience you do it faster better cheaper
ok yeah point form please stop stop without claudia water the critical success factors for jobs science
by startup
first what i said is
really make sure to product
that's why something being on the sidelines as as mad the second is
you need to have
an amazing team that came before and you need people
who can have covered space when they built things how to
average on yeah excellent job program doesn't necessarily
get you what you need
building a good
data science environment a scale
that even program need around
handling data so you need a team that has experience
preferably standard before
point home wrong
so yeah i game i'm bringing vc perspective so what is very important is that
you know it's the same mining play after all this
this panel was about mining itself first is that the size of the addressable market
if you say you have a startup that south to like know
bookstores in chicago and how many bookstores in chicago to have one hundred probably not one
million right
so you're a your
market you can south to is not that be so that's one thing another thing
he is
your goal to market strategy so how you actually start sailing to
to co however your selling right
and this third thing is that your pricing
so if you south to a billion people and but the south for one many
error you're making like ten million dollars a year which is not
it's not very big success
point four morn
so we talked about team but i want to emphasize this is not all equal who's
the most important players in the miami heat right brunch change who's the most important person on
the team start-up
it's the ceo
or by orders of magnitude so
look very carefully at the ceo
point four yeah i agree with management but
i also say i would add to to what was said by on i would that execution
right so many people have great ideas great business models market size is there
and ideas ideas are so so cheap and so easy to have
is really distinguishing factors so
it was
a one off that said
you know i'll i'll i'll invest in any
boring idea would good execution any time
over a good idea with no execution which i would never invested so
ok so job down to question number three because the other was actually have been partially addressed they got a
lot of down votes oxygen question number two now
and it's very precise so we could probably get through its first new graduate soon
which path is better for starting a company in the future
are what go research lab and then start a company later
right or go big company
and start a company
if your grid getting sued send your resume yeah ok
kind of vision is ted's yeah i mean for trying to find the
ideas and the advice is just don't start a company right away
get experience whenever r as much as you can and then you will be a good
shape to start a company
so exactly what but foster but early on he faces and then i did
we get good mentorship way going to learn the most and make the most of the next few years and
let's not
examine clear whether this industry not only it's a lab claims we could be back
to back close look at who are going to work with and
what you can help to learn
ok yeah yeah and you know i mean
accident points out that
you know my great believe gradient descent
so there are two major directions here
in in learning right so learning you get from startup
are almost orthogonal
you know sociologically and so forth were choi's
then what you learn from the company and both are extremely important
so if you have the choice i completely agree with on don't
do you start just like with a phd have a little bit of experience before
with start up
to a little bit of experience before because you do this start-up faster better cheaper
and i remember in your career stochastic gradient descent yeah yeah unfortunately but that's the way it
i said question remaining is sokolniki any tips to technical founder wants to get
early-stage funding with skills from sama
yeah quick tips if you're technical founder then get yourself a business co-founder preferably
a very strong ceo
and we say this all the time for for also get a lot of business people want to
do a technology company
and the first thing we tell them as you know we want talk until you go get yourself a
technical co-founder
and they usually just go and get themselves an employee and we know that doesn't count co-founder means
they own a good chunk of the company
so i think you know it's t we
today and for the next two weeks we're going to study
what for many engineers and a few scientists is the most popular method
of solving any differential equation that they
of the kind happened to me
and that is to use the popular machine called plus transform
you'll get proficient in using it by the end of the two weeks
but there's always a certain amount of mystery that hangs around it
people scratch their heads can figure out where it comes from
and that bothers them alive
in the past i've usually promise to tell you the the end of the
student at the end of the two weeks but i almost never have time so
i'm going to break the glorious tradition and tell you up front at the beginning
where it comes from
and then to look very fast for the rest of the period of OK
a good way of thinking well plus transform comes from and way which i think
this still some of its ministry
is by thinking of power series
i think virtually all of the study power series except possibly a few students
from just had eighteen o one here last semester and probably should be taking eighty
three anyway about but anyway
a power series looks like this summation and actually and some that from let's say
zero to infinity
and the typical thing you want to do is add up to find out what
some is now the only way all depart from tradition
so i'm going to some some generic name like x
in order to identify the sum with the coefficients a colony of x
i want to make this one slight change in there
slight change in this i want to use computer notation which doesn't use the subscript
based event
instead it
this is the thing of the a function of the discrete variable and in other
it's a function which assigns to an any equal zero one two three real numbers
that's what the sequence of coefficients really is
computer notation will look almost the same it's just that all right that's in functional
notation is a event instead of a sub then but it still means the real
number associated with the integer positive integer and
and everything else is the same
so what i'm thinking of this is doing is
taking this discrete function which gives me the sequence of coefficients of the power series
and associating with the sum of the powers
let i think it's very simple examples of two very simple example which i think
you know
i suppose this is the function one now what i mean by that i mean
it's the constant function one two every positive integer it assigns the number one
OK what say that x
what i'm saying is in other words this fancy
this mystifying for if all these guys are one
i say that
one was experts x squared plus xq
look you're supposed to be born knowing what that adds up to
it adds up to
one o one minus six
except that's the wrong answer what's wrong about
it's not true for every value of x that is only true when x
is such that the series converges and that is only true when x lies between
negative one
and one
so it's not this function if this function with domain restricted to to be like
an absolute value
what is that converge to
if x is bigger than one the answer is it doesn't converge
it's nothing there's nothing
else you can put here
OK let's take another function i suppose this is o
let's see what over a you probably won't know
let's take one you will know one or n factorial
suppose a then is the function one over n factorial what's a of x
so what i'm asking is what does this add up to
when the coefficients here is one over n factorial
what summation x to the end over n factorial is
and this doesn't have to be qualified because this is true for all values of
so in other words from this peculiar point of view i think of the power
summing the operation of something power series as
taking a discrete function
fine for positive integers were nonnegative integers
and doing this funny process now becomes continuous function
and notice what goes in is the variable and
what comes out is the variable x
well that's perfectly natural that's way power series set
so the question i ask is here
this is the discrete situation discrete summation
to get this function i suppose i made the summation continuous instead of discrete so
i want the continuous analogue
of what i did over there OK well with the continuous analog b well
instead of all replace
and zero one two
that will be replaced by continue that the discrete variable
all replaced by continuous variable t
which runs from
to infinity
and is allowed to take every real value in between instead of being only allowed
to take the values of the positive integers nonnegative integers
OK well if i want to use t instead of then
i clearly cannot sum in the usual way over all real numbers but the way
the procedure which replaces summation over all real numbers is integration
so we're going to do is replace that some by the integral
from zero to infinity that's like the sum from one to zero to infinity of
well of some function but now
and is being replaced by the continuous variable t so this is going to be
a function of t
and how the rest of the rest of his copy
to the end well but instead of and i have to write t
and the t
and what's the someone well called the sum
what's the sum of function of
i integrate out the t so that doesn't appear the answer all that appears is
this number axis parameter x
for each value of x like one two or twenty six point three
this integral has a certain value and i can calculate so this is the end
up as a function of x just before
now i could leave it in four
but it would be
the mathematician would like to do that and very few engineers either
the reason is in general
well you do integration and differentiation you do not want to have as the base
of an exponential
acoustic articulatory data contains
this electromagnetic articulography data in addition to
data from various other various other sources
so i
so there's evidence so people had
used these sort of partial articulatory measurements two
improve the performance of what we might say are sort of traditional technology ASR systems
so there's there's proof that we can do something with this stuff
that's our motivation
any questions so far
the couple but asking questions you might embarrass himself in front of colleagues
OK so
the now the now the negative part one of the challenges here for
trying to incorporate articulatory models well big challenge is if we've only got acoustic information
the the
articulatory information or even
coming up with some notion of what the vocal tract shape is in association with
the given acoustic output
the other big challenges the nonlinear relationship between
production acoustics and perception and we'll talk a little bit about that
that is a very small changes in the position of articulators can result in dramatic
changes in the acoustics
and the and the
in various different nonlinear discontinuity can have these effects
finally the the coding of perceptually salient articulatory information is is also something it's that's
difficult to deal with the now give an example of an experiment that shows what
sort of problem that can be
here's a
to illustrate the difficulty of acoustic to vocal tract area mapping
we basically
can give an example of the sort of many
are they like is one to many problems the property associated with inverted inverting the
the acoustics two
two vocal tract area mapping
we got on the left
is the set of vocal tract shapes
terms of sort of area functions
we can think along the horizontal axis were basically moving from the glottis to the
and along the vertical axis is the vocal tract area so you can roughly think
of yourself as looking sideways at vocal tract and the the
the size of the you know the shape of the thing is sorted described by
by these curves
and so you see these are two
significantly different shapes and then on the right
we have associated with each of these things
the corresponding form and frequency and bandwidth associated with a given vocal tract shape there's
going to be a set of resonances peaks in the spectrum and refer to those
peaks formants they're going to have a centre frequencies designated by the here in the
top row and bandwidths associated with the b right so these are the formats frequencies
and bad associated with this
vocal tract area function and these are the following frequencies in the bandwidths associated with
this one well if we look at these frequencies and bandwidth they're pretty much identical
so with
these identical
the acoustic characteristics we get vastly different well vastly but much different vocal tract area
functions so it goes to show the difficulty
there was an experiment actually
well i in the middle ages actually
what we can do
the first
i think they tried to add more and more can here
you can use the
monarchs may like
korean of the
one of the best e
the middle and somebody
so we need some more until how
the change in the case of the difference will be with
and they don't depend on the
because the density
and why
his life
this not
the great
so this
he was the
because which describe this level
every one of them
this morning
we can discriminate right and the high become community so
what is that
i wish had more like to distinguish
after the
in the middle
and when is too high but also distinguish
well the differences between
one thing
because to use this
which is very
o function
how do you see the emulsion
along this line
around like the picture is that
so you can see
is it possible that this will have some peaks in but actually the like
and i
if experiment is kind of a change in the first
right depends on
all the things
this is a
with them
let's that is and
the right to the left
actually all these in the
the same
because the line is on the one hand
but he was
this one is that is one
just because you that there are quite
how this color
maybe someone
the high court
pro and con
which which is like
and actually we call it
and that's what i call our which
the plane
this is
the way
o two
david see
blue green red it is the combination of
that's why
the way
color space which is used to represent challenges is really and
actually all of space is most usually very calm me so there are three primary
this column
in which
so called it
o line
i have a great week and will
so that means that we have life of
which have
of y
the length of
chris my
and also
power so was some
which reflect
the light for
but the club
so that called
abstract right so that the this
like like
right now the only one
and this is one the primary colors usually imagine
o and
this red green blue and magenta yellow cycle
nick nichols thorne
they are
they managed
it was
believe based on was
by one right
and like just it is better to
present them as well as the best
describe how like you describe with the rate
they were the only
we can tell
however i
what i can tell you
you have
and we can play say
it is situated on the right column
so it is close to agreeing on this
great is if you
to be able to drive car
because somehow the
o places that actually by
visual perception
if you know
i was
is called
so we can measure
this this and this is
like what we usually denoted by and then so is this one although i was
six of particular links
and to make the the chromaticity coordinates
just by normalizing this thing
in nineteen eighty one
by experiment was built such call
the rest equals one and now we need to sweat about what the prior going
to be in
it is so subjective
well i'm going to set the prior to fifty fifty
so this is a half a
the prior
and the business end of this what it's all about in this problem is the
likelihood function and so we want to know walks through this
probably get the data that we did get it zero
which appears twice
probably would be under the other hypothesis and that's what this is all that
and the answer to that is well the probability of getting zero one one when
you send as equals zero is the
the first bit would have to be not flipped
so this is equal to
one minus at times
this is probably one minus have but it doesn't doesn't get flipped times because the
second it would have had to be flipped times
because it had to be that is the likelihood function is one minus after the
power of the number of bits that didn't need to be flipped times after the
power of the number that need to be flat
and this one here
comes to
reflect the first one
in order for this to happen on my z squared we have to not let
the other two so that's the two
when you then
do the trivial algebra to finish off this calculation
you find the answer comes out to
OK so i skipped over the trivial algebra
and the answer is but the ten percent chance that this was there was a
ninety percent chance that someone so that's decoder is the majority vote because but it's
quantified tells you how probable it is
based there wonderful i commend it to you
what's the
big picture of what was going on here we're looking at alternative explanations and we're
counting how many bits would have to be flipped and the most probable explanation is
the the one the required the smallest number of flips so that's the general description
of the majority vote because it says find the hypothesis that involve the smallest number
here's another thing
hypotheses about this
it involves
and that will be
the maximum likelihood estimator
also the most probable estimate for us
if the prior is fifty fifty
good on you can do that and here is what it looks like when you
apply that to
this particular file in this particular
and you can probably see that what came out is still not the same as
what went and because this code is still making errors
OK so the suggestion is
let's imagine changing the number of repetitions
if we had
repetitions only
we would get
nothing would get nothing habitat your neighbour
what do you think
to be willing to is really useless was the decoder going to do for these
four locations here
that would depend on what story we can tell them how we model it of
course but once we
managed to convince you that this is the right story to tell and then can
say can we do it will come we do it
so let's assume that we've agreed on what the story is
we can estimate we get the observation distribution of the observable variables and we get
this kind of causal query
this is are these intervention variables modelled in the system as well
this is the kind of thing we like to say something about how would why
respond to an intervention at x and just for simplicity
co y given x check
six hatch
OK i mean to intervene at x
so when i how can this be done
we've already one example of that we know
missing variables this is the no confounder case all the and confounder these properties allow
you to say the interventional distribution of y given you intervene indexes this formula and
we had it as an integral before take everything discrete now that was the backdoor
form that we can do that in that particular model
as night
you can do bad all formerly and more complicated models rather complicated case where
and everything is observable
i'm looking for variables that with these properties causes i can use it to apply
the back door formula and you can check from the properties of that DAG that
there's more than one choice which will work for you
you can either use the pair z three and z four that work with the
pairs that florence five that all although also work for the purposes of identifying the
cause and effect
it doesn't matter which you use if you want to be the most often say
which is more efficient in terms of statistical efficiency that's a completely different story
there's another another nice formula so-called front door formula and the of the model the
model which is appropriate for that now it's got an unobserved variable u
but this is rather important is missing our there
so tell tell some story in terms of smoking and tar in the lungs and
and some variable which can affect whether you smoke and often when he got cancer
or not but doesn't otherwise affect how much time you get in your lungs it
depends on
when this man
that's all
and and it turns out one of a few grind on the assumptions implicit there
play around with it and it's quite and the next thing you get out of
formula for the distribution y if you interviewed on x in terms of the observation
distributions form from x y and z
it's all observations there's no way needed to show that the same the basically did
using different languages to say the same thing
conditional independencies equality of gaius different distribution so
so these properties are actually equivalent to those properties so here for example that says
if this property holds then it doesn't matter what is the deserved or intervened on
i get the same distribution here
now the importance of this is that i may be able to look at my
DAG with all the variables in it and in in
i interrogated to see whether these properties hold or not and then on the basis
of that i can apply these rules
by applying these rules i can i can get variables in and out so i
can get
these had checks on and off and with a little luck i can get down
to something i want by applying these rules of succession
well i want to get something which has got had gone it because it's in
terms of things which don't because their observations and only involved
observed variables
and this is not very recently which pearl shpitser chan says if your problem is
modeled by pearlian DAG
so you can end up resorting to be in any way
and the do calculus is complete again three rules any computable causal effect can be
computed by
among a hundred thousand
here's another example in text filtering so feature selection is being used a lot in
the biomedical domain
but also
in text processing
and the authors of that paper
use various
non copyrighted in the writers the twenty news groups and web
page database and for all of these they simple bag of word representation with about
a hundred thousand features
and again see on this particular data types of data
we have an increase in performance as a
number of features
so the best we can expect in terms of performance is to not degrade too
much performance on that significantly degrade while using a very small number of features
that alone can be a big win both computationally and also from the point of
view of the data understanding
in this case here i'm showing as an example for the twenty news groups several
examples of features that have been identified as very predictive of this particular newsgroup like
for all that it is and not surprisingly you have these activists in reality
more interestingly perhaps four different newsgroups that deal with religion you don't necessarily have
the same the exact same keywords that are interesting
so have got church in singapore sort the coalition the christian because jesus going into
over four hundred queries and this
so what are the details
art that can be of interest
so now other petitions have been tried like face recognition so in this application
it is interesting to see that people have merely use the pixels they haven't done
any offensive feature extraction and try to find which part of the image is informative
for classifying male versus female
and they tried to types of feature selection algorithms
one called relief it's filter that does it all all ordering of the features in
doesn't attempt to remove redundancy between features and the other one simbad they devised does
take into account correlations between features and tries to find those features that are most
complementary with one another
you see the result of using a hundred features five hundred and one thousand top
ranking features
for the first algorithm that does not remove redundancy you have to kind of see
symmetry between the two sides of the future
so features that are redundant because for example they represent the two eyes
they are being selected whereas with the second algorithm that removes redundancy only half
of the features corresponding on one side of the image of being selected
i just presented unit to give you a rough idea some examples of feature selection
before moving into
the meat of the talk i would like to give you some nomenclature i'll be
talking about univariate methods
as those messages that consider
one variable one feature at the time
by contrast multivariate method considers subsets of variables of features that together
are good for making predictions
filter methods ranked features
of feature subsets independently of the predictor of the classifier the talking a lot about
this application but i like to remind you that this also holds for regression problems
and wrapper methods use a wrapper method uses a classifier to assess features or feature
and therefore determines the usefulness of feature subsets with respect to give a prediction method
first let me talk to you about the simplest methods the univariate filter methods
the easiest
is first to determine which feature irrelevance is
by contrast will determine which feature relevance means
feature irrelevance is that as it turns out is well defined mathematically
imagine that we have a single variable
x i
and that we have to classification problem with the positive class y equals one and
the negative class
y equals minus one
and i'm representing here
the density of the examples on this one axis
x i
so if that particular feature is irrelevant
which expect to see is that there is going to be two identical blobs for
the two classes you won't be able to distinguish the distribution of the examples of
class one
with respect to the example of plus minus one
mathematically this can be formalized as the joint probability of x sin y
is equal to the probability of exact probability of y so there is independence between
x i and y
all right
using bayes rule you can also said that p of x given y equals p
of x i
or again
you can say that p of x i given y equals one
the quality of x i given y equals minus one
the distribution and the marginal distribution
p of x y is the same thing
a specific site conditions
why call one and is also the same thing as felix i conditional on y
equals minus one
OK so how do we
define now
reference by contrast with irrelevance
what we need to do is that we need to
measure some displacement between these two distributions
and this has long since been done in
a wide variety of ways
there is only one way of defining irrelevant but there are many many ways of
defining relevance
and one of the simplest way is to use this as simple parametric methods and
parameterized distribution with just two parameters there are the mean and the standard deviation
define the criteria
of the relevance
as the displacement between the means of the two distributions
normalized somehow by the standard deviation to for example normalized by the average and the
standard deviation
so this criterion has been known as the signal to noise ratio criterion
the community of DNA microarray analysis
but as it turns out it's very similar
to the the person correlation coefficient
at least in the case where you have an equal number of examples of class
so what's special about this particular one will
i sing about this particular one is that there's nothing even close to it right
so it's far away from all the data points
all right so
with this
blue buffer area
it's called the margin for that particular
a hyperplane OK
the number of features
and learning does matter OK
but it doesn't matter if the margin is white
and the examples are somehow
close to the origin
all right so let's make it a little bit more concrete OK so if it's
very very simple algorithm again this is perhaps simpler than naive bayes OK
i'm just going to assume that two classes of called the positive one negative one
and i want to start with a hypothesis which is just all zero vector OK
every time i get example which members just to support vector
and what i look at the end product of the example of the sort zero
OK and i look at the side of that so the i'm will be positive
or negative for this year the first time around
OK if that's the right sign
and then i will basically just incremental counter so every one of these recent case
that i have every hypothesis is going to have a counter which will the number
of times the correct prediction
right now if it's not right that i'm just going to take the existing examples
of vector what had
the example that i got wrong or
if it was a positive an example should be negative subtract example
all right
so will gradually over the course of hypotheses for an incremental could create new hypothesis
to by adding an example or subtracting it with the new counter for this new
so this is a very very simple i mean if you think about it kind
of makes sense right so if you are continuing to to higher two well let's
move things in the right direction
can we remove them with this example
and we don't want to classify
by taking all these recent case i'm going to vote them and the number of
votes each resupply is going to get
is the number of times it was correct
OK so the hypothesis that persist for a long time to get a lot of
things right can have a high weight
he got have an example of just sort of transient will get pretty low-wage
so what can you say about this site so it turns out
you can fairly easily say
all right
every example
is close to the origin so what does that mean there's some number are the
so the norm of the vector is less than or
can just the two norm of the vector so it's it's it's within distance are
there are some classifier dual OK so i think of one of these recent case
if you if you can classify these things around the space then there's nothing we
can say about but there is something
all right this not too large exactly want say the norm is less than or
equal to one
and furthermore
they get every example right
OK i'm not only to get every example right
OK if we look at this
this number is here so this is inner product review in x right so the
prediction would be the sign of that OK if we multiply that by the actual
value which is either plus one minus one
so this was class i multiply by plus i should get a positive number if
it's negative and multiply by minus one or get a positive number k
right so basically saying is greater than zero was saying that the prediction was correct
saying is greater than some number delta
it means that it was correct initial margin of delta
so if there is some u that's not too large and gets right answer for
what if there is a situation like
this picture here where there is a wide margin
then this particular algorithm is going to make a relatively small number of mistakes
in the process
covering these examples OK so the number of bits takes depends on the radius and
the on
the and the inverse of the margin
that is making very relatively few mistakes it basically means is going to get most
of these predictions correct in this online process
OK so
let's just can't take these mathematical things and translate them into
four gary english for text OK
so suppose we have text let's forget the frequencies for psychosis we just step binary
features here one
if that document has if every document has no more than one hundred words and
obviously it's
the two norm is less than one hundred
and it's less than this is one hundred from the origin so immediately began radius
by just saying the documents are short
OK as i pointed out before this thing right here basically means the margin is
at least delta
this is a really nice result and for anyone who might want to think about
is barred to really understand american when you look at the paper and look at
the proof that the whole proof you can actually look at this in the slide
when you go home not going step through it right
it's it's something that you can really put on your head once and it's worth
doing because it gives you into action as to why this curse of dimensionality
doesn't hurt here
OK so one of the lessons of this well the voted perceptron a very simple
actually later i'll show you some experiments to show that in fact it's pretty competitive
and lot of situations
all right but basically what it shows you is that you can make few mistakes
in incrementally learning OK
right provided there is some u that small has a large margin OK so here's
an idea
all right this is kind of seems like a neat idea
but it seems like kind of a silly way of coming up with that
are approximating this number you will i just look that directly
all right well i dislike about my books on
optimisation and see if i can figure out how to get that you correct directly
and in fact that's what you do when you're building the support vector machine OK
so support vector machine you minimize the norm of view subject to some fixed margin
not really the other way around you maximize the margin relative some bound on the
OK so the best optimisation methods and what you do this
i won't go into the details but they tend to work pretty well
so again some nomenclature here so again this is a very simple idea
but there are some fancy terms so when you're looking at
that picture
you should have like copy here the picture we got that big problems stripe with
a hyperplane in the middle
at more complex intentions this is not that clear to date
so if you wonder who this is is obviously ten tom cruise
and this is from the film minority report because minority report is movie that uses
very similar
the idea
with the kind of different biological substrate obviously two
predict crime and this is just here to remind people that the technical applications that
you can get out of this this research model also something that
it's possibly worth looking into but also has a specific ethical dilemmas raised with them
but we could also talk about
so if we how do we explain
people's behavior
especially in psychology there's a long history
of trying to explain behavior based on conditioning for example
stimulus response conditioning response stimulus conditioning and so on and so the idea is that
what happens if mouse for example learns a route towards this target here the route
is ultimately given to this animal by a sequence of stimuli that are associated with
rewards and ultimately what the animal is doing is driven by the external sensory stimuli
that cause specific rewards expectations possibly but this reward expectation wasn't mentioned in the papers
and talk about that and then you ultimately under the control of your environment you're
under control of the reward structure of the environment
and obviously this is very impoverished way of explaining human behavior and so in the
nineteen sixties miller galanter program came up with the rather different model this is kind
of a related graph but the basic idea is that you don't understand trying to
understand behavior based on the external stimulation
but you try and understand behavior based on internal states and these internal states our
goal states that them the organism is trying to pursue
so you can think of this so some kind of feedback from higher order systems
introduces the reference signal some kind of target signal and then what you do is
you find out whether your system is in a different state than your desired goal
state statement is absolutely trivial and then what you do is you perform an operation
you have an effect on the environment and then you perceive the environment again and
then you test again to see if your environment has changed towards the goal you
want to have for example examples of the uses for example using a hammer
and and then you have to for example if you want to put put the
nail into the into the wood then you have to minimize the distance between the
head of the nail and and and and and the bottom end of the wood
and then you have to nail it in and then the distance gets minimize this
is a very simple example but most motor movements of course related
well the basic idea is now we've got this different approach which is an internal
reference signal and the question is where all these internal reference signals these goals stored
in the brain
and i'll show you three different approaches but first let me just talk about the
technique be using
we use bold for my
and classically people have used bullet for my to study the brain and the resolution
of approximately three millimetres and the reason is you can't make these voxels much smaller
you can make the box much smaller than say one millimetre is already pushing it
and this is perfectly sufficient because classically psychology and you're psychologists think of the brain
in terms of broad money areas they don't think of it in terms of cells
or columns but they think of it the basic units of neuropsychology brotman areas and
this brought areas have several cubic centimeters and obviously if you have a voxel that
has three millimeter resolution you're pretty good if what you're interested in this problem areas
but it seems that the information
is not stored discourse level but it stored in a much finer level as i
will talk about in the second and what you measure measuring each of these volume
units here is the change in the oxygenation level of the blood that's ultimately
is the consequent well leads to certain changes in the magnetic properties of the blood
this was skip this
the problem is that if you want to if you're interested in the storage of
detailed content that are relevant for cognitive processes
then electrophysiology and optical imaging have shown us that the storage of this fine grain
the details of say for example visual objects that we recognise stored in the fine
grained cortical pat tern colony patter with the resolution of say around half a millimetre
or bit smaller
and the problem now
you find very similar topography is for example for object features in the temporal lobe
and you find very similar structures also in the visual only visual cortex and the
one of the famous boehm will pattern that describes the distribution of selectivity of cells
to different orientations the release so these are the different orientations and each color here
tells you where cells with a specific orientation preference
this column in architecture the basic the basic anatomical hardware
exists also in prefrontal cortex has begun to prefrontal cortex you find similar structures that
so the from the is same sort of work that i do when i pushed
i get back in terms of gravitational potential energy
by lifting the car
so if i wanted to move the car by one metre
and if the ratios hundred to one
i would have to move down by hunt me
that's a little bit on practical so these hydraulic presses i designed in such a
you can just check it like that every time
to bring it up
the liquid flows back in again into this
the site of the hydraulic jack
but in the end you have to go
effectively a hundred meters then
but it can't to go up
by one if the ratio is hundred one
no gravity of course has an effect
on the pressure in the fluid
if you go down into the oceans
we know that the pressure
will go up and that is the result
of gravity
and i would like to derive
pressure increase
this b
the direction of increasing y
and i choose a
liquid elements of this is in the liquid itself
i can choose in any shape that i want to i just taken nice horizontal
and this is every eight
so the bottom is also a
and let this be at height
white was delta y
and this is the y
and the pressure here
his wife was built y
and this object has amassed
delta and
in the liquid
has a density rho which could be a function of y we leave it open
for now
and so
this mass
the math that i have here is the volume
times the density
the volume is n
i don't know why
then times the density which may be function y
so if i put in
all the forces at work here
is gravity
which is delta and
i'm sitting
in this direction
i have
four upwards
due to the pressure of the fluid that's what we want to evaluate
it's always perpendicular
the services we talked about earlier
so in this idea comes in like this year comes in like this the force
from the bottom it comes in like this
and from the top
i call this
i only
the vertical direction
because all forces in the horizontal plane
will counsel for obvious reasons
so now it has to be equally
this fluid element is not going anywhere sitting still in the fluid
and so i now have that everyone
in this direction
miners have two
gold and
it is zero
only then is fluid element
static equilibria
but everyone
is this pressure times the area
what is the
level why
i'm ever
f two
it's the
level was delta y
times area
delta is the delta
y times role
so i could minus eight
and delta y
which could be function
could be function y g
and that equals zero
notice i lose my area
i'm going to rearrange this slightly and divide by delta y
so i get that
with some positive L  H is just that there's no condition on H then you
can show that prox the proximal gradient method converges and that
the distance to the optimum decreases as one over K times something that depends on
the distance of the starting point to the solution and then this L in the
Lipschitz condition so this is much faster than the subgradient method in the subgradient
method  I might have forgot to say this but when we had in the subgradient
method as a convergence result was one over square root K instead of one over
K so this is quite a bit faster than the subgradient method and it's less general
because it applies only to problems that can be written like this with an inexpensive prox operator H
this is clear so this is quite classic this approximate gradient method and
then more recently in the last ten years or so people have studied faster
versions of the proximal gradient method and they're  actually several different variations on these fast
methods it goes back to work by Nestrov in the nineteen eighties who tried to
improve on this one over K convergence of the gradient method or a proximal gradient method
so he developed fast versions of the gradient projection method and the gradient method with a
one over K squared convergence instead of the one over K convergence we
had here and for the same conditions on G so that's very interesting
in practice because it means that if you want an accuracy epsilon  for example
there's a big difference between obtaining that in ov one  over epsilon iterations or
one over a square root of one over epsilon right its diff difference between ten thousand
iterations or a hundred iterations so increasing this from K to K squared is actually important in
practice so that's what he did in the eighties and he also showed that again
for the same category of problems it's not possible to improve this one over K
squared so he called this an optimal method because this rate of convergence is optimal
within this class of algorithms and this class of problems
so  since the last ten years people have really worked on these methods
very intensively so one popular method is called FISTA it stands for fast
iterative shrinkage thresholding algorithm but it's actually quite general it's a fast proximal gradient method
so it actually extends these methods one of these methods by Nestrov to the proximal
gradient method and then there are several other versions that have similar complexity but different
advantages so here are just a few things about this FISTA method so the FISTA method
is very general it applies t it's very simple it applies to the same
class of problems that we had before in the proximal gradient method you have a
composite objective with the differentiable G and a non-differentiable H and again the only condition you need for
H is that it has an inexpensive prox operator so the FISTA method is actually a
simple extension so instead of one series of iterates X you have two X
and Y and at each step you apply the standard proximal gradient update to Y and
you call that X and then your next value of Y is an actually an extrapolated
version of X so this is a standard proximal gradient update but at Y
and then you use this X K  to construct your next Y K and K is the
iteration number so you see that very soon this coefficient here in front goes to one right
so that's the FISTA method so you can interpret it geometrically like this suppose these
are your iterates  X at iteration K minus  two at K minus one so
so at those iterations you would make this extrapolation so you'd take X K and you add to it a multiple
of the previous step a multiple that's almost equal to one so that's this you
take X K minus one you add to it previous step and that gives you a Y K
minus one then you apply the proximal the standard proximal gradient step to this point that gives you a
point here for example and that's where  you move from X that becomes your next X K
so it's sort of an a gradient step with extrapolation
and you can maybe intuitively interpret it as an a method for improving on this zig-zaging behavior in
the gradient method by this extrapolation
but there's a very  sort of interesting convergence theory for this method and the result
is that under the same conditions as for the proximal gradient method you get instead
of one over K in the   convergence rate you get one over K squared by just
using this simple extension of a proximate gradient method is that clear also in practice it turns out to
be actually  to work quite well so this is an example where you
just apply it to a differentiable function so just a gradient method and the fast gradient method
yes maybe this is not the best example but this the  blue curve would be the gradient method the green
dashed line is the proximal  the the fast gradient method to you see it actually converges much
faster and it reaches in this case a very good accuracy one difference is that the
FISTA is not a descent method like the gradient method so the convergence is not
each chapel contains confidence which means that the
people person names smith has a social security number one eighty five this event only
happened with confidence of forty percent
so we have one record it to represent each different the case in this social
survey data
and on top of that we have generation rules
because the person names mister can only have one correct social security numbers so between
t one and t two only one can be true
also because rock only has one correct social security number though
between t three and t four only one can be true
and also because one eighty five is assigned to smith and brian stable but we
know that one
correct number only belong to one person so we have a generation rule
between t one and t three as well
this is the how we describe the uncertainty in this example
as another example in the
o example we may two different things that we talk about in the first part
for example a very common method is to use record linkage
the associated this one with some external
sources to design that seventy four percent confidence to topple
so this is something we know that we describe it in their probabilistic table
so for example if the five NBA players
we know that has the capability of NBA players is crucial thing for selecting good
players for good
basketball teams
but how to evaluate the capability is quite difficult
typically we use the technical statistics of NBA players to estimate that capability
for example here we think about and two attributes number of rebounds and number of
so here one point represents the number of reponsible points in one game
so all in all points belong to the player brian
and already points belong to the player you
so you this data we know that the probability of you and the not certain
there a distribution on this to space
so this introduce another that another example of
uncertain data models this is called the uncertain up
so you example we know that you have is an object
and you can take different values so
we use a sample to represent object
and also for brand we use blue samples to represent this object
and this is different from the uncertain probabilistic table models
so here in uncertain objects and object is uncertain if you attributes like a number
of points and number of everybody
but we use to sample and or a probability density function to describe the uncertainty
on this object
another example
we know that nowadays it's quite useful to track the location of a moving object
that the famous i has built in GPS so that you can report the UK
report the location of
your current location
but due to the
pure radical reporting mechanism of the affection of other like tall buildings
so we are close to the tall buildings in location may not be precisely reported
so this
example we have formal the objects
a b c d and e
the location of the moving objects are not precise we can only know the possible
region of each object
so in this example each moving objects is set up to it
and that one point in the possible region it's possible instances of this sort of
and then we may use like uniform distribution on august distribution to describe their probability
and also in the example we can also use set up to model to describe
the incident
for example here we have two persons smith and abroad
each one can be modeled as one uncertain object
if we only consider name and social security numbers we know that because we can
this is the probability
one is the probability of the set
samples which satisfies this formula
but that does for the formalism
you may ignore it
anyway we rewrite this probability is the probability of this union of two events
then the right hand side we can rewrite
the probability of this union of these two invent
is equal to the probability
of the individual events
one minus the probability that both of them occur at the same time so this
is the standard
formula for probability theory
these probabilities are non negative we can throw with this term therefore get an upper
bound on the probability of the union so this is called the union bound but
it's just trivial thing for
probability theory
and you can see that this this is an upper bound and you're losing something
in this of aren't exactly when these events are not disjoint
we can plug in this upper bound
get an apology on the right-hand side which will look like this are probability of
interest is upper bounded by the sum of these two probabilities
now for these two probabilities we've only
i mean you to these events only depends on one fixed function only one function
so therefore for these we can use the channel islands
to them
so we get the same kind of long term here
only we have factor two in front of it
and you can probably see the same thing of course works for finite limit functions
we have a classifier functions we decompose
this event
the supremum
of these
differences in risks being larger than epsilon as a union
the probability of the union of a finite number of events
and then we can
apply the channel on the find finite amount of time so we get
despite the number appearing here
in this case we get
where we just have to factor in over here but it is a factor in
the size of the graph doesn't disturb us the least because we have exponentially
converges to zero here
so what happens if we have infinitely many functions
it's interesting case because if we put an infinite number here than the bound becomes
during the sense that it will not tell us any more
things go to zero
so in a way you could you could already receive
if we put a finite number here
and everything is easy in this will go to
zero exponentially fast
but you can see we could even put something here which is not a constant
something that increases with
with the number of of points that we've seen
so we could put something here that increases with a man as long as it
doesn't increase exponentially fast with him
we would still win because the this thing goes to zero exponentially fast
and we would like the function class
given n examples
to be
growing with n
sub exponentially
the trick
is the following
the empirical risk only refers to m points
so on these points the functions
the function class can
take at most two trillion dollars because i need to point the functions take values
plus one minus one
so on points
given only in points
then the function class
it has to take at least two possible values from this point so no matter
how big function class is
it's effective size is at most two to the
so the effective size which plugin here is administratively and of course to the bad
has to the and would be an exponential increase in here we have an exponential
decay and we don't know what's going to happen
however if the function class
growth more slowly than to to the
and we are only interested in the limit so we only interesting whether at some
will start growing more slowly than to to the if that's the case then we're
in business
so we almost find i've told you that
over here
we have something that's which effectively
at most it grows like to the
but maybe if we have some
i thought that might grow more slowly
over here we still have this
actual risk which depends on the whole distribution we don't like that so we would
like to
remove this thing here also
rewrite in terms of something that on a given sample with the finite
and the way to do this is to use something about the two things have
called symmetrisation
and this following
and i'm not going to spend too much time on this
here the idea is this quantity that we really interested in
can be upper bounded
in terms of another quantity
which no longer talks about the difference between the training error and test error but
it talks about the difference between two training errors
one two different examples
and you know we're heading the ones i have this upper bound this quantity
in terms of this quantity involving two training errors
once have this i can apply this modified chernoff bound which i showed you when
i first introduced the telephone modify channel one that was talking about the difference between
two empirical means
so i can then
by this modified telephone and here i have only this nice empirical quantities that depend
on n points each
and m points each
function class effectively finite
you can look like class of size two to the
but if we have a nice function maybe will look much smaller
i think we were almost end here but i'm just wondering whether i should just
give you the main idea i to years and then we can maybe go through
it again next time so i'll just give you an overview of
how things are going to work and then we will briefly review the next time
i think about how to get the remaining time in the next to so
roughly speaking work was
we will introduce
a the quantity called the shattering coefficient
which will be something like the maximum size of a function class
on a certain number of points
so let's call this thing calligraphy
down in the basement
so let's indicate that with
classical symbol and this
altogether put out about twenty volts
and then what he did as he was a professor of physics understood some electrical
engineering so he had choke coil here
so chill climate would take the the current
store up and eight times the second
eight times a second
it would discharge
and would discharge at
thirty five thousand volts
so he could take twenty volts and upper two
thirty five thousand by the use of this choke or so a times the second
he had thirty five thousand volts coming off
cathode here's you've got bam bam bam bam and speed up about eight times and
that's what that's what's going on and so with thirty five thousand volts he launches
electrons off the cathode and they go zooming across what is very very low pressure
gas and crash into the and
mean time to keep this thing dynamically
at low pressure this goes to
a vacuum pump
vacuum pump to keep this thing come down as low as it can
he was measuring what was going on inside the gas tube and so he had
detector and his detector was over here
the detector was off to the side
the detector consisted of either a piece of cloth
or paper towel
which had been painted with a chemical that would goal
what i was struck by
something what with the something b
something would be
electrons or
photons that have an energy
high enough
two corps x citation of something in
and then re emission in the visible doesn't do any good to excite
electrons in the detector have andrea outside the visible
OK so that's what's going on so this is this was a paper
four class
it was painted with an aqueous solution
flat no cyanide
yummy stuff very plateau of cyanide which glows green
glows green
when it's excited
and this is called a scintillation screen
scintillation screen
comes from the latin word for spark scintilla means parking lot so when the screen
is struck by some form of energy
it will glow
and so
he had dinner and was up and the
up the second floor cranking away after data
i was was dark was raining
at the windows open street was was coming and by the way to a ranking
suffered from dalton isn't he was red-green color blindness was the green screen
and with thirty five thousand volts even at reduced pressure given the capacity of those
days for vacuum pumps he still had a lot of global from the
the two
so the tube is going
he's got a street lighting the background so he decides
to close the drapes and
take out the street light
and further more he decides to darken
darken the room so
he puts a cardboard box over the
so now the tube is enclosed in a cardboard box what's
it's not going visibly to him
it's going inside the box and he continues to see
continues to see
things going
so he says
it's not something interesting the other thing that happened was kind of interesting his graduate
student who is prepared some of the apparatus
i guess he was practising painting the
scintillation screen so what the student had done
was too
the letter a
on a paper towel
he left the paper towel on the lab bench
so now rankin's got the
the two
enclosing cardboard
this things going he looks down and sees the letter a
the latter is school
it's going to this is crazy
so he says are right so he takes a piece of black paper
and he puts it here in between the two
and the screen and the screen continues to go
and then he says he takes only had a deck of playing cards is
in his lab so don't laugh home-and-away have discovered periodicity so so he takes the
playing card puts the playing card in front and the two continues to grow
and then he takes the book and he puts the book in between
and the two continues to goal
so please so then he grabs a piece of land foil puts the lead foil
and here
and what happens is that where the oil is the screen is not glowing
but then he sees the outline
of the bones of his hand
on the land holding land for you
so this stuff is going on and he just he just goes
goes to town he says you know what i've got i got it
this can be electrons because electrons cannot live on air
there will be stopped by air
soon he knew about radio waves from her he said could this be some form
of mysterious radiation that's capable
he was really afraid to say this is a form of radiation is capable of
it's eighteen ninety five you got to come out publicly and say i have the
form of radiation that can penetrate
so he gets a magnet out move magnet doesn't change
so this stuff is insensitive to magnetic field
but if you put some magnet here of course it gets changed
you can't see this stuff you can only see evidence of its mysterious
it's mysterious
so he calls it
access the unknown quantity it's x radiation
x radiation
this is november eight nineteen ninety five
and to show you what what a great scientist he was
rather than rushing to publication he spent all of november and december repeating the experiment
and trying it in different ways until he is convinced that the effect is real
and then around christmas time of eighteen ninety five he sends offer manuscript and published
in the first week of january of eighteen ninety six
and it takes the world by storm
he's announcing that is the form of radiation can penetrate matter and furthermore
he's got an x-ray
of the human hand
you know this is t ninety seven people or
you know very proved very private he's got to form of radiation that can look
inside the human body
this is really shocking stuff
so already
on january sixteen
january sixteen eighteen ninety six
this article in new york times
article new york times about this stuff
mysterious form of radiation
by the way you know he was doing is experiments housing recording his results his
recordings results on photographic film is photographic films foggy
photographic film stored in the cabinet of the other side of the lab
and half time it takes the photographic film was fired
so whatever the stuff is it's
its penetrating everything is penetrating the draws his file cabinet
they were still case there probably wouldn't file can
widespread widespread adoption
widespread adoption some of it
what's the some of the silly ones in london
there was a manufacturer announced remember this is prudish victorian england
so that he could sell you x-ray proof ladies' underwear
in france there was no such thing the french don't care about such matters so
just have to be
which ones
fourteen has to be unwise fourteen have to be
one fourteen three has to be in there
one of the minimum wage
no one has the overall smallest weight
so can somebody argued me the three has to be in the
what is
that's the moment the two which means that if i had a if you add
something he said was a minimum spanning tree include three
so therefore had to include fourteen
i could just delete this age fourteen put an edge three
something of lower weight
so three has to be in there
other edges have to be in
too little
little puzzle logic
six and five have to be in there were they have to be there
year well i mean it could be connected like through this or something
and as you have to go this way
six definitely has to be in there for the same reason the three had the
because we have two choices to connect up
this guy
so everything or connected but it works
twelve was in there i could always then say well let's connect up this way
OK so definitely that's in there
council on everything connected up
what else has to be in there for minimum spanning tree
seventy five and a y seven five in a
OK so can we argue that was one of the time
why is phi have to be in there
OK so we have for connected components can have this one
this one
we actually have this one here
and this one could
we need these three edges to connect them because each edge is going to reduce
the connected component by one
so we need three edges
those are the three cheapest ones
and they work
that works
right any other edges are going to be bigger so
that would good
so now we we have a spanning tree everything is we have one being
a connected graph here right
so i got a has the same right
life is predictable
so really the idea of what the minimum spanning tree is and how this OK
what what's going on
so let's
first of all make some observations about this
puzzle and what i wanna do is remind you
about the optimal substructure propery
because it turns out the minimum spanning tree is a great optimal substructure property
so this up is going to be wearing have some minimum spanning tree let's call
it t
and i'm going to show that with the other edges in the graph
i'm not going to show
so here's
the graph
OK here's a graph
looks like the one i have on my newspaper here
so the idea is this is some minimum spanning tree
now we want to look at
a property of optimal substructure and the way we get that going to remove some
we have an arbitrary edge u v
in the spanning tree so let's call this you
this the
so removing the search
so when i remove an edge in the tree
what happens to the tree
what's left
i have two trees left
five two trees left now
proving there
that's basically one of the properties
here are some examples of settings that are commonly used so the so-called line supervised
training pairs that are given to you and the goal is to produce a model
that predicts well on future instances
semi supervised learning you post training areas like x y and also unlabelled data
and you want to produce a model
that predicts well
you want to predict function that assigns a label to every
future incidents
trans activist like different
the same input string there's an labelled data
but goal is to
predicts well on
unlabelled examples
all the new x you want to predict the y
and the
so you have to predict the performance at each step whenever you get an example
i mean there are some variants that you've probably heard of like reinforcement learning where
predicting some labelled you want to take some action and then you get some reward
possibly not immediately but later on
so these are
what i call settings that's the way you set of the problem and i like
what you ask your question
if you're not going to confuse these settings with assumptions that
you put on top of that
usually the assumptions are about how the data is generated
in this case is go back
you know how do i assume
these data
generated training pairs or
the instances that come one at the time so
you know you've probably
i mean actual which is to say OK they are generated by some
probabilistic mechanisms of a random number generator or something like this
maybe they are denoted by
some natural phenomena observed in nature and so on
and this assumption that before they are only used if you want to prove anything
but otherwise you know
they don't really make sense in the country
justify any of those so
you know
the probability is more you know how you
he said the same this page of of your
learning problem and how you the instances are coming to you and what you get
to see all these distances and so on and this is really the relevant part
when you want to create algorithm because algorithm must have two feet with this problem
then there is this notion of success measure
which is how you would be
measuring success or when you say i'm satisfied with this algorithm
sometimes they are the stubs success measures are abstract like for example
the reward infinity in finite horizon like
how much will or the number of errors you will make
if you are infinitely many data points this kind of thing so these are target
but you can't really matter them never we love infinity
many data points
but they they help you ought to guide you towards
deriving the right algorithm
then there is what type of analysis you are doing in this you know given
the setting given
this success measure given you is how you will analyse it and what kind of
statement you are expecting to prove about this algorithm
and again that's relevant one that's only relevant within the certain
data generation generation mechanism
and sometimes also offers the respective assumption so you
and assume some regularity about the data or
you may assume that you're only looking at certain kinds of functions discounts
this again is not
i mean it's useful for designing algorithms because then you can respect rather the
i agree somewhat only work or would only provably work and there is this condition
the point here is that if you have an algorithm that has been designed under
certain set of
you know for certain protocol
we certainly limited limiting assumption
this algorithm may perform well under some other circumstances so my point here is that
you know
people will tell you OK
i presume that are based on a on
inference for example are working better
you know
the same is that
you can prove that within this restrictive framework within the right assumptions these can be
proved to be optimal
but then beyond that you don't know
you cannot prove anything
but still they can they can work well so you can't really
we use the fact that an aneurysm is proven to be optimal in certain context
to derive the fact that it would be good in another context but it may
just be because it's good
because it happens to its with these the assumption of these sort of context
another point is that you know i was
i have a proxy that trying to optimize which is not the real success measure
the thomson
so measure that hopefully will converge on the success measure
OK some examples of all these things
data generation mechanism
you can have several ways in which assume the data comes to you
in the kind of bayesian interpretation you can assume that the underlying function describing a
phenomenon is sampled from song
and that data are also examples of some of the
distribution so you put in probabilistic assumptions of probabilistic generation assumption
on both the function and the data
in the
i i d setting
i i d stands for independent identically distributed
you don't assume
that the function is sampled
approximate algorithm
so we can i mean you something called the MLP kernel like all of the
MLP kernel something chris williams derived which is an infinite
neural network with an infinite number of nodes the reason i like it is because
when you search already have problem with this
this is a
we're going to
so for example the current web data and we have a lot in regions where
the data of this sort of data and he
data outside this is observed data on the x space that
we'll do this ill-gotten non-zero
so i bx space as you move away from the data it it tells often
goes to zero to regions where data the the these comments is defined zero thing
about peak oil
is you my characteristic that's supported like this
rather than dropping the edges
like that it's going down and coming back to zero
it's sort of saturated
i think
published smith pointing that out to me that some characteristic he's made of used in
control applications and we'll see what kind of useful here as well
in some of the examples
so let's revisit data is to use the full training set in we use the
RBF kernel again the GPLVM and compare with the mapping i think that the problem
we have no real data by recreating the experiments
and something very similar to the thing in the original paper
on this grid of points and you can kind of see your point
how can tell what they done in the original paper you can even sort count
this characteristic
it's an easy algorithm this responsibility but has characteristic of the point responsibility saturate one
or close to once you get a a lot of different points depending on the
same space and points along lines you want to get an edge effect when
this is the end
bold where you've laid out the grid of points so these serviceable cluster along the
so it can be difficult to see some structure but
you have to be really careful i think what i'm saying things visualizations such as
this because
what do people realizations is getting people to look at it and if it's useful
sort of experts or whatever and i and that so this is hand-waving different characteristics
which might be better off or worse and you'll see in the roman army people
use may used PTM for clustering and this is better and may be in actual
fighting the costs associated with the point to show you some results in the DTM
favourite moments he quit from that
this latent variable models
you get to structure of the green somewhat separated but not to the point
reading on each other
you get some
it's not clear these
regular commitments of the former
check my defined them
it lies but it could be local minimum
and i think it looks pretty
that's about it
so to
the spectrum kernel
the QC is similar because the transition from PCA but this is completely rotationally symmetric
any rotation is applied to this data would be equally valid so that could be
upside down but it's not the same as you see many points similar to these
points is similar sort of structures up here
what more can i say
so becomes difficult to
i guess without experiments it's difficult to come up with what you might say is
a objective evaluation measure should be the sensible thing to do is to have these
different labels which
i should be taken account of the all in the fitting of visualisation newark new
politics class labels i should mention that first i apologize
seems sensible
in this two-dimensional space one i see how good spaces for classification how separated how
well separated the data i
so need to be sort of classification experiments that what you find is that you
that's all those previous models you know peaked at no
the kind of the DTM is that both of them so this grading
the GTM is
using the likelihood that is converging towards the situation is that the DTM because it's
better converge model it doesn't have to use the sparse approximation has said in capture
the manifold better
i mean we're not necessarily but it's actually the separation between james patterson so this
material is something that of course
measurement associated with it
should just a PCA
PCA the classification with linear PCA fourteen percent so far worse than the non-linear any
linear methods
kernel PCA
i can't to
because i can't
but parameters to select
so you this problem and so on and
doing it DTM that's not really the DTM because TTN selected remove the number of
grid points as well
but just months later in the paper
so can be
would probably do quite well as well and it's got a lot of advantages
so this
change this tool but fix this first so this is the identity
and this is written
in cyclic notation by
three four
so this is the
the subgroup and we are going to construct cosets of the subgroup
from here
we go
through green
green lines to see the green line
this is the identity
the order it doesn't change which the ranking
of course we leave will lead to the same
the same ranking single here the range sources
and the other one is is using
sigma one which is the identity right
is there are the elements of the to construct another set is
this is what we saw before the trivial coset
it is one here now
it is one here across
so these are in black here is the ranking
first position second position the position
four position
and the items that goes
you see i ten three goes here
i ten one goes here
and then i have flip
i tend to
an item four
those who
so you have
the final rank so that you have there
you're right
one is to prefer
over one
but now
two and four
i don't care
which rather they become
and these are
these are partial rankings
in this this is extremely useful because
press forms of course set
and you can always ask
among all possible choices
first k
it doesn't matter
like when you search in google you just get like ten
the first
and ten
that if you consider only
this subset only this guy and you disregard all the rest
you have all of space much more
you have some models made on permutation
and more recently you have probability models
based on
partial rankings
of course this has a generalisation this is just one example of partitions that you
might be interested in this case here you fix the first two
let the rest
you don't care
you can you can have many for for all partitions of and
you would have different
the core set
which is this generalizations with the here in
you read
the point
to go from there
i mean that
so this is written in and
the general but
the point here is that
each one of those
it's are
it's one core set
of the whole group g
now one calls set of this subgroup given by bipartition here
of the group of all permutations which hassan
indexed by
the permutation pi
and you see that all
rankings given by those
are consistent with the permutation but it keeps
the k first
preference don't stride
so if you're doing and a model on on the probability space
and then you have to check
if you're on
if you ordering are consistent
with the choice of the first k choice you have to search and in the
main space
so you can start
from you can start working from the stock with consistent
if consistent
what you can do
with this space both the space of the probabilities of the book both with the
space of all permutations
o with the smallest space of
permutations of the subgroup given by one particular
particular partition of the group
holding the distribution over the parameters fixed and the arms that i compute a distribution
over the parameters holding the distribution of the
in variables fixed in these equations characterize the general solutions
to coordinate ascent
of this objective function
so this is an expression for what the solutions look like yes
the question is is that the choice q only affect the speed
so the choice if q
the quality of the bound that we get as well
okay so let me try to explain this with a picture
can people see when i right here
sort of
the basic idea is
i'm going explain it with a picture
in the minutes okay let me go through the rest the slide because the picture will make more sense
in man
this is the algorithm
iterate between these two is now it is exactly that you algorithm
if i limit
the distribution on the parameters to be a delta function
so that you algorithm has an e step that is exactly like this
em step doesn't impede distributions over the parameters the end step optimizes the parameters right
if you
raise your hand if you are familiar with him algorithm
okay almost everybody here
in the the algorithm to optimize over the parameters
that's corresponds to
the special case in this way restricted the distribution over the parameters to be a delta function
but in the more general case
but i have a distribution over the hidden variables and the distribution over the parameters
what's going on
is there
the product these tools are approximate posterior q of data
time cube x would try to approximate the true posterior r p theta ant acts
given why
by maximizing the lower bound is equivalent to minimizing the scale divergence between the approximate distribution
and that should distribution
so now i can draw the picture
here's my true distribution
piiv access and data given why am
can use red
which color can i use
reds allowed okay
you don't have to like that of the board you can see it
this is my family of cues
family of distributions and what the variational bayes in yemen algorithm will end up doing
is they will find the distribution q
that minimizes
the cale divergence
scale qpi
the cale divergence between q and p e so it's basically going to
wander around the space until finds the point
that minimizes the kill divergence
and then kill divergence is asymmetric
cale peak u
is a more desirable thing to minimize but it is intractable to compute because you're averaging with respect to p
scale qpi
we can compute
and we can optimize efficiently
and in the limit you can show that this variational bound approach is the basic
criterion like you know everything sensible should
any questions about this
so the expectation propagation algorithm
different form of deterministic approximation for these kind of integrals
some people mistakenly say it tries to minimize scale peak u
kill beacuse impossible to minimize so actually what the epee algorithm doors which is in the appendix slides
for every term in the in the cayo
holding only others terms fixed it locally tries to minimize scale q
but globally doesn't achieve yeah
on the
so essentially what we're trying to find and not sure i completely understand the difference
between what you mean by double-sided are one-sided
there is only one optimization problem that we're doing here
we are
trying to
maximize this lower bound
that's equivalent to minimizing the scale
there's no gap between these two those things are equal to each other are maximizing
this term is equivalent to minimizing thee
the difference between these two terms which is the kale