technique for storing information
so he was very optimistic
computers even
obviously scalably matches the computer of nineteen fifty one
would be able to
achieve quality with human beings
well we can see that
hasn't been achieved
that it well
during tests
where you compare computers human beings
so far i haven't got terribly far together there was a
for the one of the most successful was recently i just heard but nevertheless they still
don't uh
they aren't able to imitate human beings convincingly
and other point it's worth making because there is notion when you come to quantum
mechanics you see i think during had the idea
there might be random elements
the quantum mechanics introduces and therefore it wouldn't be exactly
the turing machine it will be something like a turing machine with a randomizer
but the point is can hear
it's not difficult to design machines behavior appears quite random
to anyone who doesn't know the details of the construction so you can and this is a standard technique
to produce
random numbers if you like
random outputs
which of these not strictly speaking random because they are produced by some
complicated computational procedure
and if you don't have produced then they are effectively random so i think it is more saying here
the randomness doesn't really make any difference you can pretty well simulate randomness
okay so that's they
there's various quotes
i want to talk about
what i think
is the argument
really nature and think he might need to go beyond the idea
of a universal turing machine
because if this thing zones i won't say great deal about ordinals
i mentioned briefly at one point
roughly speaking
it's iterating this procedure which i'm going to indicate in just a moment
that's the would those articles will play a role in what i was later on
so while during
actually what i'm worried if you like
well where during this words is another question
but it's a question about the perception of mathematical truth how do we judge
whether a mathematical statement
it is true or false
and do
i'm going to restrict my attention to
what we might consider the be very
straightforward statements these are statements about natural numbers are not geometry for instance we might
worry about what kind of geometry are talking about
i'm only going to talk about statements which are very very clear cut
and they just things about
the natural numbers zero one two three four so the non-negative whole numbers
he idea that statement here is that the perception mathematical truth
cannot be reduced to a set of mechanical rules
this comes from
the famous theorem due to go out
hand during most certainly very familiar with this
it features very much in his
thirty six paper the original one
because he was very much concerned with things that computers could do if you like
that's with probability with trying to do and so say
what you could do
by mechanical procedure
we had to define what is meant by a mechanical procedure and then show that
there were certain things that you can't do with a mechanical procedure
well i'm phrase ghost theorem
in a way which is not normally phrase this is
a perfectly correct
deduction from his
his theorem
tells us that for any mathematical theorem
this kind of thing i'm talking about here with natural numbers and so on
any momentum
for any
it tells us for any set a mechanical
theorem proving rules
and when i say mechanical theorem very proving rules i mean you have a set
of procedures which can be checked by a computer that's the crucial point u if
you follow these rules
hand you come to the conclusion
it prove some mathematical statement that can be talking about
could lead to prove can be
checked by computer
that's the kind will talking about
then what you can construct is a particular mathematical statement
which kernel shows you how to do
and i'm calling the jaafar
which if we trust the rules that we believe in the validity of the rules that say if we believe
anything we derive using the rules must be true
if you trust the rules
then you must also believe that this particular statement geva is true
it cannot be proved using the rules that's a very striking remarkable thing because it's
what is what is telling us
is that whatever these rules are
if there are rules whose consequences we believe in
then that's belief about trust extends beyond the rules themselves
and that's
you have to know
the rules are trustworthy and that's belief that they are trustworthy enables you to extend
if after sort of fifty-five minutes you sort of feel uncomfortable standing we do remind you that it is being recorded
and can be looked on the web afterwards and I said for tomorrow we definitely
get to try to get a bigger room
ok thank you it's a pleasure to be here in sunny Geneva actually it's warm Geneva
compared to Chicago it's been really cold in Chicago and in fact something really remarkable
was seen last week there was a Chicago politician walking around with his hands in his
own pockets so the program for this week is today i'm going to give
an introduction concentrating more on observational astronomy and the basis of this standard model
that leads us to the idea that there is dark matter
and dark energy
it is a talk about the universe observed from the viewpoint of a theorist
then tomorrow I would like to talk about inflation because this also plays a role
in the entire picture of the standard model of cosmology
then on Wednesday I will concentrate on dark matter
and Thursday concentrate on dark energy
now what wasn't mentioned in the introduction is that I'm a cosmologist
and I'm proud of it now one of the things that a cosmologist does is to
look out
In in the universe so not only to see what's there and how it moves and a
description of it but to look beyond that and try to understand why
it behaves as it does so we want to
in ancient times it was you know mechanical gears crystalline spheres
but today at least in the civilized world we understand the the workings of the
universe on the basis of the laws of physics and of course particle physics plays
a large role in that and that is what I would like to concentrate on
now in part
To understand
this working of the universe we construct a cosmological model
just as in particle physics there's a cosmological sti there is a
particle physics standard model
in cosmology there is a cosmological
Standard model
and let me give you the
relevant aspects of this standard cosmological model it goes by the name of lambda CDM
lambda stands for Einstein's cosmological constant or dark energy
and cold dark matter stands for what CDM stands for cold dark matter
one of the aspects of this cosmological standard model
is the present constitution of the universe what is involved in the universe today what is it made
of and this is the constitution of the universe according to the cosmological standard model
although the early universe was radiation dominated at present the radiation in the universe
contributes only point zero zero five per cent of the mass energy of the universe and
almost all of the radiation in the universe is in the back the cosmic background radiation
this pizza
chart also illustrates why chemistry is not important
the chemical elements elements other than hydrogen and helium only make up about point zero
two five per cent of the mass energy of the universe
there is much more mass energy in the universe in the form of neutrinos today
about point one per cent
point one seven point two per cent stars make up about less than half a per
cent of the mass energy of the universe
so there is most of the baryons are not in the form of
stars but are in a hot gas
that is to be found in clusters of galaxies
so five per cent of the universe are the things that are observed and
we understand and we know about
but in this cosmological standard model there's ninety-five per cent of the universe that's
a mystery
and it's thought that twenty-five per cent of the current energy density of the universe
is in the form of some type of cold dark matter and the remaining seventy
per cent above is in dark energy or a cosmological constant
this is the constitution of the universe in the standard cosmological model
also in the standard cosmological model
there is the need
for some
primordial sea perturbations
that grow to become galaxies and large-scale structure that we see in the universe
In this
is in this model thought to arise from the very early universe
In the epic known as inflation
finally I won't talk about this in these lectures because I'm only giving four
but the standard model has to have some idea or theory of the origin of
the asymmetry between matter and anti-matter baryo Genesis or lepto Genesis
and the relevant thing for high-energy physics is that cold dark matter
dark energy
inflationare inflation in baryo and lepto Genesis seem to require physics beyond the standard model of
particle physics
so this is in twenty five words or less
the description of the standard cosmological model
now when I go around giving public lectures and I talk to them about scientific
models whether it is the standard model of particle physics
or the Standard Model od cosmology
I think that the general public
including our colleagues at universities in fields other than science
do not really know
what we mean by a model
for instance there was a very well-known economist in the United States who wrote
about models and he said the construction of a model consist of snatching from the enormous and
complex massive facts called reality
a few simple easily managed key points
which when put together in some cunning way becomes for certain purposes
a substitute for reality itself now I don't think as scientists we view a model whether it is
the Standard Model of particle physics of the standard model of cosmology as a substitute
for reality itself we view it as a description
of reality itself
and I think when we talk to the public we have to make that that idea clear
we want more
from a model than be able to describe what we see
and account for the data
there is a long history in astronomy of introducing things that will allow us to
account for the data
these were known as epicycles
and they were in of course the model of Ptolemy in the Almagest
and they were also many more epicycles in Copernicus's book
you know and also this represents the trial solution to the segmentation problem so this
says x two is in the background and x one is in the foreground
and so
the cost of that configuration
apparently is thirteen units
now is this the lowest-cost that we could get in this graph
to do that we would have to wriggle around with this red curve and try
all possible configurations one across here one across here one going to the negative slope
and that would be actually all of them for this particular network
but of course
you know how the number of cuts grows exponentially with the number of nodes which
is one of the reasons why you know if anybody has smart you know the
naive algorithm for this problem will be exponentially with doing exponential amount of work so
this is really worthwhile if anybody have something better than a naive algorithm
OK so now
let's see what would you like to simulate
a flow through this through the network by the way one thing i forgot to
say the beginning
earlier on was that
it's all very well
taking this
cut and wriggling around to see which
cut gives the minimum cost but was that we wanted to know does anybody want
to know the minimum cost
i mean if i tell you the minimum cost is is eight units will be
they will help you know with the computer graphics problem with it i mean we
didn't want was we want to know not the actual value of the minimum cost
the big so we we actually need to know you know we've solved this for
this minimum cost we better we better also know how to recover the configuration that
that gives the minimum cost and
so in other words we when we push and also when we're pushing for flow
through the network we need to know which are the arcs with which this minimum
cut will pass and it turns out this is part of the full focus on
the cut passes through exactly those pipelines in the network which is saturated
so all you have to do with the end is to read out which
pipelines with the final flow that to achieve have reached their maximum capacity and the
it passes through each other
we will have to do with the end
OK so now we're going to stop pushing flow
the black
figures are capacities
i think the best is the red figures are flow
initially we start with zero flow and so actually what you have to do is
kind of search problem building a search tree starting from the source here searching for
unsaturated box so the beginning it's not very difficult to find unsaturated ox you imagine
starting a breadth first search for factory quarks you'd quickly come across that one that's
a and you see
OK how much
can we
pushed down here well it might be as much as two units
and that will be fine provided and this is the next step in the search
we can find arcs after this node will take two years to flow and thank
goodness there is one here so provisionally we can push two units down here and
now in principle we would have to look at any node there was down here
to see if it had an exit
that could take two units afloat but actually in the image processing problems typically you've
reached the sink after
after two steps on vertical arcs so now we know
but getting into units through that through their we are going to be able to
get two units through
the entire
network OK so now we repeat the process but with very now looking at the
residual flows so now we're a residual capacities rather than now we examine each of
the arcs again looking at the residual capacity this has zero residual capacity because it's
flow already
has some saturated the
and so then we do breakfast search carry on examining arcsin x one is this
one it hasn't saturated it's
capacity so now we can look pushing for flow through there and so on
and continuing the search
we find that the maximum
we find a route
we can push three user flow down
and we got there
OK now we continue the process
looking across here for
arcs which still have residual flow
are there any
yes that's the one the same one again still has some residual capacity
so we could try
pushing will flow down here so we
expand the search tree again actually pretty darn to have collapsed the also is true
because the first part was useful so clever algorithms don't do that they maintain fragments
circuitry for later use
and we get this on we can see what we can no residual capacity down
but is there any other on with residual capacity turns out this one has residual
capacity so that but that's promising but only if we can exit from this node
any know any here with residual capacity is this one and the
so now we get
the next
increment flow
and strictly speaking we haven't finished yet because now you'd say well NER NER carriage
here with with residual capacity and
and the first one
the the
the rightmost one does have residual capacity so you try again you get here is
there anything i coming here to ask you know that it's true that saturated finished
OK so now the algorithm is terminated because there are no
and no roots left with residual capacity
now this point we have to do what i promised which is to examine all
of the arctic char residual capacity which have no residual capacity which is saturated and
so all the one circle in yellow have zero residual capacity and so now
that red line the separating surface should go through all of those yellow circle arcs
and we found the solution to the problem
and it turns out that this is the minimum cost six units which is much
less than thirteen units which shows the cost of the the thing that i try
to random initial is a good thing to have done some optimizations and we've cause
we've got also our optimal labeling after this which is that
this big so is is in the background in this because in the foreground
and it turns out that there are there are many varieties of algorithm of this
form the ditch algorithm is one of the earliest ones and thank goodness although this
this problem appears to have the potential for exponential complexity it turns out that in
each algorithm has only order nq complexity so that if you systematically direct search pushing
flows you can show that you will have examined all over the possible flows all
you need to examine in order q steps where n is the number of pixels
across and q is the pretty large number for when n is one mega pixel
so thank goodness heuristically things you know
faster than NQP
and there are special opportunities also in vision because of the very particular and you
know you could do this on any shape graph with many intermediate nodes and so
on but in vision we tend to have these very wide shallow graphs only two
steps vertically but many steps
in terms of angular distance is of course the same complete symmetry
and so do here fighting which roughly
without being very precise
the weight of each one of those big
must be roughly lambda
divided by and
so i take off this this
think this is all these things are
angles in radians
because science there
very much smaller than the data
you can see that the larger and is
the more of these openings you have
the never these lines are going to be but i think of these being aligned
that means you will be
to distinguish two neighbouring frequencies from each other two different led us
and and that's what we call spectral resolution
so the larger and is
the band spectral resolution you have
the ability to separate two neighbouring frequencies than increases
it's very easy way
but i can convince you
without any mass
a little less
why the width of these pics
two weeks of these maxima maximum
must be proportional to one
over and
and that during an energy conservation arguments follow me closely
if i have enough of these openings in discrete label that and times more light
then one opening that straightforward you can tell that you get from
if you have an opening industry you get ten times more light through than if
you had one openly that's non-negotiable right
but if the maximum is and script times higher
the only way that you can conserve energy is if you make the maximum and
times smaller than you know that ten times more likely
the argument once more
you have an openings
give you an times more energy than one opening
but if the maximum
if you light intensity with groceries and square
the only way that you can conserve energy if you make the maximum time
so it's very easy way to see
that the which you must
go down
was increasing and
very powerful i
now i will make you see in another way
if we have for all of these
openings industry
why there are only three
and all these methods that i'm using in a way i complementary
it's all the same thing but i just wanted to see it in different ways
that helped me enormously
look at it in different ways
so we have an equal four
and i started with delta equals zero
so there's no phase difference between adjacent sources
so this is the case
that this is the vector of source number one this effective source number two
number three and number four all four factors lined up in the same direction and
i doubt that could not be zero
therefore i get sixteen times the like because i square
and i get sixteen this is your
factor of sixteen
you get maximum
now go to build eagles while the
ninety degrees
i don't have to look at that equation
i don't need that one i know ninety degrees is i went to high school
and educated
this is one factor
this is ninety degrees that's the second factor this is ninety degrees at the third
factor this is the force vector ninety degrees what do i do was
so if all four
relative to neighbors ninety degrees
phase angle
then clearly zero here
now i go delta
because by
i know why is one
three four
what do i end up with
i have four vectors under a degree flip flip flip flip what is the net
this one
is this one
and the second one is this one not going to do this one for you
equals three as five
three houses two hundred seventy degrees
this is one this is two hundred seventy degrees this is two hundred seventy degrees
and that is two hundred seventy degrees what is the net result
well let this one
now i'm going to do to pi
i mean i don't report back here
get the next
and that this one
so you can see
fury biplane vector is very simple high-school level
you can see that there will be
n minus one minimum
exact minimum between
the prime maximum
well the first thing that
i wanted to see
is when i take the grading that you have
and i use my
laser pointer
the first thing i wanted to see
incredible impact
of using
many many lines
why laser beam
has about diameter
of about three millimeters
so here is this laser beam
and this
i estimated to be roughly three millimeters
no grading believe it or not
is a supergradient
upgrading at thirteen thousand four hundred lines per inch imagine how anyone can pull groups
in your plastic
thirteen thousand four hundred
that means that the separation the
between two groups is about one point nine
times ten to the minus six meters there is only
two microns
how anyone can do that beats me but it can be done
so i can calculate know how many of those lines i have used into three
millimeters and i end up with
and is about sixteen hundred
so when i shine my laser beam
through migrating i effectively sixteen hundred of those lines
brother triangles of course
that's not true
for the triangles it's not but for
a right triangle somehow
that fact should connect to that fact can we just make that connection
what's the connection between this
test for orthogonality
and this
statement of orthogonality well i guess i have to say
what is the length square
so let's
continue on the
board underneath without equation
give me another way to express the length squared of vector
let me just give your vector
the vector one two three
that's in three dimensions
what is the length square of the vector x equal
one two three
so how do you find the link squared
well really it
you want the length of that vector that goes along on
up to one out of three
and will
come come back to that right triangles stuff
the length squared is
this is exactly
x transpose x
whenever i cx transpose x i know i've got
number that's positive
it's length squared
a lesser unless x happens to be the zero vector that's the one case where
the length is zero
right now this is just x one squared plus x two squared plus on perspex
in square
so one in the example i gave you what was the length squared of that
vector one two three
so you square
one four in nine forty
so the vector one two three has length fourteen
so let me just put down the back
ah that's the
the vector one two three
michal kovac orthogonal to it
so what
so the right here
x where
one four nine forty
let me come back here that orthogonal to it
i will get
right that those two vectors are orthogonal
the length of life where it is
and that was why
one and two making
one month
one making one really zero making three
the length of the square
o nine was one was nine ninety
and sure enough
i have improved
just like
check to see
best friend of y equals zero
which is for everybody the next round of y zero here
that may be the main point
you should
you really quick doing extra y
so if
this was the first is that
and sure enough
that played with
forty five agreeing with ninety
let me just do that is
that's why have called y
and this
well why
so i'm looking again this is always true i repeat
this is going to be true when we have a right angle
and the does
well of course i'm just going to simplify the here
the next round of the air
and there is a wide variety of why there
and the friends of y
and there is a wide range of
i know like
do that simplification because
and matrix multiplication and to follow the rules
extract from that can fall
y four y
and what about these guys what would you tell me about
the inner product of x with y
and the inner product of y with that
is there a different
i think we well we're doing real
bacteria which is already doing now
there is a difference is noted
if i
extract y given a zero quite
why transpose x i would have the same
x one y one x two two y two and x three y three
it would be the same so this is
this is
this is the same as that really all not that guy out there too
so i believe that the
this is a quite boil down to the thing being
everything else can
and this equation boils down
so that's really all i
i wanted to check that
four right triangle
let me
to there
i thought i can for the two
no problem
and for like a zero at the
you know what
the dot product of orthogonal vectors is
it says i want to say
that's really
it can
it comes out the
all right
what about now i know it to back what it means when two vectors are
orthogonal by the way
what about if one of these guys is zero
suppose x is the zero vector
and why
it is what
are they are not
she was
favourite reason doesn't support
this tracing
compute justifications then you would need something else and we can use the black box
technique so black box techniques do not depend on the particular reason that you can
you should be able to use them with any reasonable
and all that we require for this black box technique is done
and the reason it can i tell us whether a class expression is satisfiable
with respect to
a ontology
we using power in these demonstrations due to a couple of implementation issues factors plus
doesn't work so well the justification were working to sort out the justification workbench working
to sort out the
so i say it just requires that a class
we can ask for the satisfiability of the class in other classes satisfiability
so satisfiable and the reason for this is that if we have an entailment ontology
models ontology entails c
this of course did
in OWL
there's always the corresponding class description
that would be unsatisfiable with respect to ontology for a given entailment
so here you see the phrases across the in the class here
c and not the
it's going to be unsatisfiable
and for all
we can always generate an unsatisfiable class entailments that we're interested in
OK so if this entailment holds you see that question is satisfiable if intend doesn't
hold is satisfiable
just a little bit more about this black box strategy because this is the one
that brought show uses
so that it doesn't depend on the particular reason
so these blackbox strategy typically use some kind of expanding contract strategy
so we start off with the entailment that we're interested in itself if it was
we wanted to explain why he was supposed to die
we take this signature
so c and d and we can then look vaccines from the ontology for that
define c and d
we start with an empty ontology and we
stuff in axioms gradually doing some kind of structural expansion
so the thing turns out is satisfy unsatisfiable
so we have this ability quite quite a few satisfiability cheque city-states gradually expand our
ontology and my actions in israel the force technique
when we get an unsatisfiable class
then we know that we've got a superset of the axioms required entailment to hold
so we start to prune these off often until expression is satisfiable and now from
this we can determine which axioms actually constitute justification
and then optimize this is for slowing quite a lot of satisfiability checks but several
optimizations in particular to do with the expansion of axioms are stimulate contraction of axioms
in the second stage several and optimizations we can introduce so that in practice is
not too bad
and one of the nice things about these modularity stuff is that as well as
in doing this we use scenario where we can pull out a small section of
the ontology and use it in
import into another ontology network we working on we can also use this more programmatically
we can use it for optimisations so we want to know why something is satisfiable
we can compute the module for the thing that's unsatisfiable
i guess small portion of the axioms and then this sort of
explanation this technique generates explanations really works quite well
so the techniques that we use here is that we use this black box strategy
or glass box strategy to find one justification so in this case we would use
pallets to compute the what explanation
all part of the computer with any reasonable what explanation we find one justification and
then we use techniques from all diagnosis to find all justifications in the answer for
a given entailment this uses
this a sum up my diagnosis in particular
right so algorithms for computing hitting centuries and the worst case this is album is
with the number justification so if a lot of justifications is quite slow
some key optimizations we can apply here
so again it doesn't work so badly in practice
OK so what i want to do now is just have look small justifications and
i want to
as such repairs ontology and i'll show you a way of doing this
so i
and we should focus on average is unsatisfiable classes if you want to move
ten of these classes satisfiable
so what we do is we select all of these is unsatisfiable classes here
and then on the right-hand side
for each time we select
it will have the justifications for the entailment of the panel on the right-hand side
so we get quite a few justifications here
that's that's continuous so
i had a couple of questions during the break may be repeat here so one
question was related to this figure
and the question was
one of these noise free observations and indeed i i did use noise free observation
is right actually
actually require that the function should agree exactly
with the data points here in the formula down here the noise level here which
comes on like your functions in allows for noise in principle but active set sigma
square the noise to be zero in this particular equation
this is one of the interesting things about casting process you could actually fit them
to to noise free data
so for example you can use the prior metric models to right
because it might be that
for any set of parameters
you can get an exact fit the data is typically the case you can just
you have exactly today
in one of the other comments was shows that shows the pretty pictures maybe some
sort of very nice
it is a very humble questions
that's right so the question is exactly what is the shaded area
in this area what i did was i just computer
for every point x i computed the mean
and the variance of the core of the corresponding
garcia predictive distribution rights were just evaluated
this thing here for all possible values of x star
and the grey shaded area
it's just the mean the middle of the gracious areas just the mean
and goes up to plus and minus two salutations that corresponds so two and ninety
five percent confidence intervals
of where the function could be
of course the core looking at this is that you have these are pointwise confidence
so obviously the the function is the true function values up here then it can
be the true function value for the for nearby points will be done here down
here right
so the joint
confidence intervals
you can also compute
but this is this is a a big object this is a matrix of so
these are marginal
point wise
pointwise confidence intervals so therefore i also plotted functions that are drawn like may of
course are drawn from the joint
predictive distribution
you could also the right to
so so what's happening here is just that the
that the predictive distribution here
the distribution from under the prior
one from between minus two two actually of serving these things
at the value five did not to change that
very much or at all
i just says that the that the
that the
the information about the data contains about what the function is doing out here
is almost zero
yes yes they just run drawn around
that's right now
OK so let's try to sum up
we're we're where we've come to so far right so i i spent a lot
of time to tell you what is the gaussianprocess trying to convince you that this
is the distribution of functions and i've shown here in a graphical
format and also in
using a drug
how you update
prior process to the posterior process by conditioning
on the data
like so the things that
so i think i haven't told you about it
it is well what are the properties of these functions right
because if these in this class of functions functions that look like this
if this is in some sense is a useless class like if you're not interested
in functions look like that
it doesn't make much sense what i'm saying right
so we should worry about
what kind of properties can functions have
from these process so that's what i'm going to
tell you more about
so the so so so it's important to understand how we got from this picture
to this picture
at least
in in the concept away by saying well you just draw this function around and
have this distribution over functions
and then you
you can select the ones that agree with the data points
you can think of each of these are doing in graphical way it turns out
that it's actually very easy to compute
this thing
let's look first a little bit more
these these equations since there quite long
so here first this is a graphical representation of what i constant process model looks
like i got the process model involves a number of
these are latent variables of these variables the
tell you what are the on what the true underlying function values right and if
you had noise in the process then you don't have certain effort so you only
observe y
we observe the the things around in in square here
and these are these are latent variables
and what you're interested in is the distribution of
of wise otherwise star here and why stars are connected to the things that you
by the fully connected network
of latent variables
what you need to do to do inference is you need to
figure out what is the
the conditional distribution of y one
all the observed
now relating back to students talk about graphical models because the fully connected network
there are no shortcuts
you actually need to take all those
dependencies into account
but because everything is jointly calcium you can actually compute without distribution
so things like that that you only thing which is bad is that these these
great measures actually grow very rapidly right so if you have
a hundred latent variables and you have to work with one hundred five hundred grams
if you have millions of observations that might be a problem
and it also shows against the graphical models sort author
tells you about
this this
this thing that you can do that if you add another random variable here
but if you had a test point here for the added an unspecified test point
so doing that if it's not observed
then it doesn't change the distribution over the variables
that's a graphical models way
a thing this marginalisation property
if you're only interested in one of the variables then it just has the covariance
and mean
by picking out those those elements
one of the matrix so you can add in
these test points without changing the distribution of these things
so let's let's look at this look at this sort of this is the main
result here
so that is the predictive distribution now i look at the british precision of the
corresponding latent variable
the difference between the latent variable and the corresponding served variable is just discussed in
that's really physics and actions a one all the way
most really morris velocity when he hits the floor
the fall believable
the guy was bowled for one thing
and so the impact time was very short
and when in fact i'm assured even if you get the frozen modest speed
exploration is high
and that
i was too much
and so
that's why
this school
what crushed
so it what matters is this
change in velocity
and the impact time
now i want to make one last
step from average acceleration
we want to go
acceleration at any moment in time
just the way we did that
and that now is the natural step
the acceleration at any moment in time
it would be
and then
for delta team
goes to zero
for the
national because delta t
the minus is the
divided by
is the instantaneous acceleration this
you will recognised
is the first derivative of velocity versus time
which is also
the second derivative of position versus time
so here comes the second equation
i really want you to remember
four ever
and ever and ever
that the acceleration
which is also
two x
you can square
we can
go to plot
and we can ask ourselves the question now
where is the acceleration zero
where larger than zero and where is it smaller than zero because this value can
larger than zero equal to zero
and smaller than zero
you have to be
very careful when you try to derive that from this plot
you have to be very careful
because you and i have no good feeling for second derivative
velocity is easy all you have to do is looking at all far
but when it comes to the second derivative you have to see how of is
right here
the velocity is not changing
sorry acceleration everywhere you must be zero
here the velocity is increasing
thirty acceleration must be larger than
zero here
the velocity is almost constant
is almost a straight line
what does that mean
forty acceleration
here what makes this rounding curve
the velocities positive feedback but on this side is negative
what does it mean for the acceleration
negative you got it
so you can now
roughly find
the acceleration is positive whereas negative
and where
it is
let's do
straightforward example
the way
that you could expect it
on an assignment
if you are extraordinarily lucky
you might even get something like that
on exam
very straightforward i'm going to give you
the position x
as a function of time
and then ask you lots of questions
about it
so it is example is working example
he calls eight
minus sixty
plus the square
so this tells you whether the object is at any moment in time
let this be in meters
what now is the velocity at any moment in time
well that's the
the relative bxt t
and i use
the following
x y equals
two the power and
most of you
you know the xt is then and times t
so that we can ensure that we can start behaving according to a new values
and it was part of our strategy walking the dog tradition sharing and thirdly it
was also for new innovations
and as as the story
and they well this is our nokia way jam looked like we were looking for
creating new nokia how to role in consummated markets what does it mean to be
leader leading and winning in devices and then accelerating business an option but in general
and with adults course of IBM which was of course very important for us so
we could engage more about i employees and what was you has been even more
importantly to me and to us afterwards was that we started to use
the nokia way jam content as the wealth of ideas so we had they're like
seven thousand seven hundred posts
so ideas all parts of dialogue and then we
notice that twenty two present active posters against the readers these for some very high
if you know that if you take an average discussion forum there is one idea
it may mean that the one is posting that idea ten may comment and one
hundred is following up the other thing is that the different these these the length
of threads the dialogues were almost ten
and that is again very good it means that we had to dial we just
put up any any comments whatsoever
and then what is also very nice that there was not the single proper unprepared
but we were looking at that and our senior management was leading the way
oh PK was spending seventeen hours during the seventy two hours i mean he has
some of these things in his agenda plants that i think he had the privilege
to sleep during those those hectic hours
what we also did was that it it was it looked like a quite ordinary
discussion forum and then we had our facilitators in each and every time zone we
were monitoring the discussions and i called it positive manipulation so it is our expert
presentations facilitators know it is very good idea they could eat more in from in
the jam user interface so they were like the hot topics and they were not
like like mechanism created what are the most on the core used conversations but it
was really that hey
let's put the wisdom of the crowds to the joints these topic and
indeed pressure that it seems that it's like six months almost six months of the
the jam i AM not
honestly i'm not in the position now i'm not very open to tell the concrete
results except that maybe one thing is something that would interest us so we noticed
that people were a lot of discussing about what does it mean to be an
internet company
so we need like content analyses and created internet company star which i have eight
arms or dimensions and this is how we are driving the change towards internet company
we are using these for analysing not only our own attitudes but also the attitude
of the team attitude of the group and open innovation is likely to do there
a very strong clue indeed
so this is basically that's what we succeeded in that part then the other one
was the one on the case that i would like to share with you is
our community forum nokia so when we launch this ovi service three months ago we
had two point eight million
believe that
early birds and technical experts to really
you know started
developing and all the all the all the
former not is our answer to open innovation
and well our fifty six different ways of innovating
inside the company and outside the company and to six ways of doing it a
bit of a lot so there will be some open innovation strategies come soon so
we've been released with spying on what do we have
so it's very important for us
leading the small communities and i was previously working for for a company which was
in this to me
in the field of multimedia e-learning insanity and
danger is our biggest customer was not just far too big strategically for company very
and i recall two thousand one two thousand two when we we had some kind
of ideas in the field of content
not find it interesting that they didn't really know how to approach it now in
two thousand seven and colleague of mine learning and learning and e-learning community approached and
asked that hey we wanna do some mobile learning in a in the n ninety
in nineteen with the answer and n eighty which is our platform our tablet PC
and i was kind of thing dr how should i help you know i know
the answer mean we're not interested in content in forty five minutes i found the
right people to have a meeting in ten days how to
do how to do utilise with API how to find i mean the not first
was offering different is you develop the the user interface statistical parts further and i
was really amazed myself and all the links where they're all the help help for
for the user of this being the multinational company training a lot of people all
over the seas so that yet and they wanted to give each and every of
their trainee for their distance-learning phase a tablet PC for doing it so i think
we're really changing and we're really opening and this is how forum nokia feeds in
ideas innovations incorporation so what happened to patterns what will happen with with PR's i
don't know the answer about
yes two minutes yes unfortunately i don't know the answer but i've seen this happening
in practice
and it's just fascinating
to know this and to get the same enthusiasm and this is part of the
that we are working internally now
of finding good elimination ordering
it is a complex question and i guess for arbitrary graphs finding the best elimination
is in NP complete control
those out the in practice usually
you will see that you don't really use the elimination our as it is here
user more sophisticated version
the problem is that
here i have a computer all these because they want to the a given query
p of x one
but what if i want to compute p of x sixty four p of x
three and p of x
we had to withdraw all this procedure
there's a nice little voice
that's called belief propagation
so basically
it is also called some problems with him sometimes
it does not repeat computations you see that if you don't do this european competition
for this list
and specifically designed for three structure graph
also see why that's the case
immediately here we have
more heavy
slide but let's try to understand what's going on
assume you want to do elimination
let's assume that we want to compute p of and
we have a changed here
this a very simple graphical model is just change
this is extant
we just want to compute the marginal that's OK
what's the marginal of xn is the sum of all the variables that are smaller
than xn
and the virus that are larger than xm
of the joint probability distribution
which is given by these according to the home sixty four
we just take the maximal cliques which are i and i was one
now we just separate these problems into two problem
one problem
for the left hand side
and the problem with the right hand side
and this
now we observed that
devi temples in here
and the violence and here can be separated in this
we bring the violence here to this violin
now immediately
i have to solve this
two problems here
in order to compute p of xn
how to compute these problem here well
we've already seen how to compute this problem
a very simple example
we just use the distributive law
and you push
since we summing up two x input minus one
we push this sums as far as it can go
for example push this in mind is one of the last
factor which is
x i minus
two and i n minus two and minus one
then to compute that some
and they come back and compute
take the problem to compute something present that something
so basically it will be only quadratic in the size of the table here if
i have a tabular representation for function
it will be just linear in the number of
factors because i have to compute
is many times
well i have the same computational complexity here because the problem is identical just magically
what's going on here is that
i actually in the process of computing p of xn
i compute these local
summations that they store
in a viable so they call
nu alpha
or music
and then if you think what's happening here
what p of x in these
it's just the product of this incoming message
as we call
two x and coming from the left
this is mu alpha
of xn
and this is mu beta effects
so we have constructed thing the way that
the marginal for these
but you know and
is just the product of this
with this
but in order to compute these any to compute first one
in order to compute using compute first one and this n is completely arbitrary right
so i can start with an in here if i started in here what we
well one of these terms immediately is of p
and they only have these problems so i started that
in other words
look at citation networks you can look at the co authorship networks you can look
at section that networks where an edge means that some section interaction or something and
you can look at also clickstream data
how do you create the network out of text
people also that
i think so
but just like any then you can just like you you can create a network
of of everything and then it's like
i don't know
i mean because because the think that
so that i could be good company
OK so right and there is a lot of also graph models that they also
i describe what is good and i described but preferential attachment this was developed for
power law degree distributions copying model is something that gives you the power law degree
distributions but also user communities we had also small world model i described and so
on and for example this one
i want to give you
we generated graph that there's a fight but the diameter is increasing and again you
just got from property but not the other and so on and so this is
the problem and here's here's one solution x o
you want to model the
for which can proven then fitted and does all these
the thing here is that this morning
have like a very nice
generative semantics OK
it will be like
something that you could say is happening in the nature in some sense
and let's let me define this chronicle model kronecker graphs
and what we basically do we will we will try to generate our graph recursively
let's say we we do it because you that so we start with some initial
graph and then somehow recursively expand nodes of this graph to get larger and larger
versions of the graph that and here is an example of what we doing so
basically the tensor product of graph adjacency matrix is that this is the graph adjacency
matrix of the following
i go and expand each node here we don't miniature copy of the graph itself
and then introducing some additional edges and this is exactly the process if i think
this matrix and tensor multiplied minutes which means that i think the constant here and
it and multiply the whole matrix so here i get g one and here i
get zero times g one which is zero OK and i'm just doing
one of the exactly nothing at this operation
would be
he met his vision
for the the the this is how it i mean this mathematicians have defined is
a long time ago i mean this is a kronecker product usually have two types
of products between graphs one is this that the product of kronecker product the other
the other one is cartesian product which doesn't really
right so here is i could do one that i then i have multiplied itself
gadget to if i would know which obliged to read itself and this is what
i would go so i will be getting some kind of nice i know similar
structure like
and so
right we start with g one on n one and you want and just recorded
initiator and then we get
sequence of growing graphs each one we have and one to the k
known structure
the size of the matrix article history is not nine
just how the product works and then four so this is the model
and here is where he is more precisely what
the tensor product or kronecker product of two matrices it is but if i have
a and b i just think the elements of faith and like speaking the the
whole the matrix OK
and here is that if if these are the sizes of a and b this
is the size of the of the problem so the the matrix is growing
i explained this right so we get case chronicle part the just
multiplying g one which itself
so the intuition you can have is basically having this because you've growth of communities
with every
we're right this is like my our building block and now every node in the
in the network gets like expand we we is building block right and this continues
the other thing is
what i want to show you here this is all deterministic right so i have
matrix here it is zero sum someone so it's completely deterministic process how i can
analyse it
is is here so this is the idea how to get nonstochastic were how to
get around the world of of the and the idea is that instead of starting
with zero one matrix i we start with some probability matrix were here now every
is is the probability so it's between zero and one in the sense the need
to sum to one that just going on what is an arbitrary number between zero
and one i can now kronecker multiplied this mean itself
i get some probability right so for example here i get get point five square
here get point five times point two and so on right now i can i
i will
the ability
office circuit
to fight the magnetic flux
it's produced by the
circuits themselves
if you have a circuit that you want to current through the circuit
you create magnetic field
and if the currents are changing the magnetic field to change changing
and so there will be an induced EMF in that circuit
that fights
the change
and we express that
in terms of a self inductance l
self inductances
and would sell speaks for itself
it's doing it's to itself
magnetic flux
that is produced by
the circuit is always proportional to the current u double the current magnetic flux doubles
so does the proportionality constant
that we call
that is the self inductance
and so therefore the
the induced EMF
the phi dt
that is found a floor
so that becomes minus al
the ITT
it's only a matter of geometry
l is not a function of the current itself
i will calculate for you are very simple case of the self inductance
a of the solenoid
this be solenoidal and this is a closed circuit
and we want the current i through the solenoid
and the radius
of these windings is or
let's say said and windings
the length of the solenoid is the well
have you remember
that we only have derived using
if the magnetic field inside the solenoid
his new zero
times i
i'm capital and divided by all this is the number of windings parameter
if we attached
open surface duties
closed loop
very difficult to imagine what that open surface looks like we we discussed it many
inside this solenoid you have sort of staircase like of surface
that magnetic field penetrates that surface and times because you have and groups
so the magnetic flux
if i being
is simply the
every year
by the laws craig which is the surface area of one little because i saw
the edit field is constant inside the solenoid
and i still that is zero outside which is a very good approximation
so we get by the are square
the surface area of one loop
but we have n loops
and then we have to multiply by a constant
magnetic field so ligands create because we have and here
zero i
divided by l
and this
we call
well i don't definition for self inductance
so to self inductance l
purely geometry
by the last created
capitol and square
divided by l
and zero
check this
while little was created
the capital and squared
that's correct
divided by the way
so we can calculate for instance what
the self inductances
four a
solenoid that we have used in class several times
we had one whereby we twenty eight hundred windings
are i think something like five centimetres
after work as i of course be careful
we had a length
o point six metres
we had several times on here
and if you substitute those numbers in there
you'll find that the self inductance
all that solenoid
is o point one
as i units
and we call the as i units henry capital h
it will be the same as for seconds
and here but no one would ever use that to call them
every circuit
has a finite value for the self inductance however small that may be sometimes it's
so small that we ignore it
but if you take the simple
the same simple current just won why it goes around whether it is
rectangle whether it circle doesn't make any difference it always produces a magnetic field
always for those magnetic flux through the surface and so it always has the finite
self inductance maybe only nine nano and may be only micro henry's but it's never
so now what i want to do
is to show you remarkable
consequences of the presence of
self inductor
in a circle
and i started very simple
i have your battery
which has
i have is which
and here i was helping doctors
we always
draw cell conductor in a circuit
with these corals
and we also have in series
which are always indicated with this
and i close
this which
when there is no current running
in other words at time t equal zero when i close to switch
there is no current
when i close this which
the current wants to increase the self inductances
easy lens law
i don't like the change
of such occurrence of the self inductances fighting
the current wants to go through it
the concert time
that the self inductance loses the fight if you wait long enough
and these are so these are separate
gas and some of the files to do all these things together it's again again
and then i need to normalize out the context and that gives me a new
gas distribution and then just replace
the factor here by that gas in distribution and move on to the next one
right ninety two
we and especially in a situation here because the because the the likelihood function which
we are having at having trouble with is chosen to be the cumulative gaussians and
the cumulative gas in his log concave or convex i always mix them up like
it falls down like that right so it means that when we doing the the
the this this step here where we multiplying by by by that distribution here we
don't have this negative variance problem because we know that the that the that the
likelihood function is always convex
OK so so so things go very nicely
so here have a plot of phi to work is that so that's that support
which is comparing running
the EP algorithm to try to find a posterior approximation and comparing that to using
the fastest method
OK i'm going to run out of time someone OK so that the three parts
here so the first part here is showing you the value of the marginal likelihood
so this so these are the two hyperparameters OK so sorry i'm new i'm doing
i'm using this for
did for handwritten digit classification OK i'm just using a very simple case where i'm
just trying to distinguish between three and five because so is very simple
classification problem binary classification and i have two parameters in my model so my gaussianprocess
two parameters as the lengthscale that says you know how close should things be before
there before the could which
and i have magnitude parameter saying is some if the if the underlying process that's
very extreme values in the probability get close to one right so you get very
confident predictions and if the manager is very small then you get predictions around fifty
fifty all the time right so the confidence is also encoded by a parameter
right so so here i show the value of the marginal likelihood so
that means when i showed this dataset have seven hundred training cases then i can
optimize with respect to the marginal likelihood and the marginal likelihood landscape i painstakingly computed
the marginal likelihood for every possible combination of the hyperparameters
OK and i show you landscape here so normally i would just go to the
to the most likely to the most likely model
and this is for
this is for you EP
and sorry this is for the light passes method this is EP
and this is based on the on mark marketeer monte carlo so here we tried
really really hard to run the markov chain for for very very long time to
compute the right answer to this intractable problems and you can see that some of
these things ought to be the same as the approximations were good
and you can see actually the EP approximation was very hard to read the numbers
the distance but the number of this is minus minus ninety two in his mind
and minus ninety two one of the same contours was in the same place and
you can see that these countries plots are almost exactly the same like this one
already has a little bit wobbly because they used MCMC so i'm only getting estimates
up to i guess about plus and minus one in the in the log domain
so but this does not tell us anything about whether whether this could be because
they this could be exactly the right answer that's been data perfectly agrees with this
whereas past method doesn't seem to be doing as well it doesn't which is high
the marginal likelihood and also the shape of the contours is different and the maximum
maximum is in a different place
the down here and looking at the predictive performance and actually looking at the
the amount of information
that the predictive distribution has about the right target
in this case i get up to
o point eight four bits of information so the maximum amount of information you could
have only one bit
and now the corresponding to if you're always exactly right and you always completely confident
and zero bits of information would be
if you always a fifty fifty
so here we get more information on the predictive distribution also agrees very well with
the with a markov chain
so now we can ask the question
you know what what do they want to the posterior distributions look like why is
it that that passes method comes up with with a bad approximation or worse approximation
why does EP come up with with a with a good approximation to not have
the problem that my gas distribution is seven hundred dimensional
right so i can i can support it
so what i've plotted instead of plotted uploaded to of the marginals
right so i have a seven hundred dimensional distribution and i just want to other
models i looked through all the models and found the marginals that with one module
which was the least gaussians
and the way i did that was by using the markov chain so in the
set we tried to
we tried to get several clusterings of our dataset and we don't really want to
choose one in the end so we just want to look at our data from
different point of view
and then we can be end up with a list of subspaces and corresponding clusters
the subspace is something like this is
the projection of the data to a few features some to do something like feature
selection and the new
cluster based on those features and there's no way to implement this is not the
crucial point and there are many implementation tricks so you can do that
again here references
OK it's something different class called clustering it's also called bi clustering
there you have yet again a different goal so what you want to do is
so in the case so i assume you have you have
two variables actually this is like we can take the text example we had before
so you have documents in your words in the document
you make the bag of words approach and you generate
you generate huge matrix
which contains throws it has document so you have document one document two and so
and you have all the words you one
and in this matrix is the term document matrix you just count how often does
word one current document one
three times maybe and were toolkit occurs
not at all
and so on to make this huge matrix
now i think
i want to cluster documents
based on the statistics which words they have so what in the end you would
get something like if i have documents which are about politics i don't know the
name of of certain politicians will appear very often so you can cluster the like
looking at the world politicians will help to just documents
and of course you could also ask the other way around so which are the
words which are really
the important ones if i want to figure out
which text is about politics
so we can so you either contested documents based on rafts or you can cluster
words based on documents and also the dual viewpoint on
now what co clustering actually tries to do is
he tries to do both at the same time so the goal is in the
end you want to have
you want to find clusters such that
like the clusters of documents and clusters of works that if you want to identify
groups of documents and groups of words which can be used to describe the school
of documents
so ideally what you get is to re order
after clustering if you really seems to have something
so long as i mean that's really ideal situation something that they are can also
here we have all words
appearing in this class of documents
and again that's
the problem of solving this is called co clustering
and usually what people do is they their heuristic again so he start
clustering say the documents
and you obtain
so you just starting to obtain that
all those documents should be in the same cluster
now you reorder the matrix according to this clustering and then cluster the workspace so
you will then take those clusters is features in
the word domain the new cluster the words based on
those documents and you you go back and forth until convergence
that's just a different approach to clustering and then of course you could also imagine
that may be
this is not just block diagonal thing but it could be that there are certain
words that on this thing you might have actually subclusters so might look like this
we might even have something like this so it's
so you could have more structure than just block their structure
you mean in the in the in
well actually you what you do is you change the order of so you first
cluster the documents and then obtain i don't
doc one doc eleven talk seven top ten
the the first first and then
the for documents three
five seconds
now what you do is you change
this is the key by but one two three
but now the numbers right into your matrix
you can't often does but
one occur in any of the documents of one so you make an aggregation sort
of information
which is in those rows
so maybe you get fifteen are because you have very documents
you do the same here so the matrix so you are that i forgot to
tell the story you are not but the aggregated information
and then you cluster the words
and then you
you do it i mean the other way round you have no clusters of france
one test the second test and then
you again take the the rows of this matrix individually and clustering based
so you always use if you want to cluster more than just one variable
with respect to each other
and of course you can think of doing this and more
then mentions but like having three different objects but it gets very complicated
OK so
the main point is i mean they really really
thousands of clustering algorithms and there are lots of different paradigms how you
you could cite it right
so now there's not really
it seems so far there is nothing which is really a common so you try
just to do something which call clustering
and it and releasing for about
so of course there's been lots of people who try to define what clustering is
most of it i mean it's really hard to define in the and what i
want to do now is i want to show different different definitions
the conclusion in the end will be that that it doesn't have very much because
we just have
different have different definitions for different settings but i think it's still helpful to see
give an impression what you could do here
OK so OK so now let's let's take a slightly larger viewpoint so why is
clustering actually so difficult and i really spend a lot of time thinking about this
because it's i don't find it's obvious why this also difficult missing there are several
reasons and i just wanted to put a few of them here
so i mean of course is an unsupervised learning technique okay
simple so we have data points we don't have labels and we want to do
something with it and we don't have any supervision
but some of this can be all because there are lots of unsupervised techniques which
today i spent being reused in front of different works so again another example of
it being cat
a bit of work to understand the aim that of the data link
before you do that
for the most sophisticated approach is
we actually properties in particular entities are being used as the basis for doing so
a good example of this is how has been linked to geonames
so in this case the the as far as i understand process started with matching
taking an entry in the pedia
that's an attitude had latitude longitude entry so therefore can be assumed to some kind
of location
looking looking for string matching geonames and then if the
the coordinates of the last year to match a certain range of the margin of
error then these two entities were said to be the same thing
so that's the
the situation with this pre the most sophisticated way of doing that we need to
i mean the doing the more reliable more robust talk
so the never refused to how he's going to talk about taking these things
with human blood
she is
OK so
just learned about
automatic interlinking
now with
a couple of
months ago we started about thinking using human power basically the same idea
behind the games with a purpose or what you know from wikis are tagging
to actually
make humans to create a kind of link
humans are especially good to create a high-quality links
and there are actually certain use cases or certain resources type
especially with multimedia
where you know you want to have a kind of fine grained description you look
inside it talk about not removing their whatever
and these are we found a good candidates for many interlinked as we call it
is contributed including
i might not be able to democrat now and i don't have the time and
all that is the first concept demonstrator with with using flickr so you might have
seen flickr
possible to put a note on an image in a certain region so we kind
of people that using that node facility in flickr under your right for person in
the world
is that the like
so here
the user would actually go to flickr could note on on the image
picture thing this person you're i whatever
in our two what kind of crawl that data and you could create to tell
the photos were this and this person is depicted
it works with self profiling
six for any kind of of document which is out there
and it also users
over here is in the g
two kind of extend the interlinking
you know the the
the images can be tagged you can look up at tagging sunday june find out
bit more and basically at some RDF see also links that is part is automatically
does it
exposed to RDF and
sparql endpoint as well
so multimedia basically
it's a good candidate for that
and this was possible
was that our children and i could definitely
that tool
i could
basically create kind of
triple or technically that kind of triple so the containing
i i mean you knew you were i would be the subject of the triple
and the implicit semantic is this region actually
fourth depicts
a certain
person so i went to the URI for our youngest child here and then i
could agree that
as well
you could imagine the same works with video
the temporal dimension as well which gets more complicated
and still the the infrastructure if you look at youtube whatever is there
it will work as well
from the fragment identification type as well
so to sum it up it's quite new linking paradigm and we don't have that
much experience with it yet
there are several issues around that so for example you expose the process should
the user be aware of the actually creates some interlinking there or should you hydrogen
build UI around the user doesn't actually know the building
triple their their provenance trust and privacy issues can i really believe that somebody somebody
human that's that
then somehow take track who actually provided the link
and the basic question here is this was all human
driven things what the motivation for the end user why should he or she should
provide the kind of link but i think that for certain resource types especially multimedia
from there are more out there is
what you can think of one
this might be a very good way to get high quality
including says well i think
i i can come back to your should from earlier with the web what is
we're actually going to
compute a lower bound on the marginal likelihood
that's nice because it gives us some
definite information about the marginal likelihood if we want to model comparison
what we're going to do is we're going to
these lower bounds which of course
is not like comparing the true thing but it's the best we can do with this method
so how how do we compute this lower bound well
the log of the marginal likelihood is the log of this integral
the way we're going to write there is we can multiply
the term inside this integral
by some arbitrary distribution q
the hidden variables x and the parameters theta
we multiply by the distribution and we divide by the same distribution
so we
pointwise multiply this thing by one something whatever dividing by zero
so clearly this is an equality here
now for any arbitrary distribution q
it turns out that the log only average with respect to q
of this ratio
is greater than or equal to
we average with respect to q
of the log of the ratio
and this comes
this is called jensen's inequality
and it comes from the fact that the log function
is concave
the log function is concave
of these
is less than
sorry is is greater than
we average of the log for any averaging distribution
you can see this by
you know drawing
a picture like this
that's a log function
these are two points
this is
point in between
o lord
average point
and this is the average
the log
averaging not equally averaging with respect any distribution
this of course holds for any
concave function we use it for the log and that's called jensen's inequality
so here we have
a lower bound general lower bound on the marginal likelihood and now the game is going to be
this holds for any distribution q
let's find the distribution q
within some family
that's has the tightest lower bound
the tightest lower bound comes from maximizing
as a function of q
so in particular
you can do various things you could say
q is gonna be
this accuser galaxy and i'm gonna find the best galcians fit
i to
maximize this lower bound
well i'm gonna talk about is assumed that q factors in a particular way
assume the q factors
as a distribution over the hidden variables and a distribution over the parameters
and then optimize this thing here with respect to these two distributions
so we write this down as ef
so functional these two distributions q v x and q theta
why is fixed
we optimize over q x and q data
algorithmically what we can do that optimizes we can alternate between optimizing q x holding qx theta fixed
and then optimizing incubator data holding qx x fixed
back and forth
okay i could i could write these equations
with the fact that expression from the beginning
it's true
it's a choice in this sense there
this holds for any q
this is the most general expression of the variational framework
i'm saying in very commonly used choice
is a factorized q
but other choices might be a galaxy enjoyed q
are there could be other choices
as well like partially factorized q
the rest of these things are choices from here on
let me focusing on the choice
other factorized q
and then i get this expression here
and then
variational bayesian algorithm for the factorized case
corresponds to
yeah like algorithm we can actually formalize their relationship to yemen a second
and ian like algorithm where in the e step i compute a distribution over the hidden variables
we have
all go home was the
all that
the first artist to come shortly
come on this side studio
during your
maybe you to be nice to
what think have to
i think it out completely
if you want to
so i can demonstrate that the that's all you right
which is in
it was
so you should not
you also we show this don't
that's it
the only about those are the only way to resolve this
if you were all that
i was talking to one another
if i can if i can put
just one for them and one first come on when i wasn't going to use
the word fundamental
then it looks very boring
and i'm going to do that first by making you
listen to a year
twenty four michael's if we can get this up here
the first which
so it's important that you quite because all the sound you make you see
let's first it's boring
four hundred forty hertz was nothing else
no overtones only for some family
all the images of four forty five
to fifty six using
far apart or because
and new rule
do you
what i would like
whole the first
he's trying to do something very close to four forty
four forty
in this you will be different you five
and the story for
forty instruction
here's might try to make it for forty
you don't have to be exactly
o just
if you're like
i'm trying to identify something that's on the order of one part in ten to
the ninth century to less than one part in ten to the ninth of the
whole human genome carrying out purification is like that
really kind of
hard to imagine
but the way it was done was by the invention of cloning
let me briefly over here the idea of cloning and then will dive into the
the idea of cloning
the latest to purify individual molecules would just be to take the molecules and just
delete them so that there was only one
of each molecule
that's very stories and the problem is is not very much
so you need a way to take a single copy of the molecule
and then
make many copies of it
so purification is not hard just deluded down to work with single molecules but then
need to copy it back again and again and again and no biochemical technique involves
for fracturing cell and replicating some inside the copying siemens and copy since can copy
that was the basis so here's the the way it goes the basic over will
look at is taken DNA and cut
your DNA of interest maybe the human genome
into pieces
to find sites
paste your DNA
which is
more technically like it
the word we use case your DNA
to some other DNA
called a vector
so cut DNA case to DNA
each piece of of your say human DNA gets stuck to some piece of effect
insert this
in two
can replicated
in bacteria
so i'm going to actually take my piece of human DNA and not just like
it to any piece of DNA
i'm going to take my human DNA
and i'm going to like it a vector
it has all of the
the machinery all of the ability to to cut to be copied in the bacteria
that's what i'm going to do is i'm going to transform my DNA
in two
a host cell
host bacterial cell transform
means introduce
when we talk about transforming DNA when not talking about changing it's the word that's
used for taking my
DNA stuck into a vector introducing it into bacterial cells ideally each bacterial cell
would carry ones such a DNA molecule
and then what i want to do
is i want to plate
my cells
and select
the carry human DNA
my DNA DNA effort on so i put them on the poetry play
and i want only the
that happened to have picked up
an individual piece of human DNA to grow
that's the that's the trick is very simple trick take total human DNA cut up
into pieces glue it to a vector
that's able to copy it's able to be replicated back to report the vectors into
bacterial cells every bacterial cell picks up no more than one vector
he played out and you simply arranged so that the only cells that grow
are those picked up the piece of human DNA and every one of these colonies
is the descendant of a single
bacterial cell the picked up a single human molecule but is obligingly copy that molecule
for you again and again and again and again
and as you have what we refer to this whole collection here is called a
library of clones
this is called the common library because every piece of the human genome is somewhere
in here
you know this one here
probably is active
and maybe this one here
maybe it's college in eleven that one there might be others beta goal
OK actually when you look at the plate there's no way to tell but in
principle they all there so there will be this question how do we look at
the library and pull out what the right one is but somewhere in there should
be a bacterial colony that is pure beta globin
gene the DNA for better tomorrow the next lecture will be about how you actually
find the today let's just build this library so our goal is to be able
to build the library like this so
we have to cut DNA pace DNA vectors senator so that's what are subject will
think my information and fact extraction
and then look at machine vision
topic which we will continue tomorrow
well you have to do is really we have become symbolic techniques to craft items
to extract the information
and dr of court you have seen in the message understanding conference that it really
of course you
it to work that you have stick to the mean
very restricted subject area
when you deal somehow with have language
so when you can restricted all the time that expression
twenty years
can be
comment what
we be
many of the things natural language
very well you have a large variety of expression
i tell you this content only
think of a very similar
so we have many
to many
two to implement
and also the fact that you find might be very
and they might need other knowledge
contextual knowledge
many information to really understand what the graph the
and last but not least the fact that
i showed you have to be
this more of a large text
at first the french community
they are quite
i think
this languages
the real the language being used
the used change a lot
so you need somehow to adapt continued
the fact that you have
actually manually if you
you need all kinds of
and i told
we meanwhile want to nineteen ninety six onwards
love came up with the idea that maybe we should learn better
i mean she and she lived a
she developed a very simple machine learning
which would been know
della retreated that
actually will
based on very simple to these matters
it's almost as good as in terms of form
when you have
so she
kind of course
and what we
a lot of communication
all kinds of machine learning techniques
starting with induction of decision and the same thing
many have been
in this
more to the well to the sea more support vector machines
maximum entropy models hidden markov model
we also have unsupervised learning
i told you yesterday
the would like recognise the topics of the documents of text
the the
when you go to find information extraction
they are sometimes quite different but someone who knows what more provide that
like probabilistic topic models that could be useful
and to the
we'll get the key to provide
we use that
from and manually and i t and u
lot of
thank you
so what we looking at the
first of all i will
what kind of features we use
how do we select features
we also to support vector machine and kernel
thirty two probabilistic model
i think may be
and also the maximum entropy
tomorrow we will could people who
the markov models conditional random field
and then also the
and so i probabilistic topic models
where you actually have to take into account also the structure of your
it could be also the
four of no
and from time to time i
the figure
well it
just another
it's not to the
that's the that's all the time
very much detail
it would not be
we will not have time to do just one lecture
i want to
to focus the attention of some aspects of the model
the dog
when you the natural language
text to extract search
the other thing that we use we will speak about which
a feature vector
the object that you want to classify the piece of information
that you want to track
or to identify in the text
it represented as
effects of which he later that you can see some of the structure of the
object represents
we use
in the key is to keep class
that you want to find
remember we do some kind of classification pattern recognition so why is the class label
that you want to assign to object represents the
individuals you find the between june twenty first
discriminative classification
general classifier
you can learn a model of the joint probability px y
and make
in the county because it's more convenient
the conditional probability can actually fly
given the object x x
very often we use well
to make computations facts about
you would think is an example of me the way to use these
on the other hand
in natural language processing
right because of signal processing variations of the above that of the different com
so when you do face recognition assuming is of the late elimination condition and you
know frontal and so on
it's one thing it's only when you want to bring in illumination and variation invariance
and no robustness to pose and so on it becomes a very different problem right
so well the way they approach the elimination thing is that them to the training
set well if you are in the SVM more for example
we all know from
pattern recognition classes to the extent the training set looks like the testing set
you know we're in good shape but in face recognition what happens is you often
how only one galaxy per person if you look at the
FRGC the face recognition grand challenge
test and so forth there's only one gallery image per person so there's not a
whole lot to learn from that so if you have here in one hundred database
hundred person database you only have one hundred images to speak that that's how the
protocol is construct constructed right so if you
i don't have all these images then it's going be a problem
so that's the
think and we want to work on either somebody other what it is before but
we like this idea of sparsity
and if you look at i signatures there are quite a reasonably better controlled illumination
conditions than face face you acquired many meters and sometimes even tens of metres
the advantage is that you can't be wheel farther than one or two meters and
you can have been a good elimination and also i signatures to answer for the
usual out of plane rotation and so forth that face
suffers from right so
iris recognition problem can be view more as a signal classification problem then a face
recognition problem that's all i'm trying to see if it's being the object it produces
many many variations corresponding to pose and illumination that is you don't see that many
variations dies but i still creates problems due to occlusion and so on you know
i it's closing and things like that so we want to do
of course is blurred specular reflections segmentation which led to segment
you know i this image and so forth so we wanted to see if we
can get more out of this spark city methods that were developed berkeley university of
illinois for the idea signature and so we pretty much just reproduced the algorithm for
iris recognition and of course we didn't want to pick the for light is a
signature you know we did some modifications so called the sector processing and so on
we just divide the city into many sectors and have
you know we treat them independently and then take a joint work so you take
in classes and images per class so you believe these things and you then assume
that the training and testing training image can be written as a linear combination of
there is a and then you can not go through the same procedure and look
for a recovery the coefficients alpha corresponding to the i class using the basis pursuit
and a side benefit of this approach is that mean is also mentioned in the
family paper
his you have something known as a quality measure
it's OK this will come out of algorithm them and you can use this as
a measure to to reject quality it's images or already face images also hope so
basically you can
you know inability go through the procedure and the performance is pretty good
we have all this various image quality would segmentation and so forth and
the idea is you have to be submitted different world if you are not at
least ninety percent even the conference paper is not possible in phase eighty five percent
of the respective in ideas ninety five it's respective so you've got to do better
than that why because it is usually acquired in very good illumination conditions the signal
quality is very good and i was right compared to what you can get face
OK so you know this is going to be and biometrics confidence in two thousand
nine now