so in other words we have to do some kind of collaboration
and so on
this means that that the subject has to assume certain brain states
and then
we use that
to do statistical inference
from what we have measured
three different trials
for example
try to infer in in for what is the left in this and the rightness
of some certain brain activity
and so this is the
offline training part
and just
two to clarify so
if you would come to the lab
somebody put put the cap on your head
that would take some time
maybe thirty minutes
we're not as good as the people in all the new that they can do
this in ten minutes or fifteen minutes i was quite amazed for the technician and
then you would
do the following
so you
with the video says is that you should relax
and now
you will see later on the screen and what you see the letter
you should imagine the respective hand
relax left again
and right
and so this could go on for about ten twenty minutes
some of us
consider this extremely boring
for example i do and i sleep after five minutes so for this reason we
always had to find algorithms that can deal with a few data points
so if you have twenty minutes of data then we have about a hundred trials
on each side and you can actually also see you actually have experienced how difficult
it is to be relaxed
and focused at the same time
because you really have to keep the timing
you have
don your imagination of left and right with recorded some brain signals and then the
idea is to get some
some classifiers
to infer what your brain has been up to
what your brain has been up to so this it's it's about
individual differences
and so
after we've done that that's the upper part
we measure
we have some labelled trials we two featureextraction machine learning
then we can go into the
feedback session and we just take a window
and classifier where this is left to right or or maybe nothing either
so it's an asynchronous BCI
and this is where
benjamin will take over
to torture with tall tree with some mass
o my intention was not to fortune with my and it's it's meant to be
a very
practical course i'm not
introduce some fancy can reasons or talk about and find
this but would be very
practical entropy
and between them and the church
there was room full freedom to grow up
freedom was the kind of an accident it came about because the usual ways of
doing things were not possible
into some of that space
towns and cities reappeared
and with new supports for freedom
taking advantage of the rivalries i mentioned they obtained charters from the local powers establishing
the rights
to conduct their own affairs and to govern themselves in italy
some of these cities were able to gain control of the surrounding country
and the become city-states
resembling those of the ancient greek
autonomy was
assisted by the continuing struggles between popes and emperors between church and state again a
thoroughly unique western experience
in the states
the modern world began to take form
although the people are mainly christians
their life and outlook became increasingly secular
and not only in italy but in other cities north of the alps
a rose a worldview
that celebrated the greatness and dignity of mankind which was a very sharp turning away
from the medieval western tradition that put
god and life in the hereafter at the centre of everything
this new vision is revealed with flamboyant confidence
p co
delamere around a lot of florentine
i thinker
who said wrote the following
god told me that
meaning god have made the neither heaven nor
neither moral nor in more
so that with the freedom of choice
and with on
as though the maker and molde of myself
dummies fashion by itself in whatever shape that shelter for
supreme generosity of god the father
all highest and the most grateful city of man
to him
it is granted to have whatever he chooses
to be
what ever he will
now this is a remarkable leap
even beyond the humanism of the greeks
something brand new in the world
according to this view man is not merely the measure of all things as the
greek sophist protagonist
radically proclaimed in the fifth century
he is in fact says got more
then more
he is unlimited by nature
is is entirely free
to shape themselves
and to acquire
whatever he wants
please observe two that it is not his reason that will determine the human actions
but his will
a lot
of the moderating control
of reasons
another florentine machiavelli
moved further in the same direction
for him and i quote
fortune is a woman
and it is necessary to hold it down
and beta
and fight with
the notion that the greeks would have regarded as dangerously arrogant
and certain to produce disaster would have seen this as an example of the words
they use and we'll talk about a lot in this course the address
this kind of violence paragons which comes upon meant when they see themselves as more
human and behave as though
they were divided
francis bacon
influenced by machiavelli
early human beings to employ their reasons
to force nature to give up its secrets
to treat nature like a woman
to master nature in order to improve man's material well-being
he assumed that such a course would lead to progress and the general improvement of
the human condition
and it was that sort of thinking
that lay at the heart of the scientific revolution
and remains the face on which modern science and technology progress
a couple of other english political philosophers hobbes and locke
apply a similar novelty and modernity to the sphere of politics
basing their understanding
on the common passions of man
for a comfortable cell preservation
and discovering something the greeks had never thought of something they call
natural rights
that belong to a man
either as part of nature
or is the gift of benevolent and reasonable got
man was seen as a solitary creature
not inherently a part of society
that's totally on greek
and the basic rights which seem to be
huge contributions to our field especially to planning and reinforcement learning
it is also done incredibly well in stage where he regularly wins awards
so we were for good reason for certain but it is
it is also
things that
i have also led to several reports critical legislative is
next crosswords
hence the meetings of the national
cross borders
it's more about
and it's a great pleasure
thanks very much
just as it just as a quick
check but c so people who are here how many of you already know reinforcement
learning and are working in the field
we have
i see and why am i giving you to talk i like just a chance
first of all you know i had together so i those who are left how
many are here because there's really does nothing else to do incorporate now
gets three hands
six miles and then the rest how many people here actually interested in learning about
the background here and but are already aware of it in many ways
i could swear that the some of the same hands are going up but right
but that's okay i'm going to do my best ipod for people who are already
doing this stuff and i apologize in advance i'm lately teaching why they have been
introduction introductory computer science for people who are going into computer science so i think
that kind of adopted a little bit of
low-level kind of presentation style i apologize in advance if you're an expert already and
you'll hear that
but that's what i'm going to do and
beyond that would also want to tell you that benefit your work in this area
and inside you i'm sorry but asking a loaded question at the end we say
you know how does this relate to the work of energy and i'll talk about
how cool uris
excellent right so i'll be talking to model based reinforcement learning
basic the basic flow here is to talk a little bit of background lies about
markov decision processes and reinforcement learning general because
model based reinforcement learning is a special kind of reinforcement learning so it so we
need to make sure that we're on the same page about what reinforcement learning is
the bulk of what i'm going to talk about is as the problem of efficient
exploration how is it that we can create algorithms are going to explore the environments
and be able to perform nearly optimal
but with bounds on how much experience it takes to do that
so that's an area that's that i've been focused on quite a bit of my
own research with my students my lab and so that the most what to talk
about later become very intrigued by bayesian reinforcement learning and its connection to efficient exploration
and i don't tell you about that and then the bottleneck here is learning algorithms
that are very good at acquiring their own models but then they actually have to
plan with them and so there's a bottleneck there and i'll talk a little bit
about what some of the current approaches are for
for planning with these learned models and also fascinated by
the connection to human cognition so i'll just mention a little bit about that
i would say more except i don't know that much more but i'm fascinated by
it so if you have information about i'd be happy to hear more about it
another some workshops going on that
whistler at the end of maps that they get not particularly remarkable is reinforcement learning
but various issues about how people learn and what that tells us about machine learning
and vice versa
so i definitely encourage interested people to get involved in that are so i forgot
to set this up but i think
i think we can start off with the game
people already know this game in which case that would be kind of unfair it's
not that many about the many
all right here you
this is a little video game
actually on saturday student and i went to
the quaker bridge mall in new jersey we we have laws in new jersey and
and people actually do this and we recorded their the results and you're going to
do much much better than the people in the model did and the reason i
say that is because i've given this in talks many times and had a good
guess as to how it was going to go on the mall it didn't go
as well as i was hoping would go so so here's the game this is
what you see this is your input state information and your goal is to win
the game and its that you get to make a series of decisions each step
you get to choose up down left right
a or b
if you've seen this to please don't say anything because you ruin it for the
rest of us were trying to have fun so OK so that you tell me
what you want to do up down left right a or b
alright i heard a belonging to do the opposite was louder
you may think for a moment and you have to tell me the next thing
to do because the you have one yet
i had read again i hit rate again
up and right up to them both
up right
confidence a
left a week
was too many things at once
no i did i did
i would be
he down
that's the time when you make noise that was very good
the people in the mall did make noise i was i was very disappointed
left left
this fine
i'm getting the probability distribution of actions back which is very nice
so wait i think i can be but it didn't seem to be did you
one congratulations on so
i to shopping in the mall on saturday
i need to actually stop the experiment gone and i ran upstairs to the video
game store and ask the people in the video games to come down and help
us to boehringer for our experiment so people what what non people were doing they
bumble around a little bit then eventually figured out that they were controlling the orange
square some of them
actually managed to go and visit the little circle thing and maybe even picked up
baby and maybe even walked around with it but they never quite figured out what
was supposed to go it supposed to go
right you read
of the form
a x b prime the exclamation marks of this is that
object x has value v
for attribute a
and again i have an exclamation mark because it could be no node has exactly
one value for each attribute OK now what i do is
for each line in the CPT
the bayesian network has a conditional probability table for the chosen function of its parents
and going to define a clause or a conjunction for each line
and the way to that class
it's going to correspond to the to the probability critical it's going to be the
log odds of the probability the table
OK so very straightforward translation from the vision network
two markov logic networks and there is no loss of representational efficiency
now of course in practice people almost never use vision networks with full cpts is
because those get too large
just like potential function get too large
these things like context specific independence
context specific independencies where you're conditional model for child as a function of its parents
is not table but is decision tree
this is potentially much more compact
so how would represent alchemy
very simple
what we have is one clause for each path in the decision tree
remember each by the decision tree corresponds to a rule that rule becomes the rule
in the AML and the with the weight of rule is log odds of the
probability of the other class or the child attribute given the state of the variables
along the path
and i think that people often use you know is logistic regression so your child's
logistic regression and the parents were decided do that
and then another thing that's popular that will reveal it two is noisy or
we implement noisy or an MLN is as deterministic or is of logical function plus
a bunch of pairwise causes that represent the filippo
so pretty much all the all the major ways in which people build new models
for bayesian networks can be easily represented in markov logic
but no of course the payoff is that
now you can do more than just the vision network now you can start to
talk about dependencies between objects and you can do rich kinds of modelling than than
than the traditional business in particular we can see
you can do the various kinds of relational models that we saw before knocking so
for example
how do you do knowledge based model construction of the basic thing that you have
to do is to allow only horn clauses
in case only have one hundred so if markov logic with unknown causes you essentially
get knowledge based model construction
this is going to it basically does the same thing as bayes nets except that
in bayes nets
you only have relations of one particular for binary relations with the with object always
the first arguement here you can not have arbitrary relations another different combination functions that
people using KBMC we deciding to let you know logistic regression noisy or or you
could find some other function externally and link it
what about stochastic logic programs
well stochastic logic programs are generalizations of PCFG is and where it is so hard
to pcfgs so again we're going to allow only horn clauses
the weight of clause now is going to be the log of the probability that
the course heading the SLP
and i need to have the same form as that i have been pcfgs which
is to say if they had holes in exactly one body holds no more no
and this implements and SLP
here and how to implement them
well the basic construction appearance may to to first order logic is that you will
only binary relations
so we need to make the same restriction on markov logic
you will only binary relations and then what you get has a similar expressivity to
probabilistic relational models
now again what you get here is similar to bayes nets except
that be bayes nets the predicates are also all binary except that now the first
arguement can vary
i can be talking about multiple objects at the same time as opposed to always
only the properties of the same object
what about relational markov networks
well remember relational markov networks specify the model of the conjunctive SQL queries
well you can equally well expressed them in datalog
and that log is a special case of first order logic right so once we
want to converted the SQL to datalog that's in the long query can just be
in the
the corresponding formal in the MLS
so that's the structure part then what happens is that there are admins remember specify
the full distribution the the full potential function
breach quickly create in this way and we do this now is by having one
clause in the MLN for each state of the clique
and again the weight of that clause is going to correspond to the to the
value of the potential function for that which
OK now this could be a bit cumbersome light if you have you know pretty
things which most cases plus
and then afterwards we find out the truth
and now we know it can be f two for example we cross out all
the inconsistency functions
and we continue to the next example
it is
we can now look at the computer functions that are still alive when crossed to
the majority of their predictions
it's plus
and we find out the truth
minus we can cross that none of the function and so on this repeat
any questions about
this intuitive al
so what can you say about this is very easy to analyse this of look
every time this algorithm majority of makes a mistake
we know that we've crossed out half of the functions in our family
right because because we predicted according majority if we made a mistake if the majority
made a mistake that means crossing out the majority of functions
it can be too many left so we're crossing out the majority every time
then we can only make
log base two of the number of
functions before mistakes before we've crossed that everyone and we can cross that everyone we're
assuming that there someone who doesn't make any mistakes
so we already have this nice
guarantee that the area of
this majority function on the data is not more than
only a log in the size of the
dataset divided by n
how many people here are familiar with VC dimension and things like that
great so
some of these things might start looking familiar to you hopefully as we go along
these bounds you get here and all the corresponding once you've seen from
VC dimension
so it as we said the online learning setting is is is
at least as hard as the batch setting so that means that in batch setting
we can also get to guarantee
like this OK
so what do we do in the batch setting
so suppose there are some
again the batch setting let's do the same
the same warm-up setting where there is some perfect function if there is some perfect
so we now get a lot of data advance we get and is the data
the nice thing would be to select a consistent function
and here's an example where
that will work OK
in this example
i want to show that basically what i want to show you is that that
in in the back setting you're not going to do i mean we know you
can do as well as he did in the online setting we can actually do
much better so the bat setting that take some consistent
function here
it might be that there was that one perfect function and everyone else wasn't so
great maybe everyone else had this
ar here which is kind of what we're trying to
to guarantee
so if everyone else had that error rate
if you work it out
but there may actually be one of those bad functions that
it didn't make any mistakes in the dataset
so what's the chance that someone who has an error rate
so this should be
on the distribution
but if it has ar g if it has this error rate in this mission
magenta didn't make any
mistakes is exactly this thing here
the image is right now one
inequality et cetera really big
OK so one
this is something that'll come up a couple times
so if you
take one minus over into the and you get about
e to the minus x that something is probably seen from
your basic calculus class
so this
of sorry finite set of functions
and how we can do that so we have to somehow kind of replace you
know groups of functions by one representative function
and then
you know that representative will hopefully take care of the whole group
and the way we try to do that is by
actually getting down to a finite sample of a finite set of examples
and and then by classification you can only have a finite set of things happening
on the sample
because you you know you can only do plus minus ones on these examples
but the problem is that we always have this test point which we don't know
what it is so the first thing we do is replace
the test point by ghost sample
and then we can sort of
argue just in terms of
two samples drawn from that distribution
and then it's a finite set
so this is known as the double sample trick
and it it effectively gets you from dealing with an unknown test example to just
dealing with two
random samples one is your training set one is the ghost sample
so it's it's a
useful trick that can be applied again i'm trying to sort of you know give
you little sort of units of
thinking that you could use in different contexts
so this is how the double sample trick works
what you're interested in doing is again you know think in terms of bounding the
probability of being misled things going wrong whatever so we were interested in the probability
that there exists a function
but again i just taking the zero training error for simplicity
has zero training error
true error
bigger than long
and what we want to do is to replace that probability by the probability that
we have two samples x and y gain both generated i i d and there
is an edge in function class that looks good on the first half bad on
the second half
and notice that there are
the probability is twice here and there next on two here
so we sort of replace the test error by a finite sample
there are basically three
events concerned one is that the
training error zero
the other is that it has high
generalisation error and the third is that has a high
error on the
on the ghost sample
and the point about this is that if it has tried to high generalisation error
then with high probability it's going to have
a high
error on the ghost sample because we you the ghost sample is generated
so there's no reason for it to
mislead us
you know we're we're trying to
use the
training sample to do all sorts of
nasty stuff which makes it likely that we're gonna be misled by the training example
because with training our algorithms on the ghost sample is is independent
so the
this is basically encapsulated in this statement here so probability that this is the
the ghost sample having high error given that there is zero training error and the
generalisation error is paul
it is actually this
ghost sample doesn't care about the training sample as separate samples can just throw away
so it's just the probability that the
there is high
are on the on the ghost sample given that there is a higher and truer
and that's very clearly
just the binomial tail bound it's very easy to show that that's going to be
big than point five
for reasonable
sizes of training
i mean very in very small sizes
so this this now can be put together with the if we just do this
sequence here
probability over the double sample of
zero training error
and higher is bigger than
sorry and and high ghost sample error
is greater than or equal to just including in an extra condition that actually has
high generalisation error
and then we can just separate this into this probability and the conditional probability that
the conditional probability which is bounded by
and so
we can turn this around this is the half
and we get this quantity which is the thing we're interested in here
but how big is a finite set so the question is how many functions can
you get
when you look at just the finite set of examples e got function class h
which could
we know will have infinitely many functions potentially
we're going to restrict ourselves to looking at its performance on a finite set of
size and more in fact will be interested into and because of the double sample
and we're interested in how many functions do we actually get because those are are
equivalence classes we only have to think about those
well we're doing our analysis
and that's what we'll do the union bound over those
so we will actually have so i mean it could be as high as two
the end because there are to do the impossible functions classification functions on n points
and so the log of this number is less than or equal to n
but obviously we want to have much much smaller than that for the
the analysis to work
so if we just look at what happens if we plot this with a set
of linear functions in a twenty dimensional space
this is the ratio of BH of them to to to the end
so i to
about twenty one
or looks a bit higher but anyway up to
something close to
mention here
we get this ratio being equal to one
but then about
you know
twice the dimension
the things suddenly zooms down and the fraction rapidly gets very close to zero
and this is the kind of regime where learning kicks in where we can
get the number you know because we're going to be a union bound over this
ph and we want this number to be much much smaller
then the size of the training set in order to get the ratio to be
but this is this is looking like good news it looks like the number does
fall off
in the way that we would like
so the actual number of functions equivalence classes we need to consider
is small
and this is what about nature and increase dimension measure
OK so that each other
the dimension is the size for which we can get
find some examples and we can do every possible classification now the words it's the
point here
where this
curves leaves the
the value one and start the down below one
VC dimension is defined for general function classes not just the linear function classes
for linear function classes it just turns out that the VC dimension is the linear
dimension plus one
so what we're but we we can apply this idea of more generally so it's
just saying the largest sample size for which we can find some inputs
the pressure
at that location y
and that must be constant
and this now
new york
it is a
of energy
and as you i will show you it has a very remarkable
first i will show you an example
well by
i keep y constant
so i the true which changes diameter
the two is not changing
level why
as i do there
so i come in here
cross sectional area a one
why didn't it
cross sectional area
a two
why is the same for both
i have here
inside pressure one
i have pressure p two
this is the density of the fluid
there is zero velocity v two
and as your velocity v one
clearly the one is very large than the two
because a one
i'm one
must be a two
nine feet because the fluid is incompressible
the same amount of matter that flow through here in one second
must flow through here in one second
these have to be the same since a one is much smaller than a two
its velocity is much larger
then v two
i'm going to apply the new equation
for the first time tells me that one half
the ones created
i can forget the second term because i get the same term you is to
get there because they measure pressure here and i measure the pressure that have the
same level of y
so i can ignore the second term
plus b one
must be one half role
the two squared
must be two
that's what the new is equation tells me
now if one
is larger
then v two
the only way to this can be corrected
is that the one
must be less than two
he was a big deal well it's a big deal
because i would have guessed exactly the other way around and so would you
because here is where the highest velocities
and or instincts would say oh it's the velocity as high as a lot of
pressure it's exactly the other way around here is a low pressure and he has
a high pressure
which is one quite bizarre consequence
you must all have
encountered in your life what we call the size
we're using evil still used today
you have here
a bucket in general is used was water lakes
could be any liquid
and i sticking you're too
small diameter is substantially smaller than this area here
and there will be a warning you're up to this level
his level p two
y two
by one
increasing value of y
he high differences h
two is one atmosphere one there's atmosphere
here is it's open
then p one is also one atmosphere
so does every year
and there's liquid in you
i think is open and in my mouth
and i struck the water in sort of this fault with this war was
strange as it may be
it's like making the whole
this tank
if i take my finger off here
the what will start to run out and i will show you that
and you have your velocity
if you want
wonderful stream down into this year
and the velocity here is approximately zero
because this area is so much larger
and this cross sectional area
the two good approximation
this what is going down extremely slowly
let's call this by difference
i applied is
now we have a situation where the wise different
but the pressure is the same because right here
at this point of the liquid i have one atmosphere which is barometric pressure
and since is open to to the outside world p one is also one atmosphere
now i was my peter
there i lost my whiter
now i lose my peter
so now i have that one half role
the is role of the liquid
we want to create
rowe g
times y one
must be one rho
v two square but
we agree that was zero so i don't have that term
so i only have
she y two
i lose my cheese
i don't know much is
one of rose's group not this one
and so
i lose my role
this is one half
and my role
so you get one half
he wants clear
because g
times y two miners y one which is a to
so what you find
that this speed which which is what is running out here
if you want
is the square root
one of the gh
you've seen before
if you take a pebble
you really the pebble from this level you let it fall
it will reach this point here is level
this is the square root of two g h we've seen many times
so what is happening here
since the pressure terms and the same here and there
now it is only a conversion
gravitational potential energy which is higher here than there
it is now
converted to
kinetic energy
this is siphon would only work
if d is less than ten metres
because of the barometric pressure you can never suck up this water
no one can
a vacuum pump can here to level that is higher than ten metres
when i did the experiment there was no
cranberry juice i was able to get it up to five meters then leaders would
be the theoretical maximum
so this has to be less than ten metres
you go up
if i would have made a hole in this thank you
just like this
don't do exactly this level
and i would ask you to calculate with what what is running out
so this actually this he actually sees coming out as a result just kind a
real factor
but either i y is gone
what's the the i wireless
the key now
this is by the most fantastic form
in the i y is the same as the cosine why was it times the
why is a real number
so now i see the real part of this is that the the x cost
and the imaginary part the the one so there's pair
quite an interesting pair that we could add to our list either x cos y
and the exciting one
the that
that x is in the exponent
up there
and times cos why well
right i mean we can just better to check maybe what's the second or the
second x derivative of this thing
i i just want to see that this really is the winner
this if i take the second x derivative this
we're thinking
it doesn't change right
if i take the second wider of what happens
because negative because cosine becomes minus sign becomes minus cosine so so
and sure enough
two pieces
cancel each other
and it's also process equation
these are called
this is called if i use the word this is called an analytic function
who knows why
analytic function if it's if it's
very smooth has derivative and so forth
DNA the functions that we would sort first think
and these pieces of these pieces are called harmonic functions so so that says you
this is the harmonic function that's i mean plus equation is so important that it's
given the special name not
not a matter of great importance
now i still in
really say
why does this work
so we should be able somehow to see
so in some way
it works OK so the cost y and x i might have over there
as of here
OK so why does it work
let's see
i mean i think that if i take this function of experts i y it
will work too
and the last great i think that this the function of x experts i y
here here's the statement and the function of x one xi y will solve all
possible ways
now if i take the real part and imaginary part of still find but why
can you supply that internal classes equation
well let's see we don't know what the function is so how do we do
what happens if i take the derivative of a function of x i y remember
i just get the outskirts of the derivative will be f prime
the extra
but what's the y derivative of the extra
because the extra
what's the wider
of this thing
i'm not yet on the second derivatives distance
first of
remember how to take the derivative
the function of another function
the chain rule is the thing
so the derivative of this
the aspect of the y derivative about this memory you you take the derivative of
and then have to take the derivative of what's inside the argument
which is the y derivative of that is
where the extra but it was if we really use the chain rule was the
derivative of the function times the derivative of what's inside the extra what's inside was
just one OK
so that's the extra
now let me do the x x through
Due to adaptation is that we read and that both demarcate according to that of
course of readership and also was a target distribution
look it's so that the chorus and so so you knew you could you propose
according to exist at the state gave you will accept or reject the new will
dates and estimate dollars a year cause violence of the target distribution which we view
with all sorts of compartments of the increment distribution and the new we know that
this is a global scale of low value of your goal of winning a kind
of just 2 to convince you that it's the walls y to do is that
this is so that I haven't been dimension did call 12 the target distribution is
a normal distribution this governed but got around to conditions members 100 which is not
that that that is not extreme and here pupils according to the increment distribution which
the along all covert project which is the identity and marries the optimal skating and
I assure you just out of the clouds so it should be
1000 website with those instrumentation taken from Ireland and projected on the largest of the
the 2 first-round disagree news is that it's it's the change
it is extremely bad weather makes
the big thing is extremely bad and you just visits you are as a cloud
is extremely solid which is also
look at the trajectory of each competencies although so also the correlation coefficients also mixing
In those that
the judge orders them where are you are you proposing now according to sources with
the 2nd provided the target distribution and consider the cloud much good correlation is much
better than the club also spread over isn't the ellipsis industries which adopted
so perhaps I assured
Brokers Armenia treating improvements to be that can be done here
Of course I just want to invest 5 minutes it we just want to describe
that another type of allegories and where this time I I use of media metropolis
things but instead of proposing according to a random walk and propose according to independent
proposals so this time of year when what you do is that you pupils from
the division Q which is selected independently from the busses of you propose according to
distribution and you accept
this time with this ratio
so what you can do what you feel that this is rather easy to prove
is that the detainees do it again body if and only if
the target distribution in the will distributions of poisonous
relations and the rate of convergence is controlled by the consent and so the idea
is that in this type of algorithm what you need to it to obtain the
fastest rate of convergence of new shows that the 2 spoke polls according to distribution
which is which is which resembled target distribution executives said thing that you do for
example exit projected extremely close zone with assisting reasonable proposal is extremely close to accept
reject mechanism in the only differs somewhat way is accepted it you can is is
that you don't look too little of the bounding constants
Britain's ratios a proposal institutions
so I what don't want to do that uses a technique which is rather than
the standard in an important something judge us so you you you start with a
biology from your problem distribution we still constraints of 2 constraints are are you you
should you choose family which is easy to sample from the course in the the
the single constraint is that you want to family which is flexible enough in order
to capture most of the details of the target distribution Indiana you want a lot
of time in which a kind of universal approximation process and the what you do
that as I said before ah
what you can prove is that to the speed of convergence is maximized when she
Wiesel resemble to crying and whether we win there's the resemblance
the closeness of off the target distribution by impure future musical divergence and you kind
of did them is a which is so called lying chemicals and which is point
disease which is so determined in this paper Poland also prepared by ruled on that
topic him Mr. Christopher you which appeared this year on and also applied to the
probability were all this of course is described and this just to show you a
nice picture so that we we want to see that promises distribution so yeah it's
a distribution which is in dimension through where we chose a very complex is Quebec
and this is this is this is a distribution constructed from Britain functioning in
which is used in from money optimization which is that India to function because it's
a it's a kind of at the end of the story of a reasonable fee
to and museumgoers and called extremely fast
so I guess I would just as keeps so what as a result is completely
center with the results of would be approved as the paper that appeared
I think it's interesting that it appeared in Kosovo
perhaps it last year but gravel in generated by and member so we would let
proved is that under certain assumptions I didn't describe this type of adaptive algorithms that
converges so you get established the wallflower numbers
under conditions which doesn't implies a convergence of parameters for decades so that condition of
costs for the type of with described we to which is important that every couple
and GMC with Mr. passing approximation with decreasing stateside
so you have conditions on the gamut gave that to be so 1st can't will
not number and then can prove also said John Maturin sort of thing week environs
principle to be more precise because in the like to get to his senses that
the virus appearing in this
is violence which is which would have been obtained using optimal chores of the parliament
and stop a centerpiece of his adaptation calls so that its conditions for an end
to the conclusion work at of Ishtar 3rd existed brief presentation of his 2 2
2 2 Susan various so seriously
since the of
there is a kind of a new type of intimacy and sentiment of commodities Minnesota
would be sufficient to students in that incident statistics in computing
as in November
uh and the IDB idols is methods is to try to make a poison which
it says June according to the bus simulation shows that this is the way of
it that no other way to try to save Tuan and this is this is
the high the high order thing i'm trying to get across is that that we
start assuming that there is independent of various pieces and once we made those assumptions
we can say let's quick learning to those components
OK by observing enough times in estimating the parameters
and the the bounds for doing that depend on the number of parameters not on
actual size the state space
that's not a robot
sorry does just that was motivational shot area so this is again this is being
tracked by an overhead camera the robot is trying to get to
the goal position which is the corner here
and obama by
OK hasn't learned much yet the bonobo released we
plotted the motion of it's very brownian actually moves really very very nicely
it's almost markov i mean it really seems markov
which is pretty cool considering that is just the bubble
and we want to learning trials we actually really implemented some standards
rl simulator simulations but we did them with the actual robot simulator
right and so
there it is the robot heading for
the goal here goes to the goal position can success
notice anything interesting
it doesn't know word spaces
it's all the positional information comes from the overhead camera even though the there's a
camera the of its nose weren't not using that for any state information it's trying
to move in whatever we get to the goal fastest because it's sort of watching
itself as an out-of-body experience and
it does it it turned out that because of the way it was programmed the
backward walking was slightly faster and so the learning algorithm figure that out
we use backward walking this is that this is an unfortunate trial where the bonobo
are kind of
part itself in the way
so the robot
it has a policy which maps all positions and orientations to where it should go
and these low probability events keep happening
to get out of my friends
i think this is more or less what robot frustration might look like
that point you start checking for is really random is it really really doesn't seem
any many more
but eventually eventually come on you can do it
to do that
o o o also left
she squeezing there before the ball gets in the way
and there we are so
the reason this was so that was like trial fifteen or something like that is
that the reason was able to learn such a small number of trials is because
it's totally took advantage of all this conditional independence to be built into the
the function approximator for the transition function
so that's one sort of function that you can build
OK i think OK so there's i think if you think we're saying like ten
more minutes or something like that there is something i want to speak to the
thing because i think i'm going
i got myself little bogged down but there's other kinds of ways you can introduce
various kinds of structure to learn things faster in the example that i just gave
the were in spite of horrible picture that you there was no independent of the
state on how things are going to change
which makes sense it's history there must be some influence but but let's say that
there's another way to think about it is every individual state has an influence that's
back to the original model well what if there's different types of states and within
each type there's a mapping to how things are gonna change but this but this
is a separate types can be learned separately so
we stood model that have been published in the important learning literature for doing that
with mdps kind of factorizing the MDP into these types
and we took advantage of it we able to learn
a great world a lot faster
the right hand generalizations speeds things up we do the same thing on on a
robot examples here this one is actually being tracked using
motion tracker things little silver balls
and it's trying to get to this white box you might not be able to
see in the corner here and we told that
different color regions may have different dynamics so learns a separate action model for what
all all sections do on the sandbag
the first is on the black painted wood
and the result of that is actually is able to take advantage of this in
a substantial way that if we if we if we ignore those distinction certainly if
we learn each individual place in the world map that too
an action model to to take forever to learn if we take the whole world
to say no it's really just one big space and just learn the same action
model for the whole space that doesn't work well either because the sand is actually
a little bit slipping and so it tends to do is it it tries to
point itself to the goal while in the sand and often overshoots and then falls
out of the world and it's minus one so
being able to condition on these two tight ends up learning more accurate model but
still very very quickly
we do something similar
the question who did this for almost all of her time trying to find a
different surfaces
it turns out that it's really easy to find the surface that the robot can
if you're a statistical learning
theorist i guess you might consider this
form to be user friendly
but i think probably you degree
and most practitioners would agree that
it just looks like a split symbols so we now have to do is to
turn that into something that means something to a practitioner so going to turn that
formula into if you like the result
the way to do that is is you mention
i mean it's it's really just interpreting what that formula says that in words that
in a way that is understandable what this formula is saying is OK this is
the probability of messing up the that means that with probability one minus delta
we want to mess up
right things will be OK
what does things OK mean things OK means that if we actually observe zero training
then the true error is going to be actually less than or equal to this
and that's exactly the
the bound we want
i want to be able to infer something about the generalisation error of the function
that we've chosen which is the one with zero
training so that's exactly how we get that
and this is the about you can see again
with probability you know you choose anything you choose q and then with probability at
least one minus delta over the random m samples the generalisation error of the function
fn with zero training error is bounded by
rfn is less or equal to and i've just written a slightly differently in that
i've split the log onto qn times delta
the log the product is the sum of the log so it's log one qn
plus log one delta
and you're already looking at
you know
i will result in
statistical learning theory
so i i mean hopefully i can
you know sort of
you know if you're
we already in this implicit the sort of structure of many of the results of
statistical learning theory very typically you're going to have the
one and so clearly that's a very nice property that the
o thing is scaling
inversely with the sample size
you've got a log one on delta now that's very nice because the delta
confidence parameter is coming in very benignly under log
so even if you sort of
double the
confidence you're only going to make one and the difference in the whole sorry marked
by the conference by doing like one and difference in the bound again
and then you have this to
which is i'm going to start to think of
as the complexity term
in a sense it varies according to the function
qn remember was chosen for a particular fan
and you can think of it is somehow the complexity of the function fn
in this particular training scenario
and that's what i say on the top of the line here we can think
of the term log one qn is the complexity description length of the function fn
so if we manage to get a good training error
low training error with a simple function then we get an even better bound on
generalisation if we have to use the rather complicated function OK we get worse
now that we have to put a prior weight on the functions that was that
distribution q
if the functions are drawn at random according to distribution p m
the expected generalisation will be minimal if we actually shows that prior to be equal
to the site which is due to be equal to the prior
and if it's we choose it differently we actually the expected sort of loss is
the KL divergence but so this is actually the starting point for the PAC bayes
analysis what this
sort of simple theorem leads through to the so PAC bayes approach
so i'm not going to go any more into that at this point as i
say leave it will be picking up on the PAC bayes
in his talks in the second part of any questions on that
q was p in this case was an assume prior is the kind of thing
bayesians do they assume that there's
you are actually
the the likelihood of certain one of those functions arising in a particular application
it is known beforehand
i know this is this is the a distribution over functions this is the distribution
over the
so this is the assumption that they know that the likelihood of this function arising
in a particular application is
you know
i don't know enough about it to know what is free
to be clear
when it is there for
latest data only that people talk about certainly get discussed the problem of dark energy
what it is is the expansion of the universe actually accelerating or not
in the area
it because with a real puzzle or not time to leave that is
for example are the idea is now
that's in addition we've talked about so far
there's one for some
the mathematics of the standard model
it's just not be there
we met
the electrons electrons and quarks
we have met
w z will be forced the fundamental particles of matter all fermions spin
four carries of those spin one
why is the force has been one matter particles with
could you imagine
this image
there are also
spin-off of terrorism spin one
so this is the idea of supersymmetry
which is that to every variety of
that we know
there is a supersymmetric partner
with which is about
and the idea was that we know
there's supersymmetric partners in the firm
and what you need to know what are the names of these things so
convention is that the supersymmetric models for
you take the first name with s from
so the semantic while becomes squall
this is not true
concentrate this select support here it is
would all the time
she was
are real and so put in afterwards
so in supersymmetry photons the folk scene the movie
that's what we know
the why
now i want to know is that supersymmetry cannot be exact
the masses of supersymmetric particles would be identical to the convention
and if that's the case we wouldn't be here is we are here is because
the light is electrically charged particle
this debate has exclusion principle which says you can't go to the same quantum state
that particular reason why there structure
in the atomic elements in the periodic table
four which gives rise to
real stuff like us
if the light is charged particles have been imposed on
there would be no
both songs sort of like penguins millenarian
and by the late so
challenges that you get horrible horror movie
we have no idea
b so the fact that supersymmetry is broken
i mean this is
particles must be much more massive
the ones which is again a very fortunate to be here
so there are two possibilities one is
this idea is complete
there actually are in such
that supersymmetry is part of nature's
and that it also has been broken by mass
the semantic particles are at
the energy scale at the LHC will change why do i say that the energy
energy scale because
for which i can't you hear this more detailed quantitative shown that what is it
estimate altogether but using the semantic information you have about ads on pages in collaborative
filtering that is so missing people assume
but this is again not trivial salangi
the other thing that can be done is by using something like biclustering
so you have the feature in the new cluster query and ad space
then in the contribution that comes from the residual space depends on which cluster the
query belongs to an which cluster that belong to several clusters going to have its
own contribution so this is what say this is how you avoid the curse of
dimensionality cluster the queries cluster that and then for every block in the
in the two dimensional clusters you had
you have contribution and so this has been done it was so this also works
so there is hope i think since the this model was that what works i
don't see any reason why the first one will not work but again it hasn't
been tried
OK so
let me end with some challenges so you know so we have seen so we
saw some case studies we began with some challenges that arise when estimating click-through rates
we saw some case studies and then we also saw some
open problems in some approaches one could use to solve those open problems but let
me end by again
you know
mentioning some of the other challenges which we might actually lead to fruitful research a
feature so
so these are some of the challenges summarised again we already talked about that so
you know if you just use the information retrieval approach it will miss the context
in many cases and that can be compensated by using click as as a feedback
mechanism but you know once you
once you start estimating CTR using click feedback
you know
you have to worry about introducing features that will granular you have to worry about
sparsity have to worry about bias issues you have to worry the body about dynamics
you have to worry about training cost
know how long if you cover the model take seven days to
train them that's not
that's not a very attractive proposition so you want to model to be trained quickly
and you can come of it models where the prediction
it takes a long time
be computed because
when you add in an online setting you get equity you have to evaluate the
whole bunch of ads before deciding which one to put their so if the
prediction function is very expensive to compute you will never meet the latency requirement requested
that is again another constraint important constraints which one has to keep in mind when
the when coming up so you can't do something which is done in netflix competition
for instance coming over two hundred projects and melting them all together that is fine
to win the competition was not going to work in the system
because it's just too expensive to compute that you have to compute that function for
maybe ten thousand to select the top k
because you don't have the time you have like forty or fifty milliseconds to do
that you can't do that
so so that's another constraint to keep in mind you need to more com you
need compact models that accurate that can be computed very quickly trying to
so again we
some other methods which have not been tried but
might be useful to try to like
in know boosting your decision trees all these methods are all fine but again the
the my name is and you could for a faculty member here at the center
for language and speech processing have one the commute to this day event in the
two week event and for some of you another six weeks after that the first
a quick round of king of my introductions how many of you have the macro
students i know there should be about of your hands the mako sponsoring your with
here this is
is that these are the people sponsored by the north american association for the
for computational linguistics OK so there may be some of missing then because i see
one two three four five six hand
OK maybe there are more if you
OK OK so there one group of you who are here only for two weeks
they are supported by sponsored by this organisation
which most of you hopefully know about but if you don't you can find out
and that the rest of you out here thanks to NSF and you're going be
here for the long haul not just these two weeks but another six weeks after
that so
a little bit about the summer workshops these started back in ninety three
and the summer workshops model after some things that people are doing in mathematics at
the institute for defense analyses in intrinsic
this is the kind of this is that if you have any of these books
this is from the legend of all these code breakers we used to sit in
these classified
i secret lab could work and so they started off with that and the idea
was you get a bunch of smart people locked them up in a place for
the summer and the problem solving and go about working on it for six eight
weeks and this was happening in mathematics and they were called scanned sense can stand
for something i'm never going back and a summer camp for advanced mathematics something
so anyway so
people who are working on speech and language technology that we have some hard problems
and these people have been working on for ten fifteen years nobody is able to
solve then why don't we try to scam by david about a bunch of people
locked them up in some places and see if they can solve the problem
and that's when it started in ninety three and in fact the first two summer
workshops held at rutgers and ninety five these workshops came over the johns hopkins because
at that time the center for language and speech processing had been established here and
the essentially said hey we can do a better job hosting them in the UK
will give you try and for the given to us in this period since then
for the last fifteen plus years
and so the main idea is that in six weeks we get a lot of
very good researchers from all over the world to work on problems in speech and
so as with a lot of these enterprises they need money so we have to
raise money for these workshops are typically the defense department gives us some money but
then we went to NSF and said hey why don't you get some money to
and this will give you money if you have some students in there
it OK students are good be therapy very good grad students that's nice to do
some good work in fact most of the really research in the world gets done
by grad student and that
none the of women undergraduate
what do we do with undergraduate
and then of course you very happy with the pool we got we got some
really superstar people the only problem with the people they know anything about speech and
language they were doing the kind of whatever electrical engineering computer science psychology statistics
and we said have you heard about passing the like
four that have heard of all n grams no we know about speech i mean
the way you and i don't know how well the speech signal have you heard
about spectral characteristics evolve no
OK we have a problem so we decided to get the students to come to
weeks earlier and in two two weeks for the common where we can about speech
and language into their heads so that for the next six weeks and they can
be on par with the rest of the researchers and do good research and that's
really the origin of these two weeks workshop two-week summer schools the idea was to
get these undergraduate usually everything we know in two weeks essentially to a dump of
everything you know and then for the next six weeks there will be on part
of the reason said well
it turned out that the idea was more successful than we thought and more and
more students started saying hey you want come to come to an then organisations like
next step and said we pay for the students to come to recover the travel
and housing you OK alright so it's grown and grown in now to become what
it is and so every summer for two weeks we have a lot of fun
we created two-week program and just in case you haven't thought about it if we
add up it's about four and half five credits worth of study that you're doing
these two weeks so if you're in school and if you initiated the number of
lecture and lab hours that course in half perhaps at the graduate level for undergraduate
taking two courses in two weeks
so be
there's a lot of information coming at you
i don't know if you've heard the expression drinking from a fire hose but that's
what you've been doing for the next two we have one and the way they
are going to be structured is going to be a lecture two lectures in the
morning typically in love in the afternoon lectures at all her money
and the lab the outgoing chief when tried to over one quick thing about the
last today do go to the lab early because nearly you need to get to
compute accounts which reminds me the second part of my little five you should be
looking to be administrator so all of you here got to know you need to
know a couple of very important people and i'm not one of them for his
money que
hopefully one help was not make money can
OK after me to write very important otherwise you want function in place that get
money communication assistant called is added to the set on the third floor of the
building money because the centre administrator there is the interesting and they essentially run the
place for your anything like and if you come to me and you have a
problem as as all the money for i do
that's how it works
so up to taking the minimum second you have to get to know systems administrator
justin martin he be began the afternoon in the lab and who help you set
up a computer account and every new computer account is like a new relationship to
figure out what the other person like and how it works and what happened in
one thousand so basically allowed to spend refined lab this southampton getting use computers to
do come early and there's only just and i think he may have the student
assistant but a couple of them be going around in the of you thirty become
while to get everybody's problem sorted out so do come early to the lab and
changing and then you can actually bigger and bigger and and everything will be OK
sometimes we want to make changes and play
they do that
say OK i don't want to search number of in
so if you if have
this guy
we always need to show all this in the first of all we have a
lot of of index size of collection and they do so action in all of
them and then that result from the search
OK so if you have a smaller index new version of all documents
it's extremely easy you can you can look into source code different search engine so
what we have is that says from from the biggest index
and you remember that we always have
and so are the least of document idea
then the area
following index
and what we can do it again
if you have a new so for example if we have edit war in the
next olympics
this implies have foreseen
if for example
we had work begun one bigger
so it didn't have no national document so in the end they don't hesitate to
get it from this index
to handle the
patient handling delicate over from from documents
then it's going to happen
least of all documents in every index
simply a list of football idea
and during this and that's something you need to remove
ideas of documents from all units during marriage
if you see the document actually in this in this but not in the old
OK so why the
talk so much about compression of
if you have these
if you have a list of all document idea
based on what
i have talked about
compression of integers
this leads
it will become pressed extremely well i can assure you that if you one two
percent of all
my maybe less
because it we have a lot of
close into and we can use an approach that we have
and we can compress the extremely extremely well
so it's not a problem at all
the problem the problem here is going be only performed during
of course there some performance because doing this
this is now
but again you can search for literature and you can see that you do that
you can prove actually that
degradation of
is what is
it's not so bad at the same time the speed is now so see if
it if you want to find some combination between the evidence search
this is near optimal
now we are talking about another approach
so we want we don't want to
reviewed index or using some sort of for example we are concerned about how to
search in the number of units in parallel how to
pratt said big number five days
so it's in place traditional so we're trying to keep all index always
we are making changes in our index
and there are a lot of ways how we can do this
but i want to discuss only one approach and this is approach is how to
create an inverted index in but
we discussed the material in the second lecture
and this is very well known structure
this is a classical structure and here you can find
millions of way i believe not maybe thousands of wafers about optimisation implementation and so
there are many there are a lot of good implementations of a structure
because of this you know that
but really is perfect when you are limited in memory
because always working with these blocks is limited size
if you are limited to is random access memory
also we can
create in place update about inverted index using battery
so how we can do
remember from the second lecture so in every
so a lot of help
of the three they have some key
and we can also always attach some data for the key so
what we need to do we need to create this tree slot that we're going
to to put into the streets
and this is what is pretty obviously can
forty four
and block of course lists of some part of course list
last i don't know class
again two hundred fifty five i of documents already compressed
and this is one element of the history and the building of tree based on
how we can compare so we remember that always we need to
to have some or all of this because it's sorted arrays that are in tree
and we need to put them in order
so we can what they can do they can come work if words equal we
can compare fields
the idea of document in this post LI
and that's
features because i'm talking about change so the idea is very simple
they have arbitrary on in every slaughter of history you can look on in your
books into my slides from the second lecture
they're putting forward and they're putting part of course list
of course you can say that sometimes put full on both these deputy warden many
but at the same time as i said usually far smaller than possibly is now
part of course this and also they can compress it using preface compression
so it's very naive implementation and
for example open source search and research
two key that they're using this implementation of inverted index
and it's pretty fast in case of limited memory but how we can update this
let's start with the
that's what we can do we can create it from scratch if you have pretty
good collection don't have indexed
and i want to
prove that we can create a
the tree for this index this
slots as fast as
recreated inverted index
the approach is very simple
so we are getting our down because he is regarded as the had it
four inverted index
and the creating of slot and simply trying to put them into a
but that's usually messy and not only going to talk about that
so you might want to
we look at some of channel to colour something talk
go through it in detail
but it turns out that quite often just going for the motive distribution can be
a good idea
always but in many cases it's good enough
we've looked at two very popular
got some prior
the conjugate prior
that surprised visitors just will fly around this more than five
because prior was like
well the just
similar trend of mixed and often added to it
and which is sort of problem
and the really important thing is these are all convex problems
and there are lots of ways how you can end up with a non convex
we might touch upon something later on
but this least
is all fairly nice
any questions now
a want of one
so the graphical models
so what do is result briefly refresh
what salmon martin did last week
well talk about conditional independence happens at people decomposition
message passing and dynamic programming
so this is all familiar to you just relax
taken as
conditional independence well
six next prime
conditionally independent
given c
if the joint probability of x x prime given c
nice simple example would be
it's about the x
this is the probability that i'll be carrying an umbrella
defectors from the probably the matter will carry numbers
and i usually don't talk to each other before
to decide whether we will carry an umbrella
bottles might look out the window
we look at
civil there's some plants so
therefore it's probably a good idea to bring for
so c
within the files
or the absence thereof
and so therefore well the probability that that i will be an umbrella will be
highly correlated
this this and that and
but a well given scene in the clouds those events independent
i could go and model the overall probability of each clustering and related the same
and this really complicated distribution in that we may be eighty nine people in the
so it
the distribution over
two to the a two dimensional state really wanted to store all those coefficients well
there's no computer that could do it
at least not at the moment
but i could go
and model
each individual probability fairly efficiently
i could for instance what you for a couple of days and see whether bring
an umbrella or not
people a good model for
and and then something that you don't talk to each other before but they will
bring an umbrella or not
this will give a good estimate
of the overall probability of people bring an umbrella
OK so that's conditional independence
and this is really what would allow u
to estimate the distribution of umbrellas
very easily
even so
if you don't use any of this factorisation knowledge will be nearly impossible problem
now obviously
function that generalizes
so given some graphs
some vertices v and edges e
we associate a random variable x with every
vertex on the graph
what you have number or not
this is a vertex in the graph
and the some might be another vertex transitive
now subset of the random variables are conditionally independent given x
if when removing those vertices from the graph
the rock breaks up into disjoint subsets
well that's really amounts fall of the definition let's look at some pictures
that's timberlake example
more than the other one
markov chain
a simple example would be
the traffic lights
it's a traffic light and if you know the current state well
the previous states in the future states decouple from each other
so you don't need to know at least
knowing how traffic lights are what all the previous states were if you know the
current one
we can easily predict what's going to happen in the future
some people think looks like that
so that future events only determined by the president
more generally
graphical models
so only talking about undirected graphical models except for small exception
and here qualified to move those three to eight nodes
these green blocks decompose
so you can have a a whole bunch of random variables and they might be
connected and really complicated ways
i can model that very efficiently
by really just dealing with those
you probably still remember from my talk is celebrated theorem of hammersley clifford actually they
wrote about
and the proof is wrong
and they usually bizarre for proof today think like two three years later
to state where the first ones to write the theorem best name
this is quite cool
that delta
entailed a contradiction
which was not just of its stuff
then there exists
of about guy
from that
for a relation
there exists
the population
of about things
from some
of that
if some delta i
because we can just go just make i
big enough
to be bigger than the subscript on anything in the finite subset
all right by that stage of the construction
but in this
and here is god as being considered either included or not
there is no such derivations
that's what we already proved
i guess if you really want to be
convinced know another observation the AI
is in delta only if
i i is in delta
this again
you can observe this day by induction on i
that makes this to
in fact obvious
there's no other way that anything can get in delta rather than being thrown into
until the later stages we considering adding something different
and just as well
all right
properties of this big set delta
super set
is inconsistent
that is
for people with a
if a is not in doubt
then delta
together with a
and tells the contradiction
why is that
well by construction
OK gamma is a subset of delta
during the construction
it's not a five plus one
for some i
greater than or equal to here
at some point during the construction begins the the board
if we didn't put it in delta one
from delta i which is a subset of delta which is also a subset of
delta together with it
we can get a contradiction
so if we get a contradiction from a subset of delta
together with with with the time one and also the derivation from old
so delta is not only consistent
does consistent
this is because it could get without going in consists
which one more formula into it
even if his wife fifteen you can't put it without delta explodes
and then to everything
putting those two properties together
delta is what we call the maximal
on system
now the enumeration to be absolutely anything enumerations just
just which formally number one number two number three or four
what we have established
in fact every
so set
a maximal consistent
that it's a proxy for data compression transforms the data throwaways little guys transmit the
big eyes
the receiver invert transform and i
let's see what i guess
so if you do this
you get the picture that looks like this is this projection is not
but what you see that there is very little difference between these two pictures and
what showing you the data compression
so you can store away ninety seven point five percent of the
wavelet coefficients and no do not suffer the perceptron loss and what i'm telling you
data compression kind of works to mathematically what we've done is we've had this blue
vector of wavelet coefficients we set to zero in red almost all of the chapter
largest one
and so we truncated expansion to only retains the expansion the s largest coefficients
OK so that's far
and the fact is that images that we care about
very often are sparse in a convenient representation
OK so sparsity has had an enormous impact on people's thinking it's
link to play the fundamental role in the late twentieth century in how we can
estimate things how we can compress
it's almost a tautology how when and how well we can model
things with a few parameters and so on and so forth but today i would
like to discuss another implication of sparsity which is the sparsity has bearings on the
data acquisition process itself and as we will see its sparsity determines how quickly i
can acquire signals in the non adaptive fashion
so the the the first premise underlying compressed sensing its sparsity the second is incoherent
which is
the topic we have not explored yet
so let me explain what this is you'll see it's very very simple
we have
signal that we wish to acquire that has a sparse expansion
in the basis site
so now we have two systems we have the systems in which this object is
assumed to be spas
and then we have the system that we wish to sense
the object which i denote by phi k
so for example if we do radiology
if i k because i do m would be sinusoids and then signed for example
the thing is sparse in the wavelet domain for example
if we do or angiography where most of the images black and only a few
pixels indicating blood flows along vessels
are actually not zero
it could actually be the canonical basis
OK so now we have two systems the sparse the system in which things are
assumed to be spas or nearly so far
and then the systems in which an sensing objects
and now we can define a coherence between these two systems
phi and psi
which is a very simple notion so i'm going to assume that the basis functions
are normalized to sparsity waveforms and sensing waveforms are normalised so the unit vectors
and we're going to do is we're going to introduce the coherence spaces between the
basis phi and the basic as follows is essentially is the dimension of the signal
times the maximum
of the coefficients the correlation coefficients between the sensing waveforms and the sparsity waveforms
OK so it's very very simple
i'm looking at the maximum correlations between the sensing and the sparsity way from the
squares that correlation coefficient multiplied by an and that's incoherence between the coherence between the
two basis for
now this coherence
is always between one and because of course this is a no-brainer product between unit
vectors is less than one and therefore the coherence is less and and
and it will be actually maximum if for example the two bases are the same
is the two bases are the same then this maximum inner product is one and
so the coherence is and
always two busy share an element coherence and
on the other hand its minimum
if all of this correlation coefficients are equal
two one over square would have an
so its minimum is the coherence is equal to one it's easy to see that
the coherence has to be greater than one because of some parts of the relationship
which if i saw
over j i get the energy of five which is one so one of the
coefficients square has to be greater than one of n
and therefore the coherence has to be greater than one
so the coherence is the quantity that measures the similarity between bases five days is
side its minimum if it's equal to one and its maximum for example in the
case was identical
is the coherence is equal to
so let me give you an example so for example let's say we're doing communication
signals where we assume that we're about to see is signal that has a sparse
frequency spectrum for example of bandlimited signal that we have discussed earlier in that case
the signal would be sparse in
another way
without making specific assumptions about what kind of shape you're looking for but this can
this can
so this kind thing is very flexible way
another thing to think that
of things the this
peak around
this the late spring here
it's getting larger and larger
up until the place we have trained it actually think this is getting larger and
the other one thirty percent
we can look at the hyperparameters of the the the same computer as
the magnitude of two point four million
this decay time the characteristic time of the periodicity
if but that would be about ninety years
we only had
fifty or sixty years of data i the thing that's what things look pretty periodic
inside the the
the interval that we have data only
between the very early part of the of the there very late there might be
things that are not exactly periodic
what i hope to show with this example is that
doesn't persist are quite flexible models
and the idea
that you can
what you get used to thinking about covariance functions
there is a nice way of
understanding the properties of the function that you're looking at
in in this particular case you could actually understand the data by just putting the
data and looking at it
but because the one-dimensional data all these methods can also equally well be used or
what about my life not so easy just to look at the data and you
can still trying understand things in terms of the properties of the covariance function that
maps the data well
that's an important way
try to get
inside about it
one thing we talked about a little bit about yesterday and had
but question about this as well
actually doing maximisation here and i was sort of early on i was saying well
we should be careful if you do mathematician
that's exactly right when i i'm i'm optimizing over eleven from here should really
check that the result i'm guessing
it is a good approximation to the right
two of the right and the right answer would be hard to get right because
that would have to integrate out those eleven promise have some
and the functional way the enter into the covariance function is very complicated
that would be a real challenge and analytically probably wouldn't be able to do that
that we have to to resort to marketing column and the producer you went back
i also showed on example
situations where
doing maximisation with a good approximation give you almost identical predictions
two when you actually do things properly
the nice paper
about this paper called optimizer integrate out
but by the car
the interest in this issue which is an interesting issue
then the place to start
OK so that that may make sense
somebody asked me about about blind model just talk a little bit about the relationship
between line model golf approach
it turns out the girls processes
well many models that are commonly used in the basic and machine learning
actually special cases the golf pro
the final one of those
but ryan in and quickly
it sketch of
what the connection is between you've explain model
and the golf course
in fact i'm going to i'm going to show you
the golf course that could be my morals
so i apologize looking for people not familiar with and by the way the too
fast to understand exactly what is going on
the idea in in my models the the u
look at this
i function like this
it has been if you look at the
function here
and the square difference between the function value in the information and you have the
regularisation term
which regularizers with which penalizes basically
dedication to ensuring that you are clear about where you're going and that you're clear
that the things that you're doing right now
contributing to where you want to go ultimately so the the second step and i'm
not going to spend time on this morning because i could see i the number
of people that i got all my i god is going to do is go
development workshop call
help me
get me out of here no and not
there are dozens of programs you can do and in fact
if anybody here
doesn't have for themselves and not asking for sure and
if anybody here doesn't have themselves a clear compelling set of goals
make sure you let me have your
email address before the end of the session
because i have to send you
i documents of book developed by a friend of mine in australia
and he wrote this book
and he made the goal that he was going to give away free of charge
one million copies
and it's a step-by-step process
for putting together a set of personal and professional goals really well done sort of
thing you expect spend a lot of money and he didn't do it because it's
just a really nice guy he's a nice guy because he has his name and
he has a telephone number on the back of a million copies of the floating
around the world hasn't done any harm whatsoever but if you don't have clear compelling
goals if you don't have confidence self talk if you are not absolutely positive and
focused you cannot be
a charismatic leader you cannot inspire others
to engage and trust
those are two critical first steps
the next one is
charisma are is the physical side of things and i
i mentioned already
a large part of charisma is trust
you want people to engage with you you have to win the trust first before
anything else they have to trust you
nobody is going to give you their time
their energy commitment nobody's going to believe what you are committed to the goals that
you have them unless they trust you
and a huge amount of that trust
comes down to things that have nothing to do
but the words that you've said or did you say
now when i stepped up on this stage this morning
in about two hundred milliseconds
you decided
what do you like me or not
whether i was at friendly person or where there was threat when i was an
enemy when i was going to give you something i was going to take something
from it all happened you know
fifty the second it all just that you made those decisions without any real conscious
thought you made that decision you made that determination and that and that shape certain
amount of the way you reacting to me now
that decision was made in a small part of your brain called the amygdala
the amygdala is a small almond shaped part of the brain right on the brain
stem right in the core of the oldest part of the brain
they tell us that it's probably about five hundred million years old and that was
the first brain that we all
when we evolved into reptiles
used to survive and it basically has the same functions as a reptile brain has
today date the
the scientists refer to it as the reptile brain at all it's about is keeping
you alive
a reptile doesn't think oh look at that eagle over very looks rather big
i wonder is he going to now that they think is the carnivorous or omnivorous
what know he sees something
and by the size of it by the shape but by the way it moves
consistently it makes the decision and i gonna fight you've heard or my going to
sleep and my going fight or flight
i'm going to fight this thing are run away most basic
of survival instincts and deep inside all of our brains
we react in that way to every single person we meet every day
every second day way way down below the more complicated parts of brain to make
those decisions now when you look to me walking up here you look at my
if you look at the way i was presenting my body you look to what
shape i was making what was going on in my face and all of that
happened recently and you we decided to say you like me or you didn't like
me and then on an ongoing basis you you really you redefine the decision again
and again and again you say when you going to trust me or not now
as i stand up here
i consciously
try to use body language that will appease your reptilian brain and make you feel
OK i make you feel that i am somebody to be trusted because long before
i speak anything to you that you like or dislike you will make that determination
every single thing you do every single move you make is important
let me give you for example
r is a crucial you have shake hands
OK now i that very basic body language could could issues would you mind
now focusing on going to teach me kill this from moment to find me
the first thing the teachers show you how to shake hands and the way
that somebody what absolutely mistrust you
will not like you and will have a negative impression of trade-off
OK so what's this gentleman's reaction as i shake hands with high harry it's very
nice to meet you have to go
so that he knew he knew
i was going to do something that was going to but even though we knew