only practical
how can you
a lot of the rules
not bad
you are
the other
you know
i have
these are
it's true
he is
and it would be
in march
there are all these people
OK case
why are we
which is better
and that was
is that
part of
you will need
in the
i decided to be
the the help me
and took good job in NASA JPL which was actually an amazing just sort of
kept me
quite look into the academic community
give me the opportunity work
the top scientists
and a lot of stuff happened
then i moved out of the time with a lot of people
i would leave such a great
only seventy one
but in the context of one of the most successful projects i worked on while
i was there
so let me know that it's kind of project which was about classifying about two
billion objects
to start galaxies
and most of these objects
look like this
that's what the images were
in that in the survey which took about seven years to do
and finished in ninety five
it has images of of the images that show now i'm showing this
two things one
is one of the data on the top
it looks like
no resolution
an astronomer looking at and actually a lot of methods in astronomy trying to understand
these images
i can tell the difference pretty much
now that i can tell you what
which one is the start which of the galaxy
if you look at the bottom
an astronomer will readily tell you it's very clear
which one is this
which one is about
very very certain about
turns out many of astronomers
the big one year is not guaranteed to start
and that's clearly is
the point is
we were able to solve this problem with amazing accuracy using data mining and machine
blew me away
because this is a group of
this is the community very very smart people dedicated
they can spend all my lifetime studying one
one problem
first of all secondary
one instrument
i know it inside out
they really are very familiar with the idea
expected in real life
so my first lesson
even when you have a lot more people focused on very specific problem but was
was very successful actresses work
much much higher than we thought
in the nineteen these objects
so it it was really like a magic box and it led to a bunch
of discoveries in astronomy
a lot of stuff
that happened from that
so that's basically microsoft's biggest
get me to leave GPL and go to microsoft was to ask me a simple
which is a group of very smart people
who can dedicate their life to one dataset set
could not solve this problem but in many parts of
imagine what it could do in the business world
and part of the building efforts
want to introduce me to see what was happening in the business world in corporate
america and
basically very
the reason why things work well by the way
it's not magical
humans then
because this problem was inherently high dimensional
what do i mean by that
this is in that respect
measurements have to solve the problems
we found that out of fifty that was we were dealing
and today by the way is this part of the fifty sounds very small right
because a lot of us deal with a hundred thousand
and millions of light
but fifty years
it essential
we didn't know which way ahead of time
o thirty years
he's very smart people working with a very smart it's not only in the right
this problem
pretty bad property which is the removal of the
think this is good dramatic actually had to discover the right
and what they do they were themselves up to four five six dimensions
but that didn't help they just couldn't get out by humans
designed to get up to about eight dimension
which would solve the problem had a normal life
microsoft research was a major shift in
direction and along with the
in scientists
but i was worried about scalability and systems and and i learned a lot of
about databases from a lot of people
began to worry about what it takes to product starts to put it in the
and actually had the fortune to work
research group and the product was pretty interesting
so this is my second lesson came up and ended up leaving microsoft with two
colleagues microsoft to do is to
now i do that
even though the environment with microsoft still
like to come
we did that because i discovered the real problem is not technology from
the problems data management problems and people
people didn't understand it
so what we did is and by the way the world is pretty much worrying
about how do i make a database with finite memory and find this
one very large
a lot of the work being done today is referred to as essentially most of
the time in the history right you only one person so there you never want
more than one
and if you take your password to come up with the best possible results
let's start with the a good work
didn't read
didn't get used a lot
and the reason for that is people do not use
and the reason for that
and this is i think microsoft word
is discovering this sort of shift between
business challenges technical two
we in this community think about algorithms and technical tools how to scale of stuff
and what you have here this challenge is how
people who will ultimately use algorithms to think of the
and in between there there is no clear
i had to basically
was statisticians extremely hard to find
in the nineteen fifties TV is consultant it becomes very expensive just interested between the
that's a lot of misunderstandings system was that company basically sensible simple idea
let's do it has been
well we did we operate on it and we do the data mining
and companies just give us the
now addressing these
second lecture at the second week of machine learning summer school
and today we're going to have a new speaker which is the u i t
from the gatsby computational unit
he's going to be there
talk to
got talk today and then two practice sessions today and tomorrow
so you which he did his undergraduate in mathematics and waterloo and then he did
his graduate students with geoff hinton cannot be is now
in two thousand three he finished his phd and immediately after he post-doc with michael
jordan UC berkeley
and the lee
qu one u
i don't sing about that
OK and since two thousand seven this electrode the gatsby computational so you reduce expert
in based bayesian techniques and approximate inference
and unsupervised learning
and today is going to talk about usually processes and forward
the lecture OK thank you
is it working
really ought to be here to tell you about the process of how i am
very excited about this
o area is not currently
i'm really happy to be talking here about this so
i guess what doing today and tomorrow is that
is that
a tutorial right now and that the paper will cause today in the afternoon and
more useful
so let's start with how does this dirichlet processes basically
what's called bayesian nonparametrics
a model so as
congress with the value of the constant positive that's another class of bayesian nonparametric models
and this model which are not from parametric in the sense that
they generally have a very large or infinite number of parameters in the
and so in order to prevent overfitting is this model you
you basically have to be paid to integrate all this infinitely many
and dirichlet processes has become pretty popular nowadays in both the machine learning
so how can i like the
general applications that have that has been used in both in both communities
that the estimation
the estimation so that basically estimating
that use of distribution basically and is also being used a lot in what's called
semiparametric modelling
and it's useful are in biostatistics
and finally in machine learning is since the dirichlet processes that mostly used at the
way of might like that being model selection and averaging
so it would on the process was followed by a practical cost on implementing a
dirichlet process mixture
i will try to cross the NIPS papers if
if you manage
to get that the quite interesting
i presume that everybody here is somewhat familiar with the paradigm
and you should know this from the open call
cost as well among the previous back across the
in and market
so this of course been quite a number of other foreign countries the processes both
in machine learning and statistics
you can think of this the for life on land but they can take a
look u
one the other people present
with different viewpoints taken
that's part of the our policy going to be
but also in the first half of the article
got to the free applications that just popped the ball and you
tell you what dirichlet process
they take a break and that
we will go into a bit more details into the how dirichlet process
can be represented are represented
and then will only link back to their applications by talking about how
the dirichlet process then used in terms of modelling and
i will be talking about
that you've been using
for example
the kind of locally optimal
important distribution so as to some for your state OK so you do that
in this case i showed you that essentially the weight
basically the importance weight that's going to appear
it's going to be something
it's going to be essentially the product
sheikh or one two
so choosing instead to two
of p y j xk minus one OK we had this guy
is the integral
OK so you can do that
so assume that you're able to sample what exactly from the local optimum publicity then
time and your weight
it would be basically
the point of the oldest towns
but like this thing
OK is going to have difficulty also
violence or related violence that is going to increase exponentially with time indexed so you
can try to is good it's important to try to put forward basically
sample paul
basically having trying to optimize this morning this important distribution so as to minimize the
loss of the weight but it can only mitigate this problem that cannot be eliminated
because all the time you can and that we were essentially a weight function which
is the product of terms and it basically means the divine stability increase exponentially with
time index o
basically involves something will collapse
so it seems that we have stuck because we have this
importance sampling algorithms very unfortunately
if you basically
use it on particle problem after a few time steps whatever you do
the algorithm collects basically the approximation as to why violence so what can we do
well what we're going to do is something which is actually only
some of the important
on some of its looks like act
but you can show that it's actually principles
so the thing
do what bothers me we've all this despite the categories
i time and increases my clients of the unnormalized weights
increased typically over time as soon as you can see the state space model you
could come up with the example but for the moment interest this increases over time
which means that when you normalized those weight so that the sum to one one
guy's going to basically be very close to one and all the others can be
very close to zero sustainable basically a very poor approximation following very important
we can essentially monitor
it's the
the weights the normalized weight
essentially what we can do is particularly with many of the weight of when basically
i'm going to find the particle i as the weight normalise weight which is small
is always more related to the kind of perfect monte carlo case all the way
to normalise weights would have weight one of event so we're going to find basically
particles with low weights i'm going to try and get rid of it
where basically the particle
as i weights what i'm gonna do i'm gonna
david could it multiple times because basically it means that this particle is in promising
region part of the space
OK so that's really
the singapore kind of
genetic type idea genetic algorithm type idea if feeling good basically original display that means
you weight you're going to basically be given multiple copies if you in a region
where you have lo just forget you your child essentially that's what we're going to
so that's the idea
are really it's gone you can think of is congressional act you try to focus
on the promising original of the space
so we tried to do that basically in a bit more principled frameworks instead of
trying to
it mean deterministically particles with low weights on the black particle evaluates the slides i'm
a little bit subtle so
assume you are time
then on that you like is which is like a sequential importance sampling algorithm so
you have an approximation
basically at time and of the target distribution and we see the weighted
essentially so
of that time as OK
all these women are positive and sum to one
well what do you do
so as to get rid of particles with low weights on the black particles by
well simply wasn't going to do
you're can result paul capital and time
for this
basically distribution
so this thing you can think of it as the discrete distribution of OK
so what you're going to do
you saw core resource for capital n times
these distributions
so i was basically to obtain new distribution
which is of this form OK so
that seems to be crazy you multicolour approximation of the target on what to do
you do a further approximation by resampling capital and time from this
essentially a weighted empirical measure so as to obtain
the new approximation of the target distribution OK
something you should mention obviously
basically when you do we sample from the distribution because the distribution is discrete in
this basically new
approximation of the target distribution
you can basically particles
XI which i call two xj for i from from g because you might have
so we can discuss a lot of this experiment i'm not sure we have time
today so i would just insist on these how can we determine the size of
the atomic nucleus from this experiment
as the first estimate
you have to consider the popu elastic scattering that go back
and you had at the distance is zero and the kinetic energy of the alpha
but you know because it's already at the beginning of given worse
so which is equal to the coulomb repulsion here
so then you know exactly this is zero based distance and with this experiment they
had discovered that the size of the school nucleus
it is around ten minus forty meters
so if we compare the scale with the atomic nucleus
you see that you have
under a thousand times
and it is a hundred thousand times smaller than at home
as i told you this nucleus is made of z protons and neutrons what we
call the nucleons
we characterize the nucleus based mass which is the sum of neutron and proton number
and its atomic number z
so we write it like these
so now the question do
the nuclei all the same ranges
in fact no
here are some
the results were you have to register and family depending on the mass number a
whirlwind foot in some of the proton and neutron
and you see that you have different points from carbon twelve
too late late
that seems to be that are
along the straight line
and you can find this relation
air force one one twenty five
in one the family
so this is a very important feature that the radius increases with a one
so it means that the volume
of the nucleus increases with the number of particles
and this is similar to what we would drop of liquid where you have the
volume that is proportional to the number of molecules and this is one of the
reasons why
you will see that in a second course white people of food that in case
can be interpreted as the fluid liquid drop
so if not
we compare the scale all the thing
so this is the size in matrix with the mass kilogram you are here
ten minus fourteen fifteen
four nuclei nuclear arms
if you go to tony minus my man matt one
and then starts to cluster
support can add two
very huge sort of the cluster
so the nucleons nuclei are really the first stage
in this hierarchy of complex systems
so massive
i'm sure you know that very well
just to remind yourself
but i neutrons problems that they are made of three quarks
they have almost the same as
which is around nine hundred thirty eight any which is two thousand times
bigger than the mass of the electron
so that's why
if the rutherford experiment
these out for particular really don't know these electrodes
to compare with something we
we feel better is mass of the proton is ten minus twenty seven kilograms
so now you know that in in any case it's made of proton and neutron
that do interact so these interaction the strong interaction you have here is interaction
the strong interaction is very intense and of short range
it is amazing isn't it
and you have here is
well we're
the same
these is
i thought i knew
one hundred
after all
by the way
the error rate
where we are
and he
related to
they will
during the right
so all of the world and
for each
you is know i good i
the goal of my life that i will
also you
on the
what i
well he
so what
between you know point one point nine
and everything is bound in the worst possible
but the story is not so nice when you when you log probability
arbitrarily close to zero is still pretty bad things to be pretty large
right your question
if you think about it that way
one way to think about this is
here's the technique
taking any classifier learning algorithm and extracting
because probability a posterior probability
which is maybe not so obvious you can do when
is predicting
either zero or one that something in the interval
all right
so the reason why i'm a lot of this
it is because they can under these
and can compute this
but what you really want to say that this
minus actual probability
is small
in this kind of cool
which is
the are equivalent
the semantic constant
and that the constant is is there for every classifier to the same constant
so roughly speaking
and it is
your plug in the probability of
minus the actual observed y squared to expectation
the and cystatin c
and that's what
the only difference between these two things
OK so that's the problem
and then maybe we want to
i think a little bit about what i wanted to probability sometimes
you know there's a lot of situations we don't want to probability
you want to make some predictions prediction annually the you that prediction tells you what
to do
and the do
you don't have
but there are times when probabilistic and requires
one of them is
now when talking to the doctor
maybe it doesn't want to be unemployed so
if you prefer that
next time probability in existence about what to do
rather than having classifier tell actually do
and then another situation comes up this
sometimes you have
a lot of
data sources which is spread out all over the place
and maybe it's expensive to communicate
between the different places are summarized
the probability of y given x from each individual sensors
and then somewhere later you have use them so instead of
instead of transmitting all information
every location to one location
is transmitted the probability
from one location to central location
and they can be arbitrarily t
these comes up is because you should want compatibility you what you want to think
here's one component systems using perturbation technique and his american-born systems using classify technique and
now maybe one extraction of probabilistic predictions you can
in kenya few things in the right way
the reason
how does this technique were some call technique roving
so this is the basic observation it starts things off
which is that if you have a perfect classifier
and perfect classifier is one
o thing
the probability of y equals one given x is greater than point five
you go that's interesting
what if
i picked some
random uniform random variable between zero and one
make this importance weighted transformation
so i can create an importance weighted dataset
the importance of being
why minus p so if y zero minutes p and flies one minus p
and then you can
think about that bit
and you realize that
if classifier
for this importance weighted
it's perfect
that implies that one class versus one
the probability white was one given x is greater p
so is a predictor is approved
in one table
so if the prediction is
expected so the importance is going to be
and the probability is zero is minus a one given x
and the prediction is one important is one minus p
problem like probably like this one x
and these two are equal
he calls
this probably like this one given x
in the system that are taking the sign which works
it has four campuses about that case first
it is just
thank you for this analysis doesn't matter
you can take it
take it however you want
o point three point two whatever
in this this analysis holds the statement always holds
and the question about how we actually do it
and they will be taking a randomly
or maybe take it from the grid but
sort of and yes
but this is
the one of them is likely to do so the question is is
how do you know the first project
the answer is you don't
but it some tricks which all
or alright so
is probably our them
this is sort of the data flow graph
you start with your binary data set the top
and then you choose mps
however you want
and then you create an importance weighted datasets
and then you have a prior importance weighted learning algorithm
fancy creek that would
you know you know i think it might work at the university
for some reason to work anymore
i mean really wants
what scary
like this one
it's written
i mean it's your personal thing and taking on account of what else this is
the kid in the forward backward with it
are trying to the
you can use to get
the only difference is that now i have to been involved
all right
so for you to always works
his only i
how many of you have solved one or more problems
how many have sort of two or more
three or more
four more
how many have some of the first one
is that
the the first of all sorry for this problem is this one
how many have solved it well enough that they could come on the show is
the solution to your in front
i think most of you probably OK we have a volunteer
thank you
which is you can choose any color any black box
the right
but give you
why should
of showing this one of the positive DNA the dying
she was the
we know that
if you can use this
it believed to more
OK thank you very much so you get you get the point
the so
and the surprising thing here so
so you're solving this optimisation problem in the reproducing kernel hilbert space associated with k
which could be an infinite dimensional space for goes into this process surprising thing is
not the solution has
kernel expansion but the surprising thing is that the kernel expansion is centered on the
training points
so we know already from yesterday
the construction of the reproducing kernel hilbert space the space that effectively all points in
that space have this kind of form
plus some limit points but we didn't
i mean normally in this expansion we could have arbitrary points from my input domain
so here the surprising thing of this
theorem is that the solution only depends on current sitting on the training points in
the training set is a finite set so even if you solve this optimisation problem
if dimensional space
this tells you the solution
really only needs
finally many alfie's if you wanted to compute the solution you only have to optimize
these many coefficients i phi
and the nice thing about theorems that it's very easy to prove the above
i will actually show you the truth
OK so the proof works as follows we first of all decompose
f into a part in the span
of our
kernel sitting and training points and into part which is orthogonal
so this kind of thing can be done we are in the space so it's
it's nice to have the products where you can do things like that we have
things like orthogonality
so we can decompose
possible candidate solutions into two such parts
since this part is orthogonal
the span of the training points we know that for all the training points of
sorry for falcon sitting and training points this equality holds true
so now we apply
this general function
we haven't lost a gender as yet to an arbitrary training point
if we do that so how do we evaluate point function in an RKHS on
training point we just take the dot product with the representer of evaluation which is
the concept on that point
so we do that we plug in
our general form of function
in into here
now we can use linearity of the product
so we have the product of this thing
with this term which i written down here and we have the product of thing
which is zero by assumption
so we left only with this part here
the crucial thing and this problem is that independent of the orthogonal part
OK so if we evaluate
the function f at an arbitrary point
for of the training set solution will be independent of this thing here so therefore
this first part
which only depend on f through the training points
is independent of the orthogonal part
on the other hand if we look at the second term
of the objective function so
now we have shown that if our solution f as
and some nonzero orthogonal components in this orthogonal the component will not affect the first
part of our objective function in the second part of the proof will actually show
that if we have a non zero components it will only increase this
population inference
we need to do inference
around nineteen
no matter what you do
this one
the value of the marginal likelihood of what you need to do is just
marginal likelihoods
friends and if you want the actual results
different to our friends
this is an operation you have to have code for
you object to the best of the
and it is
he can be in a position to write code for the discrete ricci flow inference
the inference was right because have to
so he said all the things that are added do that in the end that
just involves called here are
the language so this is essentially no more work
and you are asking
and we're going to use this procedure monotonically improves life
so always converges to a local optimum of the likelihood
as indeed you are going to
the right wrong
so this optimisation strategy for objective functions can be interpreted like its present
yes it is not an objective function is
but maximum wage
it's just not the end
march mixture gases
you should say
training you
you actually trading psychology
so this just an optimisation and
it is clever
but there's nothing that says
this is the crucial slide so
if you have nothing to do with this proposition
but this explains
i gets really offended
this that turns off and six
it said about
OK that's OK i'm about of this year
so this slide open systems
this might explains the way in which you can use
the algorithm to optimize likelihood
and and what it does is it is actually working
the figure
what it does is it defines a quantity called the expected complete log likelihood
so this complete log likelihood here is the likelihood function that we would get if
we knew the latent variables
so it's just if we evaluate the likelihood of the model at a specific set
of data x and a specific set of latent variables
OK now for any distribution over the latent variables we can define something called the
expected complete log likelihood
which is if we sample the latent variables
from this distribution q
and then building those latent variables alongside our data and evaluate the log likelihood on
average what log likelihood what we get
so this is just some quantity which is the
the expected complete
likelihood under the model you would get if you were generating hidden variables
from this distribution q
OK now i i told think about the distribution q maybe it's
the distribution maybe it's very similar to the true posterior it doesn't matter but for
any distribution q we can write down the
and the amazing fact is that this quantity
can be used to create band on the like
so this is like for my calculation but we're going through so is just area
here is the marginal likelihood is the
they can explore the probability of x
and that is you know a lot of this sort of problem in this
inside the summation of all point by the distribution
q of variables
so by multiplying by about the same thing certain changing his brain
and now
what i'm going do is i'm going to rewrite this
distribution here
as the
first order of the law in this in this reversal of the order of log
some expensive and is making is crucial quality content and called
so i can never remember jensen's inequality goes
whether it's the of the sum is greater than or less than the sum of
but this to will be remembered so there's a lot
and what i'm telling you is that if you take any two points on the
and you take internal combination of
so in interior sound
the sum of those log values is always less than
the log evaluated sun
so once you
so imagine that these are the two values
and want
if i had raised their blogs
is it going to be
more or less than fighting towards the average
here's the to and you to lot at time this picture convince you that for
any average to one average in feature combinations
the average of their lives is always about what happens
now this picture also tells you something else which is easy to forget
if i take an exterior combination extend this line here
this inequality no longer blocks
so please do do not try to to apply this inequality when q is distribution
it uses a set of positive numbers
don't someone want to apply to replicate it extends line here doesn't work so use
you can see that the average velocity of the west
one of of the and that's we get this thing
o three practical use to you
o is algorithms that are present very easy to implement men fifty minutes
really something useful so in the first section i will talk about
spatiotemporal features and the classification
of cells and in particular about shrinkage of the covariance matrix
because of the
explain that and the application that i wish to demonstrate these algorithms is classification of
single trial he's in
attention this fellow
every short some some background is needed to understand the application
so if
it is defined as
presented this is a sequence of stimuli and two types of stimuli one the
presented called standard stimuli and the other type is infrequently
presented that's called the
and that this subject is attending and waiting this infrequent stimuli the specific components
evoked most prominently the p three hundred of p street
which is the positive peak approximately three hundred twenty seconds after stimulus presentation and it's
century and earlier this also negative component and one
and on the other hand if there a visual stimulation
and the participants focuses on the stimulus in the
presentation of the stimulus elicits visual evoked potential which
maybe two components for
according to p one second and one
true positive negative component
one hundred milliseconds after the stimulus presentation and this
the visual cortex accepted
so and based on these components this very well-known classic matrix speller
proposed by don't you use very much in
BCI research
if you
i want to start to be for example in this case new concentrate on the
letter b
and then randomly rows and columns
flash intensified
it's an
kind of what experiment is introduced before so so then they infrequent stimulus type is
the presentation of a stimulus value attention to so in this case the column that
contains to be on the road
containsa b
and the stimuli intensification of other of some kind
so we expect
p three hundred only after presentation of the target drone target kind
in one study that you can
find more details about the poster w seven hundred years later
he compares the classic as well as the something
new that
it is based on the text of the idea
the government has introduced already but no in the visual attention based paradigms
so it is quite similar to this again if you want to the
the two steps to concentrate on
as i said that contains the group
and in
circus flesh and random sequence
if this group is selected then
these five letters of the group
ninety five
two this layout and then the next time
then i concentrate on the e
so that they can be selected
this is that is
caesar's this post comes passes two
better designs and also
comparison of it against
covert attention
so this is in the data set being used to illustrate
the average
for the success rate
spell out
and these are the pieces of this is just an average over
after stimulation of the target
so circulant non targets
then you see in the occipital area p one n one
number of
a small number of very rich people and a high number of poor people then
the slope would be
this would be a this is again graph from MSN messenger
so the number of people
a particular person these talks to on microsoft messenger so you would have
number of people so on
here it is
this is in degree so
a small number of
people would be
a very high number of people would have just a little bit of colleagues on
the on the messenger in
some people would have also
thousands of people which they talk to on so this is
extracted from the
so probably this is done by this is generated from the data and then you
have also these bots which
are not people but they use are still registered users so this is
now let's see if has
about the for me it was not obvious
for me to meet has one of the nice bot which talks to his friends
related topic to this small world is also
long tail so the concept of long tail you might know from
so we got popular this book one of the things
the that long tail was published
from chris anderson i think which is
editor-in-chief of wired magazine so the idea is the following
but if we take amazon
and here we have the
both but with the end this the curve of the states
this would be the peak of the most popular the most popular books which amazon
or any other store
is selling
very much these companies can store
these books in march in the bookstore and so if
they have a bookstore then it would be able to store just does this speak
because at some point you cannot store any more and more than a certain amount
of books in in a bookstore and this will be the long tail the long
tail of books which are
less popular research less relevant for the masses
and also in terms of sales of business among them less relevant but so what's
m is on
makes for even we have the proper science so that the percentage so this would
be what
forty three percent from the
from the peak
the most popular and most so fifty seven percent of all the sets with come
from the long tail
so this is something which which is internet economy brought somehow which reachability of this
long tail and this long tail appears as relatively important concept in many
how successful applications nowadays including wikipedia and everything and so this is kind of underlying
reason for the success of many many applications
including the companies like amazon and so on so
this is well good to know
OK here we have
a few more features of the
networks like
network asylum so this is something which which is relevant from another perspective so we
observe here
clinic DVD of
this never change as if we remove certain vertices
that's a good application is so epidemics starting epidemics
now the question is
i think that he plus one is that minus it that he
times gt right so we can plug that in your
just expanded out
now this first term if you stare at it long enough and hard enough you'll
see that it's actually just land of the key
now we get this
this second term we
we use the product rule
of calculus to split it up
into this partial
and this partial
for the second time i make an approximation
so this is now approximate but i'm not going to justify here it's a reasonable
approximation the second term becomes just a thirty times
and this third term now
is it thirty times
the partial of the gradient with respect to the past
if we we can now use the chain rule as before to split that into
the partial of the gradient with respect to the parameters
and and that is just the haitian the matrix of second derivatives
the partial of the parameters with respect to the log
and now
this phase without the haitian here just land to be i times this
is exactly
what we said is lambda the key
so we wind up with
so out of all the gory maths comes as a nice compact little update equation
it's a simple iterative update it allows us when we have the key to compute
t plus one
at time zero easier is just the room so it's easy to start up
and it's moves
correctly over multiple time steps in and also allows you to handle correlated input signals
which is something that really screws up
the algorithm that just uses pt times TT minus one you can imagine that if
that algorithm gets short-term correlated data
that it will disorder correlation will really be wrong
the measures
a property of the data instead of a property of your optimisation trajectory
the one thing that a bit more some in this update is
this HPV t right this is the haitian times
the vector v
the haitian is an n by n matrix if all search space has an dimensions
so this normally doing this naively
calculating the haitian is order in square multiplying it with the vector also ordered square
so it seems that now we're down here in this realm of of expensive algorithms
and this is not where i want to be
it turns out fortunately
taking its product with the vector of your choice
the only
sheep operations you can perform on the haitian
that's very fortuitous
course the whole algorithm is designed to exploit that
this is sort of a bit of magic and i cannot explain it in great
but for those who know calculus i can i can motivated a little bit
what basically happens is
it's done through differentials differentials
i sort of hasan's two
partial derivatives
derivatives are chained backwards through a function was differentials change forward so
one way to think of differential is it's
it's a perturbation an infinitesimal perturbations
and when you calculate with differentials you calculate how such a perturbation propagates
through a function
if we take a simple example lets say you know if i got the bad
f of x
sin x plus exquisite something
really silly right
now we say we apply a perturbation
two that function
so we
what we're basically
asking is well what is
the f of x
what is the perturbation of the function value
and i want an expression for that now in terms of x and dx which
is the
perturbation of the input
the way you can
do this algebraically is these differentials these days obey the same rules as gradients
in terms of calculus so there's the product rule this the chain rule
that's the rule that any linear
operator it you can just commute with so
i won't do it in detail here but
it will look very familiar to you if i seen on the of perfect
cosine x
and px
two x
now you know this this is called scientist
the derivative of sin two x is the derivative of x square this is just
the chain rule
sorry i should say this is two x
it winds up being sign x
plus two x which is just the derivative
of this function
and dx
so it's just a prime xtx
OK so it's just sort of a standard algebraic manipulations the only thing is you
using differentials where you know what everybody learns in
in first calculus course is
derivatives which work the other way round
so now here's the magic tricks if
i ask
what is
the differential
of the gradient g
one of my parameters
by this argument it's actually
she prime
of the ten times the theatre
ng prime is the haitian so this is a haitian
that's an important difference and the second difference that actually for large residuals so you see here that
the distribution is also much not in this case not much but it's wider
than the two norm distribution so there's some large residuals that are larger than the
largest residuals for the two norm
so it's a wider distribution and you have this high peak at the origin
so these two features are both useful
so the first one that is
is of course used in sparse optimization heuristics if you want a regularization
term that encourages sparsity in a vector X then the one norm is much more useful
than the two norm
so in this application of course it's not surprising that if you have eighty
variables and randomly generated A that you can make eighty of the residuals at exactly zero it's not very
difficult but you might you could imagine an application where B is actually
equal to A X
and then an unknown number of values of B were corrupted by noise
and then you would like to find a solution X that satisfies many of
the equations exactly it's zero error
then this will be much more useful than the two norm
it won't give you exactly the solution with the maximum number of
equations that are satisfied exactly
it won't give you the sparsest vector of residuals but it'll give you typically a
very sparse
so the behavior at the origin is actually very useful for sparse optimization the
the fact that it's a wider distribution
is useful in robust regression
and of course the fact that its wider comes from the fact that the
absolute value penalty
increases much more slowly for large values of residuals the the quadratic penalty
so there's a smaller relatively smaller penalty on very large residuals than for the
quadratic penalty
that's the
no no it's a fixed matrix I selected the matrix A
and a vector B
then I solved these two problems
and obtained two solutions X
the least squares solution and the one norm solution and then this is the distribution of the
residuals in a vector AX minus B
so AX minus B is a vector of length two hundred you have two hundred errors and those two hundred equations
and this is the distribution around
so roughly speaking you would like to you minimize the norm of the vector in
order to make all the residuals as small as possible
but you have two hundred residuals
that you minimize by single scalar objective
and you see that the distribution of the residuals
for the two solutions X is actually very different
and depending on your application you might prefer one or the other
because of this difference in distributions
yeah so this has a large number of zeros typically the one norm will encourage sparsity
in this case in the vector AX minus B
and a second important difference is that it's a much wider distribution
than the two norm
and the second property is used in robust regression
you've probably seen this suppose you want to fit a straight line to points
but there are some outliers there's a point here and here then the two norm which is en dashed
lined will be rotated toward these ourliers
whereas if you minimize the one norm you minimize the sum of the absolute values of the
differences between the points and the line then you get something that almost ignores these
two outliers and gives you this straight approximation
so that uses the fact that the one norm is much more robust against
or can tolerate a few large errors
so I think you're all familiar with linear discrimination and support vector machines of course that's
a very nice application of linear programming suppose you have two sets of points X I
and Y I and you try to find a hyperplane that strictly separates the two
then you can write that as a set of linear inequalities
so you have strict separation the variables are A and B so the normal vector of the hyperplane and
the offsets but because it's
you can replace the right-hand side by one and then use a nonstrict inequality
and you can write it like this
if the points are not separable
you can
try to find a hyperplane that approximately separates the two points by minimizing this kind of
penalty it's
an piece-wise linear function of the variables A and B
so for each
points X Y or Y I you have a penalty of zero if the point is on the right
side of the hyperplane and otherwise you have a penalty that's proportional to the
difference to the hyperplane
so you can
interpret as a non symmetric version of this
so here you have a penalty on the residuals
if you use the absolute value that's symmetric so suppose you actually want to minimize the max
minimize the number of maximize the number of zeros in the vector
so you really want to minimize the cardinality of this vector then the ideal penalty function would be
zero at the origin and one for nonzero
and then there's some of those penalty functions will be the number of nonzero
two we continue discussing basically the class sequential monte carlo methods so what we do
is essentially yesterday basically consider the following problem given target distribution pi x only one
visit the port use some samples approximate distributed according to x on one of the
still not possible to do that
basically instead in computational statistics is to build a markov chain to use markov chain
monte carlo techniques so my multicolour techniques are treaty right or is basically to produce
samples from a given target distribution to know what i'm considering noise the deform problem
which is so in some ways spectral little bit more challenging because what i'm trying
to do is that i'm trying to obtain so paul from sequence of target distribution
pi events so each physically target distribution is known up to a normalizing constant on
basically those target distribution defined a sequence of spaces of increasing dimensions so you by
one that if and only if x one y two x one x two on
cell and so forth when i want to have an algorithm that portis sequentially approximate
sample of pi one that approximate sample of by two and so on and so
forth and this is what i want to do
two she that basically
this is going to rely essentially on iterative algorithms such an MCMC so essentially what
i'm doing and using out it like stone multicolour techniques which is known in the
literature as importance sampling so it it work involves hoping when you're interested in a
given in approximating given
o point two distributions pyrex OK
then well it properly paul force it is very similar essentially to a rejection sampling
in the sense that you do introduce
proposal distribution importance distribution qx with support includes the support of five x on what
you do some more capital in time from q of x you've picked two x
so that it's easy to forty samples from it that provide you've basically
multicellular approximation of qx on then you basically used the fact that prior based on
the express essentially is the weighted version of qx you substitute basically qx substitutes multicellular
approximation all you obtain essentially
now approximation of pi of x as the weighted basically combination convex combination of that
that york mass located at basically the particle location i which are sampled from q
x you also obtain an approximation of the normalizing constant
which is not which is not something you do can obtain easily when you're doing
so this is very easy matter to use OK i told you basically the problem
with it unfortunately is that it doesn't scale it doesn't scale in the sense that
as soon as you're dealing with actually i dimensional problem in defiance of u estimate
increases exponentially with the dimension
stephen for the timing we gonna limit also have to to importance sampling of basically
later we present to show explicitly of it's possible to reduce drastically the violence of
this important something is made by using a simple trick OK
so for the time being what i want to do what i'm going to do
is essentially
come three
describe an importance sampling techniques
which can be implemented sequentially on the computer in england sampling technique that would provide
me with approximation
of the sequence of target distribution pi and on basically approximation of the normalising associated
normalising constants
so the way policy is very simple
your time one
on essentially time one which you're interested in approximating is the target distribution
pi one OK
on its associated normalizing constant first iteration what you do you use absolutely the story
about essentially importance sampling
i think that is you introduce
nine poland density that we denote you are on what you do use onboard captain
the sampled from q one OK that give you a multicolour approximation of q one
of you substitute that into the importance sampling identity
OK which is where
as your recall there on that provide with approximation of pi one basically
weighted a convex combination of that that york mass on an approximation of the associated
normalizing constant OK will remember that the weights w one of x one is a
measure of discrepancy between the target distribution pi while on tour OK so that's at
iteration one what you do is basically stand on the importance sampling so as to
approximate by one
comes time to
all that time to you interested knowing approximating anymore
pi one you're interested essentially in approximating i basically the emotional point distribution which is
OK i need to present arguments x one x two OK
if i want to use importance sampling to approximate this target distribution
i need to introduce an important distribution due to which depends on two arguments x
one x two
no basically if i were to do that so we set time two
basically what i do i need to produce new samples from q two so as
to approximate by two then basically typically the computational time with decrease with time index
because you have to sample at time and you would like to approximate by and
of x one x two xn so you would have to introduce the importance distribution
qn of x one x two xn you would have to sample an increasing number
of volleyball because the dimension of the target point distribution increased OK so you want
to be lazy and to say all basically have already done some work at time
to time one because at time warner generate it's essentially some component x one according
to q one OK
so what i want to do is essentially i want to recycle
the song
the multicellular sample
that that generated from q one at time one basically to build my importance sampling
approximation of pi two
OK so essentially you some of multicolored sample at time one you want to reuse
so approximation techniques
so let's talk about the training media support vector machines for
so need is a function here
so this is not in the original space
so this is
standard bayesian approach
when saw it is the solution is one is selected variables so this is going
to satisfy this condition is maximum of lots
we must not believe is of course true because we have we now named the
whole to see that it must be maximum
most is this is a variable able to the right hand side
so it is going to articles one minus the flight
it is greater than this
so we know it is greater than this but not only that
even if it is positive so if this is possible
so that means for example in the states minus five
it's my so even more minus five for the right hand side so that six
sort there should be grocery equal six but you really want to use six w
seven or eight years later
so why because you
this certainly in the objective function
you are minimizing the summation of selected variables
so you in a situation where you
you want to make this inequality can be any to be equal to the equality
so that the change the objective is smaller
so that's why i'm actually there is such a relationship
we can source the so we actually read write
the primal SVM problem in different way
is to be that these so we actually want to select variable we don't believe
that because it's already these already selected variables
and the reason why i write this problem to being useful is not easy to
see that
he the number of variables
so so for this optimisation problem one thing is the number of variables is the
same as number of features one
one is for this day this is the city's only scalar variable we plus one
here and the size of data is the same as the number of features
so the number of variables is justice
let me even the number of features is small
it's not very even very large data sets
but the number of features is small then
yes it is probably still
there's many variables is not
according to these the number of variables is thing that says that you have to
two two
in a situation the easy to so that
it's not going to
the details of how to solve these kind of things but
consensually now because of
fewer number of variables then they should be easy
so we can apply traditional optimisation is is directly applying traditional optimisation this to minimize
these image that this is not the just small her
maximize the zero something so this is not differentiable so
you can use
we thus was optimisation techniques
they also quite standard optimisation but also seems for use regular news
they don't going to design a anything this is just traditional once a day
some of them can be directly used and
OK so very large
well it's training similar to missus which is the largest croatian is also in the
culture minimisation
so you quite similar to traditional optimisation missus in the training time is
well then the question is what even the number of features
also the number of instances of course very large with this is changing case
so now we know the number of training instances is large and also the dimensionality
number of features is large then
it is
quite difficult
i think existing new you can use to handle many millions of
o point
running after several hours or days
if you have you know the analysis where
and that's the problem
it allows make sure that the problem of this because document
problems with respect to model so the number of features is actually a large
and you will see a lot of documents in the last century situation that is
quite difficult
OK so
let's so you have another equation
because we use decomposition process to solve
two so that the sphere
the reason to use it because of handling memory problems
but if you say oh i don't want to software packages one twenty years here
and another fourteen years you can can decomposition this is still so
large is the problem
well there are several difficulties
we can show even a number of features
is small that if you use decomposition this is
when this season large overseas the penalty parameter introduced the objective function learning is very
slow convergence that is very small as it is only like this seven hundred instances
now we are using a k two hundred sixty so many iterations to finish the
decomposition procedure so this is not good
so we can resolve projects
and this one is maybe ten or ten features or something and we're using the
you so we don't we use kernel home
so what is happening right now is we have we have a kernel matrix to
be like is so i j component of the kernel is the inner product
so this is a bi l matrix and the number of training instances ring
because of these the rate features or the number of features is small so the
rank is actually a very very small number so the
so it's so not like you use and armenia kernels like RDF
you get you get a positive definite kernel design is is smaller and you only
have positive side
kernel matrix
we suspect that because such kind of
the optimisation problem is more you conditions so four coordinate wise minimisation convergence is very
and these gamma functions are basically well they're called gamma functions and they're given by
this integral okay
basically that's the normalization constants so Dirichlet distributions are used all over the
place in probabilistic modeling and the main reason for that is be basically that
is the standard distribution for probability vectors and this is due to the
a fact that they are conjugate to the multinominal
distribution and particularly conjugate to discrete distributions
just to visualize what these densities look like okay if the
so here's the Dirichlet density down here
where I've kind of generalized is to one where alpha here is a vector
where every entry is positive okay
so that alpha that's a typo
should be distribute k goes to one to big k of pi k raise to the alpha k minus one
and when alpha is
a vector ones so that's the vector ones then we see that this part
here's gonna be pi k raise to the one minus one and that's just gonna be
pi k raise to the zero and that's just gonna be one okay
and what that says is that the Dirichlet is gonna be a uniform distribution
over the probability simplex
when alpha is
greater than one so for example if it's two two two
the Dirichlet distribution is gonna be a unimodel distribution
with a
with a mean given by basically this vector normalized okay so the mean is gonna be one
third one third one third
and the total mass of the alpha here basically describes how concentrated the
the mode is
around the
so when alpha is five five five then we see that the that distribution's
more concentrated around its mean
here okay and if the alpha factor is not symmetric so for example as two five five
the more it gets shifted off the centre of the probability simplex to one of the
edges or
to a corner here
and more interestingly if the alphas are less than one then we see that instead of
unimodel distribution we have a multimodal distribution where we have high probability around the
corners and low probability in the centre of the probability simplex okay
so that's just
it's a visualization of what the Dirichlet distribution is
right so as I say
the Dirichlet distribution is kind of all over the place in probabilistic modeling mainly because its
conjugate to the multinominal right
let's see how this
conjugacy work okay
if you look at the joint's distribution over the pri over pi and the in
cluster indicated variables z okay so that's the prior that's
the conditional probability of each z i given pi okay
so the prior is given by this Dirichlet
the conditional probabilities we could collect up
in into a term like this so basically every time z i takes on value k
then we're gonna have a pi k contribution and and n k is the number of
z ies that take on value k okay
so we can so if there're n keys and ies that take on value k then
we basically have pi k raise to the n k times right
and this is over k from one to big k
and you can see that the conditional probability of the z vector here
and the pri the Dirichlet prior on pi they kind of have a similar functional
form and if you actually multiply this two probabilities together you get the joint's probability
it's gonna be this normalization times product k goes to one to big k of pi k raise to the
alpha divided by k plus n k minus one rigth
and so if you normalize this
so that you get the posterior distribution of pi given z then we see that
posterior distribution will also be a Dirichlet okay but with parameters updated
by n k
well the marginal distribution over the z vector here we have computed by basically taking
the ratio of these probabilities okay
so the basically
yeah so if you take the
joints divided by the posterior you get the marginal probability okay
and the fact that I can write down both of these equations says that both
Sergio Verd is the
Eugene Higgins Professor of Electrical Engineering at Princeton University
and he is one of the premier informationtheoristsof our time.
Sergiois probably best known for his work on multi-user detection, which is
fundamental and critical to modern wireless communications.
He has made fundamental contributions to
information theory
in its fundamentals in terms of finding the capacity of several classes of important channels
that are
critical in modern wireless communication systems
and he has also
developed and uncovered some surprising and very cool connections between
mean square error estimation and mutual information and I think he's
going to tell us a little bit about some of thattoday.
Sergio has
too many awards and accoladestomention
all ofthem, unless I took up his entire slot
but I'll mention just a few
he is a Fellow of theIEEE
he received theIEEEThirdMillenniumMedal in2000
theClaude Shannon Awardin2007, and Ithink he was one of the
people ever to receive that honor
and he received theRichard HammingMedal in2008
and on a personal note
Sergio is from
andhecan probably find the best coffee
inPrinceton, if you ask him where to go
Sergio,thank you again
and take it away.
WellI'd like to find the best coffee inVancouver, then.
It's probably not too difficult.
So it's a great pleasure to be here. Thank you for the invitation to address
this audience. I had heard a lot of good things about this conference but actually
never had the opportunity to be here, so it's a special pleasure to be
the first talk in the conference. So
what I'm going to do here. As you can tell from the title this is going
to be a very wide audience talk.
It's early in the morning, we're not going to get into mathematics, it's going to
be mainly an historical overview,
touching on some of the big problems that relative entropy has found itself
itself useful.
So here's thedefinition,to start with the definition of relative entropy.
You can tell immediately that, this of course P andQare probability distributions, you can tell
immediately that ifPis equal toQ
then this relative entropy
is equal to zero.
You cannot tell immediately that
if P
it is not equal toQ
that this relative entropy is actually going to be non-zero because
this is an expectation here
is the expectation of a quantity that can be either positive or negative.
OK, so
specially some mathematicians prefer to use an alternative representation where you take the expectation
with respect to
reference measure, theQ
rather than theP
and this actually turns out to be perhaps more natural in some...
...in some applications.
the most important cases of course the discrete case and the continuous case, when both
P and Q...I should say,
it's very important that P and Q
have to be distributions defined on the same
set,on the same measurable space.
So, if this space is finite or is countably infinite then we have this representation
we talk about
guassian processes for the next couple hours
so i wanna start by saying that gas processes are
a mathematical object with
with a great history and theory
and also has are or something that's been used to good effect in quite a number of applications
and we're not going to focus on either those two pieces specifically but rather talk
about the peace in the middle which is which is a
from from usability context how as machine learners can we use custom processes
so here's how we're gonna go about introducing gas processes i wanna start with talking
about gasses in general both in words and pictures this is just going to be
ceremony's introduction into this so we can think about
we can think about what a guassian process actually is from intuitive perspective
and then we'll go and build out somebody equations
we'll talk about using gas and processes in a basic regressions setting
there will be they'll get is about to first hour
and then we'll take will take a quick break and then we'll come back and we'll think about
moving beyond the basics of gas in processes so what kind of things can we change
well connected to some of the different technologies machine learning that we've seen and out
just about that
right so what is a guassian as far as machine learning is concerned this tions somebody
notions bayesian inference that you've seen in the last couple days
a gas in a gas in distribution is essentially a handy tool four bayesian inference on real valued variables
here's here's a here's the specific example i'm gonna talk about
throughout the course this i'm interested in measuring my heart rate
so how how might do this for modeling modeling perspective and i'm here and a
measure my heart rate at seven am and the fact that i do the indexed
by time is gonna be important and we're going to see that in a moment
okay so
i'm a reasonably healthy guys you might think
okay up three i have some belief about what my heart rate is gonna be
when i measured seventy seven animated somewhere between fifty and sixty beats so i put
some gas in
some guassian prior on and there's a density
knocking can go in on a particular morning and i can measure my heart rate measured at sixty one
i can go in a couple of days and i can measure the three three more times
so now i've got these fore
observations these four noisy observations and measurements four different days my heart rate
and what the gas allows you do what the notion bayesian inference allows you to
is i can then take my prior this great distribution
and those four draws from guassian
and i can do posterior inference i can call the exterior this up my underlying
heart rate given the noisy observations they seem you see that's again a guassian
i now have more confidence about where that is and i see that in fact
it's it's centered around say
sixty sixty two
let's take a at
univerity in case and move up to multi very guessing so we talked about
measure my heart rate at seven am
i could also
one measure my heart rate at eight am
and let's think about how
how those observations and not just a single real valued variable but rather a pair
of numbers at seven and eight am
i would change so to do we can use the same univariate gas and we
want move up to a multivariate gas there should be an objective hour of familiar
now the multi very guessing where you can actually look at has these
a flat surfaces ellipsoids f of
i so probability
and so what is this distribution telling us this distribution is telling us now got some prior belief
not on on a single heart rate measurement put on a pair of heart rate measurements
it shows that there are some positive correlation which is the same if i measure
if you've got a higher rate is seven am i imagine will be higher at eight am
and so that we can do the same thing so here's our prior
i can go in and take four measurements on four different days
number these measurements now apparent numbers seven and eight am
so i can get the data
i can use bayes rule in the same way
and come up with some posterior inference
and now i have i have a refined belief
of what what my heart rate is seven eight am
that is a closed loop current here
i want
and that is a closed loop current here i two
when i make them clockwise or counterclockwise
on important i could have chosen one clockwise the other counter-clockwise on import
however once i choose the direction has consequences as you will see
and that's all there running
one current like this
and one current independently like that
if i assume that and i have automatically
automatically i am well being the second
rule because current
that goes around
charge conservation right is no charge piling
so the second
the rule of kish of
is already obeid
so now i go to the first one
and i can start now at any point in that circuit
and go around
i can go around clockwise angle run counterclockwise it makes no difference as long as
i return to the same point
that integral utility on this is
i'm returning at the same potential
one is the in the
of e
don't pl
in going from point one to point two
well that's the potential difference between point one and point two
so let's start here
and let's go around
and we have to adopt to certain convention namely
if you go up in potential we go down in potential again you free to
the sign convention but i would say
when i go up potential i give the the plus sign
when i go down in potentially give that a minus sign
i start here
i could have started their career started there makes no difference as long as they
don't start here that makes no sense
so i start here
and i go around like this
so right here i go down potential
v one
so i get minus the one
now i go was current i one in the direction
from left to right
so that means that the potential must be higher than their
the because i are
potentially must be higher than there so i go down in potential so i get
mine is i one hour one
now those who are three
this current i one
is going down
this has a higher potential than here so i go down in potential
so i get minus
i one
and are free
i have independently
the current i two which is now coming towards me
when i go down
and so if it comes towards me
that current
but give me an increase in potential this would have to have a higher potential
than this
what is current to do this
so now i climb up the potential hill
so i get no claws
i two
times are three
o look what i did
i wrote down
i one or
there is no capital are in the whole problem
i clearly meant i one or one
so read
minus i one are one
sorry for that
i'm back where i was because these wires have no resistance
so i'm back where i am so this is zero
one equation with two unknowns i one i two
let's go around this one
we can go clockwise we can go counter-clockwise makes no difference
that start here
and i go in this direction ones around
i go through our three
and this current i two
running in this direction
so i go down in potential
so i get minus
i two
times are three