you know
what we want
so four
i would say
there was
these three stories
so that
that is in a
one of
next the same
i will
so said
and the idea is to give you
then there's the question you're you might believe that among the sources there there are
sources you know because there are people around me this music or something like that
you know that there's a couple of sources and one of the sources might be
interesting others might be less interesting to you but at least you want to demix
the signal
and the thing that you know is well the idea that you have is independent
so you think that actually has the sources are statistically independent from each other and
that's what you're looking for you looking for independence
and well you need a little bit more information you have to have an idea
that them
roughly the idea what the statistics of that sources might be references for speech signals
you would think
well maybe the source distribution is a bit heavy tailed
and so you could put this into the model
so let's look at the model
what you would do
the generative model for that is used in ICA
is the following you would say x
they have different times t
and you have the vector x
in this axis is has is d dimensional vector of d is the number of
what we might call it sensors
this is what you observe
that's all
they have to model something
you believe that
these observed signals are
a mixture well linear mixture
so called source signals
and we don't know what a is
and you don't know what the s are and maybe
so the there's always something that doesn't fit into your model you want to put
into noise
that would be nice
we try to estimate a try to estimate this because that's what you're interested in
at the end and
well let's say if noise would be
would be gone
which is not in practice probably
then you could sort of try
and also if the numbers of sensors is equal to the number of sources they
could say well if i know
a that i can actually invert a
and put to the other side and then estimate s
so this would be sort of the easiest case no noise
there's a little bit of
ambiguity is of course the permutation of sources
because if you have some some a i mean if you have sources one and
you're just sort of
bermuda was source to it doesn't
and have also permute the corresponding elements in the matrix a it doesn't change
right so this is sort of the generative model we can
well because the basic ingredient is that all the components of s are assumed to
be statistically independent there's a couple of different schools and approaches some people wouldn't
so to do it the way i explain it here there would also in some
cases you have to do other things
you would look at the temporal structure of the signal
the very basic model completely ignores hold
the temporal structure of the model so they don't look at the way you know
how speech or whatever signals are correlated they just look only at the
statistics the overall marginal statistics of the source so actually is model is not true
but probably sufficient for doing something
a bit more into
the details were this a couple of
o thing you could do for it with maybe i'll just say a few words
sort of a list of ways of
it is doing
i see a
different interpretations actually
this could be
sources and sensors
but you could also in
for images
one way of
doing that
would be to say
if i write this in
components i have some over j
eight i j
s j
in let's forget about the noise four seconds
so we say for each t
this relation holds
well i mean this these are just names
we could also look at the following just right it's slightly different a
t in jail to see immediately what i mean
this j
if i take be the following
i observe
a spatial signal picture image
in this case so i wouldn't mean
the pixel that i observed
and this would be the actual that would be something that picture image the image
changes with time so that would be time than here
to solve this problem is that we only to consider
exactly you know
not normally and he was
not interested in america solutions at the beginning at all
and and later he realized that there is simply no way out
having exact solution so once you've got the exact solutions for many many
specifications is lies that there is no generic way of doing that
then he turned into this turned to the medical issues
and then he discovered that stuff is found are very nice problems there
so anyway so he said his is a great guy
what we start this is that we are going to simplify things little bit so
previous that i said that the policy could depend on the past on the full
but we will see that for our purposes
the so called stationary
the term is that policies such as starfish so what that is objects
so this is just a mapping from states to actions so you have
current state and given the current state to decidable about what to do next so
in this example the robots could no it's card and it's in the two d
and that's it state and depending on that no matter what the very came from
it just this side support vertical
so we only this set of functions so the acts is
the set of all functions
from the state space the real numbers
so i put this thing here
that the vietnam norm the simply on or off these finite so
supremum norm
is defined simply as
you know the size sort of the size of the function
so you take the absolute value
of the function and you take the supreme with respect to the state space
so let's call it the
OK sorry
so you given this function and
so basically but this is the function should be banned
so that's why you have this notation bfx p stands for bob for this the
space of bounded functions
so should be very about this
but if you have a finite state space
then there is no need to so
if for every of state you assign any number
you take the supreme which in this case should be just the max
this is always a finite number then what this value functions
these are just fact strike just the indexing is a bit strange since it after
seeing the of i
well i could go from one to n
and then this looks like a vector
we just say
we have an axe
where goes from i don't know one to then maybe
so we don't care about the names of the
the states
so we see that the the if the state space is finite we can call
them by the natural numbers
and in the states record like that
this is clear
so function alive at vectors but
should be treated more like functions if the state space is infinite
but in general functions like vectors and
and so these are the bounded functions and then
we define this operator t o five
for the PFI operator is
this is defined in the following way so
this takes effect i i call them back to extract no photo
think of simplicity is you take that and this operator in terms of actor
so what it does is that
it's an averaging or the next states
we suspect that the transition probabilities
and so here is the
very important
fifty five
is we
is that
so the next thing is the game
is is
but otherwise it should be clear so
this is an average we suspect next states
so why is the next prime so this is the conditional probability or act
you're executing
some actions to what action
he said that we care about it
stationary policy so the station police illiteracy and action
so given that and given the action returned by the stationary policy
you have the probability distribution over the next state
and you take the immediate reward received
you have these two government times
the value and the next day
and you just average our use some over the next few
so that's what the operator does
and then
that is this literature and that's a step
the value function
the policy is the fixed point of PFI
so why is the street
so maybe this is
one prove that i should do
because this is so crucial
today understanding of anything what's coming
so we should spend some time on it
what's the point here so was the definition of the value functions of see finite
this size or
maybe maybe a little bit larger
i i don't know i don't see from the map
so what's the value function so this was the expectations
of the
this called the top that turned
that policy pi
is executed and the first is just axe
so that's the definition of the value function
oh by the way so what do we mean by
but these activation
in the visible range is cheap because they can use in economy
to do this he must images
but if i try to build an infrared camera
then this kind of magical chemistry does not occur with silicon anyone have to use
the type of detector
i would have to use in gaza germanium as if i want to make now
CCD array
full of in gaza germanium detectors that costs a lot of money
so sensors can be extremely expensive to manufacture and for this reason i could have
far fewer sensors than the number of desired pixels
the measurements can be also very expensive and that happens in a lot of applications
a lot of people are interested in fuel cells these days it is very important
to know what happens inside the fuel cell while the only imaging techniques that i'm
aware of to actually see what's going on inside of yourself is essentially neutron imaging
which neutron scattering which is you bombards yourselves with neutrons and you look at the
scattering patterns and in fear what's happening inside this yourself now when you start bombarding
things with neutrons it costs a lot of money
and before
you want to make the next set of measurement which will cost tens of thousands
of dollars you really want to make sure that you need to do so
and on all of these applications because measurements are very expensive i can only recorded
a few linear functionals about the image of interest
it could be that it takes a long time to make up an image
and so because it takes a long time i can only make a few measurements
and so for all these reasons we could be in a situation where the number
of equations that i have about the image of interest is much smaller than the
total number of pixels it and i'm asking you
is it possible to recover
and pixel image from
so the data of from linear measurements about this image
and of course you know going back to the underdetermined system of equations looks suspicious
but yet now you've got to be kind of well educated
maybe it's not completely out of reach
and so which measurements should we take how should we go about reconstructing these images
from a few measurements
the compressed sensing was born at very practical experiment which was suggested to me
by radiology and experiment goes something like this in radiology
it's a very complicated process it's a wonderful imaging modality that relies on some quantum
effects essentially spin relaxation and so i'm not going to describe the physics which is
quite complicated and it just should tell you that in radiology MRI is essentially acquiring
pictures of living tissues by sampling the fourier domain essential
so in magnetic resonance imaging so we have an MRI scan on the right we
have an image which is the people i by p pixel image we have square
so and pixels
so essentially when you and whenever you to one of his choral zone
mr machine is essentially measuring your fourier coefficients so there's a slice of your body
which are going to call f
right so we're going try to images slice of your body
and so what the MRI machine is giving you
is your ramp up the magnetic field and ramping up the magnetic fields the gradient
of the magnetic fields corresponding to frequency point in k space frequency omega one omega
two and what the call is doing is essentially measuring the fourier coefficients of the
density of interest
now it's common in denmark to have a number of measurements and which is much
smaller than the desire desire resolution which is much smaller than the number of pixels
is if you go to MR conferences they'll tell you
that well if you take fewer measurement pixels the reconstruction is impossible sometimes it that
the decorate things with
invoking the name shannon nyquist and if you want to sample shine and then you
cannot reconstruct the image and so on and so forth i would like to state
more precisely that
everybody knows that if we have fewer equations than unknowns and the reconstruction is not
OK so the number of measurements must match the number of unknowns
can you see this picture because now it's becoming important to see pictures
and you see
it's not good or maybe there's a way to be in the limelight exactly sure
what i need to do
OK so on the left you see typically an image of living tissues that in
the spatial domain that cut
so is the body and so you see a picture
and so
the problem with MRI it's a wonderful imaging modality
it does it allows you to see things that also imaging without do not allow
you to see for example if you take a CT scan
of the body
the city will not tell you
whether it's a life or death
because just measuring absorption
of things and so the city scandal not make the difference between tissues that are
like tissues that are there
mark this
it's a wonderful imaging modality but the problem is we don't use it very much
because it's extremely slow
so the problem is that to make to collect one of these for coefficient takes
quite a long time because it uses penalized stations and they have a certain time
scale and there's no way i can speedy so it's physical process i have to
before i can make a measurement because they have to wait until the spin relaxes
and so
because it takes awhile to acquire imaging
this means a lot of things that we cannot do high-resolution imaging because we cannot
acquire a lot of data
and also we can add the video
and so
more doctors are extremely interesting now
in speeding up market which is very important to wide applicability also nobody likes to
powers and this can affect has problems to spend too much time in this camp
and you start moving and not exactly sure what you measuring anymore
OK and of course if we could make faster MRI images and you could have
this throughput of patients who can which would greatly increase which is an enormous
of enormous importance because it scans cost so much money
so everybody is interested for various reasons is to increase resolution to enable video
or two kind of increases throughput through
this can to kind of
be able to
but because of the physical thing accelerating MR means only one thing is that you
have to sample s
all right and that's
kind of the data acquisition strategy that people were thinking of
applying so
we wish to acquire as many fourier coefficients are pixels but it's impossible so we
can downsample the fourier transform and what we're going to do is we're going select
radio lines going through the origin
and then we get samples the fourier transform not only along those lines
right so we geologists of the university of wisconsin by the name of czech misread
approach me with the data set where he had about twenty two radial lines and
it's a megapixel image so we have twenty about twenty radial lines and along each
the measured about one thousand four coefficients
so we have a megapixel images one million unknowns
we have twenty radial lines with one thousand measurements per line and so we just
do rapid counting and what do we discover we discover that ninety eight percent of
the questions are missing the number of equations i have is two percent of what
i really need
we face
OK actually is one question because i would consider mathematical answer as one domain specific
markup that are close community
everybody really has
pre-arranged so is
i don't know exactly how anathema for example was created in the community process last
but not understanding is that this is a percent
pre-defined text that you can use to annotate your resources and this is actually what
also dublin core gives you four documents in a very generic way that we have
a large agreement so that people know that amount of people agreed on dublin core
as the standard for imitating documents with metadata so it's actually an ontology
there exists some translations of the dublin core into
so you have exactly the same vocabulary in RDF available and one of the features
for example that dublin included is extendable so you can extend the dublin core standard
with you
that we can vocabulary
fits perfectly well to the model so you can extend also RDF
dublin core ontology with whatever you need so
this this is exactly replication which already existed which is now standardised
you know even larger community the dublin core community that's very big but now the
RDF community is growing even bigger and dublin core will be one part of this
actually so it's a very experimental ontology but now that
it into another representation language to make it usable with the available technologies
i know which is feasible for dublin core from other there are not so familiar
with but i guess it would be feasible
but the question
which is not very
i want
OK this that as far as i know this that x seven the next one
will be about twenty one or strange what
and within and seven there the possibility to embed some kind of metadata and the
first but when i said in in our vision that are quite technologies will be
combined for example with multimedia and the state of of course how to annotate video
streams how to annotate pictures how to enrich these
multimedia documents with no we're not going to make them more findable
as we saw yesterday for example from
mean that's presentation that the problem is how to find pictures for example describe that
texts and then search for key words to try to to to give an example
and then so please find something that could be partially solved if you have a
well-defined meaning in behind which describes what is in the picture so you have an
ontology about the domain of the picture and then you can embed these metadata within
video stream or within picture for example they ever exists first approaches and as far
as i know this will be also part of one of the very promising i
piece of integrated projects which hopefully will be funded by the european commission it's called
a i think and as the target as one of the targets to handle multimedia
documents and that's small part of that
product and i see that within from years these big pieces some to collaborate so
this is what we mean by we drive our technology into other application areas for
so i think in one of the for upcoming em peg standards there will be
even more facilities for annotation
he is the man just three which that i know from
it's just the france televisions to television
i don't know national television and
i mean the guy two years ago and the real value attempting i think it
was soccer games
they had like fifteen seventy people sitting there and attempting those soccer games with key
and the highly interested when we said that we can use ontology is to describe
the domain of seconds and then you have some and trees that to i think
especially those you wanting to
companies with less interested and one of our case studies will also be in the
media sector but i don't know
the results will reach so that the and we think about how to include it
but also this these which
so what our sense is also due
so they be exactly what my problem that first
much more
further questions
so you don't have like
still others want and very interesting to you are operating with some of national library
germany something national lottery transformed to london do
a campaign mind maybe to charge them
two working together to just kind of
and next how to do you so we have one ongoing project which has one
partner the BOP
what you might be familiar with which is beyond and service where you can ask
for citation details so that we also try to enhance that michael lie i think
it's a bit faster
and they optimize distribution
forced sigma
doesn't have its maximum sigma and it's actually got at one minus one
so this is the case where we
constrain the distribution to be wrong
in a fairly simple way making it separable is a fairly standard thing to do
and then you end up with the optimized distribution having disorder properties that we kind of want
it's not the case if you marginalize out
new that you get the correct posterior the true posterior over mu
it actually a student distribution is a mixture of all those cast and so
that we have magically sort
got round about the fundamental problem the true posterior when marginalize it is a slightly nasty mixture of gaussians
it's got the right sort of properties
so if you ask what's what's its mean most characteristic with it's got the right characteristic with
okay so those example number one any questions about
but let
example number two is these spin system which we've discussed
on and off
in the past
has been system has couplings
between the spins which are binary variables
spin systems can display all sorts of exciting
so the nasty red distribution
it into minus
peter times and
one z
notice that e
addition because we're doing physics
all the temperature parameter or it coldness parameter beta
which multiplies the energy upstairs
hand it makes the z beta dependent
the way the free energy response that's is we show in
a beta
and then the free energy depends both on theta
hand beta
mccain and then the free energy is always a bound on
z and i can pick any beta andy the variational free energy minimization fall that's a particular problem
and the spring system is
of x is
minus a half
overall pairs spins
x them
x and
weighted by
jay and
and then there may be local field supplying which spins
like this and be x is lived in
minus one plus one
power and so the x glyphs on the corners over
i think you
and the reason is a very nasty
problem is because this
term here the fact that
there are couplings between pairs of spins is what makes it a nasty red
o thing
if only it were the case that we didn't have these coupling terms then it
would be a simple distribution because this is a nasty this just says energy is
a sum of terms one three spin
and not means when you experience at that these spins are independent from each other
if we only had this term
so wouldn't it be nice if the distribution looks like this
and made by saying well let's go ahead and declare are approximating distribution
the be simple
that's planet have the form
q of x is
a normalized version of he could be some over and
i and
x at
so now in this and approximating distribution each other spins has just got its own
personal applied field that favours being up or down depending on the
in and
so this is just a several with distribution and very easy to work with
emphasize that several i can write this as product from one end of an individual
distribution for the end spin alone
just like a moment ago we said let's pretend the distribution over mu and sigma squared
gets approximated by separable
product distributions so the parameters in this case are these eigenstates to
the thing i generally calling theta is the set of all these
they ends
just like this one other way
this is italy
so because it's a separable distribution it's easy to evaluate its entropy
hand it's not
trivially obvious but we can
easily evaluate the expected value of energy even though the energy couplings in it
let's go to the screen after talk through this
the screen shows the approximating distribution in green on the second equation
that equation right beta after all and colorful green and red so we can keep track of what's what
and you see
we've got a simple entropy is just the entropy over several distributions so the right hand green term is easy
they only nastiness comes in these from the red terms where we could be average value over the couplings
under the distribution q
so we now go down
the next equation in parentheses we've got the expected value of the energy
together coupling
terms contribution we just need to know the some overall then all jam many times
the average value of x bahram
the average value x but then
because q is separable
simple set
it's true
so now all you need to know to evaluate the energy is well what's the
mean value of each other spins
and the q
and then you can
our tot up all the fuel and squared contributions for each of these pairs
possible couplings
so we can evaluate the variational free energy
hand when you look at this and you say
how do i just it with respect to theta
remember theta hair is the set of
biases with individual spins
hand what effect does have well they change what the probability was being up is which changes be
i mean value of the spin so
or coming up with new ideas that cover cover four things were
you're going to yes
how making assumptions
well in other places you can
so without but not here
you will be assuming good inductive biases
no data analysis process will work with an inductive bias because otherwise assuming that it's
quite nice and anything can happen
but the main point is to be aware of which ones
which inductive biases and work
because sometimes
you actually mean something and the we're actually
and bob
we then men including
the necessity arises
which does not mean
that somebody comes in and says his learning of finite automata
and then you say but what if your data are not cannot be bothered by
a finite automata
this is not this sort of challenge
it's the other is saying
bias is the automaton mine waste
rather she work
four different one to the other if necessary at some point
somebody else is biased studios
but we really to have them at some point if necessary
it's a
five maybe
very useful for
every this life
but i don't think it's that would produce a
thank you very much for your attention during the morning we see each other in
the lab
you know if you one our
and we will go with through some examples of what i have seen here and
we will for some examples of a workflow data mining tools that are out there
i have one ready for you to copy in your and i find something we
will work with the time with them all with some
applets that are out there on the internet
i think we need
but eleven thirty statistical
o eight hundred
during surgery surgery i i misunderstood this
maybe not they want most
or we stop here only one out from here we go to the left
i i said oh my my my what still has spain time
and spain then is one hour more
and i didn't realise that we were going to
we also then
it's just very very a
a very high level description
a not too much into the
now this is one of the two himself and some methods the other being bagging
in other words we our inductive bias so to speak
it has three components
one of them is to keep distribution of probability on a number of predictors so
we're going to use one predictor we're going to combine several of them
and we will a choose weights
but are we keep waiting the observations themselves so or a because we
be offering
samples from all of generations according to weights
and that's weights we evolve over time
now the thirty
there he is
it's going to be one thing to predict
and there was this
no because howard
but please
the one that is very easy to train
very easy to construct
because you will be doing it over and over and over and over again it's
a very expensive to construct nothing like in SVM
the whole thing is going to last forever
so they can very sympathetic to
no way to each
check for it would this is making mistakes it
in doing well
where the predators is making mistakes
you can weight
to be
so as long as there is some sort of important
what would you do i mean by the
the predictor may be very
weak very simpler
the winning the one thing we need that it does
if the they data that the nothing nothing
then the whole thing is not going to work
so it seems to be very weak may be doing very little
but it has to be doing some
what do i mean by this it has to be
at least seen on better
than flipping a coin
and this absolutely
must exist and be are real numbers
a specific number of maybe ten to the minus five
but ten to the minus better than random guessing
it doesn't work if you're predictor as things start going difficult
uniquely decodable
right so wannabe ideas were floated now is
easy to code
could mean for example that we'd like a prefix code please
but we really do want small expected length
can you
let me suggest an idea now about how we get small expected length
we've found the code here
which were speculating could be the best you can do
for this ensemble with a simple code
because it happens every day entropy and we've already heard some theorems about not being
able to do better than entropy
and it has the property
is the key intuition about symbol codes and is over all the data compression has
a key property you give short code words to the probable outcomes and longer codewords
the less probable problems going that's what it's all about
and that's a possible
i guess about how
we might get the smallest possible
expected length
we could say you give me a list probabilities of sort them
and i'll give
these shortest possible codewords tonight from one
and the end steadily longer codewords as we go down the list
machete neighbour and see what you think of a bad idea
okay so suggested an idea here it's got the right spirit is giving short
the problem becomes
so long the less probable ones
second work anyone
criticize that's class
if you've got a huge number symbols then watch
it might not be good
it's definitely not good
probably not good
i might agree with you
let me give you
some backup all
intuition there
we found a case where this
proposed algorithm
is getting us to entropy so we can't be too critical that but maybe we
can find a counter-example where it doesn't
it doesn't work
andrew it doesn't need to be
we can give them all a probability a quarter
it's just a make life interesting will add that's ceylon
one of them another one over two to one subtract that's long overdue from this one
in fact that's a long
not one that's on is a billion okay
so there all essentially they all have a probability of a quarter
all right
and now
we apply this
suggested algorithm
and what can do end up with
and that with his six
all right
so this is the new probability distribution
when you use code six which is proposed by this algorithm hat
the expected length
that's is
all the links are one
three andy three is the last one in the list
and the average those things are all equiprobable
he will take long
it is now
you know who
o nine o four
link is to
and the quarter
is the optimal symbol code
how we do better how
you know
you see five
and the expected length will be to
but he length of five
so we can't just use that's simple rule that not the right spirit
we need to identify some sort of trade-off
when do you give
codewords to the most probable guy
so what and the integrals there
so now what galerkin siberia going to be
i i've got
i've got this you is now a combination of
from one to four
of the
five fifi
and i have made a smart choice of these fees and smart means that i
can do the calculations quickly
hold on a minute
well let
if i put these piecewise linear functions into this form
what is going to happen
problem we're going to have arrived
because the derivative of piecewise linear is
as piecewise
and here i've got
another derivative
yes that's right
so what i have done i just screwed up but but in one
line by changing our world
i can make myself correct
we get this term was the
so i'm going to put equal zero here OK
see what
i want this is the a weak form
that's the weak form
with before the integration by parts
and now
i could take you to be
my piecewise linear
and the derivative would be piecewise constant that's fine
and what about the v which i take for these
well i can i
i could take the same thing for the visa right to take some other choice
for vs
but but this is so i'm sorry that that's in yellow and this is in
why because this is the one
and i should have been
pointing to
that's the form before i integrate by parts and
and impose this
additional derivative on you this was much better
well i think are probably the simplest idea
let this has to be true
so you is a combination of these again wonder for these the CIP i
and what should i take for re
i'm looking for four equations
i'm just going to take for v
four test functions
the be region right
it's true for every v
so i pick any four these
and one natural choice in this sort of symmetric problem is
let the test functions b the trial function
but i don't have to make that choice so can i summarise this galerkin idea
he's got an
he chooses
trial function
and he chooses and
test functions
well if i don't say that word
and those could be the same
very often they are the same
but they need to be the same
and then
his equations are
this week he takes the weak form
where he
training be
in turn it one of these sides
so this is for j
o one and two
after n
we've got to n equations in n unknowns that was our job
we've got to n equations in n unknowns
what are the unknowns there these weights
one of the equations
there the weak form
for each
test functions
so we're testing it in time
this is going to be
that's four equations in four unknowns
i was going to say the most interesting case is when you actually have contradictions
in new knowledge base meaning it's not satisfiable
this is the first order logic breaks down
if we have a contradiction in the first on knowledge base you can prove anything
from it
this is basically what makes it so brittle
and that makes it impossible to build large knowledge bases because you have to ensure
that they consistent
and makes it impossible to merge this from multiple sources without killing them all up
and making inconsistent
markov logic however has no problem with inconsistency
but markov logic does is it weighs the evidence on either side of the probability
so this is what we want by going you know to this more general language
OK so now let's look at how we do inference
in my collection
so how do we do MEP MPE inference as a reminder the goal is to
find the most likely state of world given evidence so
well defined y that maximizes p of y given x where y is the query
index is the evidence
well let's replace p of y given x by the expression you know represented by
an MLN so here's what we're trying to maximize is the expression that we have
a couple of slides ago
now this is a constant this is a monotonically increasing function so maximizing this whole
thing is just the same thing as maximizing this
no one is maximizing this
what i'm trying to maximize here is the sum of the weights of the ground
formulas that are satisfied
well this is the a well known problem in computer science this is just the
weighted maxsat problem
so sad is finding as an assignment that satisfies the formulas max is finding a
that an assignment that says as many forms as possible the weighted version of that
is one every formula has away
and so the nice thing is that
in order to do MEP inference in
markov logic we don't need to invent anything new we can just use a weighted
SAT solver
in particular we can use the weighted version of the walksat called maxwalksat
the walksat is very scalable with
it works can solve problems with millions of variables in minutes and i'm talking about
the heart of these ones in arkansas of practically instantaneously
so this is very fast but even better than that and surprisingly is that this
can actually doing the MEP inference in markov logic can actually be faster
the doing logical inference
and the reason can be fast is the following
the maxwalksat and looks almost the same with that
if i take some of the constraints that were hard
but should have been soft and make them soft now the problem becomes easier
and i could potentially solve it in less time
this is surprising because you think it for combining logic and probability the results should
actually be less efficient than actually in this case you can actually be more efficient
the maxwalksat is just walks set with a very simple change which is instead of
trying to maximize the number of satisfied clauses at each step we're just trying to
maximize the sum of the weights of the satisfied clauses
and then we can also have a slightly different termination criterion but that's and that's
so you can basically just take this out of the box and use it for
the first not scalable inference in markov logic except there
in this slag is this problem that already alluded to earlier of the memory explosion
that you get when you try to run that you know
if you take an MLN and try to propositionalized to then running you know maxwalksat
there's a good chance that unless you the man is very small one even fit
in memory and you know you and
things will stop right there
so what can you do
what can you do is you can exploit the fact that relational domains
tend to be very sparse
what i mean by that
think of the friends x y relation
there are six billion people on earth which means there are thirty six billion billion
possible groundings
huge number
most people have only in a few dozen maybe a couple hundred friends
which means that the vast majority of the groundings of friends x y or false
because of that the vast majority of the groundings of most clauses are going to
be true
because as long as a precondition in the classes false the clause is is satisfied
so the vast majority of atoms are false the vast majority of classes are true
what we can do is we can represent explicitly only the true atoms and the
false clauses
and that's a much much smaller things
and what we can do when we do inference is we can ground clauses lazily
we started with no clauses
meaning that we assume that they are all satisfied and only is cause become satisfy
potentially in satisfy during the inference doing ground
this increases the order of magnitude in the size of the things they can do
inference on by orders and orders of magnitude
and you know the argument that this is called lazysat and even though it was
motivated by markov logic it's actually a good thing for classical satisfiability problems like planning
and again they you get very big payoffs by doing this
so the other big task
inference is computing probabilities
in the most general type of query that you might want answers what's the problem
what's the marginal probability of some formula given some mln or what's the conditional probability
of some form of given another in
now in principle
a question like this is easy to answer because the probability of the formula is
just the sum of the probabilities of the world where the formula is true
the problem of course is that in doing that in the brute force way is
just not feasible what you can do however is you something like markov chain monte
carlo to sample worlds
and then i check ritual the formula holds or not
and the probability of the formula is just the fraction of world where we're told
and if conditioning on another formula what i can do is i i i first
checked with another formula holden if it doesn't i ignore that sample
and then i'm only counting when the samples of the second formula
now if you evidence to formula two
is a conjunction of ground atoms is typically the case for a bunch of facts
that you know that it's the symptoms of the patient or the words on the
page and the links and whatnot you can do something even better which is i
can construct only the minimum subset of the network that i need to answer the
but i mean i know suppose i want question about you only need to worry
about you and your friends not the other you know five hundred nine hundred and
something to people on
so this is another way in which you know we can we can really scale
to larger domains is shown the whole world is very large but most of the
time we only need to worry about a small fraction of
in fact this is a generalisation of the the knowledge based model construction idea
and then once i had that small network i can apply MCMC or some other
difference of OK
there is another type of approach that we we can follow that people have only
begun to look at which is lifted inference we we reason at the level of
whole classes of objects in resolution in first order logic
i want to talk about that here but you know it's interesting direction
so how do we create the minimum ground network that we need to answer a
very simple
i start with an empty network and with the queen nodes in a queue
and then i the following are taken from the front of the queue and added
to the network and check whether it's in the evidence
if it's in the evidence i know its value and i can stop
if it's not the evidence i need to take its neighbors
and put them in the queue
i'm back to talk about
while gaston distributions
so either
it's an interesting giving half the talk and then
three days passing because you bump into a lot of people and has some interesting
interactions about what's going on so some people
some people said to me you know
i i get it i understand what's what's going on right i i realize that
it's not so easy to understand and some you might still be struggling and thinking
this is this is this is mysterious that's all i apologize you for not
really knowing
how to tell you
what's going on in a bit better way but if you're feeling a little uneasy
about what's going on and don't despair
you can i think this is this is a very natural when we talk about
this kind of stuff that today actually i won't i won't talk about much more
stuff but i'll try and talk about the same stuff and a few other ways
and maybe that's gonna make that's going to help you this so actually gave i
give a course on on machine learning once
and i was supposed to prepare ten talks but actually i only got around to
preparing nine
so that can happen and then at the end i was sort of had given
the last lecture i don't i i didn't have another lecture so i know i
didn't really know what to do so i just decided just to give the last
lecture again because i don't know what to do right so that was pretty embarrassing
but it but people really liked it i just happened to be the gaussianprocess stuff
right and i just said the same thing the same stuff where i can explain
any way
so i'm going to try and go to try and explain if i could give
the same talk again but actually
i i've got it
i'm going to use some slightly different slides this time
OK so there are a lot of good a good questions from people that have
been talking to you should use interrupt me as i go along and even if
you have questions that are not directly related to on talking about that's fine as
long as the related stochastic processes
so one of the questions was you know it's a bit fishy that i i
talk about these i had these infinite dimensional gaus processes are infinite dimensional distributions and
then in the end i want to talk about would like proper gauss in distribution
the multivariate constitution distribution demanding we can i just couldn't just stick with the usual
stuff and there are two reasons why you can do that so one of the
reasons is
beforehand you don't know where you're going to make predictions right so you don't know
what the identity of those random variables are right so it so it's better to
be the case that you can figure out what's going on with respect to those
random variables as well
and that's why use only to the the process there's no there's no good reason
which i'm going to talk about why why infinite dimensional models are generally
preferable to to finite dimensional ones so this statistical reason and i'll try and in
and come back to that
so also you'll notice that i have an incredibly sloppy attitude to
two mathematics right so this morning you why did a very good job of actually
telling us you know why it is that this that this construction talking about the
process that we're white actually exists in wide so why it's a good thing to
to talk about and i haven't i haven't haven't told anything about whether these things
exist actually peter orbanz in our lab he told me a few months ago that
gaussianprocess actually exist
and i realized that i had never
worried about that
so i thought it was it was great that they exist but actually to be
honest with you if you told me that they don't exist that would also be
fine with me because i know that it works
right so let's let's i can take some questions now we can we can try
to get the ball rolling again so that the this space with the place where
we left off was that i was a change this expression of the to look
a little bit more like the one that was supposed to look like on the
slide so i was trying to illustrate this cartoon example that what we actually doing
in the casting process is just fitting which is fitting actually with maximum likelihood to
this so this is called the marginal likelihood with if you if you think about
marginalizing over the over the over the parameters over the functions but if you just
think about in this space in this space then it's just the likelihood of the
data so so so one person's marginal likelihood might be the another person's likelihood that
you can introduce latent variables and then marginalize over them and so that might be
so so so you should fight about what what this is the marginal likelihood are
likely be right this way it just looks like a likelihood but it pops out
when you marginalise out the functions but you don't have to refer back to the
functions again right nobody forces you to actually have that interpretation
and i was and i was and we we're looking at this little example i
was saying well if you if you tell me that the best estimate for the
variance here is actually the empirical variance something which is called the empirical variance then
we're all happy about that that kind of statement and actually what's going on in
the gaps process is just that your somehow
you somehow using this big galson distribution that lives in this very high dimensional space
using you're trying to model to fit the parameters of the house process such that
that multivariate gaus in cloud fictional cloud of data
in this case i can draw because it's in one dimension like normally i can
draw it for you
so i think that i really liked about david livestock is that he talked a
lot about you know what is the posterior look like i thought i would try
to to right so i talked quite a lot about what does the posterior look
and and i think one of the reasons that
i was saying that is hard to understand what's going on the model and what
is really
understanding what's going on the model i think just and i'm talking he was talking
about this intuitive statisticians like as a really nice way of thinking about what understanding
means so you understand something when you're intuitive statisticians agrees with what's going on right
if you can predict what's what's going to
happen and then you're then you're happy about what's going on right if it doesn't
it is not able to predict what's happening right then then during the mysterious domain
right then you're still you know in give incorporating data into the model
OK so now i'm going to talk about a different way of thinking about thousand
process where we actually constructing distributions over functions by very explicitly doing that and in
the in the function domain and then i'll show that those kind of constructions also
correspond to gas process
so here a list of the simple one
OK so i consider classify actions here and this is just a linear functions right
so just the function i'm looking at is a express b but now a and
b are random parameters OK so what if i can be around and then i
get a distribution over functions right
each time are beginning to be again to function
so we can look at so an output output galson priors on and gauss implies
and b so i have zero mean
prior here with
variance of alpha for a another variance of beta for b
and now i can compute i can compute things like i can compute the mean
function OK so the mean function of column mu x here the mean function function
is just the expectation
of the function
friends who have
another example that given in the same paper is the problem the publishing in conferences
like if you have if you wanted have a number of coauthors published in ICML
the probability that you
publishing ICML that that's going to be an increasing function of the number of quarters
in order to have enough conference
again this is
mister scruff this
again there is that there is a similar graphs showing
there's the paper for example mentioning this in particular because the experimental results
present are actually related to the current tagging data so the tagging what cavalier
a lot of web two o two point o systems nowadays are based on the
notion of tag like that you can put something there and you and other people
can tag is that helps people to find this information online
and it's observed that tagging which cabinet people use there is a large correlation if
they are friends with each other they
and use the same wars describe objects
this is the paper by mahler and others
and so this this is actually the graph from the paper
this is the red line
represents the overlap of the tagging vocabulary of two users
that our friends to each other
and the other line the bottom line overlapping the tagging vocabulary of two random users
and as you see the the red curve is essentially shifted to the right which
the writing which i believe overlap quite a bit
and finally another example is the adoption of paid voice over IP services and the
centre for example
i'm a young messenger you can pay and sign up for the premium service that
allows you to
using voice over IP
and we looked at the data and you can actually see the all that
if you have a large number of friends that are already using this voice over
IP service are much more likely to be used
because of this is this is not really a surprise see that every river and
document in many instances but one thing that is not entirely clear is what the
source of the correlation
i'm mentioning important categories here for the source of correlation that we observed with your
contacts social
one is the probably not the most obvious one is the social influence fact that
one person performing an action can induce his or her friends to do the same
like the same way
and this can be done by providing information like buying in new product your friends
mind i know about it but you tell them about it and they might go
and buy the product
or it could be way increasing the value of the action
this is called an economic jargon this is called the adoption externalities the fact that
for example if i knew using yahoo messenger AOL instant messenger
you will derive more utility
by using the same instant messaging software as opposed to a different set of or
for example if you have a lot of friends that have cell phones you're more
likely to benefit of having
doing business
so this is one of the categories this is essentially the category that probably the
most important one the one that there is an element of causation here you
using something you adopting some technology we were looking for a new norms culture thing
can induce your friends
another source of correlation is the number of
monthly by the similar individuals are more likely to become friends well for example if
you study
the social network among scientists probably only to discover that mathematicians are likely to be
friends but that doesn't necessarily mean that
if i am a mathematician and if i if i want to become a mathematician
five become friends and additions that increases might like my life without becoming it's probably
mostly because mathematicians are just more like a more likely to come from
finally the third reason that we we can observe
correlation in the process
factors that we don't observe essentially external elements in a mormon can influence both individuals
so it is in this last part of the
the lecture this morning we talk about optimisation
OK i have i've drawn a few
functions here
from two are
and so
there are a few things that i wanted to show you
so let's think about the
and that are here
so i'm going to do is to
find the global minimum of the function
what this local minima of the function
that you have here
and i have drawn some function therefore which should
may not be
that easy to find them
there there are several ways were
you could face for
finding the minimum of the function of the first one being that the minimum may
not exist
if you think that the function that is that
gary's and then use it and you won't find the global minimum right
goes to minus infinity as x goes to zero and then
so it's useless to try to
to try to find if you just afraid to minimize
OK if you have
this function here in red
there's definitely a local minimum here
but it's not global because the the function goes to minus infinity here
you have to be aware that when you look on minimum then the they might
local or global say that if the
the point is that the global minimum is
if o
why difference than than x then f of
so why is bigger than f of x
obviously this one here in the blue colour is a local minimum
is a global minimum
OK so
let's assume that
you know
there's going to be at least some local minima in your functions
well how do you how are you going to find it
you have new ways to find it
it was the first thing you do is you want to find the minimum
i differentiate
so if your function is nice and differentiable
then you're going to differentiate your function and what you're going to find it is
all the points where the different and different the derivative is zero otherwise all minimum
they are not
right OK they're not
obviously they not ready
because local maxima are points where the different everything derivatives you as well
and then
there is another points
which of course at the points where the derivative may be easier
OK so
if you have a function you have no other information on the function and you
just take the derivative then you're not done too
to make sure that you have the minimum
the minimum if you
have the derivative and the of your function is twice differentiable like what can you
do to make sure it's a minimum
it's the minimum of the sign of the second derivative is
but was you
what to me
so it's a minimum if
you and your derivative is
getting bigger and bigger and bigger
which means that the second derivative is positive
so an
OK so you have a function you need to compute the derivative
you compute the second derivative and you find that the security and derivative is strictly
positive then
sure that you have a minute
and i know way that you know that this minimum is local or global
one there's actually i don't think there's a way and so then if you know
but i don't think there's a way without further assumptions to know if the minimum
your you found is global or local
right other than you find several
a local minima and you look at which one is the is the
the most meaning
even when everything's alright then you could differentiate and you know that the second derivative
is strictly positive then
you're not exactly sure with which i mean i you found OK
the next thing that
OK so
you could wonder what are the minimum conditions
that you should have on as one your function f so that you know that
there is
only one local
one global minimum
and what would that be
and there's no condition on how it depends on the second variable Y
and in fact Y can be an integer or constraint to be integer or can be a vector or
matrix it doesn't matter
and then we take the maximum
Of this function to evaluate this new function G of X you take the maximum of
F of X and Y over all possible Y in some sent A
and again there's no restriction on what A is it doesn't have to be convex or connected or
there's no
condition on A
well that's always convex
in X there is
the resulting function
so the previous example is where Y is just the index
or Y is an integer and the set A is a set of
From integers from one to M
and I use here in this notes we use the supremum if we use a maximum
for the Maximum over a finite set and the supremum over a set that could be
so that's the definition of
and if you like it you can just replaced by Max just keep in mind that it can be
A doesn't have to be a finite set
so a very good example of this is the maxim eigen value of a symmetric matrix which
is a convex function of X
and that's easy to see so very short proof is this so you know from linear
algebra that the maximum eigen value can be expressed like this it's the maximum of Y
transpose X Y
if you take the maximum over all vectors Y with unit norm
so in this case this is the set A
the units sphere
and this is the function F of X and Y
so for fixed Y it's clear that that's a linear function of X
if you expand these products you get this linear function of the entries and X
so for fixed Y there's a linear or and therefore also convex function of X
so then we know from this property that if you take the maximum of these functions
over any set Y you get automatically a convex function of X
and you can easily think of some other equivalent definitions of the maxim eigen value for
which it's not immediately obvious that it's convex for example if you think of it as
the largest root of the characteristic polynomial then it's not clear at all that if you
change the entries in the matrix X
that that largest root is a convex function of the entries it's actually a very complicated
so that's a maximization rule so you have a function of two variables X and Y we
maximize over the second and the condition was that the function had to be convex
in the first variable X for a given Y
there's something that looks very similar and refers to minimization
or the infimum
so here again we take a function of two variables X and Y and under some conditions
we can conclude that the minimum over Y gives you convex function of X
so it's very similar to this maximization rule on the previous page
but the conditions are much more restrictive so here the conditions are at F has to be
jointly convex in X and Y
not just convex in X for a given Y but it has to be jointly convex
in X and Y as a variable
and also if there are constraints in the optimization has to be constraints over a convex set C
but if that's the case then you can conclude that
sorry H is convex
so again there are some
simple useful examples suppose you take the distance to a convex set C
in any norm that's always a convex function of X
because this is can be written like this it's the minimum distance
from X to any point in C
we've seen that norms are always convex so the norm of X minus Y is jointly convex
in X and Y
C is a convex set so if you take the minimum distance you get
a convex function of the remaining variable X
and that's true for any norm but only for convex sets
another one that's very useful in optimization is as follows so suppose we take a
linear programming problem in Y S variable
so I take minimize C transpose Y with constraints that A Y is less that X so X is
just the right hand side in inequalities
and I define as the function H the
or assign I assign to H the optimal value of this linear programming problem
as a function of the righthand side X
so to evaluate this function in general
you would have to add a certain X
you'd have to pick X and solve this LP and Y and then the optimal
value is the function value at X
so there's no closed-form expression of this H of X but you can compute it by solving
an LP
X as righthand side
but one useful property that's important in optimization is that if you define
a function like this
then this is a convex function of X
so the optimal value of a linear programming problem is a convex function of it's
the righthand sides in the constraints
and that follows from the same rule so in this case we define F of X and Y
as a function that's has this as its domain so it's only defied defined
for pairs X and Y that satisfy these that satisfy these inequalities and outside the domain we can
give it a value plus infinity
and then on its domain when X and Y satisfy these inequalities we
define it as C transpose Y
so if you do that you get a function that's a jointly convex in X and Y because
its domain
is convex in X and Y it's just a set of linear inequalities and on its domain it obviously satisfies
Jensen's inequality
so that's a convex function of jointly in X and Y and therefore and its minimum
over Y is equal to H of X so therefore H is convex
so this is true for LPs but also of course for many other
convex problems
the optimal value as a function the right-hand side is convex in general
H is a function of X so I define a function of X
and the value at X is the optimal value of this LP
so I fix X
and then solve this linear program that Y is variable
and then the optimal value is the function value
of H at X
so the it's interesting because it's a function is how the optimal value changes it
changes in the righthand side to it rises in sensitivity analysis and and
so on
then we have a few more
so an obvious question is what about composition if I have a composition of H and G of X under
what condition is that convex
well there are some useful rules for example if X is convex and the
or non decreasing and G is convex
then you can conclude that F is convex
it looks like minor but is going to be big later on
we have a point p going in three-dimensional space
and here
we have
the entire behaviour
of the object
as it
projection along the x axis
this is the position
this is its velocity
and this is acceleration
and here
CD entire behaviour
on the z axis
this is the position on the axis is this is the velocity component in this
and this is the acceleration in the x and you you have the y
and that words
we have no
the three-dimensional motion
we have cut
in two
one dimensional motions
this is a one-dimensional motion
there's behavior only along the x axis and this is the behaviour only along the
y axis and this is the behaviour only along the axis and the three together
make up
the actual motion of the particles
what have we gained it looks like this looks like a mathematical zoo
you would say well
this is what is going to be like it's going to be held
not quite in fact is going to help you
a great deal
first of all if i throw of the tennis ball in class like this
then the whole trajectory
the whole trajectories in one plane in the vertical plane
so even though it is in three dimensions we can always represented
by two axes by two-dimensional it y axis and x axis
it's already
the three-dimensional problem often becomes the two dimensional problem
we always great success
these trajectories
by decomposing
it's very complicated motion imagine what an incredibly complicated arc that is
and yet we're going to decompose it into emotion in the x direction
which leads a life of its own independent of the motion in the y direction
which live a life of its own
and of course you always have to combine the two to know
what the particle
we know the equation so well
from our last lecture
with constant acceleration
the first line tells you what the position as a function of time
the index t
well suited to changing with time
it is the position it equal zero
what's the velocity at equal zero times t
was one half a x squared if there is an acceleration in exploration
the velocity immediately comes from taking the derivative of this function
any acceleration comes from taking the derivative of this function
now if we have a
which is more complicated
which reaches out to two or three dimensions
we can decompose the motion three
but particular axes
and you can replace every axiom by y
which gives you the entire
behaviour in the y direction and if you want to know to behaviour in this
direction you replace every xy advising
and then
i have decomposed the motion
in three
directions each of them i
and that's what i wanna do now
i'm going to
an object
when apple
in twenty six one hundred
and we know that it's in the vertical plane so we have
we only deal with full dimensional problems
this being
i call this my
x axis
and i'm going to call this
y axis
i call it increasing value of x
and i call this increasing value of y
i could have called this increasing value of y
today i decided to call this increasing value y i'm free
in that choice
i throw of an object
a certain angle
and i see
motion like this going it comes back
to the ground
my initial
we need
but i through it
it was the zero
and the angle here
it's all fine
x component
of that initial velocity
it is zero
the cosine of
illustrating what I meant course and thinking about Terminal 5 at Heathrow many of you
know about what happened over there in last week or so
which was shirk entrusted
but kicked so I'd like to show this this is actually a lot of real
and 1 show how they are using the kind of all these 3 services together
but what this is websites
the websites actually right here and then got back Amazon Web Services where they're doing
all the work and the idea is that you can upload of video filed habit
Trans crowed like from an EDI
to an impatient
and work something like this
there's so
you've got were using as prehistoric
when they are
using as historic asked U.S. Azalia workflow engine many seeking reaction to the transfer so
what happens if you go to the other
websites and post file uploaded in the Amazon street
put entry into SQL
and then
easy to that there's a job
In starts it up and start transfer of something like this
so now that seemed to work in the 1st
the 2nd one's waiting and so on and so forth and just keeps going
With the first one is puts the got got back up industries
they started 2nd jobs and so on and so forth
they are
thing is that all that you can get into a situation like this where you
have to much inbound work you can't keep up with what's going on well if
that happens what they're doing is monitoring the queue length and if the huge it's
too long
this is simply stand up more easy to instances and ketchup because you know of
transporting is easy to do and Carol
and then of course eventually you catch up and put it away
1 last 1 I lot of talk about before moving to the devil
In this is an Amazon simple B B which is what it sounds like a
database as the weather service so the idea here is that rather than actually running
which you do is you authenticate and make a Web service call into the virtual
database doesn't operate like sequel I'm really wanna make that clear that it's not sequel
but that because it's healthy mostly you can start out with a prototype and without
changing anything you can move it up into a candy by database that scales very
well now there's no scheme
so that means you literally just created what we call the Maine
and I think that's a table for just a moment section doesn't have to be
used like you created in just start putting data on and we take care of
there's no data types everything a string
and I
but it works a lot like Amazon has 3 and in that there's mobile nodes
so that when you put something in we replicate across mobile nodes mobile data centers
just like Amazon history so it's a very resilient data store
Inter High
but many time this
the state's of during very inexpensive costly to run an ongoing most cost data-transfer not
much to do with the
that actual were so inexpensive that there's lots of lots of zeros in front of
the each transaction costs
look something like this
so we've had told the straight out of our documentation but so would you do
if you start creating remain here they created 1 gold my story
and then they put in their home near Somersworth 1st think of it as the
primary key
but the the name of the record and evaluates as 1 2 3 could just
as easily have been ABC
and then you start getting at so for example an afternoon descriptions of sweaters
another 1 with colors blue notice that actually have a 2nd color
I didn't to do during the normalization Erskine anything it just put in multiple Latrobe
somewhere where
and you can do the same thing in the 2nd row just like the 1st
broke and then along the 3rd row or another name and you tributes without doing
anything just entered the United Way
so it's very very flexible
OK so if you want and more think most of it sounds like most of
the already know what that ends and
there's a work like this and that
there's my e-mail address if you'd like to to use that an that would like
it is by the way the very best way to find out information is on
our forms because I can really small but you know so with that would like
to do is jump over
case but you could also be in this position where the center of the ellipsoid
is outside the constraints and if you make it smalleryou can seeeven more outside the constraints
so we're talking about this is our posterior it's a little bit of that ellipsoid
that satisfies the constraints renormalized so we've got a precise geometrical view of what happens
in the limit and wecan see the way that it depends on the variants of
the posterior and in particular we know how that depends on the variants of the
prior and the likelihood inthis not full ranked situation what what what you get
is that this ellipsoid flattens and get smallerat different rates so this is
the sort oftheorem that we haveexpressed in some but not
complete detail so the posterior distribution in this casewith ill-posed aconvergence is
toa pointmass we can characterize that promise exactly this happens as the exposure time
goes to infinityand isquite curious situation and this is a property of inverse problems here
because even with the infinite matter data the solution isn't unique this means that to
get convergence theprior has get more informative as well that's somethinga little bituncomfortable
eventhough you'regetting more and more informationbecause you'rerunning theexperiment for longerand longer
if you want convergence to a point thenthe thepriorhas toshrink as well
what we've found outis thatthat prior canshrinkat amuchlower rate than the
than the data datavariance and we got rate andtime resultsand in the
limitwe've gotta quite nice characterizationbecause of the ellipsoidgetting smaller differently in
different dimensionsain't getting truncatedtheyactually the limit distribution is for the most partgaussian
but the presence of the boundary means that in certain dimensions it's exponential nogaussian
that's all I'm gonna say about that Iand it's the only thing I saidabout theory
in theall all of this talks but it's justan insert sort of way soyou can
get some sort of handle if you've gotten extremely talented co collaborator
you can do the analysisit'san instance how you can get a handle on
the on thesolution okay that'sthat'sthesecond seminar and I'mgonna give youat leasta bit
of thethird oneany questions at that pointbefore wedo something again completely
different okay so this is about latent factor analysis andthat's unknown
is a class of models that is much usedin machine learning typically generalized that mixturesof factors
and so on but this isa quiteavanilla version of it thethe situation
we're thinking about here isproblems arising ingenomics but where there are several
essentially several parallelassays and this is the casereally of two so we'relooking
at datafrom this paper isfew yearsago now but it was essentially relating
RNA transcriptswith some metabolitesokay andin this case therewere just small
number of conditions andtwo hundred nineteenvariables representing levels of gene expression and levels of of
these metabolitesthere's there's some structure structure to the data which I won't be talking
about modeling they're actually short time series butI'll leave outthat particularcomponent andthe data
looksomething like thisso these are the two hundred nineteen variables plotted against the
eighteen theeighteen different conditions and these are theI think these are the metabolites and those
there well I don't know it doesn't matter I am convinced now these are thetranscriptionthere's themetabolites so all I've done
they'reon the originalscale and that's more helpfulwhere you cansee thatthey've been standardized separately
to get some idea of the degree of covariation there is between thetwo sets
multiple sets oftime seriesso theparticular question we're exploring was can we find sparse
models for the dependencewell thecorrelation between thesetwo
yes II'm not sure probably everything isso
we wanted to use factorfactor models causewhat we arethinking ofhere is you knowthe factors being
somehow biologically interpretable as asas asbackground factorsin thenatural sensebut it's only
thecovariation that we're interested in modeling hereso we hope
we're gonna find a sparse representation of thatand that's so that's the objective so the
the modellooks something like thisthis is our notation for the standard linear
factor model soX J Ithe data J is the variable indexA is the observation index
and we assume this linear model and apart from an interceptwe
have essentiallyA timeslambdaso A are the factor loadings and lambdaare thefactors andthen there's
some noise and it's grosslymodelcause none of these things
on the right-hand sideare observed so it's like a linear model with unknownco covariance
that's what factoranalysis is I'm gonna use the indices consistentlyso J is an observation sorry it's avariable number I is
the observation number andL running fromone to K is a factorso what we're looking
for is low rank representation so we hopethat L will be much smaller than
P or N
we're interested indimension reductionI said that we're interested in sparsity so that
a loss of these loadings will be zero and we're probably working onthe case
where P is much bigger thanN and N is much bigger than Kso I think we'll have some sort
ofapriori belief we think nature's being kind to us thatthat
it would be commom patterns of loadingsfor multiple variables to do with variable
thing on thesame pathways andwe hope that nature would have helped
us in this regard as well that's what we're that's what wetrying to identify
this is a cartoon on what the model looks like on a small scale so these
are basically images representing the different matrices here so we have in this case it
looks likeit looks like we haveten observations we havefive variables
and we havesorry we havethree variablesand we have five factors so that's the
that's thefactor matrix and that's the loadingmatrix so factor analysis goes
so all rules that are
the problem
the above
this is talk far
one of
after the
you are also
one of the first and
so can
well that's
what i mean by that
one of
as possible
o point
that's right
of course
that are
that's all
so i hope
the curvature
the performance
hundred one
it's the
but also
last three
i write this out as a x and a delta x
next was a delta x
now what to do next
here's my
true equation and here's my
computational equation so i got those two i just subtract that from that
so i learned that a delta x
delta p
so i have an idea now of how being
delta b is
still to be
OK how they could delta b
from from this equation
so delta b is is what you get by multiplying delta x by
so all our our work on the norms of the matrix says
this thing can blow up by more than the norm of a
that's so this
these facts just come from these simple equations by the idea of what the normal
now my any better
well i have a feeling that if i just put these two pieces together
i'll get
i guess for i'm gonna do i'm going to divide one by the other
to get something like that
who was that good
i don't know if it's so great i don't think i've done it right
why do i not saying right because i want inequality where delta x is less
than something i've brilliantly come up with equality where it's larger than some
embarrassment here
maybe what i wanted to do was have inverse in this one
that would have been like
version of this one
and this one i shouldn't have taken the position should state where i would be
a x equals b would have been
all right can can i
yes on the videotape
we cannot we can
future viewers well
in this so this is the length of b is less than the normal
i'm not
line and this one says that the size of the output
let's recall the size of the universe
times the size of delta
now we're getting somewhere
now i have dealt explicitly call something
but i want relative error divided by x can i do that
what happens here
i started with this one
and i divided by delta phi x
o k eight
x is bigger than
b over the length of a sofie divided by
something smaller
this axis bigger than be the over
so if i divide instead by b already have grown more
so let me divided by b over a instead instead of dividing by
there's a divided by b
except here
is right
and i've seen i now see what's the condition number right now see what is
this condition and you see other by by
spoiled the blackboard so it should be here it's
you see delta x over x here is delta b over b and here you
the condition
the condition number is the normal way
times the norm of
isn't that he
condition number is the norm of the first times the normal
that's the right quantity
but this is taken more time and but i still having got this far i
would like to give it another
a little bit because i'm
i would like to understand what this
suppose a is an orthogonal matrix
what's its conditional
because if if it's an orthogonal matrix norm is one and its inverse is also
an orthogonal matrix that's one
so the condition number is one
what's the condition number of the sky
a symmetric matrix
well tell me it's norman tell me it's tell me its inverse so for well
we can do is inverse easily
what's the inverse of this matrix
minus thirty zero zero one
so tell me the norms of those two guys
three and
one right
so the condition number is
exactly so
those those are easy because they were diagonal
symmetric matrices are just as easy
for a symmetric matrix
so what's so so this is for general matrix if the matrix is symmetric one
i keep this this
going so this will
conclude the
our table
norms and now
condition numbers condition
OK so what's the what are the condition numbers
if it's orthogonal we said condition number was one
if now here's is the case i'm interested in
if they
if it is symmetric matrix
because we do get a lot of those
what is the
condition number
remembering remembering our formula
you have to multiply the norm of a by inverse and we did a test
where we got three and one
one i take a shot on this
the bill at ratio great raid perfect lambda max
lambda men
that tells you how are the
and you see the beauty of that number
if i multiply the matrix by a hundred
then i multiply both pieces by a hundred
same conditional so so you can't cheat by just
OK and the answer here will be sigma max
in here in in fact there is the hubble parameter so this is the effect
of the background expansion of the universe the basically tend to slow down these exponential
growth of perturbations that we had in the previous slide the solution of the previous
equation since it is at this time was something that was growing exponentially but now
you have this extra term here
and he says that enemy sort of dumping
OK so now we can study the solutions of this equation and this will tell
but to asian in the universe evolved
so let's write from here and let's see what happened in the radiation dominated area
and the radiation dominated omega if omega government is less than unity
h is one of two t
and if you plug it in here
delta grows logarithmically
so in the radiation dominated there are basically
again division don't grow the grandmother
in the dominated hand if omega on there is much bigger than omega matter and
in that sense so less than unity then they harbor
what i meant that is basically the have given by lambda remember
and then the university remember exponders financially the universe expand this actually look what happened
to put it in here and look what happened to that that the solution is
the constant loss of constant e to the minus two blah blah blah
so again petitioned don't
this thing doesn't grow
it's a that perturbation of rules
only one matter dominates perturbation can grow because when matter dominates you plug it in
there and you get something like the perturbation goes like a constant t to two
third plus some became more that we can do
how does this perturbation grow where they grow in the matter dominated they're elected to
the two two-thirds and remember to the third is directly proportional to the scale factor
in this case factor goes like one divided one c
this is very useful to know
because when perturbation can grow in the life of the universe
they can grow at the rate that you can write down in less than line
goes like the scale factor in this case if i could easily one of one
class c and c is the set of all quantities
very very useful
now the cabinet here had not always done i've done linear perturbations in gene perturbation
always work is that is less than unity
and we know that today that there's not less the unity remember for as it
was this huge number ten to fifty whatever
and so you can already see that this applies some very large scale and if
you want to apply something like this and smaller and smaller scale with traditional ladder
ladders you have to do things like revision deirdre
or more complicated stuff or at the end of the day plug everything computer and
let the computer involved is highly nonlinear equation
so what's the schematic growth of perturbations
in the
radiation dominated and remember you have perturbation in the radiation to behave like sound waves
unless you are you know outside eyes and and things like that and so the
and as long as the universe is ionized and the body and so couple to
the photons because it's mostly made of hydrogen and idea genius ionize and it's ionize
because the falcons keep heating these items then the body and to follow the same
distribution as the radiation so the body so also sources
and then at some point when the universe cools enough that they cannot keep these
hydrogen ionized then the body goes the wrong way
they behave like much but the radiation keep doing whatever it was before
and so
the body perturbation without dark matter with the then started growing like this
but what happens if you add that matter to the mix
if you have that much of the mix that method is not