but this omega is the same as that one
of course otherwise it would be in normal mode we're going to search for the
normal modes
and in the normal mode
the frequencies
must be the same of all objects whether you have five or six or two
or three
but the ratios
that's a different issue however there in phase i and phase
the ratios can be negative
on fifth
but you never have any phase angles other than one hundred eighty degrees or zero
because we have no damping we've taken them
so it is essential
when you substitute that newton's second law
these omega psi the same because they
if you the
normal modes
OK you're ready
i'm going to offset the first one
of distance
x y
i don't have mass and
they have length l
to remind you
and we are going to have omega zero screening
because g over l
and omega s
because scale
this one
i offset
over the distance x to notice
you don't have to do that always offset them in the same direction
and then there's this spring
that connect them
i to make it very
in the spring otherwise
the picture becomes a little bit too complicated
that this angle b theta one
and this angle be theta two
so we have here
you and g
reviewed the pension
roughly ng for small angles
and we have the attention
which is roughly and g
but to make the way i drew it but that's not so important now
there is another force that acts on both
and which forces
that's spring force
do we agree
what the magnitude of the spring forces
the magnitude and we'll argue about the direction
we call magnitude
look very closely offset one by x two and i offset order by x one
i was asking you a question you can answer quiz question
the magnitude of that force
and x two
is x one
non-negotiable right
now if x two is larger than x
we agree that the spring force is in this direction
and we agree then that this spring force most this direction
x two is large the next
well that means i can leave everything the way it is now
as long as i give this a minus sign it is the sign of OK
because if x two
smaller than x one
automatically for both
my older rise fine
therefore we
in my head i can think of x two being larger than x one set
of the difference equations and i no longer have to worry
about the fact that maybe x two
at certain moment in time is not
larger than x one
so now i set up the differential equations nx one double dot
but as this one
let's first dependent
there's minus
t times the sign of state i one and to use and
so is minus and g
time x one
divided by l
we agreed is that horizontal component here
the horizontal component of these driving it back to equilibrium minus sign
as the spring force is driving it away from equilibrium
so it's going to get
x two
x one
look at this
very important now
very important
and the next one
annex two double dot
because of them
the objects
it's the grouper is empty
the object is not heavy
and i'm standing to the object
now i might say well i think i can pick up the
objective all those things are true
and the other not glued to the take
OK i can pick out the objective all of those things are true
and the things like two degrees is going to get some sleep
i can pick up an object if all of those things true you can think
of a million sort of qualifications to
when it's possible to pick up an object
so the qualification problem is this problem of trying to figure out all the conditions
under which you could possibly be able to pick
the object
four which it's possible to perform that action and that in itself might be quite
OK now the ramification problem so
which we usually distinguish between the direct effects of actions of the direct effects of
action and i go over to the lights which were it might be
and i flicked the switch
so the direct effect of the action is that changes the position of the switch
from being down to y
but there are another
what we might call indirect effects or ramifications differences lights my camera
you know the white board the screen might come down
the core ramification problem is this problem of not just working out what the direct
effects of the action of the what all the ramifications are in direct effects of
and they can be quite difficult
OK now back to the frame problem how can to solve so before we solve
let's figure out what would qualify as the solution
what we got is described as system in these terms as initial state preconditions effects
what we want is a way of taking that cranking handle spinning out these frame
axioms automatically rather than us having to come up with we need an additional assumption
that assumption is that if the effects of the action say nothing about that particular
are you know that particular point sorry then that particular flight should retain its current
OK now
what we want is we want scheme that's going to be concise and the reason
we want that is that what we need these axioms
we have to write them down
they're not automatically given to us not in any logical sense deductive sense from the
actions so far
furthermore if we able to generate them automatically rather than having me write down
then this list chance making error
furthermore if i'd make a slight change to the effects again you actually remember there
was another effective action had to write down so that he
and i can read compiled this thing and get my new
and the last method which i haven't put down there is if you like me
really lazy
then you don't want to see there trying to
figure out all the things that don't change when actions
so we better to some automatic way of doing
i can get come to understand a few other bits of terminology and so on
before i get to
looking at the particular solution the frame problem
now we usually distinguish two
reasoning problems in the situation calculus
the first is this problem here is that if i take all of the actions
he all my description of
you know the state of the physics of the domain
which are called chemotherapy
i should be able to work out whether a particular floor for particular formula
is true after performing a sequence of actions they want
and that's called the prediction problem just figuring out what's true
after you put down after you perform sequence of actions
given some description of the
now the same
now the other one is well it's OK to be able to talk about what
might be true after performing these actions but we also have to reason about whether
it's actually
possible to perform that sequence maybe there is some action that i can perform that
called the legality problems and essentially what i will do it will take
the initial situation to be legal
and in any other situation is going to be legal precisely when the current situation
is legal
and it's possible to perform a particular action in that situation the next will be
legal as well
again we need to
the reason about about the projection problem about what's true in particular
situation after performing these actions
we need to be able to also work it would be able to determine whether
it's actually possible to execute a sequence of actions
all right let's try and work out how to
had had automatically create these
OK so let's have a look at this example above you were given some positive
effects for four
so if something is fragile then x this object x is going to be broken
up the robot does the drop action
if this upon the the next to the object x
then x is going to be broken after the to explore the action
so most of these examples of violence for other
if they're not usually knowledge
OK so what we can do is we're just going to rewrite them in this
particular form and the particular form is fairly straightforward what we want is basically all
the antecedent sort of stuff on the left-hand side and on the right-hand side one
particular flaw where
talking about which is broken in this case so on the right-hand side of the
implication which have drawn is the horseshoe
i've got broken sort of isolated the flow that we're talking about broken on the
right side of the implication
and all of danny's stuck all the other stuff on left
great self managed to isolate the conditions under which broke the country
and that is that if there is the robot
the action is the dropped
the robot
drop six
and x is fragile or there's a bomb the explosive these next x then
breaking against
and then a similar thing for the negative effect so forgot negative effect acting like
x becomes not broken read the robot performs repair action on of one isolate
the following on the right-hand side of an implication
and so i have this
rereading formula which is logically equivalent which is says it the robot
in the robot does repair action anything when you break
now i have to write down that essentially i have formulas of this form
i've got
so if i can just so got this form piece of which makes it remains
the conditions under which the flow becomes true positive
and then i got this in some form which is which are essentially the conditions
under which this can this flow will become falls
so isolated the conditions under which
become true
can use to interpret the data we see so for example the taxonomic tree over
animals which we might expect that the sum
you know this new feature is somehow going to be for example smooth with respect
to this taxonomy tree things nearby in the tree are likely to have the same
values of these features and we're going to
we're going to but by defining
prior on the data given structure probabilistic model of what data we expect to see
given a certain say structure will be able to use this to
give us appropriate inductive biases for generalizing this new property for figuring out which other
things have this property and we can also work backwards from all the observed features
that we see to infer the tree structure of course we have to have some
kind of higher knowledge for example we have to know we're looking for tree in
order to infer tree like this so will also specify what we call the level
of structural form which specifies the kind of relational system learning with and will even
extend the hierarchical bayesian model to to make inferences at this level to be able
to infer that say
one domain has the tree structure for the domain has a different kind of structure
and that's going to be important because not every domain represent properties is tree structure
right so
the starting work up from the bottom here how do we define the probabilistic model
of the data given structure
the intuition is like i said is that we want this prior which in a
sense is going to it's going to be flexible it's going to give any way
of labeling the objects here in the labeling of black or grey anyway of labelling
objects some prior probability but ones which are smooth with respect to the to the
graph structure should have higher prior probability this captures the basic idea of generalization by
similarity where structure determine similarity and to do this we're going to use the word
build on some nice work of you lafferty and ghahramani which probably most people here
are familiar with so i want to go into detail on the basic idea is
to define the gaussians field a set of over the graph a set of continuous
real valued quality quantities at each node of the graph reflecting sort of how much
that features associated with that point of the graph and then
we use the the structure of the graph to parameterize the covariance of the scouting
field so how
feature associations very
between a as you go across the graph the idea the intuition is that points
which are closer in the graph should have higher covariance you can think of that
also is like saying that this this feature sort of there is like a like
a smooth random walk or diffusion process over the graph so for example here's one
sample from this gas field here's another one the math behind it as again many
of you are probably familiar with is just we take the
a regularized version
of the graph posse in an inverse that give the covariance of this gaussianprocess
for the kernel you like
and then if we want to turn this into a distribution on feature extensions are
ways of labeling objects according to whether they have a binary feature not and we
can just threshold this continuous association
no no no in in order to use this distribution we want to do two
things we want to understand how we can learn the right
structured representation of the domain and how we can use it to make inferences from
very few examples of the new property and with the answer to those two questions
is basically the same so to infer the right tree structure we assume that each
of the observed features are generated from this guassian process over that
over the tree and then we just find the tree that best fits the observed
features so you can think of it as a kind of bayesian hierarchical clustering i
mean yet another bayesian hierarchical clustering we find the tree that you know on average
makes the observed features most likely under that smooth process
but the the method isn't just restricted to trees we can use other kinds of
inductive biases so for example here's the tree
here's the tree that the best tree that was found for this some fifty
animal eighty feature set but we can also
try different kind of inductive bias if you like a different kind of structure for
example we can search for the best two-dimensional embedding we're now again we have some
way to determine covariance based on proximity in this two-dimensional space and it's it's you
can think of it more less is the limiting case of the graph based approach
when you take when you take imagine take the
mesh size
two zero
and we can see well which of these kinds of you both of these are
are structured representations of the domain that makes sense of the observed feature matrix they
both kind of compression or dimensionality reduction we can ask which provide the best inductive
bias for generalizing new properties so that we now to assume that this new property
it is the complete extension of this new property which we don't observe but we
only observe a few samples the complete extension is a random draw from that same
gaussianprocess over the graph and we're going to use that as the prior for how
to fill in
the unobserved
and here's the result on two classic data sets
so what i'm planning here are there's the two datasets are the two columns here
each point data point corresponds to different inductive generalization different one of these arguments the
ones over here are have forces as the conclusion so basically we're on a very
very the
the objects which are the examples so for example this point is
is the arguments given cows elephants have property how likely is it that horses have
the same property and other points here correspond to different sets of examples over here
the conclusion is a general one that the question is how likely is it that
all mammals have property given three examples of things which have the property
and the x axis of the model predictions and the y axis are human judgments
so what you see here is a case where you have a model that are
highly correlated with people's judgments generalizations of the model things are strong like this one
are also ones that people think are strong
and once and they will also agree on which ones are weak
and these two plots here correspond to the predictions of this gaussianprocess defined over a
tree structure the ones here correspond to the predictions of the gaussianprocess defined over two-dimensional
space and what you can see is a substantial difference the tree structured model predicts
people's judgments significantly better than the two dimensional one learned from the same feature matrix
now we can
we can explore other kinds of
inductive biases in a sense what we what i would argue here's a tree structured
model is the correct or moral more and more the correct inductive bias for biological
species and properties worth the two dimensional spaces isn't really the right what you know
if you think about evolution and mutation and selection are you going to get structures
of species and distributions of properties that more let's have the distribution and people in
some sense it seems might be picking up on that
some plausible sort of articulatory position
and we can report dickinson show that they could get a well the claim that
they could get a c and increase in performance on some relatively simple
tasks with the problem in making these kinds of comparisons though is that you know
when we make comparisons with our existing HMM systems as we change the parameters as
we had parameters
we often can we can often do better so it's very difficult to make these
kinds of a-b comparisons because you have a whole different set of parameters because the
topology of your agents it is different
any other questions about
i mentioned another example where
we can use
we can modify
our lexicon
incorporating instead of representing the dictionary entries
as sequences of phonemes
you know like you i got the word and i would generally in my phonemic
dictionary expand that in terms of the sequence of phonemes
instead of doing that represent my lexical entries in terms of the bundles of distinctive
i still have
more or less a segmental representation
mister professor stephens in defining his landmark based technique he would have word is represented
in the lexicon according to this kind of model
and i think that's what
that's what motivated the this kind of thing
and so
we're still have the canonical dictionary
but we have now expanded the words into sequences of
distinctive features
and so the issue though is is how do we how do we decode with
i just really redrawn
this table here at the top of the slide
there's sort of two models that are that are represented here one
a a model of a certainty of of uncertainty
as to how the difference
a distinctive features here are synchronized
another model of uncertainty
the actual for the actual observations
a particular feature
four for a given frame so how
how likely it might be
that we substitute one feature for another in the actual realization
of this word as we speak right so get the base for dictionary
with that that we've
this has all the same old problems that we discussed earlier with regular canonical dictionary
is that when we actually speak these words are going to be pronounced differently and
how do we deal with that when the idea here is to actually have a
that of uncertainty how
how likely is it that we might substitute one feature for another when we actually
utter the word
does it work well we had some sort of sequence index here
and for for each for each
each feature i have there's a little example here where
i have the manner
and the place distinctive features
i had this feature index incriminating from increasing values as we progress
through the through decoding this word so and i see
that by having so differing feature index for these two features that describing the level
of a secret
and so
if these things are perfectly synchronized be sort of chopping through here in exactly the
same rate these guys will have exactly the same indices
as i go through and everything is fine if allowing for some level of unseen
and secondly i might have something that looks more like this different indexes for the
different features and apply some sort of model or perhaps some sort of penalty
that will describe the sort of the level of a security that i decided it
was acceptable for these features
that's one aspect of this model the other again is we're again and removing in
time here
you know when left to right is i'm is i'm decoding feature frames in the
and so
the other other model i might have is the the probability of substituting one feature
for another so for example here i'm assuming that there is some underlying baseform feature
here that might be of OWL
and so on
and then the the actual observed feature i get when i actually dakota
the entrance my system might be something different
so the model that i will have trained for the probability of substituting some observed
feature for the for
given that a particular one actually was in the base from dictionary so this is
an attempt to try and to try and undo
they these problems associated with base was canonical baseform dictionary
sure you need for this particular one in or OK i think i suppose i
was undue i have a sequence of words and i'm going to coding obviously i
have an entire search space but let's pick up after that search space and i
just have a sequence of words it's been hypothesized i'm trying to
come up with the the the goodness of that sequence with respect to this model
in that case i would i could tacked together the lexical representations for
the all the words in the string
right so
then the you know the and so the notion of
of how
when i call articulate two words for example
the notion of of
for this set the stage for the classes my accent
i will try and improve the handwriting there's not much i can do about the
next to the stage
all right so once again if both put out for the my packet to be
minus what would be we both could be possible to get plus
if i put out my pair
would be then she gets c
and i put these and she puts alpha
she gets
right that's when i have all the information that was on the sheet of paper
just added
now there is another way of organizing this is standard in game theory to get
used to it now the first
rather than drawing two different tables like this one do
i'm gonna take the second table
and superimpose it on top of the first
so we do that we'll see i mean
i'm going to do
his drawing larger table
the same basic structure i'm choosing alpha and beta on the roads
my hair is choosing alpha and beta
on the columns
but now i'm going to put both grades in
so the ones on the diagonal
both get b-minus we both choose alpha
we both get people as
if we both should be
but if i choose alpha my patches beats i get a
she gets sick
devices be and she chooses
and it's mean you get to see
and it's hard
it gets
so as i did here
the first grade corresponds to the role plan
me in this case
the second grade each box corresponds to the column player
my parents case
so this is a nice succinct way
recording was in the previous two tables
this is an outcome matrix this tells us everything
that was in the game
it's matrix
so now seems a good time to start talking about what people did so
this is a show of hands how many of you
it shows how far
the hands up so that you can catch that so just to be able to
see how OK
all right
and how we view shows pizza
there's far more to keep the weight and the need is OK
the beta here OK so long looks like a lot of going to find out
the capital of the alpha betas let me try and find out the reasons why
people chose to let me and the alpha is up again
the woman in red
i can get mike to the UK we are
you know on the run from the FBI we can also won why it uses
alpha right so why do you choose alpha
so so he wrote at least squares run part was going do respond to that
and the other reasons for choosing alpha around the world that we can get the
the woman
the density divided by the just like
the together
so it's it's name the second your name was
caught in your name was
there is so slightly different reasons same choice alpha
clarity reasons
the early stages said no matter what the other person does
she reckons she get to get a better grade if you chose alpha to hold
political come back to its parent pluralism come back to paris and the second is
talk to the beat is the second let me just emphasise this stage there are
no wrong answers later on the class become questions have right now there's no run
to optimize for that inference procedure
and then when we do that
we could get this kind of results
so this
here is this line in
all we just as well we don't have the world knowledge and
it's not doing too well and then if we have these two relations that contained
by the location
we get better results and here we constructed of simulation actually so human could disambiguate
any of the sentences so that's why you can get almost zero
sent here when you have
the world knowledge
because if have less well knowledge
you don't do well in
a more realistic setting you probably don't even have some of the world knowledge and
all of the right so then you'll probably be more in this domain
of the middle
we can also look at the
representations we learned for concepts just like in the previous talks and again you get
kind of a semantic similarity here for example it learns that female
concepts are most similar to other
and so on
so that's it for
part of the talk and we try to show a simple but general framework for
language grounding based on the task of concept labeling
and we try to make it scalable model that didn't use handcrafted features all rules
by learning hidden representations
and the real girl which
more like an artificial intelligence goal would be to train a learner living in a
computer game world to learn language from scratch
with other characters in that world like i think this would be really cool
we know we're not there yet which is actually of final conclusion for the whole
the graphical model
what you see is what
to the prior on probability
the reason for parameters which is
so it's really hard to his questions
right away
yes yes
image is politically core something like this would what
you might
i mean you may be important in the case of a one
well what the unsupervised task actually if you consider that as a tasking set-up where
you trained supervised and unsupervised actually unsupervised is mostly trained before
so if you of this then you can extend this to the limit in a
way where you have a continuous distribution
but OK so it's
in general most
convex function you and encounter are lower semicontinuous so you don't have to worry too
much about that
i markov inequality
anyone wants to
give the idea
did anyone single i mean find find the trick
OK maybe
OK so
maybe that wasn't enough
and maybe you are too shy
OK so
as i said we start from that
and we start the other way around so we start from the right
and and go
to the to the left
so what we write first is that x
because x is larger than zero
x is larger than c
is larger than
t times the indicator
that x is larger than the
it's a bit
stupid to write this but
that's how it works so
what actually this is this is always true because either
x is less than t and the indicator function is equal to zero
and because we know that x is larger than zero this is true or
x is larger than t and indicator is equal to one
we we obtain x larger than t
i mean we don't see much by saying this but this is enough to prove
this result because now we take the expectation of both sides
the fixation of x on this side and the expectation of the indicator
is the probability
so we take we obtain that the expectation of x is larger than c times
the probability
x larger than t
OK this is nothing but this statement
for the other ones
it's the same idea
you apply actually
so these are
championship in general consequences of markov inequality
you take before applying markov you take a certain function inside the probability so here
what you do is
you replace the probability
so let's write it here
so because
this quantity
it is nonnegative
you can
i mean it
easy to see that
the probability that this quantity
is larger than something
it is the same as the probability that the square of this quantity is larger
than the square of the something
causes people not be true if we if we don't take the absolute values and
and and
there is an equality inequality between those two events because they are
i mean every time this is true this is true and evidences prove this system
and you can use actually
so the fact that
one event is equivalent to the other event implies that the probability of the same
and this is a consequence if you want of
this one
here the road goes into this in both directions then you use
both statements and you get the equality i
take the square and here
when you apply markov inequality the expected value of the square here
is nothing but the variance of the of the bible x
that's why you think the variance on the right
and for general if you do the same trick
so you start
x amount of energy
this book introduction to algorithms
MIT students can get any any of the local bookstores including you might who is
also new online service
that provides the
textbooks you can also get a discount if you buy find at the MIT
press bookstore
there's a coupon in the MIT student telephone directory
four discount on MIT press books and you can use that to purchase this book
in discount
you course website this is the course website links to the stellar website which is
we're actually everything will be kept
and estimate students have their own website
a lot some students find this course particularly challenging
so each we'll have extra help we will post
weekly office hours on the course website for the TA's
and then as an experiment this term we're going to offer homework labs for this
so our homework lab is is it's a place in the time you can go
other people in the course will go
to do homework
and there will be
o typically two TA's who staff the lab
so as you're working on your homework you can get help from the TA's if
you need it
generally a place in czech we reschedule those and be on the
course calendar for where it is and when it is that the the we help
but usually sunday's two to four PM
or else it will be in
some people i think the first one is an evening right
a year to win the homework is due your best bet is trying do the
homework in advance of
you homework lab
but then
if you want extra help if you want to talk over your solutions with people
causes we'll talk about problems that you can solve in collaboration with other people in
the class
in addition there are several peer assistance programs
and those usually get all also the office of minority education has a an assistance
program and those usually get booked up pretty quickly so if you're interested in those
good idea too
make an appointment to get there and get
get help soon
OK so homework clubs i hope a lot of people try that out we've never
done this i don't know of any other course to other people have no of
course is at MIT that done this
six o one one day OK
and was successful in that class
never went OK
so we'll see
well say
OK if it if it's not paying off then will just return to or near
office hours for those TA's but
but i think that for some students i think that's that's a good opportunity
if you wish to be registered in this course you must sign up on the
course web page
so that's requirement one must be done today
we will find it difficult to pass the course if you're not in the class
and you should notify at you if you decide to drop so that we can
get you often stop the mailings stop the spam OK
and you should register today before seven PM
and then we're an email your recitation assignment you before noon tomorrow
and if you don't inform received this information by thursday noon please send us email
OK saying to the core staff generally not to me individually
saying that you didn't receive your recitation assignment
so if you have received it by thursday noon
you know if you want to know why i think that generally i think are
interesting about tonight writer this by tomorrow morning
students don't have to worry about this
problem sets with nine problem sets that we
the project will be assigned during the semester
a couple things about problems at home works will generally be accepted
if you are extenuating stands circumstances you should make prior arrangements with your recitation instructor
that almost all the administrative staff you shouldn't come to me and say can i
had in something like this should be talking to your recitation instructor
you can read the other things about the
the form there are both are but let me just mention that there exercises that
should be solved but not hindered in
as well to give you drill on the material i highly recommend you doing the
exercises they both test your understanding of the material and exercises have this way of
finding themselves on quizzes
they are often asked to describe algorithms and here's little outline of what you can
use to describe an algorithm
the grading policy is something that somehow i cover and always every term is at
least a couple of students who
pretend like i never
show them this OK
if you skip problems it has a non-linear effect on your great
OK so you know skip any problems
no effect on your great OK
i've escape one problem and hundreds of letters right we can handle that
OK but two problems it's attempt as you see by the time you've skipped like
letter grades it's already a third of five problems is not problem sets by the
this is problems
OK you're down the third of letter grades
and if you don't do nine or more so that's typically about three to four
problem sets
OK you don't pass the class
OK so i always have some students coming to the end the say i didn't
do any my problems
OK just passed me because i did OK on exams answer no
OK very simple answer questions
set it up front
so the problem sets are an integral part of the
the course collaboration policy this is extremely important so everybody pay attention if you sleep
wake up
like that's going to wake anybody
so the goal of homework
professor domains in my philosophy is that the goal of homework is to help you
learn the material
one way of helping to learn is not just be stuck and unable to solve
because then you are in no better shape when you examine all around
OK which is where we're actually evaluating u
it's not the kind of
legal break type of theorem which tells you you can take all these of these
individual marginals and piece them together into for like lower dimensional measures piecing together into
high dimensional one
what it is is
it's this regularity here
from my point of view this is the regularities here
and kind of kind of the intuition
but that might be helpful is if you think for example of
of continuous functions on the real line
so in order to define a function on the real line you have to specify
its value at every single point
so the
in general function on the real line has an uncountable number of degrees of freedom
one for each point in r
now if you restrict your find a set of functions to the continuous functions
a continuous function is completely defined if you know its values on a dense subset
so far but for example if you know all the values of the function on
on the rational numbers then it's already completely defined
because the the the the the condition that it's that's continues
oppose so much smoothness on it that effectively reduces the number of degrees of freedom
the effective number of degrees of freedom is much smaller than the uncountable set
and you can go even further so theorem that most people you will be familiar
with this decision nyquist sampling theorem which says if you have a bandlimited function
then it's actually
then then you can sample of finite number of times within its period until
and that completely defines the function
so it's bandlimited then actually find the values of a finite number of points if
you choose the right way to find number of points completely
in the series is somewhat similar to what this says is
this the this measure here is the set function that maps sets to numbers
but it's not an arbitrary set function but is the probability measure and we had
this number of conditions in the definition of a probability measure that
that we
o request require office that function in order for it to be called the probability
measure and with this says is
one way to interpret this is to say that
the marginals
that we that we started with
define the value of this measure on sets that look like this so
the the the marginals of finite dimensional so the set down here
this this overall space would be infinite dimensional
but we have something that is non-trivial shape
only a finite number of dimensions
and all other dimensions of experiments in the kind of
what the theorem says is
if we know if we know
the value of the measure
of this measure mu e on all sides of this shape
then we actually know it on all sides and i think
because the measures so regularly
it would not work for an arbitrary set function it has to be probability
that's regularity results
and in the in the jargon of probability theory this kind of matter that is
defined by the theorem is called the projective limit
of this family of march
projective limit
so now i really have to hurry up
quickly let's let's quickly run through the
through the construction of the gaussian process again just two
to see what individual components me
if we if we apply that to an example
and then i will tell you what's wrong with this kind of
gaussianprocess process construction we will choose
this this excess space which was that are
here in the form in later life
decided not to like in better
look at
the better
OK so let's go back to the
so you choose to stay
state one
with probability
o point one
good as one with probability point
probability point one
you get are still
with every change deterministically go
the probability of one point l
s two
now imagine that i told you you could you could achieve
some value
you could see some value from being in state s one you could achieve some
value in being in state s two
now how do you do
i hope have have
how do you have to achieve
that's OK was given here but all that the math all work now
in this example
OK so the first thing you say is
i could stay
if i stay
with point nine probability
that's not this branch
i can get the this one
they were singing achieve at least that value for me as well
and one point one probability
i get what
one of the transition to have to get the best two
the point one times what
are one thing to say
so point nine acted as one of the best one
four point one public invested in getting what
he has to
look at
here is is much simpler
the probability one i get asked to
and i get the of
so for each branch
for each branch stay or change i know the expected value you find these numbers
some numbers
then what action
OK you you know the numbers from which had previously
imagine to denote these numbers
if you have to choose between stay change mass one
not what the numbers are
how how would you choose the best action
OK i see you are linear algebra by that that would last year
a bit more explicit forty nine BS one was point one vs two
is greater than
the s two
do what
a course day
and if it's not true
then do what
change OK
so if you know you can see some value in end
i don't know how i know that
what will get minute you can derive the policy that what she believes that value
OK and here's exactly
so you have so we assume that we i didn't show
we were here
but that so when we have reward to for staying
and we had the war ten for change
so this is slightly different should be too
ten plus
but still
there that's correct so
actually it which maximizes the reward that you get a plus b
value again the next
OK so what i drug here
yes you exactly
right so that there are there this existence theorem that says there is a policy
only present the current state that
that is optimal there exists a policy
i have properties
so we only this assertion is based policies
yeah exactly
so i mean i actually like an answer themselves why
did did did receive policy suffice
because if if i had one action that could be
ten expectation well let's say a course stay
how expectation sorry i'm building giving notation
feature value of
and a course change had expected future value
doesn't really make a difference seventy percent
on the same
now the basic technique
so that the weighted by the case went down to eighty five
because the rate i mean cannot identify it would be much more training data to
identify that certain motifs has appeared
but you don't about this picture of the ship
this should comment
let's use the ship
to specify how much of the kernel country
larouche by ten
i can be larger than the very simple
i should add
but it's little long but
only goes up to ninety two
and i think when you increase the further
like what
maybe you can play around with it these scripts which used here you can download
from on the wiki page what you need is toolbox of visual box link
the developing the link on the on the
should we both the org and that you can download from open source
just compiled
we estimate that i mean well the heuristic i mean what we do is we
this kind of progress so we some remaining in accuracy in SVM like
so if we
we have certain assumptions how
o that is related to the training time
i mean it's usually not very
but but
other of questions for example work for the truth about what
OK so
i mean we talked about mining based on the generation of feature space where we
think about which kind of features we would like to do it
once we find that you can simply take the kind
the band for the spectral mismatch mismatch twenty of these things the position with of
the other side
based on physical chemical properties
now i would like to describe another kind of is called the fisher that uses
probabilistic model
the basis and generate from the probabilistic model
and and find
well actually defined feature which are then used to define find
OK so probabilistic models for probabilistic modeling of violence because quite a bit older actually
than than most machine learning technique markov models one markov models of one example hidden
markov models frequently used in computational biology but also stochastic context free
what is the point in a hidden markov model
there some start date and end date and then you have other state and they
when the match
one version with additional offices in motor
OK so this is like model
like a lot of what sequence which should exhibit a certain
and depending on the motor
but in the motives they are set by the emission probability
OK so important part
for parametric model
family of distributions
usually like this to have some parameter of some
from space maybe in parameters
and then you would to the distribution is parameterized by theta
OK a simple example is a position specific scoring matrices is very frequently used in
about it
and it essentially identical to your order markov chain
so the idea is that we have a sequence of this explain
and then we have
a bit of link with before then we have a metric which is four times
the length of the sea
so and we compute the probability of the secret by taking the
by using the
he index them and so this one role point eight one b one party party
and if the person is in a we use the
and i like to have magic from a metric
and for every position
but it doesn't have are are being the number of random samples you may
points the gap between the bucket of six draws from it
so that shows that really
so what i've done
here is drawing
fifty samples
from the green distribution
for every one of them given that coordinates
this uniformly distributed between
the horizontal axis
it means that all those points shown in blue yellow
those points are uniformly distributed in the area
and the degree
that's what this construction
one step
get to a point is scored x u
uniform and the green
many uses and you cut out all ones that have a low
just on the the red curves
those points must be uniformly distributed in the area of the right
so you can imagine railway all yellow ones
one you think
exactly from registration
you know
that's rejection sampling
and it's absolutely crucial that must be true in situ
is bigger than or equal to be star because
it's not true as shown by
this example
and if you draw points and pretend that you're doing rejection sampling you will reject
the yellow points to the points now the distribution q actually drawing from some strange
distribution that is the red shirt or something like that
in you
and so it's crucial that you must be an oracle start
and that these are is complicated distribution is a little bit of understand
it may be a very difficult
that you've got a few which this is true
it's not just that you have to you know that is true for some something to happen
say that it is true for a particular you need sea
the algorithm to you
but i see it
get uniform
okay so the comment is it's very easy to check
whether see
is bigger and start with the places where you actually true
points and that's absolutely true
so you could
not only
drawing you could also see if you had one
then would
sorry if you equal see times due
would still be less than so you can very easily checked
true that is true error
thank you
so yes you can check that's not satisfactory on column that you really want theorem
that says if you run this algorithm or long enough
get the right answer
so just checking is good enough
okay and here again is the estimate of the expected value
all the methods we saw earlier with using
importance sampling
and then in green answer all rejection sampling which is
growing from the correct distribution
and you can see it
so settling down as well in the same way as the other three
the other any questions about
importance sampling or
rejection sampling
all assembled into the assumption is that q is a distribution that we can draw from so
and they
real space it might be a guassian question
or it might be a mixture of gaussians you've invested in some way
in any case this means the sort of thing you could use that to
it might be
the distribution where each state end things in the magnet just flip so biased coin
some sort of assignment or the
points of
independently of each other
and that's a very easy distribution
that's the sort of human use
distribution that doesn't have strong correlations it
what it does have correlations in it among variables
simple correlation simple enough that you can still solve the problem drawing from
thank you
so rejection sampling is wonderful usually you can't do it
and you will be two reasons why
is that you can't think about few such that's you can it because you don't understand it well enough
or if you can come up with such
which you have proof this property
it may be so much higher than that you end up rejecting every single point just run never point
because you're only in this area
four agreeing thing that so much higher
and the red
so that's the sad truth about rejecting something that unless you're very lucky or very clever
you won't actually the age set
he rejection sampling a real problem
in one dimensional problems like the ones we have on the screen now
you can realistically do rejection sampling and one approach to
the methods are about to discuss
which i metropolis
i had been all but forgotten
students around princeton
i knew him only as the phantom five hall
silent goes like figure who scroll mysterious messages
on the blackboards of princeton's math and physics buildings
and outside
a small circle
of mathematicians
even people like me
i had heard about his work simply assumed he was dead
so naturally
i was
very intrigued to learn that she was alive
he seemed to be well
and he might now win the nobel prize semidefi phone calls
to me
the notion
that someone
it's someone who had been lost
for so long
could be found again
it's someone who had fallen
as far as john nash had fallen
could come back
to me
it seems extraordinary it sounded like a greek myths
fairy tale
extraordinary lives
i have this unique
unique our
john nash
who someone
thinking thinking all always thinking
is a genius
most of us are not most of our lives
don't contain the elements of genius madness
reawakening and nobel yet paradoxically
his trials
and triumphs
the trials and triumphs of this
very unique individual have nonetheless resonated with millions and millions of people
around the world
i want because because many of you in this room mathematicians i just want to
read you a letter
john to illustrate this point the john nash
got a few weeks ago
dear mister nash
i am nine years old
my name is at still so
i am a girl
i really admire you
you are my are all el al model
for a lot of things
i think the smartest person who ever lived i really wish to be like you
i would love to study maths
the only problem
is that
i'm not very good at math
i can do it
i like it
i'm just not very good at it
was that what it was like when you were a kid
have you always been good at math
please write back love ali
i love your name
act one of john nash is true
it is a classic coming-of-age story
john nash was born in
blue field west virginia
in the blue ridge mountains
he was born on the eve of the great depression
he was a peculiar
solitary intellectually precocious little boy
other children nicknamed him
but brains
i had ideas
he said later
i had ideas but they were sort of buggy
we're not perfectly sound
at ten john nash was doing rather sophisticated
chemical experiments
and tricking other children
by shocking them with electrical currents
at fifteen he was
this common sense
what is
the cyc ontology are subsite knowledge base so this would be kind of synonyms cyc
knowledge base cyc ontology
this is
o an ontology you can see these in many different ways but one possible visualisation
this would be
following like three
of concepts and these three
three hundred thousand concepts which is
a lot
and these concepts are connected weights fifteen thousand relationships if you remember before his wordnet
was roughly hundred thousand concepts connected with weights
twenty six relationships and it's already very rich while cyc
because numbers might be
and so
this concepts and relationships are
the weights more than three three four million
actually effects which are connected
into the
on the bottom of the
this conception three
we'll see examples of this
so the whole ontology is expressed in first-order and higher-order logics then it has a
special mechanism for so called contextual logic and so on so it's pretty strong
mechanism but the main formalism is logic
places all mean let's say so at the top we have a concept think
which so everything is sub concept of thing and then
we have the space part-time by imparting thinks
part of living things are also human beings and it only human beings because different
aspects of human beings and so on so this is a structured routine very detailed
way i will show some of these course concepts and later
so what is roughly the structure of the cyc ontology
on the top we have the so-called upper ontology
and these are really abstract concepts which she would correspond to a philosophical
notions how to organize how to organize the word tends want and relationships between different
things and so on
then below this we have something which they called courtier is like space causality and
so on and then below this we have more domain specific stuff
on the bottom effects which are
the actual facts of life
instances which are connected either to the domain specific or core theories
as a
in upper ontology would be things like thing
what is individual temporal think events and so on while that's a courtier is would
already have rules like this
for all events a and b
if a causes b
implies a precedes b for instance this rule which
it's through four
any situation in the
it's normal this
which we know
if you go to some other
mystic stories then maybe this wouldn't be true anymore
that's why this is quite common sense
they they also have this mechanism for contextualizing knowledge and let's say that try to
model also
greek mythology than a lot of these things don't hold any more about it there's
a mechanism how to escape from these rules as well
and domain specific theory would be
so like this for any mammal m and any anthrax bacteria eight
if m is exposed to is a
this causes m to be infected by a reference this is a rule which was
he this domain specific theories
and the actual fact of life would be that john is a person infected by
and by having all this upper level knowledge we would know that john is a
person we know
very well the person can get infected it's an animal and so on and what
it means being affected and you know what the sentence and so on because all
this of all these upper-level levels of knowledge
OK and this is an example of how
this ontologies from psychiatry slating
text knowledge into
first order logic
so if we have a sentence like this so there a couple of examples from
this there is the main because in the last
yes you can imagine that they got some funding
this kind of the domain
so there's groups are capable of directing assassinations so this is
so into the so-called cyc least like
language but you can
basically first order logic
so if some x some group
it's a terrorist group this implies that they are behavior that this group is
which are capable assistant something direct cage so they basically these concepts from ontology
and relationships and this kind of rule this kind of centres gets translated in this
kind of rule and then later on it can be used
when doing increasing
or this sentence
for those who considers an agent an enemy that agent with the world that the
in that this
gets translated into such a state
this is mainly done by hand i mean especially translation of this kind of
well let's see the actual effects
which can be fired from that in news stories
OK this is based it then
said in this kind of people
based basedinregion alqaida of constant OK that's based on region of ghana in afghanistan are
the concepts in
in the database
and so one way how they want to go through the
comment news stories
then this major effects are getting translated in such logic form and then the system
is able to to reason with minutes later on i will show some examples
so this is an
another view how
concepts in
psychiatry presented as a concept for psychoanalysts
the several lexical representations like psychoanalyst psychoanalysts and so on and this is no hierarchy
all of these concepts so
so i find it is
sub concept of medical care professionals the further on health professions professional adult and professional
market this is one way
how we can abstract cycle and this another way how to
generalize this concept is this is psychologists scientist researcher presented patient person homo sapiens and
the logic of species and on the here we are pretty high up in the
in the hierarchy already so this is just one simple snapshot from the
from the database
and if you know that somebody other freud's psychoanalyst then we know immediately that it's
also homo sapiens and whatever holds for
homosapiens holds also for right the article is reasoning engine can can use this information
a factor of of two
we multiply in the correct way in the summation right and we get
a vector over four things right we call factor
that is the function basically if i signs the number
two each possibility
right this
factor doesn't need to have some two
set of probability doesn't necessarily sum to one in this case actually
if you know one
in this case it won't
but it's just nonnegative numbers right
so in the combined these two pieces and then further we just keep doing that
the inexorable push it in
until you can no longer do that
so here we also did was
switch the switch the variables
it's fine to write
so now we have this missionary and finally we have this factor to be
that's only ever be and what way that
it that we can't can't calculate and and you will calculate how many iterations this
took as opposed to how many iterations this to commonly classes and multiplies
yet huge wins from doing
from doing this because what you're doing is instead of
instead of doing this but this was for this year doing one multiply in one
edition instead of a whole bunch
OK so that's the that's the key
the idea that they are from these both variable elimination and
the junction tree algorithm
so we actually got into
graphical models yet this is just conditional independence assumptions and
how to help us do inference right so we don't say anything about graphical models
but you know we're going there so the
the variable elimination OK and so on
if you think about how long does it take this in general right it's done
so the size of these things we generated go along these things are fixed
right so we need to worry about is the size of these factors that we
can be carrying around right
basically that is the size of the largest intermediate factor
and we picked elimination order in
some ran away tell you what i did what i said i just picked one
different elimination order is going to produce different types of different sizes of these
intermediate factors if i chose to eliminate
the first
right this would be very unfortunate choice
t would get a factor well someone to produce with factor that includes and and
well and
ian be OK so i would have factor three things because if i eliminate a
i get to multiply those guys
this guy the guy everything that includes a
OK so then i get something that's over EB right through variables so b
a size eight right
these guys are also still
so more generally if you think you know the wrong order i do get some
factors are very large
and you picking the up one is NP hard but there are good heuristics for
picking reasonable it's so
if you wanted to get right
you know
basically grow
exponential with the number of variables inside
so we have haven't said what they look like but in graphical models
this these independencies in
these properties of know how big how expensive this this inference is going to be
it becomes obvious from the graphical structure
right so
but it conveys exactly what we need
right so so so what i'm going to what i'm what i'm getting at here
is that gas and process can be used to specify
a distribution over functions
and if we want to make
probabilistic inference about functions
then we better have a way to write down distributions of all these objects because
if you can do that then we can apply probability theory
and the gas process is exactly
the object that we use to to handle
distribution over functions to specify them and to manipulate
OK so the former definition here is because the process is a collection of random
any finite number of which have gotten distributions
mathematically there are a number of technicalities involved in having infinite collections of things
so if you strip mathematician and you might wonder you know is this is this
really well defined i'm not strict in general care about these things
but but that's why
so that's the mathematicians definition here right so they
try to avoid saying anything about infinity it's just a place to collect collection but
only any finite number of which have consistent gaussian which i haven't said anything about
things that might be
all right but we don't we don't actually we only need to worry about a
thing nothing will think that will happen here
so just like calcium distribution here
it's not specified fully specified by
i mean that
and the covariance matrix
i guess in process
it's just
specified in terms of the infinitely long versions of that so instead of having a
mean vector and have the gas process has and has an infinitely long
i mean that right
an infinite
the long vectors are functions
OK so
the gas has i mean function
and similarly it doesn't have the covariance matrix but has a covariance
matrix here which is an infinite by infinite dimensional matrix
that's not that's function with two arguments
so formally this way we can write down
something like this
all right
so now
at this point you might be a little worried because
you can actually write down long vector anywhere
so if this machinery that i'm going to develop would require you to write that
down your computer for example
then you know already that
you know you can do it exactly this to make things like very
turns out the things don't get very
and the reason why things will will will turn out OK
is what's known as the
what i call the marginalisation property
so basically it has to do with the fact that the marginal distribution of the
gaussians joint council is again accounts so if we if we had something
which is jointly
jointly has a gas distribution if we now marginalise out the distribution of y
then we get back the distribution of x
this is joint distribution was calcium than the distribution of x also began
and both x and y could be vectors in this case
so now
so let's pretend that we now have a full gaussianprocess
right so we have
we have an infinite and infinitely large
long vector here right
the joint distribution over
let's say we had
so we had a number of of points are actually interested in
and they had all the other points
why here
now if you write down the joint distribution of this that have a mean where
the with the mean of the x-factor will be a and the mean of
why that to be
the the covariances between axis will be a and the cross covariances will begin by
so we're where this thing here
if this is the gas process and this thing here will be will be infinitely
large matrix is symmetric
but the nice thing here is that the marginal distribution for x is just going
to be
and all girls in distribution with mean and covariance matrix capital
so it means
if you if you ask finite dimensional questions
this infinite dimensional objects
then you get if you get some get finite dimensional right
the finite dimensional and so doesn't
depend on all these things are going on all the all the corners of this
very very long time
joint distributions using a set of local probability relationships are local distributions that are specified
actually on the graph
and the way we manipulate these graphs is we draw one node in the graph
for every random variables in our problem
and then edges between those nodes tell us something about the conditional independence assumptions and
actually the way these things work is relatively intuitive i can just draw you a
quick picture here
i can show you
this work so let's say there are four
variables in our domain x one
x two
x three and x four
in directed style of graphical models when you draw a picture like this what you're
really saying is
you're telling me how you want to factorize the joint distribution across x one through
x four by using this picture and intuitively if you have some variable
that's the parents of another variable in the graph
then the child variables
can decide its distribution by looking only at its parents so in this picture here
that i drew the idea is that first we choose a value for x one
and then given the i four x one we choose a value for x two
x three x three needs to only consulted parent x one and x two needs
only consulted parents which is also one
and then given x two and x three which is about four x four x
one needs to only consulted which is so this picture
is a way of specifying a factorisation of the joint distribution which is the following
so this is just the joint distribution between all those things and
this picture specifies the following factorisation
p px x one times
p of x two given x one
the next three given x one
and then p of x four different two
so this picture is the quote which communicates to you how i choose to factorize
this joint distribution
and the code for the complete independence factorizations is just to have no errors in
your graph
so if i restored heroes
then that would be my way of telling you that i wanted to factorize the
joint distribution not like this but just like this one
and people two
times t three
the next
there's also a cold
four specifying no assumptions at all
in year distribution in other words that you don't want to make any factorisation assumptions
you want to represent the joint as the most general possible joint distribution that you
because they want to take a guess at what the code looks like
i can help you out by drawing the picture
like this
you can also achieve nothing by looking ahead announce if your
we should do that
so what is the
how do you represent a completely general distribution
well you know that by the law
of conditional probability you can always write this distribution no matter what the distribution is
you can always write it
in a change so by saying it's marginal over x one and then some conditional
x two given x one x three given everything that comes before
x two and x one
and x four
given everything that came before x three x two
so what i wrote this equation i didn't make any assumptions about this distribution
unlike the previous equations derived which were strong factorizations assumptions here any distribution the joint
distribution can always be written this way by the law of conditional probability
so the graph corresponds to this is just the graph in which each node has
all the nodes to its left is its parents
and so on
OK so
by drawing these pictures i can communicate to you
what assumptions i want to make about the joint distribution all the way from the
completely factorized distribution which is a graph with no edges to be fully general arbitrary
degree distribution which is a graph that has many many edges
so these graphical models are also known as bayes nets or belief nets for bayesian
belief nets or
depending on exactly
you know how
what historical figure looking at and the the history here is that judea pearl was
the statistician at UCLA really deserves most of the credit for bringing these graphical models
into artificial intelligence and later machine learning he wrote a book called probabilistic inference and
intelligent systems in which he goes to the exactly the probabilistic approach to IR and
why you need joint distributions in these graphical models which at the time he wrote
the book were virtually unknown and lots of people ridiculed him for writing this sort
of byzantium book about this weird area of graph theory the obviously has nothing to
do with and now graphical models like dominated huge part of statistical
artificial intelligence
there's a lot of credit due to judea pearl's writing that very seminal book at
the time in which you those ideas were not talk today is also
unhappily the father of the journalist any pearl was killed in the middle east six
or seven years ago so if you do that think that's the same thing
there's a question here
exactly that's exactly right so everyone here the question the question was well you can
write this factorisation by ordering the variables in any way you want
and so
does it mean that there could be multiple graphs which are equivalent and the answer
is yes
any graph specifies the family of distributions based on the assumption is that the graph
encodes but there might be several different graphs which all encode the same set of
assumptions and thus specified same families an excellent
OK so there are two kinds of graphical models here i just told you about
the directed kind there's also an undirected kind of model
in the undirected graphical model
assumptions are a little bit different assumptions are that the distribution is specified as the
product of potentials that live on the cliques of the graph
there's a lot of words in that sentence so what you say it again
a little bit more slowly in undirected models
what you do is you look at the graph
which is the same thing as in directed models that code for me to communicate
to you what factorisation i want to make this distribution so x
one that has the greatest variety of things
OK so let me just mention some applications just to give you a flavour of
what can be done
with probabilistic logical models and within moments in particular
so as christian already mentioned
srl in general animals in particular have been used for a whole slew of things
in just about every domain that you care to imagine
the one that i'm going to focus on here
is information extraction
so again this is the example that that christian had our goal is to first
of all segment these citations
in two authors titles and venues
and then you know do the into resolution
right information extraction has two basic steps segmentation and into resolution into resolution is where
you realize that crossing was the same as saying that he
and tripoli as it's the same thing as proceedings of the twenty first national conference
on AI
notice that this is not easy to do right because the strings look completely different
in this case but we're going to be able to do this
and then you also realize that this will papers the same thing as the whole
and now the state of the art
in into resolution
is to use an HMM or CRF for segmentation
by using it to assign each token to a field so author author author title
title venue evaluates
and then into resolution is done by using a classifier like logistic regression naive bayes
to predict for every pair fields or citations whether the same or not
and then finally need the transitive closure step right because if if you're classifier says
that is the same as b and is the same as c
that is the same as
now if you want to build your own information extraction system like people typically the
industry these days using a language like c java
you probably run into the tens of thousands of lines of code and taking weeks
to do in the body
in markov logic it's just seven form
it takes you know half an hour to write them down and actually the seven
from fit on this slide
and that's what i'm going to show next
so first of all you can
so this is actually what you would inputting in your mln file that you then
you know
put into or commit to learn weights and do inference
you can have optionally e
type definitions
i'm putting them here for clarity but usually can just further from the that's so
that we have to do this part
so going have talk and field citation in position
tokens are the words that appear fields are in this case five thousand anybody could
be city organization person et cetera
and all citations and positions are the obvious things
and then this predicate next thing need to find the predicates
so this predicate tokeniser evidence predicates is that this talk and appears in this position
the citation
and then these predicates of the query predicates
the infield predicate there's the segmentation
it says that this position in the citations for of this field like for example
the first position of the first citation is part of the off field
and that these two billion to resolution
the same field as the resolution for fields and same citation doesn't for citation
so here is the ML and that as the whole work
seven formulas as advertised
the first three formulas implement the CRF
or or or hmm if you trained discriminatively
the first formula
effectively implement effective actually precisely performance the observation matrix of the HMM
so the convention here is that all free variables are universally quantified as in prolog
and this little plus
it means that we want alchemy to learn weights for every grounding of this formula
for every one of these variables
now we have pluses on both the token in the field
so what learning weights for this formula does is matrix of weights of token by
which is the correlation between tokens in fields like conferences like appearing title smith is
likely to appear in a moments for
and then you know the other forms of basically just below know this one is
the transition matrix
and this one is a little trick that allows us to not have you know
special state four
you know something that doesn't there's not part of any of the field but the
bottom line here is that you can set up an HMM or CRF in markov
logic with just two very short
now this parts into resolution
the first formula predicts whether two things are in the same field
you can think of this is like a similarity comparison saying that if these two
if this
appears in both of these fields that makes them more likely to be the same
and i'm going to learn what for how informative the token is so this is
similarity comparison it's also
a logistic regression where the predicted variables saying field and these
which is lambda
then we take all the strings of length one that's just individual entities then all
the strings of length two then all the strings thanks three and so on so
makes a nice order in which we do have the strings that arrive more or
less like with like
so with the hierarchical order for just got to letters in order alphabet which are
a and b we would find is for strings for this order the strings at
so got one string of length
one two strings of length sorry one string of length zero two strings of length
one for strings of length two
eight of length three and so on
so just for the sake of an example
if we got a b and c with a smaller than b and smaller than
for the lexicographic order we'd have a baby which would be before a b
but if you took the length lex order
you have it the opposite way round because one is of length two and that
one is of length three seems easy
and carefully if you're looking at the prefix oil well maybe is neither a prefix
of a a b nor is a a b prefix if a
OK so this is one of the ideas of topology to put order over things
the second idea typically into apologies to distances things because you've got a set of
strings or a set of objects and you wanted to put some sort of the
distance of this we're hearing this morning mentioned the case of the k nearest neighbours
all these techniques
typically in pattern recognition all based on having distances so what we know now about
distances and how do we build distances on typically strings
so the first thing is what is the problem while the problem is to build
some sort of
a function which given a class of objects
we're going to talk about strings but at the same time there are distances on
graphs there distances on trees you can have distances on anything you're trying to represent
so these objects under all representations of these objects and you want to functions such
that the closer x and y are one to each other the smaller is the
smaller is the distance between the two that is what a distance is
i come to to the second
but then
apart from saying that apart from saying that you've got this class of objects representations
and just something that is close to the smaller the distance when you like have
some mathematical properties of the mathematical properties of these things here and they define what
is called a metric
OK now
when you read
books and articles
the confusion about the word distances is really very complete right some people are going
to call this an something that does have the properties and some people don't call
it like that some people use distance with all sorts of things are not so
it's very important to know
if we do have the properties in which when we do have or not why
for algorithmic reasons
again because you will not be able to use the same algorithms if you've got
certain properties about this distance using or not
so just let's look at what other the properties that are usually imposed one of
them is saying to the distance between x and x is zero
fair enough
the second one is to say that this between x and y
is the distance between y and x o saying the symmetrical you can think about
distance if you've done already machine learning you realize that quite a few of them
do not already comply with this being symmetrical is not always that easy
third typically that is in every case is it has that is that the of
x and y is positive so you want to distance to be positive having negative
distances and from
even if there are cases where people are doing distances where the result is not
a number or to complex number or it's something completely different for because that's what
they like and there are two other ones which
reasonable are important one of them is to say that whenever got the distance between
x and y is zero then it's because and only because x equals y that
is very important because that means that when we got that property it means every
time we are testing the distance we can actually at the same time trying to
test for the
isomorphism of the structure of for the quality of the structure of the equivalent of
the structure
so in problems where whatever you're manipulating finding out if the two things of same
take graphs for example
OK if you do distance in graphs to try and see if two graphs are
whatever the distances between them if you've got this property here
df x y equals you implies x equals y what does it mean it means
that what you're computing will help you solve the graph isomorphism problem
who knows what the graph isomorphism problem is
but it it's basically you take one graph
and you just shove everything around you move things i mean they and you rename
the labels and you've got to graph that the that you tried see is the
the same graph you know just where you move things around or not
is it just a question of representing in space the same object
so if it is the same object then that means that we have got the
graph isomorphism with they are isomorphic if you don't it means that they mean that
they are not isomorphic so this happy all the time when you are trying to
do are represented in images by graphs where people are trying to think is the
same image this this by saying is this the same graph is this
now this is what you call this is another untractable problem it's not quite NP
right but it's regarded to be
hard in the sense there's is no polynomial algorithm either to solve the problem
at least people believe there isn't one
OK so this means what it means that if you are thinking of doing nice
distances that have all these sort of features but at the same time you're lovely
little distance is solving some problems with this supposed to be
difficult then it means that something wrong somewhere
probably all those are your algorithm is exponential all your thinking you're doing something that
you're not doing
so that's why i know a little bit what we're doing about this is important
this the last equation is known as the triangle inequality which is
typical right we know that if the distance between x y and added to the
distance of y z should be larger than the distance between x and z this
is not always the case in a lot of distances that are used in practice
typically in bioinformatics
but why is it useful to have it
however can think OK you know it might want is all we may not want
it is just because we want to do mathematics no for algorithmic reasons when you
do have it you can actually you use it the triangular in equivalence to avoid
for example searchengin hold whole chunks of the data space
because you can use it to say well you know i know this is already
more than whatever threshold i was looking for so there's no point in looking at
these because i will be even further
OK so be able to use those properties are related to doing things like that
what and that edge is an edge of the shortest path from s to v
what do we know
do you know about the i becomes the correct value delta s comedy i this
was called correctness lemma
last time
one of the things we proved about algorithm but it was really just the fact
about relaxation
and it was a pretty
simple proof
it comes from the fact
we we know the shortest path weight is this certainly DVI was at least this
and let's suppose is greater otherwise we were done we know DVI minus one is
set to this
so this is exactly the condition is being checked in the relaxation step and they
will actually this the DVI
well you will be greater than this
but suppose
and then we'll set equal to this and that's exactly the SPI
when we relax that edge we've got set it to the right values so so
the this is the end of the proof round very simple
the point is you you look at your shortest path here it is
and if we some there's no negative weight cycles this has the correct value initially
the idea of s is going to be zero
after the first round you've gotta relax is an edge
and then you get the right value for the vertex after the second round you
got to get you gotta relax the essential to achieve the right value the value
for this vertex and so on
so no matter which shortest path you take you can apply this analysis and you
know that by
if that is the length of the path
is here we stand it was k edges
then after k rounds you've got to be done
so this not actually in the per
so this means after ten rounds
we have the right answer for k which is
so the only question is how they could KB better be the right answer
and most the minus one
the claim by the the algorithm that you only need to do the minus one
steps and indeed the number of edges in a simple
in the graph is at most the number of vertices minus one
OK is it must be minus one
please simple
so that's why we have to assume that wasn't just any shortest path had simple
one didn't repeatedly vertices so there must be vertices in the past of the minus
one edges in the past
and that's all there is the number four
it's pretty simple
incorrectness of course we're using a lot of elements that we had last time
which makes it easier
OK a consequence of this theorem this proved is that
if the bellman ford fails to converge
and that's what the algorithm is tracking is whether this relaxation
still requires work
after this the minus one step further and the album is run another round of
heathrow and see whether anything changes also the argument fails to converge
after the virus one steps
then there has to be
a negative weight cycle
OK this is just the contrapositive what we proved we prove that you assume there
is no negative weight cycle then we know the DNS is is zero and then
all this argument as you've got to converge after the minus one rounds can be
anything left to do once you reach the shortest path weights going monotonically you can
never hit the bottom