even the consumers are infecting themselves so
i just want to consider just the there are viewpoints or they have share and
there you can that your marketing strategies according to them
so there's some not only speaking their mind but they also because their opinions
so these blogs are basically informative sources and the track consumers beliefs and opinions
you can use them
that their reaction to a launch
and you can understand the language
you can track their trends and buzz words
and you can be segmented based on these things you can find tuning strategies
block and relations of the leave behind the trails of links
which are also useful for understanding how information flows through this blog network
and how opinions are shape how this can influence others
are other customers consumers
this also helps in gaining deeper insights
there have been some systems which
opinion mining and blogs
so system by a gamut of cardboard
we use the a base classifiers
now manually annotated sentences with positive negative sentiments and the site reads this and i
presented all the unlabelled is adequately classified
one of the system now it improves the blog retrieval by using opinionated words which
are obtained from wordnet
given a query so they find the
proximity of this crater using the wordnet and then they had to
finding the right to retrieve similar sentiment blogs
other well-known opinion mining and sentiment analysis techniques could be
following in a book by not being you
what are you basically of blogs has a lot of textual content so you can
board of these textual
analysis text mining techniques
from different occasions two plugs
this is often called
which is an open source software which performs
sentiment analysis on text corpus
so it separates the takes into the desert in two phases the first phase it
tries to separate the text into subjective opinions which is fact sentences and when they
get the opinions the
seventeen people parts basically the positive or favorable sentiments and the negative and sentiment
next we want to
influence in blogosphere
let's look at some of the interesting applications of data mining influence in the blogosphere
there's a lot of word of mouth advertising in online media
specially blogosphere
people talk listen and the follow
in such a scenario influential bloggers
could act as market movers
they can also
help in suing
opinions about the government policies environment campaigns
and you can use these influential bloggers the knowledge bases for improving customer support and
as i mentioned earlier in blog mining they
good sources for market research
the force from these influential bloggers gordon
act as representative articles since there are so many sort of traffic coming from blocks
they can also help in advertising
we can identify the products which influential bloggers give positive feedback for and please add
of these products
there's a high chance that
years after reading the informative piece by influential bloggers click on these acts
the blog influences basically
you can two types one is an influential blog sites within the site network
which is done by some researchers and there is another type of influential documents which
is only on the community of blog so
you can
you can have a lot of fun you can have some influential blog sites but
not all the since not all the blog influential but then those non influential bloggers
thank you mister find some blogger which are influential
so you don't want to start
that's a very good question because
now they part of the talk will present a case study of how to determine
whether a blog influential are we have developed tomatoes and we have gone through the
best through it and did some experiments
and there are so many key findings
so as mentioned before there are some key differences between blocks friendship networks which
need some different treatment blocks while finding
influential bloggers as compared to finding influential nodes in friendship network
so only there some that the banking approaches which can be used to find influential
bloggers you do
there significant differences pointed out by these works
let's move
the trust issue
open standards and low barriers to publishing have created overwhelming amount of
an activist
so it's getting more difficult for readers to discern whom depressed in some cases
there's all this same to the world wide web case you find authoritative webpages
so blocked those people do
create as well as the content
it comprises the sanctity of the original content
so you don't have no actually which
blog also which blocks a crest
there exist some work for social friendship network domains but not many researchers have explored
the blocks area
so there a huge potential for precedent research in blocks
so go through some of the works which
existing in across four blocks
some people have transformed the problem of christian doctrine to the one in social and
social networks
the study of propagation of trust among different blog sites
the mine has undermined sentiment
from the window of words
based on the links so that when the words which are the surrounding buildings they
try to find the sentiments from those words and then they associate
like miss he did this for those
block states
so given this kind of network
existing work like out
propagate the trust between different modes of the blogs
but there are some concerns like
they need the block sites to be linked to get the trust propagation
which is again are
not many good in london because people generally don't link that well in blogs
and this is computed between blog sites based on how much one blog agrees or
disagrees with the
OK let's look at some of the works that are done in community extraction
not oxford doesn't have an explicit notion of
i mean it is
except the community blogs
like individual blogs you don't see a lot of interaction you just have one
are blogger who is posting blogs and you see a couple of readers who are
commenting and sometimes you don't even see that
so this is not a notion of communities there so in a community like that
so i'm with corporate research
copper technology of humans in munich
and part of the department of maybe thirty five people
working on and learning systems and related issues and i am heading a group of
approximately ten people
focusing on machine learning techniques and
trying to apply them problems in the company
so my talk today is about the usually processes
nonparametric bayesian modelling
and i encourage you to
ask questions
but always look reasons of everything a little bit
so the motivation is the infinite dimensional models have gained
a lot of attention invasion
machine learning recently
the most prominent ones costing processes and usually processes
and today
focuses on the usually processes just briefly want to mention casting processes and the advantages
that they offer great flexibility and in many applications allow for more truthful representation of
the problem
trying to sort of
so got processes are sort of simpler and maybe some of you
i have heard of them already in the middle of it
got process essentially defines prior
distribution over functions
and which means that the centre of the gaussian process
so back function from x to y is the input space output space you can
write it like this guy got it passes the mean function and you have some
covariance kernel function which specifies the gaussian process
and i was impressed is infinite dimensional generalizations of finite dimensional gaussian distribution
so we simply let the number of dimensions
you can think of course
typical problems we might have samples of the underlying true function
and we want to calculate posterior distribution over functions or made make predictions at a
new input
so if you have the exact
measurements of function you might consider this to be constant process smoothing in most applications
you have only
noisy measurements of the function
and then you have to deal with gaussian process regression
so this is all i want to say about casting processes
so today it's about the usually processes and a lot of ways is similar to
a lot of other ways have a different but this process defines the pile of
probability distributions over measures
and these are the things which are negative and after to integrate to one in
some sense
before we had a good simply forgot to process was the function now we have
a sample of a dirichlet process is is a distribution and the notation typically they
right speak g let and there are two things you want the base distribution g
not and the concentration parameter alpha not people
learn about all of this later on
in the same sense as in in
the process is infinite dimensional usually is a simple generalizations of the final usually distribution
to infinite dimension
and here is a typical example we might have samples of the underlying true distribution
and we want to calculate the posterior distribution are calculate the predictive distribution for sample
so so the big difference here is now we don't have sent the function but
we have samples of the distribution of the true underlying distributions
and again we can also consider the case that we don't obtained samples
from this distribution but something like noise from this distribution and this will be
the most important case
the most important application of the usually processes in terms of this seriously process mixture
so this is a very short introduction and we now we go into the details
of all of it
political so i would start with a brief introduction motivation modelling measure if how many
lectures in summer school have taken station view on things
so get everybody sort of warmed up
then i will talk about nineteen almost anything with usually prior to this the finite
dimensional case
and it's very important because it sets up the whole situation for the infinite case
so if you understand this
immediately then the usually process is quite simple
otherwise it seems always like all these definitions like chinese restaurant processes stick breaking processes
come out of nowhere what if you sort of see the finite dimensional case infinite
it was discovered is the direct application of one of the terms will be starting
so it's
fema as looking or well what can these abstract matrix terms be good for
i was incredible about
OK so an optimum branchings systems
a system of k
branching into an optimum system of k
edge disjoint branchings
each was specified groups
which is the cheapest or the most value for doesn't matter we're minimizing and maximizing
of course
so that's the optimum branching systems problem and i hope we will get to
seem to have the
matrix theory
and and any and you know the theorem that
every point in a polytope is a convex combination of the given finite set
in particular the set of extreme points are vertices of the polytope
the polytope can be defined as the bounded polyhedron that is bounded set described by
a set of linear inequalities
the basic theorem of linear programming is that the same thing as the convex combinations
of a finite set and finding that the current theorem says that factor
any points point is an active the a point is an b
it only it's common convex combination of the small number
these extreme points
and p
colin p
let's back
what to predicates that simply states that the variables
the inputs to and the statement is called a and b
and whenever it's true
there's an easy proof for certification that it's true right
many times today
people have said something is NP hard
and that
if necessary use of the term
tended to give and the bad name you know better at
but NP is a very very positive thing
very positive thing in particular
of course the predators colin colin b
if in a lot the negation is NP
now a theory is called a good characterisation
of that predicate
is about
that predicates
it says how
that predicate is in NP and co and p
and it's a practical conjecture
the predicate is in
and p intersect second peak
then there exists the palatine algorithm for deciding
this is this turned out to be true many many times
it it's an includes for recognizing primality
by this time you know
so quite some years ago now are not that many years ago by time frame
there were four
linear programming
almost almost every
almost every theorem that has a place to predicates in and the calling the
has in fact turned
a polytime algorithm
now we're going to be speaking today
the important example of that
namely a
submodular minimisation
we will show very easily
so we we have an oracle that and as the values at the best
any subset as
or after submodular
we'll see
the characterization
minimality of function
as an example of this
that will be
lp duality theorem
together with
and easy description
right hand side
and the dual LP
four years two
classically understanding linear programming only as an explicit list of inequalities and explicitly given
in combinatorial optimisation
if we treat
where this is an
exponentially large systems where
each one of each member
it is easy to recognise
each inequality is easy to recognise the standard two
so really here
if we had a better example would be
actually no peace with that that has
exponentially large collection here an exponential therefore an exponentially large
collection of
and all variables
but we have an easy description
that enables us with any one of these inequalities and to us
to see yes it is one of the describing the columns
and he had that situation
then the
the minimax theorem
applies to these that's potentially large a systems
give you
and p
colin np there
actually two types
the linear programming
it gives you choose
one linear programs
gives you
are linear programming system one inequality system actually gives you two
very disdain
np co NP there
let me see that i had written down here
one problem is
by an article in the system in any colonies
we're given an act
and we want to decide if an axe
satisfies all those inequalities
then p one and p co NP there is another to good characterization of when
a point x
it satisfies all those inequalities
well a are so our predicates
x satisfies all these call
well that's really colin p
because the it
predicate is not true
we can prove that it's not true
but just simply displaying one
of these
and in the
and it applies to
come to that
markets that
in this if we know something about the others if we know that you know
the organisms most is more likely to choose such functions over some other functions
we can as well just that in the PS potentials are correspondingly and then get
about that would be better because we would have signed always the functions that are
likely to be picked
and and get an decrease factor
but importantly
this way shorter
it should be picked before seeing the data again i this
in the union bound
that's all that does not depend on the data right up saying the problem
to deterministic wanted so we cannot
change the way because otherwise it would be too easy right we we would say
o we know that the function the younger is an aspect is this one after
seeing the data that's what it's all the weight on the function
and then we get rid of this quantity right he was one of one of
our key zero
and then we have the perfect have been found out of
but that's cheating right because we can't really change the weight
as we
once we have seen
OK but that's that's one possible way
these are
again we might
now another way
here's the divine
as we've seen before
what we have seen before
when the notions of small variance we can input about this use this district in
slightly different way
let's look at functions that actually makes similar predictions in class like this
g one to g capital and
there might be functions that actually
always treated the same way or
in a similar way
i mean if you look at the different classifiers using this one and this one
is likely the
maybe the you know them all is making the same predictions so they are thinking
on is the same mistake to some small difference
when comes we exploit this fact right
in particular
this was
i mean if we take such action that are
that's close enough then the probability that the different would be small
and we can do this
by refining the union bound
it means that you why
o how
when we look at
the deviation for a given function
we can introduce some other let's say
i have zero
and compare the deviation of this one with the addition of this one
and the difference between those guesses would actually be something that i read in this
like to use the vision that
it means i'm looking at the deviation not of
one function but of the difference between the function
this essentially means n minus zero
minus and plus he as p and
a way to combat the patient i apply this operator the different
mister even the functions here as senior
it means that
there there is as i said before is bounded by expectation
if they are similar the expectation of the difference will be small
so we get smarter
so if i applied this directly
i did that now
the deviation from my initial function
is the same as deviation for one expansion zero
that's where i get the normal
and of things
i have some about them but
this is the main major
and then
for this part here
because this part as friends which is bounded by i mean assuming that we have
was this
property here
six structure will give me something which is
where i live by the variance fixing
and i can apply i mean the slogan comes from the fact that you apply
this to all possible functions f in my class
assuming that all these functions are at distance as far from the
OK it's a bit confused here
OK maybe i should have
picture before
what i'm saying is that let's consider the following cases
we take the function of zero
we consider that our class
p five or g i mean
f and g
i think
it assumed that all of my class are a distance
at most alpha
these things being
measured as
the probability that at minus five
different from zero
this is the distance between the function
and we assume that
i mean this is some notion of distance between the function which depends on the
probability distribution of course but we assume that they have to all be closed with
a happen to all
similar error
which of the same
it up to smaller time and then the rest of the stuff here which actually
is relevant because uncorrelated with the previous time
to end up with this kind of structure here
and there are various ways of actually say computing this
the is at time zero
corresponding to matrix equation and then you can actually get the the
covariance it's
time offsets to spike
this exponential factor here
so basically certainly for
this is for the
is it the time invariant linear system we can actually get a solution for the
covariance function
from the line matrix
stochastic differential equations
clearly is a lot more theory here is that one can do we simply use
the spectral techniques which we use the univariate case well and the small stuff in
in gardner's book for example
on that
one thing we actually saw when we look to the samples from the
for most process also dam stochastic
so a simple harmonic oscillator is that we actually saw
very different smoothness properties of that first order and second order st
and where this is coming from is basically that
stochastic differential equations of order p p minus one times mean square differentiable
the processes correspond to that have this different abilities so
if p is one we get a zero difference because we can to continuity from
the diffusion process but not differentiability and this p two we get one
you get one times differentiability
and in easy intuitive way to think about this is to say that
because the process gets rougher the more times against differentiated basically the roughest thing here
x if p is of order
white noise which is non differentiable so basically as we look these things up as
we integrated areas
three times we'll see the LC differentiability appear so
we can sort of intuitive at understand the the mean square differentiability of the resulting
process through this kind of argument
OK this is
this is an interesting point and i guess it's quite related to things that we
want my i want to talk about today because
it's question about how we actually do discretisation
of continuous time
i guess in markov process
so we have a
in order p stochastic differential equation
the question is really how rule that relate will if we discretize that some some
time interval say some great
is it the case that the
process will have the same markov properties of the underlying process and the answers you
need to be careful
OK so let's define
certainly for discrete time we can define all my process so not only the is
a i'm sorry so we have this is usually the
this linear terms we had before
autoregressive terms and here rather than just having be zero just driving it with noisy
at the current time
driving the lagged history of of these noises
this is on the process because can also of the continuous time analogues of this
it turns out that kept the power spectrum now has is rational for
i mean it in fact get the order of
two here to be less than european all of this to be well defined
the the key
he theorem here
is that if we take a continuous time
stationary testing process
and let x hp discretisation of that process is
x is an on process has this kind of power spectral density xh will be
a discrete time process however
if x is an a are process and so in other words the stochastic differential
equations of order p of the kind be talking about then actually when we discretize
it's is not necessarily and they are process actually turned out to be an arm
process so
on is to be a little bit careful about the
going from
a continuous time discrete time because of this
OK i also want to say something about inference
of course one thing that we
so want to do more than guessing processes we want to have some we've got
the underlying
stochastic differential equations giving rise to guassian process prior over functions we have some observations
of that
the process of various times meanwhile want do inference about predicting the values at other
if we doing something like an all-star process than fact
we already have this markov property
which means that
we only need to condition is essentially for making a prediction at some time t
star then we've got a whole bunch of observations of various times we actually need
only worry about those observations in the part immediate past immediate future that of all
that time t star because of the markov property everything else is is independent it
is conditionally independent of the rest of the variables given the past and future
there's a slight caveat here OK which is that if we if we have pure
observations of the process this is true
but if we have observations
which are corrupted by noise than in fact then this markov property breaks and we
actually need to get process prediction we need to actually make use all the observations
at various times
so basically
this stuff how to do this prediction is just an example of guassian process prediction
so we are interested in this conditional distribution of x fifty star given these these
under the casting process we know it's going to be
it's going to be against prediction was mean and some
and the usual casting process prediction equations apply the kind of slightly simplified because in
fact you need to worry about these two observations as in the past and the
future so we can just define this
two by two covariance matrix
well for example case to p is
kft start to be so this is just
TP TP and so on
just do this very simple matrix inversion to get these predictions such
at least under the if we can really exploit markov nature
of the ocean and that process for example
to make these
to make predictions are very compact way
OK so lose
i talked about the stochastic differential equation view
i've talked about how to work and covariance functions of these processes and try to
understand the covariance functions
we also want to talk a bit about fokker planck equations
so basically one thing we could be interested in saying OK i'm at value x
zero time zero
what i want to do
is to understand how much that evolution and where i'm going to be a set
it is denoted by the start
and i show you
it's very simple
that it is the best possible
portfolio of vector
the constantly rebalanced portfolio what you can achieve
for the portfolio
that or you can have the the
the best possible asymptotic average growth rate
it doesn't automatically is the following as you
that you
work can we need these be star
defined in the previous page
and s is the amount of money at the end of the day and very
you use another portfolio
they comp
the amount of
money you can't if you convert the average growth rate asymptotic
for an arbitrary portfolio vector b
and the log optimal portfolio that
this statement is that the
the asymptotic average growth rate of an arbitrary for an arbitrary portfolio vector b
cannot be larger
then the average growth rate of four
of the log optimal portfolio
you can calculate the
the simple
the best possible as input because of the average growth rate for the balanced portfolio
and i i d
market cross
and the proof is x three with people
here the average growth rate
at time and
it is the average of flowing
and make the break that the
at the
and and doctor throughout the
expectation of the log reader
because of
identically distributed function
the average of the red
are identical
the blue line is an average of independent zero mean random variable
the blue line
goes to zero
almost surely
but the asymptotics of the average growth rate is equal to the expected log return
for a fixed portfolio vector b
you do the same
before the start
the blue average got there almost surely
and you
i have to to call her
i didn't because i read the terms because of the definition of the the star
these acts locally are
is larger than the above below before or any other
a portfolio vector b
and it did the
it's a random variable x of ideas
it has the distribution and big but it's
this is model of park in gambling the theory of gambling horse racing information theory
and here is the list of of
it all started to look at the problem
if you
it turns out
mathematical finance but then you don't find any being on log optimal portfolio
the only exception is the
chapter fifteen in the leuenberger book
otherwise you cannot learn on
log optimum portfolio all the standard
mathematical finance those book which is the local people money is not one act that
you were recognised because mathematical department sort of portsmouth
i don't know
i am fighting but the
two to be and that the that was recognised by the
it it it's a long war
but i don't
while i think that
it's it's a long story maybe maybe during the barbecue we can talk about
let's look at some
very surprising good example
the example all of
so as the
the first as
the rate
he has value
two or one half
which means that if if you invest one dollar either you double
or half your money
this would be the first component the second component will be the guests
guess either one or remain got
if you look at this example all
that just remembering this additional instances and throwing it into my big picture doing the
same thing for the possible
keep on doing this
until all the observations are correctly classified
so at the moment all i've done is i've shown you this algorithm
actually shown you get that it will converge is made for all that we know
i could run this out of might never terminate
first look at with what they have done before we prove that will terminate
so nothing happens if we just classify things correctly i might as well not have
added that observation
if we
get things wrong then we update by why i time
now the vector of exciting one
so basically positively reinforcing all the observations of getting wrongly
the other thing is the weight vector will be linear combination
of observation
the other thing is that the inner product between the weight x
can be written
as a linear combination of inner products between
extra index
was constantly
now this looks like the most idiotic thing you could potentially right
here what perfectly good vector in rn
and now here
and summing over all the areas that i made
all the inner products there
looks like and making a lot more
now if i had just a simple linear function
you're absolutely right this will be the most important thing you could do
once we actually go to infinite dimensional spaces where i can not explicitly right out
but just implicit in some hilbert space this will be the way
how to go further
so this is just a little bit of a hit
let's have a look at the theoretical analysis
but the first useful properties that even while i'm just running the south we already
sorry making predictions might not be terribly good but
i can are used them
the second thing is
i can prove that if
the problem is nicely separable
so in other words if there exist some row in the weight vector w with
unit length
and some threshold be star
such that
this quantity here is always critical than rho
so in other words if i can separate the problem well
then i can learn it
in no more than
b star squared plus one
our squared plus one or overall quest
i need to explain what those very qualities our
the maximal length of my observations
this is the weight of the margin
this has to do with the constant offset
and this is essentially the radius of the
this means
if the problem is very well separated in other words if this row is very
then it only very few steps
in other words if the problem is easier can learn it correctly
on the other hand if there are three large
it means the problem is really
hard to separate i will need many steps
the really causing is
this found
does not in any place
involved dimensionality of the data right
it's completely dimensionality independent all updates are dimensionality in the
and this is what we're going to use light and we go to the kernel
let's see how we can improve
so the first thing we do is we just found
the increase of the alignment between my current solution WIP i
and the optimal
a large margin separator this time beast
well how can i do this well
i know that wj plus one bj plus one
in approach with the star and the star
four mistakes
it's just
well the original terms
plus y times
x i and y
but this time the stock
that's just my original in the product
by the way that should be an i j
and here
i've got an inner product between the traffic sign one w star in peacetime
however i know that this quantity here by assumption has to be larger than rhode
so therefore
i know
but this quantity increased by at least wrote
after one update
so therefore i know
that inappropriate WMP
w star movie the star
it is at least j time
the alignment increases linearly with the number of errors that i'm going to make
the next thing is
of course i can apply which is why
so close parts means i can be found in prob
between w
w star movie the star
or of the of the children
OK so when shear
q a
and having a and i could move from here to here
i changed this position now which
does not need to read the name in the
it doesn't have an input so here you have the current state of the automaton
here you have to
since the two sons the chairman of the current state and here it means that
the automaton
is going to
generate competency QA
and then for example q a that's impossible things you can do
but you can also do QA
the station
i mean there are many possibilities but it may also use
still be based on this
originally but i guess that in the next step for example
the left something to be the right some be labeled by a
so if i managed to make the computational time basically what they have locally
is a transition state q
here once it q prime ICQ second here with be
to justify this transition it was because from my reading b i could have
in the original automaton
last year i added information about which label it can be a and b here
by building such a thing
the white i in which is accepting come in if i manage to build searcher
was have the
regarding the columns and the color
as in the original automaton
i managed to do this it's quite easy and of this
input free automata to build a good run
except in one of the
original automaton for some input
i mean she
is around the origin of the automaton and some model
and we have to get that
we have to guess possible label
so now that you have about
the we can have an intuition of this as just show you one example of
now what i can do is to show you
the game that we derive from these automata
which is input free
it less cooperative
so i mean put my USB stick and now
six along the way
so we have this understanding of this input free automata that in order
to find such good
around this input for how to solve it
translating the problem
in two main problem will be the following
it will be simply here
here's so maybe assure you first the definition so the game i derived from new
so which is basically transitions
of this kind
so from here
from this date it generate this state and this state
so what we do is that the position of the the b
just of the input tree automata which means one state remember the states
these kind
that player
zero chooses metric such positions
players player zero he took up he chooses the move which will lead him to
another position which is this track particular transition
of the input from
so here is the game
we start with this position
also started to be with this
ocean player zero has to choose a possible transition in the input
that so there may be things that are that are missing but i mean input
field much
and when he has written this can give the two
play one
who has to choose in this
particular transition and by
players zero
the following content is provided under a Creative Commons license your support will help MIT
OpenCourseWare continue to offer high-quality educational resources for free
to make a donation or to view additional materials from hundreds of MIT courses
visit MIT OpenCourseWare at ocw . MIT . EDU
you announcements at the beginning today this is for those of you who are new
to the class welcome
a couple of administrative things when you join 309 1 regardless of what registration took
place outside please check in with my office I want you to check in with
either hillary lorry who will assign you to both to a lecture section as a
lecturer now was afraid 11 obvious also lecture when he was referred we're trying to
level the populations so that the balance the seating capacity and then also likewise with
the recitations representations run all day long tuesdays and thursdays earliest 1 is denying the
latest 1 of 4 and again we're trying to balance the
occupancy there so that we have
good access to
recitation instructor so please don't go squatting we need to know
with the populations are on their offices just down the hall here
the union of the 2
to 1 the so there's the that light out but maybe by the end of
the semester miracle occurs so what you look over here so there's the coordinates in
2 0 1 and talk to lorry or to
Hillary but they'll be a test on tuesday based on homework 1 10 minutes at
the beginning of the recitation you are allowed to use on the test the official
version of the periodic table of the elements which was you should have 1 now
there is a ship in the cayman way through the of you didn't get a
periodic table swing by the Office just down the hall from this lecture theater and
you bring periodic table and the table of constance a calculator and something to write
for I to show up sit down 1st question as it does anybody have a
pen or we may not have that many parents so those for items you do
not use a cheat on the weekly tests for the monthly tests not for the
week and I that's all my recitation instructors to
state office hours a nite too will have office hours
if you want to come and see me
Monday 332 30 just down the hall come and see me if you can't come
by that our you can send me e-mail and I'll be happy to meet with
you and I most mean that I get to meet a lot of people through
the course of teaching and recognize a lot of
cancer remember everybody's name but I will recognize you and the same thing with the
office hours for the TAC office hours are at time when they will be seated
waiting for visitors that means they will not look at their e-mail they will not
take telephone calls they were they'll be sitting there waiting for visitors if you cannot
make the office hours again contact recitation structure make other arrangements
no I don't hear the question is is there a limit to the kind a
calculator I don't even bring mainframe and on truck I don't care
doesn't matter you you
the calculator and you know I'm I'm holding on your honor and I'm assuming you
haven't loaded the Encyclopedia Britannica into the memory it's a calculator to aid in computational
efforts and wealth to have to tell you about the readings the readings allow the
readings here's the homework this is what it's based upon and we were neutrinos knows
when you go to outside of the class get a copy this by some people
ask me if you've bought the earlier version of the text you can find their
translations of the earlier
version of the text on these questions numbers and if you go to the website
and you look down here faltered old to go to falter motu and those homework
listed bilingually last year a list of them in the review of the many people
that have the 1st
edition of the text so that if you if you have the 1st edition of
the text go to falter motu and show you the the earlier translations of in
preparation for lectures I urge you to do some reading and so up here you
look at Lecture Topics as the 2nd buttoned-down and you get to a page looks
like this and so for today for example it says classification schemes mandalay of atomic
structure reading chapter 1 chapter 2 Appendix A. cover everything in the region and high
school anymore
you regional here come electronic at some high points things that I find particularly interesting
but it's not sort of what he said we're going to read this but then
he didn't talk about it in class when I get
now when you start looking for our next week you're going to see and references
to chapter which is in the cortex and you also see this ln ln ln
archives what these are archive lecture notes that were written by my predecessor professor with
and if you go to the park and go back here and you click on
archive notes and so forth buttoned-down that'll take into something that looks like this and
if you look at archive notes number 1 and this is what you'll see so
in some instances these notes are superior to the text there's a reason for 309
1 has a syllabus that is unlike
general chemistry taught anywhere else on the planet that's why you pay so much money
economy here campaign where you come here to take something that you can get just
anywhere that that's the good news the bad news is there isn't attacks that fits
and minus one is greater than zero
is heat flow in this way
so these are just
pictures that we saw last time
and then we had some statements
of the second law of thermodynamics that i will rewrite up here but
there are for example clowes gave us the statement that it's impossible for system to
operate in the cycle
that takes heat from a cold reservoir transfers it hot reservoir that's act like a
refrigerator without in some way
at the same time converting some work into he work as the common to make
that happen
we had a similar
calvin about the heat engine that required that some he gets dumped into a cold
reservoir in the process of converting the heat from the hot reservoir into work
now what i want do
is put up a specific example
of the cycle
can be undertaken
inside here in an engine
and we can just calculate from we've already seen for dynamics what happens to the
thermodynamic parameters
and and c the results in terms of the parameters including entropy so let's try
the engine
i'm going to illustrate his color carlo engine
and the cycle is going to
it's called cato cycle
and it works the following way
we're going to do
pressure volume work
so this is something that
by now you're pretty familiar with
so we're going to start one
o to two and this is going to be in
temperature t one
and all the paths you're going to be reversible
so that's the first step
we're going to have an about
extensive studies of isothermal expansion
here comes an eighty batic
o point three
so this point the temperature will change
and we're going to have
another isothermal step of compression
to some point four
so this is an isothermal
at some
different temperature t two
the core temperature because this was an expansion we know needed but about expansion the
system can call
and now we're going to have another
idiomatic step
and a diabetic compression
that's it that's going to take it back to our starting point so that are
of course there are lots of ways we could execute the cycle
but this is a simple one in your steps or all
familiar with this point
this is the
and this is the cycle that undertaker so let's just look step-by-step but what happens
going from one to two
it's isothermal expansion at t one
delta u
is q one we'll call it
plus w one
for the first step
going from
two to three
that's an idea about
so q
is equal to zero in that step
delta u
is equal to
what called w one prime so use w one and w one prime to describe
the work
involved the work
during the expansion steps
step three to four
isothermal compression
delta u is
going to be q two
plus w two
and finally we're going to go
back to one close the cycle with another idea that except
two is zero
delta u
is w two
the total amount of the work
that we can get out is just given by the area inside this curve
well call capital w
it's just
minus the sum of all these things because of course these are just defined as
the work done by the environment to the system
so it's minus
w one one w one prime plus w two w two prime
the heat input
it's just q one
well defined that
capital q
and i just want to write those because what i really want to get at
is what the efficiency of the whole thing
and in practical terms we can define efficiency is the ratio of the heat in
to work out we would like that to be as high as possible
so it just
capital w over
capital q
which is to say it's
into this
feature space of the polynomial kernel of degree up to two
and we find that the data sets have the same meaning that feature space
any any guesses
what does that mean
so it means that the datasets
not only have the same empirical means
but also they have the same empirical moments of all two
because empirical moments just functions of these
the features of all to
so that means uh
more generally if we
is a polynomial kernel of degree d e
end map to datasets into this high dimensional feature space
we find that the two data sets have the same means so this is same
first moment in the feature space
it means that in the input space
they have the first that all the first moments after already coincide
so just looking at the mean in feature space
that means a lot more in the input space depending on what kind of kernel which is
and then it turns out that if the kernel is strictly positive definite
remember positive definiteness
and are just write down briefly again
always could see definition again
so positive definite this meant that
for all
one throw and
the real numbers ant
four x one
x in
the in all the main
this inequality is true end
strict positive definiteness
just meant that
if the pairs
if the points are pairwise distinct
and then equality is only true
if the
all these or zero
so that means strict
positive definite means
four i j
with iron
not in
we have x i not equal exchange
and then
that this spector is identically zero all entries are zero
okay so
it's a slightly stricter conditions
and so it turns out if the kernel is strictly positive definite
that means only coincide or they coincide if and only if
the two datasets identical point by point
so that's kind of surprising so it means
so we take the datasets we map into the feature space and then we compute
the means in this feature space we throw away all the rest we don't
uh store any of these individual things we just store the mean
but nevertheless the mean remembers all the points that me the mean characterizes the whole dataset
so why is that the case so these sentences so easy to prove
we can briefly go through the process
and then we prove something slightly more general
which goes as follows
so suppose we have these two datasets x and why
we assume the kernel is strictly positive definite
we assume that
for all i and j
uh all these points x i in this expansion are pairwise disjoint
and likewise in the second expansion
all the way i is why i wages are pairwise disjoint so that's
well that's a reasonable assumption if they were not we would just
rewrite this expansion by adjusting these coefficients
so we have to general kernel expansions
and then the claim is
four some
the set of coefficients
so if for these coefficients from nonzero coefficients
we have this kind of equality of course we should also assume non-zero otherwise
it doesn't make sense so we only take sensible expansions with
we have which have unique points and we'd have answer expansions otherwise we just throw
out the ones that had a zero
so if we have such inequality we make we can write the same data in
the reproducing kernel hilbert space in two ways
and then these two sets have to be identical
actually one can also prove that the coefficients that have to be identical but we only worry about sets
so in all cases
because only advise one over and all the bitter taste of one over and
and that's the only case that we want and we would just want to say
if the means are the same in the two sets of the same
and we put this slightly more general thing
and don't this photos
so let's assume without loss of generality
there's one point so is by contradiction so we want to show the two sets of the same
went approved by contradiction we assume
they not the same in if two sets are not the same it means there's
one of the two sets contains one element which is not only on the one
at least
so we assume without loss of generality this element is the one that we call x one
and we assume x one is not in said why
so the first thing we're gonna do is we will subtract
the expansion over the why expansion
thing that we had before so we just
move this to the other side
in addition so then we get a lot some
being a zero
and again we make it a sum over pairwise distinct points so if maybe some
of the points in the set x might be identical points and this is why
if that's the case we just always combine them into one and get an updated coefficient
so the coefficient could now be different
this coefficient in particular could be zero
so we remember that the coefficients we had before
other than when nonzero
we bring this to the other side and make it again some more unique expansion kernels
then some other confusion might become zero
however we know at least one other confusions will not become zero
because we have assumed that the point x one doesn't appear in the city why
so the first coefficient will not become zero
so here this is our expansion that we get
and what we know is that if we
all the things such that the first z here is equal to the next one
x one is not understand why
then we also know that the first coefficient is equal to a from one
which by assumption is nonzero
and all the other ones that are real numbers
so we have this expansion which is zero and we know that one of the coefficients is not zero
next we will take the
dot product in the reproducing kernel hilbert space
of this thing with itself
that gives us this equation here
so what have we used here we have used the fact that
the kernel is reproducing
if we take the product between
this kernel end
the same kernel again
course now in the second
well do it in this column in this column gives us this kernel here
mainly two reasons one is it's very useful for modeling because as we already saw
in some examples yesterday many types of nonlinear convex constraints that you find in
applications can be written in this linear form if you use the correct cone K
and in practice it turns out that a very small number of types of convex
cones is sufficient to represent most convex constraints that you find in practice and we'll see
a list in a in a minute so and that's very useful for modeling
tools and modeling software because you can develop tools that can take an co
general convex optimization problem written in a natr natural language and then translate it in this
standard form with only a few types of convex cones and then if you have
a solver that efficiently solves these convec problems for a small set of
possible convex cones you actually have a very general optimization system so that's one the second
motivation for using this linear format is that it precisely looks like
a linear programming problem so it's a very convenient format if you want
to extend interior point methods or other algorithms from linear programming to convex nonlinear optimization
because it's almost exactly like an LP and so we'll see it's also easy to extend
methods from linear programming to conic optimization so we look at some let's first
look at some of these basic cones that are useful and in practice first one are cones
defined by norms so for example if you take the Euclidean norm and you look
at all the vectors X Y in R M where Y is a scalar
X is a vector in R M that satisfy this inequality norm of X stays in Y
then for a Euclidean norm it looks like this I mean it's called the second-order cone
or sometimes the ice-cream cone so if you Y is on the vertical axis so if
you choose an specific Y and take the intersection of this cone with a horizontal
plane then that's a disc with radius Y right and then if you increase Y you
get this second order cone but you could take any cone here also the
infinity norm cone or a one norm cone and you always get an a cone if defined like this
so we s later we'll use this notation for a second order cone in dimension
M with Q for quadratic so this will be the second order cone in R three so
if you want to you use this so let's look at the second order
cone program that we discussed yesterday so have a linear objective and then constraints like
this with the norm of some linear function and a linear function on the right-hand side
so this explains why we call this a second-order cone program so you can interpret
each of these inequalities as a linear inequality with respect to the second order cone
for example if you only had one inequality like this then if you want
to put it in this form A X less than or equal to B and K is the
second-order cone then you would use this matrix A so you take this vector inside
the norm here you append this scalar to it as a last component and then you interpret
this inequality as saying that that vector is in the second order cone
so if you write it as A X less than or equal to B then you means that
you use this matrix A this vector B and then the cone as a second-order
cone if you have multiple constraints like this then you can just define K as the product direct
product of these second-order cones and stack all the data matrices in one matrix A
and one vector B and so that's why we call this a second order cone program you
can interpret as nonlinear scalar inequalities as vector linear vector inequalities respect to an nonpolyhedral
cone the second important example is the semi-definite cone and because in this lecture
we'll always use a vector notation for the inequalities and for the variables we'll need some
notation to convert matrices to vectors and vise versa so if Y is a symmetric
matrix then I'll use this notation vec of U for the matrix stored as a vector
and how you do that precisely doesn't matter too much here we use the
under we store the lower triangular part of the matrix Y in packed storage as a vector and all
the weightings with square root two are needed or they're not necessarily needed but
if you add if you weight the of diagonal or of diagonal elements by square root two
then you have a nice property that inner product of these vectorized vectors
of two matrices stored in this packed vector format gives you the same result as
the standard trace inner product between the original symmetric matrices so that's the product
we use inner product we use for symmetric matrices the trace of the
product if you use these introduce these square root two then the standard inner product
is the same as just euclidean inner product between these two vectors
and otherwise the inner products would be different and that makes things more complicated but
basically it's the matrix Y stored in packed storage in such a way that the
inner products are preserved and the inverseof this operation I'll denote
by mat of U so if U is a vector then this operation
unpacks the vector and makes it into a matrix so that's just notation so now I can introduce
s semi-definite cone so the semi-definite cone with this notation will be of order P will
be the cone of semi-definite matrices of that order but in that packed storage for example
this would be semi-definite cone in R three so the two-dimensional matrices of symmetric
positive semi-definite matrices I stored M S vectors of length three that represent the entries in a
positive semidefinite matrix of orders two an then this cone is a cone of vectors
that represent positive semi-definite matrices right with the weighting again to make sure that the inner products
of matrices these matrices are the same as in their products of the vector
so this would be the semi-definite cone in R th three so you see it's
a nonpolyhedral cone and so this is X Y and Z so with this
notation I can use the semi-definite program that I introduced yesterday and write it in the standard
same conic inequality form so you have a linear matrix inequality like this with B
funny way social circle
so that sounds good we also know how to compute powers of things relatively quickly
if you remember how
i need to define for this notion was power notion to make sense i should
say what eight to zero means
and so i need some kind of identity
matrix and for the first year the identity matrix is this one
right zeros along the diagonal
and is everywhere else
OK that's sort of just to match
this definition DHA zero should be zeros on diagonal infinity everywhere else you can check
this is actually named entity if you multiply it with this funny multiplication against any
the matrix you get the matrix back nothing changes this really is valid identity matrix
i should mention that for ATV and to make sense
you really need that your product operation is
so so should be the and circles make sense
because circle multiplication
is associated with
and you can check that not hard because the administration associative addition is associative and
all sorts of good stuff
and you have some kind of distributivity property
and world wide and this is in turn because the real numbers with an get
the right
order here
with me and as your addition operation and pluses here
multiplication operation is
a closed semirings
hello everyone i know
powers make sense this is a good rule if you have a closed semiring then
matrix products on that semiring will give you an associative operator in that
could you can take products
that's just something some formalism
so now
we have some intuition question what's the right algorithm
there are many possible answers
some of which are right on which
are not
so we have this connection to matrix products and we have a connection to
major powers
we algorithms for both
the question is what should we do
so all we need to do now compute a to the past twenty power and
minus one
and minus one is one we get shorter spans assuming we have no negative weight
in fact we can compute larger power than n minus one
once again
beyond and minus one multiplying by a doesn't change in any more
how should we do it
giving any slices of the stupid answer
you could say well i take a and multiply by a and i multiply by
a and multiply by an normal boring matrix multiplication
so i do
like and minus two
the standard matrix multiplies
so standard multiply costs like and q
and during like and the
so this gives me and to the four thousand feet all shortest path weights and
the before
and no improvement
so how can i do that
right natural thing to try
which sadly does not work is to use some cubic matrix multiply
we will also sense get there in the moment with somewhat simpler problem but it's
actually not known how to compute shortest paths using fast matrix multiplication what stresses
good suggestion term
you have to think about why it doesn't work i tell you but it's not
obvious perfectly reasonable
suggestion in this context doesn't quite work we will will come up in a few
the problem is strassen requires in addition subtraction
and here in addition is medium
and there's no inverse to me
when she take the arguments you can't undo women
so there is no notion of subtraction so we
from the quadratic forms and functions OK and your name is higher ok so I
couldn't tell that you what it looked for a moment going well that's a lot
of numbers is that we were doing
OK so this is how I got to be professor OK so high chance that
you're wrong OK means that a lot of numbers terms that these are all the
right numbers because I want to tell you this 1 2 and 14 are like
one-line proof of this is the the just little things that I wanted you to
OK so it turns out the actual homework is really 370 17 so that these
should be these combined should take 6 men the others combine them 106 6 hours
12 hours
lose track after a while so I guess the point yet OK so what does
this mean so let this and many of you downloaded the
lecture notes last night
I menu downloaded the lecture note on Newton's method less units when this morning or
OK so question 70 in the new notes Newton's method says prove Proposition 2 .
1 and the notes and if you look at propositions if you were to look
at Proposition 2 . 1
depending upon when you downloaded the of the notes
82 has
says prove the following 2 things are equivalent or prove the following 3 things are
equivalent OK
because I took out the 3rd thing even though it's true
I thought you don't really need to prove OK so that that's what this means
that you should prove that 1 and 2 are equivalent and if you have 3
in your notes you don't have to you don't have to mess with
all right
and so on and ask you to the 2 of you come right in front
of me and said over there
alright so I won't talk about Newton's method and let me just ask
anybody who has use Newton's method OK how would you use Newton's method
the work of the application of the entire classification really means that following OK and
you had your hand if you look at
the units of the network around actually evidence
OK who came up with this and actually I don't even know that I have
added that cannot one-dimensional problems and I think it was
a mathematician and Raphson right around the time of the new new extended to multi
dimensional problem but we're going to look at it actually in the context of optimisation
OK so
Newton's method is
I just give you have to give you a history because
I started teaching this course for the 1st time in 1985
and no 1986
and Newton's method has changed
oddly enough since 1986 so it's been 18 years and Newton's method instead of being
actually sort of a method of last resort
because you have to solve
quote large unquote systems of equations 500 by 500 systems of equations now is a
method of primary resort because all you have to do is solved large systems of
equations like
50 thousand by 50 thousand right so the computational power has changed the role that
Newton's method plays in optimisation
OK so that's 1 thing and the other is
interior point methods which we will learn about in-depth after the midterm
OK rely on Newton's method interior point methods now are the dominant
conceptual lands
In convex optimization and so Newton's method is really important because Newton's method is what
drives your point OK so what is Newton's method so if I have an unconstrained
problem minimize F of X subject exiting some open set which let's just take that
has to be
right now
I can really think of f of x at a given point X bar
so I have a given
my current period of my algorithms X bar and I'm going to build a Taylor
they would continue to go
they wouldn't have anything to do
pull on them anymore
let's look at it
an object that we're going to rotate
i have a glass two
i want to rotate and in the last two
i have
a model
glass very small
i you the class two
he was marble
i'm going to rotate it in this direction
there were some angular velocity omega about an axis perpendicular to the black
so the
the marble here
as a velocity
like so at this moment in time
but it's a very small class two
and the model is very small
the glass
cannot push on the marble
nor can the glass
the more
now to model gets desperate because the model
a centripetal acceleration
in this direction
in order
to go around like this
but there's nothing to provide that centripetal acceleration
so to marble
is doing exactly the same that the planets will do
if you take the sun away
the marble continues to go
in the direction that it was going
so by the time
that the
to be here
marble is here
and by the time that the two tube here
marble is there
the marble finds its way
to the edge
and and that's of course
the basic idea
my grandmother had always
he was a great lady he had such a fantastic ideas i remember
when she
made lattice
we have no good way of drying the letters
and i would take the lead
like this
paper towels
she had the method of overall
she took a color
and of course first of all
we would watch the letters
that goes without saying
i would wash it once
my grandmother would wash it three times but that's what you have grandmothers for
now comes the
let's we've also very fond of spinach
at some spinach
we would wash
o to spinach
then she would take something to cover it up
maybe some surrender something else
well over it
rubber band
to hold it
and now what is going to do which is going to swing around and now
the water is like these
one of the work its way to the edge
but there holds
so what i will come out
isn't it clever
OK of if your demonstration
you may get
so what are linear connection nodes but i want to show you the basic idea
behind it is very interesting
she would go out to do this outside by the way
but i have no choice of with here
every go
this is the way
i lost my magnetic
strawberry that's the detailed process so
you end up with
you end up with drive
and clean
a nice
let us
this is a to one at work
and this is clearly an early version
the centrifuge
my grandmother's methods very tragically
has been replaced lately
we something that you can buy
crate and barrel
we have it here
it is very boring
it's very decadent
with saladin here
all you do
she rotate
it drives a centrifuge this this is actually a high-tech version
of the much more
sophisticated invention of my grandmother
and is nowhere nearly as exciting
the days
of romance i really over
that's the way it goes
i'm not going to make
a connection
between rotation on the one hand
and centripetal
x a celebration
on the other
i'm going to make
the connection between the centripetal acceleration
receive gravity
and pattern
will be
we really
find these
i mean you
so here
i know
these all these
this is a much
they are
these are
because this
i i
and we show
they are
and you your model
all right
the model
once you see that
you can say
this is a class one or class
i give you an example
so that's what classification or association based contrast patterns
the one that i talked about tom tom mitchell's work when he was at stanford
you know very senior process can and he actually worked on
so for example his interest is that
you know you look at functional MRI
i'm you collect this stuff and can you recognised by the activation of the brain
what the individual is thinking so so he had a very nice experiment to show
so what they have done is to collect the data so the short two kinds
of things one is
building instruments like hammers screwdrivers
you know
all of these instruments and the other one is just vegetables like you know
i don't know spinach
commandos and things like that
so why should this patient and look at the brain activation in what part of
your brain
is actually
consuming oxygen base
so so they do the MRI images and they do the segmentation collected stopped
and and what they found is that the next time they can tell what this
user so then then you present the MRI signal
your classifier or machine programming
and he tells you are dispersed just saw
and the building
equipment or actually seen vegetable
so so they can actually now tell
people what they were doing
so in fact now we're going to the extent that you know if somebody
you know
happened and any kind of common situation
basically they can't communicate they can't move in your body
the question is how do we know
but there
brain or not is the big question because they can still see some activity in
the brain but is it cognitive activity and now there would act stretched to do
that so what they're doing is that
so they make one exception to this individual
if the person is still conscious
hopefully there
the hearing is still working with the assumption
so so what they
how this person is that you know how good this patient and television
if you are
you know able to think
when i tell you
i know
ask your questions
because the person cannot communicate
i just think that you're playing tennis
that's what you do
when i asked
if you want to say yes to my question
you you think you're playing tennis
if you want to say no
sing a song
and as a result what happens in your brain the two parts of the different
parts of the brain gets activated
so now they're asking these questions to these these individuals
and they could see the brain activation you know they can say and as a
result you can decide whether the person is active
this kind of very scary but so expensive
you know if somebody
had a bad accident and you know properly
paralysed incontinent speak
then you wanted to know where to turn off the machine
or to keep the lights
lots of press socialized issues
are coming to this place but this is kind of work he is is doing
now so
so his earlier work is on version spaces so basically what you're given you given
positive instances negative instances
and you want to find
decision surfaces are binary logical statement that tells you
if this is true
then it is the class
if it is
full sixty miles that's what you want
so he came up these notions of version spaces this tells you
a kind of disjunction of conjunctions statements
that counts you
what the places
and the d minus is similarly
the disjunction of conjunctions all
so typically what it means is that you have a positive instance
you make more generalizations OK so for example it's a if this is red
or in another you find are also green is also
the players or green and you believe that you know more generalizations
but then you say
if something else is negative instance comes
then you do in conjunction so that means disjunctions to grow by generalisation by giving
union operator
and conjunction
or you know whenever a negative is is the negative one so when these two
surfaces meet that means you have perfect learning
that means you have a complete knowledge of model
but of course you generally don't have complete knowledge so you give two surfaces basically
so this is this is how it's done
but unfortunately there are not very useful for machine learning in the sense that
you know we don't have perfect knowledge
you need some being the probability to
an interesting is that once you put probability into this model
then they become basically contrast patterns
so how we can measure contrast patterns is that
i think in nineteen nine
the band on
they came up with this model called search
testing for
understandable consistent contrasts the call
to call
so basically what they've done is you take a part in x some you know
i think that there are
there are that are not important at all
they have such
and it's not important
all of the articles from the articles is not important because russians my
native language information in this article
i don't have any sense
again against them out very is
OK so we have all these problems in the world how we are going to
solve them in OWL
i search engine
and there are two main approaches
and you can see this approach in all colours are and open source search engine
and basically
it depends on how lazy argued during development
the first approach
this stuff
do everything during index
and much as possible
so people stopped
we use them all
norfolk from your point of view steaming
steamer and expand or do something is all operations
this is one
another approach you can do all this stuff during search
so you can
i don't do any more followed during induction
and port all words is
and to ensure that you can try to much more
and what this approach
the cleanest of positive and negative
o point attributes and characteristics
therefore i one hundred percent sure
that right solution somewhere in the middle
you need to think what will be slowed during charge and you should do it
in advance and what it can do better in advance
and what you can do but there is actually based on this do this
what what what they're going during indexing but i'm going down
and now we have
the result of
minimisation of all structural features of documents
to be or not to be
now by our
sophisticated algorithms river
not lazy
and we decided to implement every now everything that was on previous slide except stop
removing because otherwise it will be simple and to slide here
so you have to
and the attribute the this it was capitalised
it was stopped or you have this flag that stop word position one from body
and from the same document one
then the that it was uppercased against of words
and then we didn't
excuse me for this phrase but it is four bays so only one well known
abbreviation but but actually it's funny because i really
had this
case in real life when people remove all the
and for medical collection from any collection of medical documents they were
really surprised that they removed a lot of relevant documents
i have
this example of
abbreviation expansion
i have this abbreviation for forms
i don't know what i can be computed as the law if you're doing operations
it's still stop because they use the same flag as for the role
forty additional flags this aberration this thing position because we know that it's in the
same position in the document
from the same document and the concession for all other work
if you think that you know where to features
you should extract extracting put them
there is one
pretty popular
very common but popular because of who they are engine
and and what they're doing the also extracting
the result of all syntactic
parts of all sentences into these attributes and the index of this
for example is not
a little bit of delay here because
some reason the packaging coming out there so
my computer switched off so i'm going to play
i so discovery program it's it's due to come at the beginning of next year
and it's discovery program called the a bit of political we connections and so basically
what they do is they basically come up with like the hypothesis all three questions
that the kind one asking episode and i want to go although one in our
thinking this episode one is the ability to recognise faces species specific
the things they want to collect can monkeys recognise human faces can
humans obviously we can recognise monkey faces and what's aspects that they sort of the
empire we part the impact the kind of basically come going well
the most species independent thing that you can get the computer callow computers recognise faces
track places and things and so they came to see me only showed them how
the big database that we collected so we have actually a big three d room
it's pretty cool
she is messy thing my computer here
pretty cool the three during the civil war the animation so it's very logical virtualized
reality right
and it's got
so essentially gone
cameras from every direction and we're essentially for every every camera about thirty cameras and
then for every different directions and and then every camera we then have a
for every two cameras we have a single computer
and then we have different lots on the two so then we synchronize it all
up and can this capture that are all at the same time
see if you can show
so for instance like this is this is an animation of me
taking the three this frontal
taking the in whatever with
over the following eliminations that's all taken in exactly the same time
and so we do that across all the expressions of different poses and across time
so we actually have to be very very large data and school multiply sent its
largest database of its kind in the so that's what we're trying to play model
so again
the learning part is important in the computer vision but data that is so important
for the stuff and things so
and so they go the other way close
it was
this is like another one
so the different poses this is this is this is a snapshot for
the ideal elimination
and so
any single but we have that sometimes the recorded as well so it's got all
the state all different plant we do different expressions and across the street hundred thirty
different subjects
it's quite quite a big data
i think you think
because it
in in in in in the hard rock store
can you copied this
ah just
so let's start up
sorry for the restart of this
well again
we actually so temperamental but i've had some things can with my macro with a
for some reason thought about so i sing the praises of maximal tolerance competitive traumatic
but for some reason that on my mac when it gets too bad
it's going really bad about gets about seventy percent battery life whatever it is
doors and so on the guys in the next or going to give me new
battery but didn't have any left for left so are kind of display
every time i use my computer i have to have plug was to stores and
the the same issues
there you go to replace a battery fixed
i really
i've done that already
but it still doesn't so you get doesn't mean that we can talk about one
of the very very
we can we can we can have a mac form after the talk
so getting into the last talk and you guys will be very patient and i
realize that we've been surfing into all sorts of things today so i'm sure it's
getting kind of tired but
this is essentially says user talk but beginning to realize this works of the economy
to wrap up
the things especially talking about what's coming in what's going to different rather than kind
of and hopefully have got good intuition of exhaustive search greedy search but you can
kind of see that we stopped off the gradient search part just with essentially PCA
there wasn't any real kind of like machine learning all
kernel learning going on there being so this is the last kind of mad about
why can't i apply
and SVM to grant said why can't i apply a out of was and that's
worked really well for exhaustive search what can i do the same thing for ready
for gradient search
and he is you know what you get out of this is that you can
but they're all
it comes at a cost
so so we can we can skip relevant to this sort of so obviously the
goal of alignment is defined
you want to find out what between the source image and the template
you the parameterize wall what function
we want to find p it's all about finding a
and generally for the generic problem
we call object recognition whatever we do
we obviously we
might have a lot of lot images of objects
this object is probably is going to be my training set so can i generalized
such that i can align this with this with
a high accuracy
can i also instead of doing it with rigid shape can i do it with
a large what functions so obviously
exhaustive search can work well with something like this
so this is the desired outcome should them things of
of what was going on there
get through to this
the city like when thinking
of what's going on with an active appearance model
it's essentially a can come to think of it as a generative duality
so you've got a generative model for shape
the linear generative model for shape that we've kind established in it for little thing
we can learn through PCA can also have the generative linear model for parents we
got the two together and there's some sort of nonlinear interaction goes on to get
this final installation here
to come up with something forty we've already established that and they have all different
names we like the name i am but you can call it
you can call it whatever you like
what and essentially with this generative duality
is that we have a source image
we instead instead of trying to synthesize something we essentially trying to invert the whole
process and we the whole process so that i can see
the go lecture 10
so let me say what lecture 10 is about
it's gonna bring back it will be entirely about
and what we did before
but is gonna bring back these matrices you remember this was K for in from
the 1st lecture
with 2 all the way along the diagonal
of the 1 with the change at the top of the change that to newer
and then I don't know if I gave this 1 name this is the 1
that where the changes down the
and and so it's really just it's very very closely related to this guy
just the changes in the age maybe for hanging because this was that it change
came at the bottom when we had those springs and masses hanging in a in
a line
where the change came at the top is the top boundary
free so this is
all users of this is
fixed effects fixed at both ends and this 1 is free at the top and
fixed at the bottom and this 1 corresponds to a fixed at the top and
free at the bottom
OK so
1 thing to do
which we poses an exercise for a problem was to figure out what was going
on with the inverse
these inverses are very pleasant
and we can capture those very quickly and by the way that everything I say
about H is gonna come over immediately from everything we say about the
so all of those 2 where are really the same job
but provided that are not so
approach question
and I it I opened the sort of thing on the web page the question
of finding formula
for the inverse matrix
suggested to like take the case that 3 by 3 or the 4 by 4
cases as examples
and a
here and
let me see what the inverse is to be written down
I remember the one-fifth and so what is the 5 represent their
In an inverse 0 was dividing by
determined and the determinant of the 4 by 4 matrix is 5
and in general the determinant of the n by n matrix is n + 1
so that part of the pattern we could spot but this was maybe not well
this looks pretty clear along the top of the world
and follow me and the role
because turning it upside-down isn't changing anything here where returning this 1 upside down converge
to that and turning that website down convert this way but now the number that
came in here were not so
but you
the pattern there was to be discovered
a core against
Dataset someone approaches and verified
and several other people didn't quite successfully
made made made a good guess
or they may have been
reach their allowed by this is some systematic I shouldn't say they because it made
out of it may have been done differently but