so i'm very low and
from carnegie mellon and this is chris christus was unable to make it and they
will make it today he sent his sincere apologies and i think the slides are
online the
what if you go to the conference website website and click the tutorial tab should
the PBS show should be at the bottom
and they interact with the clarification questions
since we're in tutorial i want to make sure that i don't lose anybody
the tutorials on graph mining techniques for social media analysis and so before actually getting
the real meat of this tutorial i want to talk about what graph mining is
then why we would want to do such a thing
so graph mining is essentially extracting useful useful knowledge for
that is patterns outliers centre from structured data can be represented as a graph meant
for our purposes this is usually associated social network however you can
use different kinds of network besides just keep a social network of people for instance
so here's a
here two examples one to facebook graph which
the government touchgraph website that were no nodes are networks in
and then from for the graph from livejournal violent from lehman in color
where each each node is one then the links are
extracted from all the
the friends list
so a couple examples of graph mining is some unnamed social media host just to
be unbiased tries to look at certain online groups and predict whether some group all
continue or disband within the next few months based on the interaction that they would
get from that group another example is that some phone provider might look at cell
phone call call graphs to try to figure out if there are certain users are
users in in the network that are
that are result of identity theft
just by based on who are calling and when they're calling
so why why would we want to use graph mining
well thanks to the web and social media it's only now that were even able
to get this sort of data on a very large scale
it used to be the case that sociologists would have to go into high schools
and monasteries and survey each person in their to and ask where their friends are
this is a very practical to do and it's
time consuming you have to get IRB approval but now thanks to net thanks to
social media we can just crawl the web get the stuff for free because high-schoolers
just like to tell us who friends are on myspace
so it's also on a much larger scale because we have millions of users not
just hundreds or thousands even
and that we also want to be able to understand relationships as well as content
like we may be able to
graph content such as text and images from the web but we also want to
understand the link structure and what these relationships mean
and large amounts of data will always raise new questions
if you have a big monsters amount of data you need a bit more need
for need for organisation of this data
so some motivating questions and graph mining are
but we want to answer is how how do networks form evolve evolving collapse
what tools can we use to study these networks
who are the most influential central members of the network
how do ideas diffuse
can we extract communities
and what sort of anomaly detection can we perform
and these are questions i will answer in this tutorial and here's how we're going
to fit those and in part one
i'll go over here is the question of how do networks form evolve and collapse
first few for some introductory material and definitions and then some patterns and laws that
have been have been discovered on in real real graphs
part two
are going to go into some detail on some tools that are commonly used to
study these networks and part which which also includes
it's the questioner ranking in how
how we find the most important members of the network
and in part three
after a quick break that's what your five-minute break will be right after part two
we can look forward to that
so far part three will
go into some case studies which we answer some of the some other questions that
that are active research areas such as diffusion a community extraction anomaly detection
part one of first go over six definitions and then some patterns so i'm just
starting from the very very bottom up so it
there be six very basic definitions to look over and then explain some of the
and enrique in real graphs
so in the first definition the network is we can define as the graph a
set of vertices or nodes and the set of edges
and these edges may have numerical weights between them for instance this is a little
toy blog graph
where we have a lot one block two block three block four we have directed
edges going going between the blogs and sometimes the blog belong mailing to itself
it's in case
before right here at least two itself three times and it links to blog two
twice and log one blogs you need link to each other and so on
so we represent represent the graph the graph is using adjacency matrix
for instance if you if one has one link to be two then we would
i find the find the i j
entry in the adjacency matrix from from from the one to be two
and before link to itself three times you would have
have into right here
so on unweighted graphs all the entries are going to be easier one because we
will be using these numerical weight here
in an undirected graph
the matrix to be symmetric because they're being mutual links going either way between all
the graphs
between all the nodes
so next bipartite graph has to two distinct sets of vertices and edges will only
occur between
nodes of the different set
this presentation is delivered by the stanford center for professional development
so welcome back
what i want to do today is that have our discussion on support vector machines
and in particular was the idea of kernels
and then talk about the one norm soft margin SVM is well others
apply it seems even today that is not linearly separable
all about the SMO algorithm on which is an algorithm for solving the optimisation problem
that that that we post last time
so to recap
right we wrote down to the following convex optimisation problems
and all this is assuming that the data is linearly separable which which is assumption
of fixed later
and this
but this is the south african people back in
they was
and so with this optimisation problem given a training set
this will on
yes the after all margin
classifier for the dataset that maximizes
the geometric margin for your training examples
and so the previous lecture we also derive the dual of this problem
which was to maximize the
right of
and this is the dual
as the optimisation problem where here on using the piece of angle brackets denote inner
products of this is just you know it's i transposing exchange
the vectors exciting
we also worked out
the weights w with the given by some of i alpha i y i x
and therefore when you need to make predictions of a classification time
you need to compute
the value of the hypothesis is applied to input that which is actually the second
suppose would be
right which is that threshold function developers plus one minus one
and so this is key of rye rye
so that can also be written in terms of
in the products between input input vectors x
what i want to do is not the idea of kernels which make use of
this property that it turns out we can take on the only dependencies of the
algorithm on you on x is through the inner product and they can write the
entire algorithm without ever explicitly referring to expect that only
and the other thing in the publicity
input your input feature vectors
and the idea behind kernels is the following
let's say that you have some input attributes
of course to say for now zero number maybe this is on the area of
the whole
the you trying to make some particularly whether it be so in the next six
are quite often will take this
feature x and one at
two which is set of features for example we take a step back to these
of full polynomial features and then we actually call this mapping phi so that five
x denote the mapping from your original features to some high dimensional the features
so if you do this and if you want to use the features five x
all you need to do is go back to linear and everywhere you see i
xj right we replace
on the inner product between private five SG
right so this response to running a support vector machine with the features given by
five x rather than what you know your original maybe one dimensional input feature
and this not i want to consider sometimes i fx will be very high dimensional
and in fact sometimes five x seven example five x may contain very high degree
polynomial features
on sometimes five x actually even be an infinite dimensional vector of features
and the question is if i have actually extremely high dimensional
then you can't actually computed these inner products
very efficient seems right because computers you to
he represents an extremely high dimensional feature vector and taking the product in that would
be computationally inefficient
it turns out that in many important special cases we can write down on scholar
kernel function
denoted by k
which will be
we should be in the product between those feature vectors
it turns out that important special cases where computing five axis is computationally very expensive
maybe is impossible there is an infinite dimensional vector and you can't compute infinite dimensional
but the important special cases with five x is very expensive to represent because it's
so high dimensional
but none the less you can actually compute the kernel
between its and exchange can compute the inner product between these two vectors
very inexpensively
and so the idea of the support vector machine is that everywhere in the algorithm
that you see these inner product
we're going to replace it with the kernel function that you can compute efficiently
and that lets you work in
feature space five x even if i effects on
very high dimensional
let me also how that is done on
and actually a little bit later today where she see some concrete examples of five
x and the kernels on analysis think about constructing kernels explicitly
three dispenses phase one example so
let's say you have
on two inputs x and z are normally actually write x i and x j
but it's easy to say the writing
let's say might know is k if x common e equals transpose where
so this is
right this extract fuzzy either to this thing here is xtrans lsi and distinct sections
if you
i want to add k nearest neighbors well what you have to do is
you need to
not just sort the arguments but then just pick
the first k terms that's all
the the code doesn't really change much
and if you have a nearest neighbour regression
the code actually gets easy you just wrote the song here
that's basic nearest neighbors
does it work
is example
on the previous studies
and you can see that
more or less kind of get it right i should tell you that the optimal
separation of it's just a straight line
is that just taking two normal distributions
and so you will get the same variance
the straight line here
it's not quite straight well let's see what we can do
this would be seven nearest neighbors
and the shades of brown and violet seems to depend on
how many of the neighbours are
all right or all blue
so that we all seven we also blue
and these will be somewhere in between
if you look at the decision boundary it's a little bit smarter
so a bit like the coastline
a lot a lot nicer than what we have here
if you if you have more nearest neighbour need more data
and so the convergence properties of the nearest neighbour classifier conferences like world
the neighborhood needs increases my sample size increases but not directly
to regression
so that probably looks like assign right
the one nearest neighbour regression
looks god-awful
well what the seven nearest neighbour regression like
actually preclude right
i mean i not very smooth but overall it actually broke it's quite
this is the other thing i mean you don't necessarily care that much about the
curve being pretty what you care about is it actually working with
probably will work quite well in terms of their
this was
the simplest algorithm you could come up with
it does work fairly well
the nearest neighbour search will find the nearest guy predict the same label
you can do that for regression it can classification it's trivial to implement supplies for
you don't need any training
doesn't work that brilliantly well but if you have any algorithm
you want to
find out what it's good it's probably a good idea to compare against nearest neighbour
just in case it out was might actually do quite well
from his safe
now let's look at another problem
looks quite unrelated initially
estimating probabilities from data
so here the goal is
well we go and rolling dice
and then i count how many times each site comes up
i could just failed empirical probability
according to wall the frequency of occurrence
what if i have a coin toss it and made it a hundred times in
four times he comes up eight six times it comes up tails i could say
maybe the probability of
his forty is point for probability of ten is point six
so this will be actually what's also called the maximum likelihood estimation
name and trying to find the most likely
set of parameters that explain my daughter
this is not this
this is a good idea in every case
made me give an example
let's say
a student comes to school and he said well i didn't do my homework
the tests why
students as well
the dog the homework
this is perfectly valid in the maximum likelihood seems to explain the outcome namely student
doesn't have homework
it could really happen that the dog at home
but we know that dogs usually tend not to eat homework and maybe the more
plausible explanation was well the student was elated by
teacher will reject that hypothesis
even so
in the maximum likelihood scenes
student being a lazy farmer the homework are two equally
plausible scenarios
so what if the teacher do is we use the priors
because you know he's been probably teacher for a while so he knows what reason
what are unreasonable explanations
they basically use the posterior
we had a prior on possible explanations how reasonable they are
and then use that to perform inference
if we just count the number of occurrences here
you have number of trials
which would be the most likely explanation of
it would be falling into exactly the same trap of the homework
i'll see afterwards how to fix it
now let me show you what is a bad idea
thank you for taking
just a simple random number generator
which was equal probabilities
without it
one and
i've just
both the accounts
so that would be i think
twelve observations twenty four
sixty and one hundred twenty
what you should be seeing a straight line
what you are seeing is anything but the straight line see it appeared to here
should be for their
the team here
and so on
what's happening is that my empirical observations are not really that close to the true
if i were just doing a maximum likelihood estimate i would say well i this
is probably occurring with something like
you know almost thirty percent probability is this is around fifteen
whereas in reality although frequent occurrence of the machine
before i tell you how to fix it let me first tell you if you
could properly be
there's something called have things by
and this is the following
but the probability
that's an empirical estimate
deviates from the true probability by more than epsilon
is less than two
e to the minus
two in its long square
in the summer observations it's like the confidence
so in other words i have exponentially fast convergence
to the answer
for any given epsilon
that's the good news
the bad news is
if i ask
if i keep this term here fixed
how does it scale within
that's what you eat some scales like
one of the square of number of observations
this is really bad right
was in order to
get the ten fold reduction in my confidence improvement in my confidence
i need
well a hundred times as many observations
this is really
the only good thing about this is that
this volunteer doesn't hold only for a single probability here
holds uniformly over all of them
so this is converging to be according the fixed point of t
so this the about fixed point theorem for the contraction
you're blind operator
people applying in its convergence to the fixed
since we have these inequities and should have the same inequality for fixed points
continuity of complying lectures
then i can take the maximum suspected p
four pi
so i think the maximum suspect apply so this holds in particular any state prize
so we comparing these vectors is all compliance y so
i can write
this for an estate
and then i can take
these animated prove
the maximum possible sites
maxine you suspect pi
what i had
if i get here
the optimal value function that
so i got the optimal value function
it cannot be larger than than the fixed point
so that's so good so far that's hot off what we require because we want
to conclude that i actually if
so in order to see if the article that's become policy that greatest respectively
so no
maybe you should
raise some alliance because maybe such a policy doesn't actually
so i am assuming here
maybe not finite MDP
and so greedy policy we suspect two any value function always exists what do i
mean by that
you know
these maxim is taken somewhere
if if you if you have infinite action spaces
this is not maybe you would need something like compact mass continuity about
but if you
have a nice small MDP everything's finite the maximum is always taken from there
and if if it
state access to maximize taken that action in one then i call
i just
call that
so that be my policy
the player
the greedy policy always exists for suspected leaders of creation
and so if you have that so definition for greedy policies that people buying
applied to the
is the same as he applied to be so we're taking the policy with respect
to the fixed point
but then you can keep applying t of
both sides t to both sides
well in part because here of the is the right so
if you black p
as many times as you want you always get the me is the fixed point
you can apply to your reply
and the
on this side
but then what do you get so this is the
so we apply to game
you get you keep eyes that the
you get keep i
but the five we
what is that it's TV which is b
so no matter how many times you applying here by
two we
you get we
and we know that upon
if you apply to to your
indefinitely to some unusual factor
then there is that the
the process is going to come back
to the value function and the output of policy pi
so this
this site here
the parts are going to come actually apply
so we have to buy it was we
so we have the following the policy
was value function equals the
isn't that great
yes it's great
because we already concluded that these stars
cannot be larger than than we
but right now we have to follow the policy
so that we BFI was the
so we start has to be equal to
because we just demonstrated the distance of the policy
this value function is v
so it cannot be the optimal value function is really smaller than b
because of the existence of this policy
so then we can conclude
from this anecdote is that we equispaced
that finishes approval so
the fixed point
the panel operator is the optimal value function OK and we get something more
from this proof
we got that the greedy policy we suspect these five or the fixed point of
is an optimal policy
because one
because the value function of this is just the
which is the on
the optimal
got it
ask questions
greedy policy with respect to
we start with a fixed point of t
and it's going to be up to that that policy is going to be able
if you take a greedy policy suspected any value function that it could be rubbish
so what does this mean so this means
that it hurts four trying to compute the optimal value function because once you have
all the optimal value function
computing an optimal policy
balance into their problem
just have to solve this maximization problems you plug in the function here
well OK
you have this sound could be over very in a large number of states and
that could be daunting process as it can be computationally difficult to do that
but at least this is one way off for
discovering optimal policies right
so this is a very
crucial fundamental activation
of dynamic programming and many of them at once
the VOC
and hopefully right now you see why
we had that slide that was all those abstract constructions was lift stuff
so one the first
are given that counts the mind
so we know that these studies the fixed point contraction
in april one
you know i
it's just a with to
what are your
more than thirty
then of course this is not just
so the single neuron
this is my one
one of the
need to be wrong
he made
all right
he may
you like
it is
you get the ball
and the right
you can see what she
due the
now we all
for each
you know
and i believe it should
you need
just because
it was
one of the
so all
you know it just
he is
can you give them
it called if you
it is
what you need to be some
the it is to see one
some these people who
i never had some
all right
in the right direction
then the fixed point iteration based
what does
the impact of using this back trick that was to trick of computing this kronecker
product in off into the three rather than off into the four
on the run time
as you can see here
roughly one order of magnitude
is gained by
using this vector compared to the original way of directly computing
the random walk
so this was a technique by which monotone it out to speed up traffic computation
but of course they did not deal
if this problem of torturing
which is
depicted here
as i said before walks allow for repetitions of notes
what can visit the same cycle of notes all over again
a kernel measure similarity between two graphs in terms of common walks
hence small
structural similarity can cause a huge
kind of value
as i said
if you graph is undirected and it contains
and if both graphs undirected and they contain
two nodes a and b which are connected by an edge
then you walk could go back and forth between these two notes all the time
and that would be in
a good example for torturing
and it would completely
mess up your draft value
because it would lead to a huge controversy although it is only a tiny structure
relationship between these two
my hand i
tackle this problem
by transforming
two input graphs and they transformed
you know way
that's four bits
tottering between two nodes
they increase the size of the original graph so they create
conditions from graph not only for each node from the original graph in also for
each edge
from the
the original graph so
is increased tremendously
then they create edges in this new transformed graph
two connect nodes
that represented
nodes in the original graph and
knows that represented edges
in the original graph to each other and they do this in a way that
makes it impossible
back and forth between the same two nodes in two consecutive steps
so you cannot go back to the same node that you
it started from
in two in two steps
if you do it in three steps it's possible
and that's actually one of them
limitations of this approach
namely this approach for bits
tottering between two nodes but not tottering along any larger cycles within your two graphs
and that might be the reason why my here
could not really present experimental evidence showing uniform improvement of the classification accuracy based on
these graph constant forbids torturing
also and this is the
move around ten problem of course if you
create a node for each edge
in your life
original graphs then you increase your graphs arise from all the
o of n two order of n squared
and this is an address
effect on kind of computation time
my et observed that
and therefore they came up with the strategy to speed up
graph come computation
and they did so
by adding additional labels
two the graphs
they observe that the larger your product graph
the slower year-round
i should mention
this year in
the case where you have
graphs of node labels
your product graph
only contains pairs of nodes
that have identical labels
i didn't
describe that
in the beginning because they're only the topology but if you have no neighbours in
your graphs then
your product graph only contest contains pairs of nodes
this is identical node labels
and of course if you're number of node labels of different node labels in your
graphs is larger
this will have effect
that the product graph
then be smaller
and so the trick that my head i use is that they introduce new artificial
node labels
to reduce the size of the product graph
they came up with the idea to use logical distributors of notes
its natural extra labels of these nodes
so to add an extra label to each node
for instance counting the number of neighbors of the node
i'm adding this additional labels
they then reduced the size of the product graph
which then has an effect on the run time that is necessary to commute across
and this idea just described of counting
the neighbours of the node in the graph is the so-called morgan index which is
more than forty years of
and it's based on the idea of counting the neighbours
of nodes in the graph
and doing this recursively
it's you higher order morgan indices
for your footnotes in your graph and this
technique actually had
a significant impact on
and kind of computation around
but still
nine of his father i nor
my here at our
could completely remove this
the problem of tottering even in my head as approach we still have the problem
of tottering in larger size
and natural
extension or
that way of dealing with this problem was to study
looking at other substructures them
walks could remove this problem of torturing and obviously if you do not allow for
repetitions of nodes
in your walks
then you cannot suffer from torturing but then
you're not commuting walks anymore your computing power
in your two graphs
we study the better
it would be feasible to compare all have into graphs
but of course
it's well known that all
to compute all pass into india in across is an NP hard problem
the same holds for along path in your breath
average value that you would get of the random variable in the limit that your
sample size would be infinite
that's the
essentially what the expectation value is so if you have a finite sample with only
n observations and somehow the obvious estimator to use is simply the arithmetic average
the values of the random variable that you are observed
right so i could write a new hat
and that would be the the function of the data
that i would use for that estimator
that's a very important estimated that comes up all the time obviously sufficiently important to
have its own
notation sometimes we write x bar
the bar looks like a something like a hat and it is sometimes called the
sample mean which is a little bit confusing because the mean
it is not an estimator of the mean is is is the parameter itself constant
whereas the sample mean
it is is an estimator for the mean
OK so the two important parameters that we want to consider for every estimator for
the bias and variance and in this particular case it happens that the bias is
identically equal to zero so that that's nice and that's not always true for many
estimators but in this case it is
you can also look at the variance of new hat that's not too difficult to
do i go through the calculation here but what you find is that it is
equal to the variance of x the original random variable
divided by
the number of
observations of x in your data sample
so that leads to the well known result that the standard deviation of the estimator
of the mean is equal to the standard deviation of the original random variable x
divided by the square root of the number of measurements
so you're probably familiar with that
let's just consider one more
the sort that is that the variance
if that's the parameters that i'm interested in
recall that the
the meaning of that parameter one the expectation value of
x minus mu square so it is the expectation value of the variable itself minus
its own expectation value that quantity square
clearly if you only have a finite data sample you can try to approximate by
taking something like the average value of x minus its
estimated expectation value square so that somehow seems like in natural
a reasonably natural formula to write down
to estimate the variance
you might wonder
why not just one over and y one over n minus one
the story there is the following is that if you
were to compute the variance sorry the bias of the estimator sigma had squared defined
with the one over n minus one you find the bias is zero that is
to say that the expectation value of that expression
it is in fact equal to the
the variance of
if you need to consider any other factor here one over and one over n
plus seventeen or some other factor in front then you would have had to have
a bias
i sometimes statistics books that
that factor of one over n minus one is is explained in a slightly strange
something about something about losing a degree of freedom when you when you put in
the sample
i mean there but really the story revolves around whether or not this estimator has
a bias
the bias itself
this is zero you can work out then the variance of this estimator and it's
this one
but we sent our little note to nature pointing it out in input with a
verbal argument and they just back so we had to do with simulation model to
convince people
so the
the deal here is that by using
artificial neural networks by using evolutionary search algorithms because the kind of the complexity of
the simulation model that happening was constructed kind of propelled them to the results but
they were hoping for without really understanding the
but the effect but they were looking at
and we had dave and i were forced to write a whole new simulation model
to debunk it
i never gets cited and no one knows about it is very irritating
so here's another reason why you might resort to simulation which is maybe more
less negative
so math models often encourage us to embrace the limits this is infinity
often it makes sense or it makes a model tractable to consider infinite populations
individuals the interact over infinite time frictionless systems well mixed populations kinds of idealised asian
that that
the theory might lead us to believe that those idealise asians that we would be
better off if we didn't have to make them
some of the organisations often
need to be made
so what they they don't leave much room for
transience isolation between parts of the system delays and lags locality
it's a new kind of maybe sum up
this the rest of logistics
so who does what to whom where when and for how long the individual level
in factors
which are averaged out
when you consider that when you consider the system in the limit
the notion here is that it's these things are not good just because they're more
realistic we're not going to want to include them in our model just because it
takes us closer to the real world we have to have some theoretical motivation for
thinking that these are important in our understanding of the system was all all no
system is infinite in any respect
so it's always if we were just motivated by realism we would always want to
get rid of these things but sometimes they useful organisations theoretically motivated idolization
so an example of that
this good work on the piper cycles
which is nice and simple two percent
a big mess of chemical reactions
if you set them up
in the right way you'll find cycles of catalytic reactions reactions to catalyze each other
in a mutually self-reinforcing way
i cycles
they can be vulnerable to parasites reactions which don't take part in the cycle which
use up some of the the the catalysts some of the products
well some of the the chemicals that take part in the reactions
and those who wrote guide the cycles and
and destroy them eventually so when systems like this
are embedded in space so instead of considering
big bag of chemicals to be well mixed solution a jar where every particle is
is is as likely to interact with every other particle
what if you spread out your chemicals over space in the system i'm talking about
you you see spirals of chemical reactions on these spirals resist parasitic invasion so
whereas in the well mixed population you don't see how cycles because they get destroyed
by these parasitic chemical reactions before they can get started once you distribute the system
in space you do see them
so this is what by fourteen who will break i'm sure i'm not pronouncing those
names correctly
the hold about and they don't pronounce the g end of
i'm going to try to find the it's impossible to pronounce dutch names when
somebody tried to convince me what dennis bergkamp is called in in holland there's just
nothing to this nothing like way it's written down
you start off with a well mixed
the distribution of different chemicals
and the system evolves under a set of rules that govern which chemicals can interact
and when interact what they give rise to what things catalyze that interaction
and very rapidly the system organizers into
spiral wave fronts which propagate across the space
because there's a nice there's the rules imply sort of chain reactions and so green
gives rise to yellow which gives rise to orange which gives rise to read to
pink and that's why see these
waves and for some reason the waves are not just
horizontal parallel bars
but they
our initial ice from the labelled examples
and so if there are several different clustering is that might come out from different
random initial the stations of the clustering algorithm those
supervised labelled examples will assure that
we at least pick one that's
pretty consistent with these labels so then that becomes the nationalization
but getting intuition right
OK so any comments
suggestions clarifications on this
what of
how use this
well um
i don't i
short answer is i don't think anybody knows how the brain works but there's is
plenty that but it but there's just no way on
the question was how does this correspond with what we might know about what happens
in the brain
because we don't know what happens exactly in the brain but it's interesting that there's
pretty active
so the research group in
cognitive science and also in developmental psychology that's
very interested in how is it that humans can learn so much
it's so rapidly as children
from apparently not mostly on labelled example
mostly labelled examples
so it the question that is
considerable interest there my own hunch is that well i don't know if this stuff
has any
is an appropriate model for that are not my guess is that the second method
we're going to talk about is a much more appropriate model for
how humans get away with using of labelled data
that's what
you know you are set you know of
so i was
from despair hearts
so i
yeah i think there's it does top out somewhere below a hundred percent for a
couple reasons one is that in some senses the classes are inherently ambiguous and so
for example even something apparently obvious like spam
what's spam to my not overlap perfectly with what's spam to me
although probably it overlaps ninety percent of the guess
but even if if we had two independent people label spam documents they don't agree
completely so there is
that kind of ambiguity in the labels to begin with the second is that there
are some really severe assumptions in the naive bayes
model for text classification the of words model so it's like saying
the sentence machine learning is great is the same as saying the sentence
learning great areas fishing
and to people they don't seem like i'm saying the same thing but to this
program they of this is john bellingham altogether and ignoring
the content so there are some modelling problems here to
OK so let's move on to the
i thought hard about how to use my limited sixty minutes here
and what you should know is that there's actually quite a bit this is a
fairly hot topic in
of statistical language analysis right now how do we use on labelled data to improve
on our learning
in sixty minutes i thought the most useful thing we can do
was cover what seemed to me to be the two
he types of problem structure that people are web urging with these algorithms
and so
i can show you a lot more algorithms for leveraging
that first type of information that first type of problem structure but i'm not going
to because i think the the most important thing to get out of this are
talk is from that first part is all i see is
documents naturally clusters into groups based on the words that currently in and if those
groups have been actually clustering to happen to align with the class labels that i
want my classify to assign
then it's probably a good idea for me to be using on labelled data augment
and furthermore i could probably test for that by running an unsupervised clustering algorithm and
then seeing to what degree those natural clusters do
a line with class labels
and if you get that idea then i'm happy and you could probably yourself often
think of better algorithms than the one we just talked about before we talked about
it's pretty easy to to grok and it falls right on the naive bayes quest
just talked about
this one
and so on
max intl
new coefficient
the problem
this is so
let's call recursively
because the one plus w one will be the two
what does that mean
my claim is that
if i get it right
basic scale
automatically got it right and all higher scales
these function functions of t
or two t
this seems to be to to to the stated that
you've got the right scale
but now
look how we got here
the zero plus w zero
three one
so suppose i plug in
said one
bringing everyone down into
these are all
plus w zero
plus w one
that's our government
that's the multiscale here's the averages
here is the course details
here is the fine details
i guess i'm realizing
these are always
to give this whole lecture
would be to bring in matlab toolbox
wavelet toolbox
and see
these pieces
so i don't know what
know you meant of course
there are all these
well what i
what i get that
OK i will that toolbox you
this is probably is
so here i am a mathematician
so i was tired talking microphone
ah well i could see the done so often
usually by my colleague however
and i could probably do it
really so maybe
let me check offline after this lecture what might be feasible
but what what what we say hypothetical in in this for this additional image
what matlab toolbox the matlab wavelet toolbox
it's one of the many toolbox
one of the many toolboxes by the way
so matlab course is the product of works in
but you know
right toolboxes
the individual
scientists around the world
well thank you know what
i know how to use matlab
wavelet theory
alright toolbox
and then they mathworks is the authors which in this case were four
four additional french
i want to mention
they created the toolbox for the gooey the license user interface
so that you could call it
copper signal
what's the signal itself
well it's discrete actually looks like a continuous function
but the toolbox to work
and you say OK
figure out it's
this level
it's averages
he so so you would
here's the five we can say here is the
here's the function and now
the toolbox would break into pieces
so it would have these that was very smooth
he was
four of these
is this
catching some consolation that would be w zero is
smaller probably much smaller
but possibly more rapidly taking
other isolation would be the w one part
and we could have like five scales are we just
well the toolbox how many skills we want
four five would be to
the rest these functions together and of course back to the right
what i'm saying is the toolbox
i'm writing things at the level of the whole space of functions
but what that means is for each function
just like for each function this weight function as a fourier series it's going away
the series
and the box with computer
so what would the wavelet series b we use these functions
we use these
these are
w was at all scales so
so the the way
expansion of function
compare it with the fourier expansion
four vertices
and obviously has five edges
its minimum valence
here the religious history
two so the minimum balances two
and the maximum analysis three
and as i mentioned earlier
the matrices aren't
the graph invariant
although if you take the spectrum of the matrix of the
adjacency matrix it is graph
what is the spectrum it's the collection of of hiking VAT so the idea that
these are graphic variants
they are independent of the limitations of
simultaneous politicians frozen sums rows and columns of
adjacency matrix
any questions
let's go to subgraphs and contributing
if we have a graph and if we
that's the
and select two subset
there the subset of the vertex set
and f which is the subset of the answer
then it may happen that this pair you have is
a graph or it's not
if it is a graph
then it is called the subgraph
but if it's not the graph then of course that the sum
so for instance
so let me just give you a little example
or random graph here
and if we select this edge here
and this vertex here
this is not something
because together with this edge
you have to select the two endpoints
if you select the three vertices and and one edge then that would be so
of course
if you equals v
then we say that h is a spanning subgraph so this means
we just remove some of the edges of the original graph in order to get
the subgraph
the other extreme
it is
if you have
if you have a graph and you just select
of vertices
that this collection of vertices
somehow defines the maximal possible
on that induced on that
set of this is this means that you get all the edges that belong to
that have both endpoints in this subset then we are talking about the use of
as we said here in this graph is completely determined by the set of this
here are
three weeks examples
the very first
graph is k four here is an example that is
the graph of the subgraph that is neither induced or spending
a spanning subgraph and that's continuous
so what is the walk
a walk
in our case
in the graph
this is just the sequence of vertices
the zero
v one up to k
with the property
that's too
but this is
in that sequence
at adjacent vertices in the graph
and in this case
we can talk about
the initial vertex v zero
tell me
vertex vk and we talk about the walk from the zero to vk or between
these are on the k
these are maybe also called the beginning of the walk and became the end of
the war
and k
the number k is called the length of the war w
so there are some special cases of walks
if i may just draw like this so walk looks like this
but it may itself so it may go
so once you
make a picture of what you don't see what was going on just
we were walking like this so here
here here
here and then back here here here here
so i walk
it's called a closed walk
is that if the terminal vertex is identical
the initial to lock so we start walking and get to the point
so that would not be
close what would be an open book
a very special case of the walk is a path
that's just to walk
which belongs to an
whose underlying subgraphs is upon
as we defined it so
all vertices in the work must be distinct
and special cases of cycle
where again all of this is a listing
except for the very first and the last which would be the same so it's
a close to walk
this is thing
so path can be also used as the subgraph of g isomorphic and that's also
the same
there is
well so f is proportional to weight so f diverges if inverse power
goes to zero
that's infinite redshift survey infinite redshift that's where the more items it corresponds to an
equal to zero now you can compute the radius of the sphere there it seems
to actually go to zero but that's true because there's also left one here and
if you compute it you will see that they able to use is finite and
the area is exactly two pi squared
our one five p one of these this constant here
and you can also put in the value of the newton's constant which is again
given exactly by string theory so these are numbers you get from the string theory
and then
the analogue of the bacon steinhardt in
calculation is simple problem
is been giving you these very simple answer to the entropy of the black hole
his area of corsi's over four times g new
i forgot to nominate biarritz put equal to one
and this is too by squirrel and one n five p
so that's doing the analogue of the same classical hot
calculation in this slightly more complicated one
now can we find the same result by counting whether the answer is yes somehow
here is how it goes
so here is our three charge black hole
we look at it through a loop remember and it is a very complicated beast
that's the analogue of having this being description of the potomac
yeah its brains little open strings that run along the brain and carry momentum
and actually there is some effective low energy theory of the brains which i will
not try to describe in great detail here that's being
necessary but if some of you really want to get into details here is for
instance in the u
let me just say the words the the effective low energy theory of the brain
this is actually a supersymmetric yang mills theory again with you and one because five
gauge groups this is exactly like the constructions of brain one the official yesterday
then there are open strings that go from d one to d five so like
the matter fields of yesterday and here they correspond to hyper multiplets of you have
suppressed marksmanship semantic theory there is a certain number of them
now you can try to analyse what the entropy of this theory is
and there is one very simple even one of the calculation is trivial counting problem
again i'll show you this
so what we need to do remember is counts the number of states with the
total number of momentum in p
all of this configuration of n one n five brains
this boils down in the simplest case counting the number of ways of distributing the
total momentum
among the and one in five massless
open strings that stretched between the ones thousand the fives
well that's a very simple combinatorial problem you can actually do it
by using what is called the generating function
there are four and one in five of these rings
each one y four one four because that's the number of
it was only come from you on being the degrees of freedom in one of
these hypermarket let's that some supersymmetry multiply so far and one five and each one
of them can carry some momentum little n there are boards and some fermions these
out of the three boys and three FIRM you want to partition functions just compute
he called the there are more chozick coefficient q to the total momentum p
is a very simple asymptotic formula on the scottish formula that gives you the answer
and that's exactly what we found was talking
so the two results agree exactly
but actually when you think about this calculation a bit more intensely
you say why should they agree since after all we have done very little two
very different calculations here
it's as if i had done the calculation for the free spins in may
more than the very start and i told you that the result is exactly correct
in the limit of
extremely strong coupling reaction
you wouldn't believe me there because there would be no reason why the two should
and something analogous is happening here and the reason is the following
in doing the gravity calculation of heart beating
i have shown that there was a nice large most geometry
now this
boils down to to saying that the various length scales that appeared in the geometry
namely our one five
the volume of the ford taurus and so on
at all
larger than both the characteristic string scale and the planck length if this wasn't true
then i had no right to use simply
today about the einstein theory i i would have to use the full quantum gravity
or the full string theory in doing this calculations that would be corrections to this
analogous to the finite volume corrections that i mentioned before so our results there was
only valid because they shown that this
scales are very large compared to the fundamental microscopic scale so the theory
but if you look back at the expressions for the scales
here they are
and if you translate what they mean
you will see that the mean for instance that the number of strings are five
brains and the string coupling is very very big much bigger than one
and now the effective coupling of young mills theory on the d brains is exactly
this one will see
the moment why the more precisely
therefore when the gravity calculations justified the young miscalculation is not at all justified
and conversely one of the young miscalculation is justified and that's what they here the
gravity calculation is not justified
these are two strong weak coupling regime in which you have the calculation again as
if we consider free spins very strongly interacting spins for month
so it's not clear why the two should have agreed that actually in this particular
case that they did easily saved by supersymmetry game namely
what we are really counting here it turns out of supersymmetric ground states in a
chad sector or as they are called one needs replacement black holes
and because of this is a number of topological index remember which modulo some mild
assumptions does not change as you very confused parameters
we could actually extrapolate the weak coupling resolved to infinitely strong coupling it hasn't changed
and i got exactly the same month
she says you may say we just got like people do this calculation it can
theta is quantity of of interest and x represents all the things that we know
about theta so far so all the data we have collected and other information we
have that we describe are uncertainty
on a theta by this conditional probability p theta given all the things we know
so far summarise by x
and we'll call that the prior probability and as we observe some new data x
then we can absorb the evidence from x had by computing this quantity which is
the likelihood function and we think this is the function of theta
so p of x given theta
in which
x that is set to the observed values
we look at this is the function of features we evaluate for all values theta
we multiply that by the prior
and up to normalisation constant to get the posterior distribution
so it using bayes theorem to absorb the effect that new evidence
so we've gone from the distribution before we observed that had the distribution after we
observe that will see lots of examples of that as we go through
and the other important idea is to make predictions we marginalize so
in this simple case
we wish to predict quantity y
we will assume that the
depends on x only through theta so once we know feat
p of y
doesn't depend on x
and so
from the sum and product rules
we want to
predict p of y given
that is obtained by taking p of y given theta if theta given x and
marginalizing so making predictions usually use each and every possible value for theta weighted by
the current distribution of hysteria distribution
another thing about this of course is that this is now effectively if we observe
it more information this is now our prior to the next application of bayes theorem
to bayesian inference is intrinsically a sequential process as you have more information people knew
about what the the likelihood function
multiplied by the current distribution which is the prior to get the new distribution which
is the posterior
why is prior knowledge important so i said the
the interesting thing about the third generation framework is that we can incorporate rich prior
knowledge into a machine learning model someone's prior knowledge important so cartoon sketch of what
might be important so miserable x and the variable y
and we we collected some data should pairs of values of x and y
and we want to make predictions we want to know what value is why did
it take for this new value of x is not been observed previously
and as things stand it's actually quite quite hard to
to know what we should say about why
not clear what value we should choose
and if i tell you that
the values of y
were generated from the values of x by a straight line with some guassian noise
added and i tell you the variance of the noise i give you a lot
of prior knowledge about the way the data generated using a much better position to
make predictions about the value of y
and in fact of course without any prior knowledge you can't really say anything there
are there are many many different ways in which white could have been generated from
x is a huge range of possibilities and the more prior knowledge you have the
more constrained range approx possibilities and therefore the better predictions you can make actually prior
knowledge is very central to machine learning really learn anything just from data alone
graphical models
kenny and we had to be already use graphical models in your research
about half the who
OK great so what i'm going to do is to
as i said skin lightly over the topic of graphical models and try to motivate
them is even is going to give two entire talks on the details of graphical
so i shall just give
a brief introduction for those of you who are not already familiar with the field
so the idea of graphical models is
to take probability theory in other words the sum and product probability and combine them
with some diagrams and pictures some graphs
this brings lots of nice
it gives insights into existing models models which already just specified mathematically and i see
them pictorially alliances to understand
but for most of us certainly for me allows us to understand the structure of
the model is much more clearly many many people myself included find it much easier
to look at the picture and save the structure than to look at the big
page of mathematics
it also provides a framework for designing new models once we see the structure of
the model graphically we can also the model if we wish by adding links to
the graph or removing links or adding new nodes and so on so we can
design are model by designing the diagram
but it's actually much better than that because we can also do calculations using
using the diagrams we can do things like read off
conditional independence properties simply by looking at separation properties directly on the graph
thank you
so in the feature selection challenge
so it's nice thousand three and it made a mistake in the future stations and
there were five datasets one is a mass spectrometry data it's the task of separating
cancer versus normal
dexter text processing dataset extracted from the reuters corpus
the idea is drug discovery data sets
corresponding to predicting the molecular activity of some compounds
she it is handwritten digit recognition and man with an artificial dataset and what you're
looking at here is the distribution
of the results of the participants in the competition
so what we measured results in terms of balanced error rate which is the average
of the error rate of the positive class the negative class it's a measure of
performance that is a good
when you have unbalanced classes it averages the those and avoids that you will always
for the most abundant class for which the error to be able to give you
the good the good result even though you make too trivial
i guess
so in that case you can see that on some datasets there is a broad
distribution so people had anywhere from from as in people have anywhere from ten fifteen
percent error to almost fifty percent error
for the next it was more peaked around the five percent balanced error rate for
the termites is very flat
so people can get you know very good results in very bad results project is
much more peaked format along it's very interesting that you have
a bimodal distribution so people are either going to try to go it alone
and knowing how you know the data set was designed causing artificial data it's no
surprise he was very linear problem can never met at x or problem where i
had put in a five dimensional space clusters of the two classes are arranged on
hypercube so if you try the linear model you would miserably fails so that's probably
in the
twenty percent are of the linear model people
and this was the best course of feature selection so we ask people both to
get good balanced error rate and small feature sets
so the class you know focused on on feature extraction feature selection but at the
same time people had to learn about you know all the
tools of machine learning some of them had taken classes in machine learning before but
i discovered i had enough to review again a lot of the basic concepts of
they don't about all the basic tools again
and what's amazing about this class is the distance considerably
i exceeded my makes speculations
i have to say that my colleagues and i who organised the challenge we tried
very hard to match the performance of the participants
and it was not trivial
and we did not succeed actually imagine this performance even though we had in all
the results of the participants so it's not so easy to what i did is
that we created
the toolkit based on the
spider it implemented in matlab spider is a machine learning package that was implemented at
the max plank institute in tuning in
and it consists of a matlab learning objects so we built on top of that
and added methods that were successful in in the challenge and i provided to the
student baseline methods
so make sure you know that the methods i had one of the best i
could i could get because i want to know that they would have the potential
to improve a little bit on what they did but then i also try to
give them baseline methods that going about the tenth percentile of the best methods secession
basically what the best i could do myself either within the ten percent i thought
okay they will maybe improve a little bit and so on
but they ended up all to really outperform the baseline methods and to even outperform
the best performers in the challenge and they were motivated to do that because i
give them more points if they would outperform the best results in the challenge the
total number of point to get the maximum grade they could get the total amount
of points to get the maximum grade without out of performing the best results in
the challenge season even if you know the exceeded
the baseline performance with a significant margin they would get the maximum point but they
get extra points you know if they are they exceeded the
first results of the challenge and so they all worked extremely hard
two to be that and that's that's what they did so what you see on
this graph the balanced error rate
eight percent of the baseline method
and then the challenge
the best results with the bar
and then the results of the students except for the durability editor dataset they always
going to propagate at different speeds depending on the kind of media is propagating through
the way we models is mathematically is the acoustic wave propagation
so imagine
first second that we're just have only one access to make things simple
things are propagating in the z direction here that
so how does this work so we have one t wave propagation
where we have the
acoustic wave equations that depends on this coefficients that are medium dependent easy
OK so you
is the unknown the particle displacement at time t and that's the
t in this equation is time and the is that
and so this equation is the wave equation which is telling you how particles get
displaced at time t
and that the
became an easy is the acoustic impedances what you wish to recover part of these
experiments because if you could recover this profile easy
then you would know as this is the corresponding to waters's corresponding to send sanitise
corresponding to of oil and so you would know that that that's
there is already a new start drilling prism
so the way seismologists probes the media
is to probe the
the the system by a wavelet what they call the wave which has nothing to
do with the way that people use in other fields the college wavelets f of
try to is the idea of making up his explosion of the surface
and so what this exit six the boundary condition which said that the derivative of
the field
along the z direction
at the surface z equals zero is whatever i put in which is way fifty
of course
this boathouse trailing some microphones that are going to collect
the article that is you use and this pressure wave and then there's an echo
that comes back
and the echo comes back because you have this discontinuity in the medium so it's
time the wave
which is the discontinuity a fraction of the way will come back
so what you collecting with microphones and trailing behind the trailing boat is essentially the
pressure with that comes back
all right
and so
what the reflection seismic grammar seismic traces recording is the surface particle velocity which mathematically
is the derivative of this function you with respect to time at the surface
and this is
object that we call going to call HST
OK so i excised the system was the big hammer i created my way fifty
i measure the the response
which we're going to call each of t and the problems that seismologists face is
to find the coefficients to differential equation given what you put in and what the
call you get
right so
the exciting thing you you hear the echo
and out of the article you're trying to fear
the coefficients of p
that makes sense
lots of fact animals which uses
for example the bat who is very poor as very for visual system
the ways about inferiors geometry nick cave is vice
meaning church then bounce off the walls
and then about processes information to reconstruct the geometry of
of the room
and about so good at it that it can also crosses the reflection due to
kind of tiny insect that it needs to eat while in flight
OK so this is a small it is it is something that is a bit
similar to what that
the proba system and out of it
by collecting the echo
the figure out what the earth is made up
alright so the way people approached this problem is
it's in very non-linear problem to actually determine the impedance from
this input data and output data
this is a canadian ice problem to make it much simpler
OK so
the thing is that we can assume that the impedance is a constant plus
a tiny perturbation and then we go through our method that is similar in applied
maths we're gonna linearized equations by expressing the velocity field you as the field which
would correspond to a fixed impedance equal to one plus the tiny perturbation which is
due to this perturbation alpha
so you know is the solution to the wave problem with the constant medium and
you one is a small perturbations
induced by
all fuzzy
and so we know as the problem and i think i'm going to skip
the details so you just write down the linearized equation you you drop all the
terms that are quadratic in the perturbation you only keep the first order terms and
at the end of the day
you give you get a new problem which asks you to find this perturbation alpha
fuzzy from the input data
the output data which is now
what the echo plus what you put in
and this problem has a very simple form
because it's actually
in isomap the distances are the shortest distance between two points in the graph so
that's sort of how they are related
but i'm short on time
i think we've seen how laplacian i can maps
is related which is not fitting the parameters the class
but the cool thing is
how locally linear embedding is related and this is the last thing i really wanna
spend a little time on
so the question needs to be constrained positive definite
that's not always easy to do with this is my favorite trick for constraining a matrix positive definite
just write in the form two
other mixes hear this is a low rank this is in my head but what
it could be is sparse and what we also can do is in order constraint
develop and we can force em transpose one to be zero
so this is just a way of constraining the any u model so that the question is positive definite
and once we've done there
we end up with this result the diagonal must equal the sum of the off-diagonals
now locally linear embeddings then specific case the maximum entropy unfolding with percival
you constrain the diagonal sums am i i to one
remember summer w was gonna receptor one instead allowing it very
hand you find the model parameters by maximizing the pseudo likelihood of the data not
the real likelihood that's typically a fast way fitting calcium random field in fact pseudolikelihood
originally proposed by people work in spatial statistics with fitting calcium random fields
the proof about
quickly sketched is that fry unit diagonals we have enemies i minus w that's the
form that you get in locally linear embedding
and the off-diagonal sparsity w matches end so you end up
without being true
which is true in early as well and says that you should look for the smallest igon
vectors of this guy
which is equal to atlassian
so that's exactly the same as what we suggest
the classical multidimensional scaling
and it's like i can i laplacian i can maps as well
the other portion is the pseudolikelihood approximation
and that's says that these
joint distribution is approximately equal to the product of the conditional distributions in the graph
so these are all the conditionals
now the true likelihood is proportional to the but it's got normalization which is the
in the gas in case the determinant of the covariance
and pseudolikelihood normalisation is ignored
this is the pseudo likelihood in this model
now if i if you cross out the and look at the logo this that's exactly the objective
locally linear embeddings
the new there is this term here
doesn't appear locally linear embeddings and that's the precision of each of these calcium fits
so locally linear embedding fits them with precision one
basically pre describes what should be hear back comes out of the mass as well
okay so
alleles approximation to maximum likelihood in this new model i show
i hands but i mean important point about allele
it is actually the sparsity pattern because the sparsity is done in w not in
the overall matrix you don't get the same neighborhood graph in the final graph laplacian
and in fact is entropy hard to work out what the sparsity pattern in w
should be
in order to get the desired sparsity pattern in al
which is kind of annoying
so you always end up with slightly different neighborhoods
so here's the
point which really illustrates
there's something funny was going on in early
which turned out to be the pseudo likelihood
so locally linear embedding is motivated by considering
locally linear embeddings the data but interestingly as we increase the neighborhood size k eh
ten minus one we can recover piece you eh
so if you're going from a local to a global linear embedding you would expect
a cover piece e eight because its optimal
but in lowell you don't
between compression artifacts right
so by the
the relative height of the speaker from this week you can learn about the relative
importance of body of course called that matter to baryonic matter
so there's a lot of you can learn from the detailed statistical properties of this
and so this is an animation
tools see for example how you can determine the geometry
so you have a standard ruler there and if the geometry of the universe is
flat it would appear to you
on the map and
given angle
but if the geometry is not flat
then c
it's possible to occur then this bot would appear to be good and if it's
negative because this spot would appear to small
so you go into the measurement and when it turns out that
sports are of the right side
the universe is flat
good so we started off from here
o point seven billion years ago or so
and we end up here how did you get from here to there
so to do that is the subject of the next class which
i have to go and the out
and so
we've seen this before
one concert they will need now
is that the
if you have a decelerated expansion which is what you have when you have a
universe that is dominated by martin remember
this class
dominated by matter
a acceleration equation a double that is negative
then there is an expand
and you can see it in this animation
so there is a dog
that sounds like polls which is represented by the green here and there is another
dog and the pattern that expands present the space that is expanding and this expansions
is decelerating
this function is decelerating you would see that at the beginning of animation the second
step outside of that called and by the end of the animation dating site that's
it could represent a eyes and right because it's fast any kind of information light
can travel and so what we have learned that in decelerating expansion the size of
the horizon
so you can get things that were outside your eyes and entering your right
we've seen this before and i'm not going to repeat sole
today we have an extremely successful cosmological model think about the friedmann equation we can
use a few parameters remember omega martyr automata body omega called that matter
the amount of curvature radiation
the cosmological constant this equation of state which if is the cosmological constant is minus
one if not to be something else and they have all around
so these few parameters
describe the background evolution the expansion history of the union
now we've added fluctuations so we may need a couple of more parameters to describe
also the prose statistical properties of those perturbations and that these two parameters were met
them before one is the primordial power spectrum which is mostly like a power law
and amplitude and aspect personal
with this parameters you go everywhere
the name of the game is to determine these parameters and for that to be
people are investing
billions of dollars in expenses
OK so you start off from here you want to end up with something like
that this is actually real data is the simulation
you just put this kind of initial conditions in computer you give the computer the
kind of composition of baryonic dark matter except except that and let it evolve under
gravity in the computer will tell you that statistically matter will be distributed in this
way and galaxies formed their x x
how the structure formation work and what we can we learn from it so let's
imagine did you start off
the morning where you have the surface of the sea the sea is very calm
there are only very tiny ripples on the surface of the sea
so this is your universe as you see in the cosmic rays back
you switch on gravity that is the wind picks up
and the the day goes on
and the fluctuation start growing
there growing start growing until they become so nonlinear to conserve them
the same kind of thing happened with cosmological perturbation you start off with small perturbation
you see them in the cosmic microwave background they grow on the gravity until they
become galaxies and planets except accepts and we want to write down the equations but
they are very similar equation for waves as
they are four perturbations cosmological perturbation observations
there is an impressive agreement between the data and this handful of parameters and physics
that is based on a couple of friends of equation that we
the basic colour
so this
the data and the theory and this again for cosmic background in this for the
class and property the power spectrum of the larger-scale structure this the data this is
a game theory
and the interesting thing here is because this is very new and hard to so
i'm going to mention is that this theory look i got some small we got
here and this is more we're going remind you a lot of this week
what do they come from this advanced topic but just because it's hard going to
tell you
so remember that they told you there is this dark matter distribution in the body
of the when they get released from the fort and they see another density of
dark matter in this world labour to fall into the because and i feel gravity
but if the body one-seventh of the amount of dark matter and matter must also
thing the same right that matter is sitting there and there is a little bit
is what does that mean what i just means that
on average
over all the possible function on average
independent of x i haven't i mean mean value of zero
and then you can sort of see that just by symmetry arguments as many functions
positive for some particular argument if they are negative
on average over this distribution functions
never going to be the new function is going to fail
all right so what about the grants function
again we just do the same thing
just plugin
what is the covariance of the covariance the definition of koreans expectations
the point x
minus its mean which is zero
the value at different points in time
and again at next prime and out
big promises in expectations or anything
plug that in
we get this
the interval of talking to me
we can pull these apart into three different
so here we can
well i expect prime they don't have to do with a and then we just
get the
the integral is where it which is the variance of a which alpha
get it over here
that means that this
the distribution over functions that we find out here
is aghast process with the mean function of zero and the covariance function which is
given by the i'm peter
this is a very complicated way of doing you know model
you can write them down process the
and two in front in the corresponding out
OK so this is this is a slightly more examples like that but two and
a more interesting example
so here's
it's more interesting
now let's consider
the function again
which is going to be
just a linear combination
a bunch of little girls in
so i have to find some girls involved the
a little beta minus the square between x and this variable
i over and
five little else in the next and have the coefficient here the coefficient is going
to be a random variable
the gamma i
i just
this debate according to the gulf distribution
have these little
the coefficient times these little girl from
now it's some up a bunch of these things and then i look at what
happened in the limit
where have an infinite number of
but that the centre of everywhere
don't worry
too much about them and maybe they could have done a little bit more serious
so let's look at what happens in the limit
well we have a limit of one over and times the
and some of the things that
i mean it turns into an interval
we have now
and now i right
gamma i here just the function here
gamma i gamma zero function of
you promised
and the
and gamma use are all independent
but the normal year one distribution
that means the gamma sigma here is
white noise
all the gamma completely independent of each other
OK and you have an infinite number of them
and they sit in front of these
gaston but they're all
on the corresponding value you
don't think of this is being sort of the limit the limiting behavior of
regression model where you have
a bunch of galveston but you see what happens when
i think you get more and more from the pond and and
and then we have to normalized by and you want to go and explode
this is this defined some distribution over functions and it's going to be a process
because the coefficient
i was trying to work out again the mean function
and the covariance function
two again to buy
just plugging in
the question here
but the
i mean function it station
overall the way that use
so you can pull the the that problem
indigo went into the thing here can you can separate the two intervals and the
last thing to go here
you know
just because of again
the mean function is zero
OK there is no great surprise by the
the coefficients that we multiply the thing with
as likely to be positive and negative one ever going to have
and then we can do the same thing for the covariance function
but again i have
i've written up here and the simple
the worry about exactly how to do it
but look at the results instead of that
i think actually on the tags
we had in the flickr dataset and this is the distribution that you get for
the social correlation coefficient out
and you see is its largest considerably larger something like the peak is around between
one and two
this this is the city
so there is definitely some element of social class social correlation if you have a
friend that using one tag
if any more likely to use the
in the question who distinguish
this element of social influence from other types of other types of social correlation
remember that we had a graph g
and we denote the set of nodes that are active at the end of the
observation by
now i want to somehow model but the model for non influence models
remember that there are two different types of
car caused by elements that influence one must lawfully which was basically the idea was
that the set w of active nodes are people first and then the graph g
comes from a distribution that depends on the this is like a pure form of
i confounding factors think that officially bought this graph g and also the w
are picked from distributions that depend on another and the value another of unobserved and
my vote which is denoted by x
so more generally we consider this correlation model that encapsulate for some of the day
we assume that this graph g
and the set w coming from a joint distribution
so they both can depend on each other in number of ways but important assumption
here is that
after we know which agents are likely to be active
the time at which they become active actually i escaped from some distribution
and zero and t
independent and i call
that's that's the main assumption everything basically the
that beauty the activation time for it in the
it's so now
that that actually gives an idea for testing
the influence like the point is that even though
an agent's probability of becoming active can depend on friends but the timing is that
it's not going to be
so the idea is that if you have two friends and if they are both
influenced by some outside factor
that causes them to become active
the probability that a becomes active before b
is the same as if he becomes active before
whereas if you have a social influence phenomena you expect this thing to essentially spread
throughout this is going to see the pattern
that's that's the intuition behind this is that trying to run
basically we are going to shuffle the time stamp of all actions
trying to keep everything the same essentially especially noting that if the social network is
going over find the area that you're observing it
we're going to try to keep everything the same so so that the number of
people to become active in this time of saying but you're shopping
and then after shuffle them going to estimate the social correlation coefficient alpha again
compared to the original one
and the idea is that if this if these two coefficients that you get a
not very different that's indicative of social influence not
the other way around if the if they are different social influence is the likely
factor but
obviously we can show
OK so and the other thing that i'm going to show some simulation results on
the edge of what is basically it's
it's from the obesity study the idea is that if you switch to direction of
if the model is coming only from the social correlation and not implies that should
not change the value of that you get the social correlation coefficient which
so now let me give you
because justifications for us what we can prove that if you actually looking at one
of these
models of correlation
that does not include influence
if the graph is large enough time shuffle test is going to allow the rule
out influences the likely factor in this model
the intuition is clear the point is that in the current model that defines
the time stamps or not
depend each other and therefore the distribution and again after shuffling is the same as
distribution that had initially the thing that's more challenging the goal is to prove concentration
the fact that we have the good ones that look this why this is same
as the original one
but the idea of the proof i'm not going to pull the idea is to
use martingale inequality in particular what quality to show that y and they are actually
and then all of these probabilities are all that
the shuffling of times
and then after we showed us the news that lamont dimension to show that the
maximum likelihood estimator continuous function as the result of should change very which
and the ticket actually the second part of
OK so let me
they're from the test on the number of randomly generated instances
and also you work for
all of the randomly generated inferences are based on the data from the flickr for
keeping the social network because constant and you regenerate their tagging data the action
according to one of these models the baseline models no correlation model basically to ignore
it and that's what we're generating the tagging events
according to the distribution of matter one of the facts but essentially the identities of
at random at the top the network
another model the influence model which is basically the same as the one that they
described in every time step each person contact with some probability
that's given by that function p of a and the variety of parameters is used
and finally we have the correlation models
which is the first american like this we can about
and the centre in this network in the social network
and let w be the union of balls of radius two around these centers
there is an effect to here is that
graph is actually very well connected so if you go further than two
each ball is going to be very large
and if you go below two it's going to be just one person and their
neighbours to tools into the right and notice that so this model essentially the set
w going to have exhibits some level of correlation because people are within this w
are much more likely to be friends
yes so have to repeat this w then after that you're making the
time stamps in the same way that the data based on model basically looking following
one of the tags on the radio later the pattern of growth of that tag
but the time that are picked independently
it ideas and grab sharks
two different so aggregate fluctuations
the result of the summation of individual fluctuations
of course
i don't know why we have this this this stuff you of course supposing that
it's for me is sufficiently small
so that each each firm accounts for one over and over the total
and sharks find violence
then the large number applies
just to give you an example
supposing that he has four hundred fifty sector of which is basically the number of
sectors the four-digit level for the united states and its sector is characterized by volatility
of terms of standard deviation
six percent
then we should end up with the volatility is equal to the point fifteen percent
which is why
order of magnitude lower than what we observe in real data for the activity to
while these
it is precisely the the average
of the value for the four hundred sixty six
OK so this problem
possible answers given by by a
i bet
you also want to appeal to possible answer is given by kebab
just slow down their applications the
of the rule number by assuming that firms are followed distributed
but even the firms are not power law distributed we can have an aggregate volatility
in line with what we observe a real that if shocks are relatively stable distributed
with infinite variance
why because by the property of under convolution we have this result
very briefly this means
that as soon as and the number of firms so the number of sectors affected
by IID sharks levy stable distributed with infinite variance increases
aggregate fluctuations decays with them
at this rate
this rate which is much lower than than the then the rate for the standalone
so it it's it's not
necessary to introduce the assumption that from power law distributed in terms of size
we can have a really competitive market
which firms accounting for a negligible amount of the total but it suffices that they
are affected by latest stable distributed shocks to the opportunity to have fluctuations which are
in line with what we observe real
this is the main results
another possible application
tell me when i'm going out of time
well how much
ten minutes
OK maybe fifteen minutes for for
and here another possible example
of application i'm going to go
very very quick about this is about diversification diversification is of course quite well known
you know it's not better to put all your eggs in the same on back
basically k
what's what's the problem suppose that we are measuring the value of the portfolio on
the occasion and these are the number of tasks in the portfolio
understand the assumptions
densification works
so as we increase the number of items in inside our portfolio the value of
the portfolio tend to increases which means that the risk of the total for you
was that
if we are
that's a
we are able to to to diversify our risk based
but this is not true
is characterized by stable distributions with alpha
lower than one
it has been shown
well this was this picture has been taken by a paper by ibragimov jaffe and
just published journal of financial economics but these results can be found even in some
papers by different
well what happens
is that
this is the case for the levy distribution which means that all physical two
o point five
as increase
the number of assets
inside your portfolio
the total risk
instead of the decreasing
it's better not to do this for
as soon as risks of distributed in this way
in this case is four alpha equal to one that is for the cushy distribution
in this case is to it's interesting to note that supposing that this is the
number of people who
i want to buy insurance and insurance firm work so can make profits just because
they are collecting customers
so the higher the number of customers the best batters the degree of densification standard
assumption but the problem is that if you are in this range
you have a sort of coordination failure because as soon as the number of people
who want to ensure that sound is higher than seventy they insurance markets works
as long as the number of people is lower the seventeenth century markets doesn't work
OK so the number of people who want to buy insurance council what
and in this case but the main idea is that as soon as we want
to study
diversification we must estimate
the alpha of the stable distribution because if we are in presence of shots which
are distributed with an awful lot diversification theory doesn't work
this is the result in finance is possible to apply another in other fields as
well according to mean but not only to me
there's an idea
which has been propagated by a guy who is called robert shaw
and the idea of ursula is that why why why we are not using fire
financial markets to to provide well-being to people