the second sentence syria accused the united states on monday of carrying out a terrorist
aggression after a deadly raid near its border
with iraq which it said killed eight civilians so this was a sentence provides different
there's another sentence and you can see that there are
really more or less the same thing so they all formula that same killing
that many people that they called a terrorist aggression
so there's a lot of
sentences that's why we ended up would end up in one cluster so take several
seconds including one summary doesn't make sense because you would get rid of you repeat
this information is
no human would do if he or she were to summarise
the documents
but on the other hand you see that the
there are differences between them because they were coming from different sources which have different
information that possession so this is a certain words are
you need to
singles and the weights would have like this see which of come out or the
foreign minister
condemned those students
the president of what they have
and what you can also notice that you even if you decide which that there
are certain phrases words that you really don't need summary given that you want to
have something short
you can read it
ignore all get
white out set
parts they it said right before
where you got the information so given that you want to given the space is
limited you want to make sense short
what it means is that extractive summaries
then a human because and
some of the problems associated with extract with expected approaches to
they can bring pronounced which you don't know
and they that there a so-called
discourse connectives however then
would be impossible to interpret
once the context is no longer there so that the sentence beginning with however
if you put it in your summary this however just confused
so the question is whether anything can be done really
those problems from problems longer sentences similar sentences without
two abstractive association so
just to reiterate we have a problem
problem we want to do what we want to do in fact is to understand
documents generated summary this is that we cannot do not feel it's difficult many resources
but so the question is whether we can do is to modify the sentence is
not take a single units changed their structures
and there
tasks related to the first is also pressure and the second one is called suspension
so first expression would explain what is about
so it's summarisation on the sentence level
so for example we have sentence a slightly a leadership congratulates itself on a virtually
unprecedented exhibition of unity and moderation they should be aware that knives are being sharpened
at conservative central office to some seventy
news articles
so what you want to get the it's perhaps the shortest as labour regenerate itself
on unity mitford things happened at conservative central office
so basically the same thing
some words have been removed the g the sense of what the sentence is really
about is still there but this sentence is much
so there is the
and the world of course
you can also think that
so look totally different then to paraphrase but
both approaches they only part word
or phrase phrases
so i said one sentence pressure and used for a
personalization and other techniques
charles very interesting is called institution so it's about using information from different sentences in
a single one so for example here you have one to three four sentences
well first it's basically summarises what they all have articles
the US's highest court ruled by
forty five that there was gun ownership in chicago was unconstitutional
so what it means that which ruled out which prohibited two
use counts
the other three sentences they're about the same thing but a bit longer and provide
different information so even those four sentences with you
i would like to generate
is i showed us like this is important for us to spend that much in
the sentence can be longer than for example that happened monday or that they were
disbanding was twenty eight years old or that words
it that exist in chicago
and so on and so on
so what my point here is that
and so usually have similar sentences and then you
aggregate them together in a single one
and this is not valid
just by combining words or to syntactic structure
so but now the question
so the first identify which percent so can find out
which information is important and the second question is how to make sure we get
to the grammatical sentence
so for the first question even that have similar sentences that they overlap content and
you know that they come from different sources you can use the heuristic
if all
see all those images
agencies music
it's almost put
this information distance
for example about this that the the word than the phrase
then on issues that
it must be important for in this context right so the information is is repeated
in different sources that support information
on the other hand you can also look syntactic structures and
start the intuition that subject direct object are important in the main clause
more important than religion or non-religious and so is on the one hand this information
petitions and
look at the
syntactic structures and first
now after the second question
how can we guarantee that get something dramatic
you can use the language model so human language models gives you the ability of
given the background calls
so if you knew it something that has almost zero probability with respect to your
means that it's unlikely that this sentence is grammatical readable
but they also syntactic rules syntactic information to the user so for example english every
sentence every clause has to the subject
so this means that if you actually read something that doesn't the subject things
sean carroll
and now
so just the different
for which i will
use the data for example to use google news
so imagine the following
this method is to use compression it is that you can present not a single
standard separated and you do by finding
try to correct
this is a bit
probably unusual for machine learning
the planets
on the second we have joint
courses in artificial intelligence which feature of machine learning in logic
a very basic introduction to logic
machine learning
and mark this for would you
a basic introduction to to machine learning logic
but if you can
and yet hopefully will understand
the materials and artificial intelligence in the second
basically what i expect you to understand is just basic
understanding the concept of syntax
logic semantics
and maybe
at the least to parse logic form lecture
i will do some truth just to give you a flavour of what
all this proved methods working logic
and i expect to understand
and this
who have some background
this week
so as you get
get anywhere in undergraduate computer science
in have
so we have
everybody from computer science
i guess said the minimum you should be able to pass logic formula lecture
OK so why
this led to use computer science
so logic started as
and activity which formalized human reasoning
of the philosophers would disagree but taking an more
the pragmatic
you like
you know
here's i'm concerned with
it's important to
acknowledge that not every form of reasoning
the even precise model
for example human common sense
comes constant or maybe not but
it's difficult to
give precise model to common sense and actually to come up with a computer program
that can
like human even ten years old chart for example
we will be looking at very specific models reasoning
which has a precise mathematical
this is an overview of some users of logic in computer science
the very basic level you
logic gates
which are the fundamental ingredients
chips processors and everything
and also
now since computer
computer science is really an artifact of human mind
and you know to discover flaws in hardware and software you have to
we look into the underlying process of human thought this
right so
logic is unsurprisingly used in
it's hardware and software verification so the famous telebox
example that was discovered by
while doing so
floating point arithmetic was because there was some error in the lookup table in certain
and in tallinn and the for example has since put a huge amount
resources into
formerly very fine with cheap or process correct
software that makes it a bit difficult because unlike
hardware is it has
finite state
the logic is predictable
software you know the the complexity of stories so huge
it depends on the correctness of the compiler
correctness of
programming language semantics
more that the problem is
when he was using was trying
the program specifications depends on a lot of factors and
generally it is intractable
but still people can focus on a specific subset of
software like microkernel which has run rather a simple and predictive
for example one project and it is
this verification of
l four microkernel it's microkernel for real-time systems
another to topics is this
high high-level programming language
so there is this thing called logic programme which was very popular back in nineteen
the idea is that
just how computer what you want and computers was to figure out what you want
and of course
we were going very well
so but still it has a huge influence on
artificial intelligence
so the idea of many ideas from logic programming fine grained
and in a second we'll see more about aspects
OK i
use of logic in a such as planning
scheduling diagnosis
and also models of agents martin my multi
this is the overview of the three lectures
i'll start with what is usually called propositional logic
covering the syntax semantics and some basic notions such models
within models satisfiability binary decision diagrams
and then the second lecture on cover first order logic
this is the lighting which can
form statements about quantification over
so only
and the last well
the technology that this is logic the reason about
different modes of truth
and the thing
of all these three logics propositional logic is
probably the most natural in terms of its application in
large scale industrial verification
so probably got lengthy of propositional logic
now what's propositional logic
basically concerned with propositions
propositional statement can
it can either be true or false
well so interested in studying composition
the truth of this
memory whether RAM memory or disk memory
so there are other resources that we may care about
OK but predominantly we focus on performance
OK so
this is of a course about performance i like to put things in perspective a
little bit by starting out and asking
in programming what's more
and performance appearing in engineering situation and writing code
i writing software
what's more important than performance
correctness good
what else
simplicity can be
very good
OK often much more important than performance
cost OK we and what type cost thinking
no but i mean it will cost of one
we're talking software right
so whatever the cost you have in mind
OK so so then you're sort of
OK there are some costs are involved in programming like
programmer time
the programmer times noting also that might be
stability came robustness of the software
OK doesn't break all the time
what else
good engine engineers here
a lot of things
what features
features can be more important
having a wider collection of features in your competitors functionality
OK is designed in a way where you can make changes in local part of
the code and it doesn't have to make changes across the code in order to
effect a simple change in the functionality
OK there one big one which is definitely especially in the nineties was like the
big thing computers
the big thing
o security actually good cunningham that down securities x one OK
that's actually been more in the two thousand OK security has been in for more
important performance
scalability has been important although scalability in some senses is performance-related but yes scalability is
so what was the big breakthrough in the and why do people use mackintosh's rather
then windows those people who were of that religion
user friendliness
wow if you look at the number of cycles of computers that went into user
friendliness in the nineties it grew from almost nothing to where it is now
the vast part of the computation goes into user-friendly so all those things are more
important than performance
so this is a course on
OK so then you can say OK well so why do we bother
then why study
OK if it's at the bottom of the heap
almost always people would rather have these other things
then performance
you go up and you say it to rather performance more user friendly more user
friendliness is almost always
you know more important than performance why do we care
that wasn't user prices sometimes performance is correlated with user friendliness
OK you know nothing is more frustrating sitting there waiting right
OK so that's that's a good reason what some other reasons why we
sometimes a real time constraints so they don't actually work unless they performed
party x well i we don't measuring user we don't usually quantifies the friendliness from
not sure that's what i understand what you're saying so we don't get he says
get don't get exponential
performance improvements in user friendliness we often don't get better performance either by the way
sometimes we do but
that's good
so there are several reasons that i think are important one is that off and
measures the line between the feasible and the invisible
OK so we heard some of these things for example in real time
when the real time requirements if it's not fast enough is simply not function
or if it uses too much memory is simply not going to work for you
and as a consequence what you find is algorithms are on the cutting edge of
if you're talking about just three implementing stuff that people did
ten years ago
performance isn't that important at some level
but you're talking about doing stuff that nobody has done before
one of the reasons often that they haven't done it is because it's too time-consuming
it's too
know things don't scale and so forth
so that's one reason OK
is this feasible verses invisible
now the thing is that algorithms give you an eight language for talking about program
OK and that turns out to be is language that is
and pervasive through computer science is that the theoretical language is what gets adopted by
the practitioners
because it's clean way of thinking about things
i think it's a good way i think about performance and the reason it's on
the bottom of the heap
it's sort of like
performances like
y currency
OK so you say
what good is the stack of hundred dollar bills do for you OK when she
rather have
or water or shelter or whatever you're willing to pay those hundred dollar
bills for
the hundred dollar bills
four for that
OK even though water is far more important to you're living
well similarly performances what you use to pay for user friendliness
what you pay for security and you hear people say
for example
that you know i want greater functionality so people program in job
even though it's much slower than c
because it has
and they say it cost me maybe factor three or something in performance to program
in java but it's but job is worth it because it's got all these object
around the number of time steps
and then you get to the door
or you fail to you failed
and then you could make the decision
right so it's just it allows this flexibility
so so markov decision processes basically recover all you can do all the things that
you do for options with markov decision processes that the distinction between san markov decision
processes mdps options is that we have what we have
we have the ability to
be executing an option for all to be able to look inside the option and
no would be doing at lower level and that has certain advantages that the options
OK so only do
so i would took like to quick things in the album one mu one two
you can define you can define own actions which includes these behaviours
call that capital o and you can find the optimal value functions with respect to
the start of sub s and beast accused are several that's come out
by the way if you have a little a you can now little only for
these options and all the value function like things that we talked about before they
can be can be can be recovered but let me give you some more insight
about that how can they would go his recovery
the award and the transition probabilities the order of primitive action is the number you
get when you take an action and the transition probabilities of the transitions probabilities the
one time step the action takes of the distribution of next it's how do we
define these beasts these quantities for
an option to do that
everything else will be will work so here's the idea
the reward for adoption
it's just the expected reward expected sum of discounted what you get
when you
start adoption until termination
that's it
the reward for a certain number
in this state if you start option what's the expected reward expect again until
the behavior for that option terminates
the more tricky part is the transition probability that's actually not
all you do
it's simply asked
what is the expected
the probability of terminating impossible states
that's not
just as simple as that because you think discounting into account so is discounted
probably because you know if you if you don't stage five in two steps that
in different
that stage five in ten steps to building
discounted probability so the way these these transition probabilities that no longer sum to one
because the discount factor is taken into account but that's the just expected
discounted probabilities often terminating in different states
and with these definitions you can write down the bellman optimality equations you can move
it and you can do
the evaluation of two value iteration and q learning or whatever it is everything everything
just works
all the matches for the future
so the very simple idea
we were able to recover now
the flexibility we are planning
or think
different timescales because these options could be in many different timescales like some strict hierarchical
notion you have some options small in duration some of longer duration all that one
everything works
we have the representation
before being able to
capture the ability to plan learn with flexible timescale
because the hard part is
what should these options b
and there's a lot of work on trying to figure out
you know where the options come from
how do we use experience in the world to learn option not think of options
the skills
we go about the world these accumulate skills we don't open the door we now
to build some notable tables
so some of us have the skill of you know powerpoint come shame but so
we have the skills
we we can we can now
plan to learn in terms of these skills and and so it is obvious what
talked about how often might come from
doors of bottlenecks you can think of bottlenecks more generally seem may have
you may build options to its bottlenecks
reuse skills that
possible policies that we used over and over again might be useful to encapsulate form
of scale are often people played with these sort of ideas
is that there is enough to show that learning options but there are
simple things that have been explored in terms of learning in terms of learning options
was going to try to give you a sense if we are able to
ways of behaving at
flexible levels of
abstract temporal abstraction
and and planning and learning which is to say now everything things works beautifully
questions about that
i'm going to skip all this in the
then you have many many results become available so
here is a i give you one flavor of results
so here is you know continuous two-dimensional domain
is it possible landmarks
you might have options that take us to landmarks in some local neighbourhood that landmarks
so each so the local neighbourhood centre landmark and you might know
how to get to the landmarks in the neighborhood and then you can begin planning
with these you plan to go from
maybe from landmark to landmark
as a way of navigating
and can do much more faster planning this way that if you are planned
low-level continues
continues behaviours of course
you could do something smart and that you could realise
this is called this is sort of simple result we have that says basically you
could show one landmark
head to head towards the other land which is the red line
but as soon as you reach
a location in which you if you start again you will switch to a different
landmarks you can switch
it turns out so you can terminate options early
and we obtain
benefits of planning so early termination of options is an easy
very easy
i think it falls out of planning that can obtain a grade
OK i'm going to start with this you can buy the learning options
here's a little thing else
again just don't you find interesting you find all kinds of literature on this so
how do we learn models of options the reward and transition probabilities
if we could only learn about options to actually executed would be dead
right because you can only behave
what's what's that
ten rules OK so it's
the animals
peter pick there
and i noticed that let's say that before the reform arises on the left-hand side
it's all sorts
all the ten levels
and another
positive than the also that's minimum levels
and this time it's a negative
roughly twenty eight years
negative twenty
so what i'm getting into the occurrence
i have a negative and negative and for part of the positive and negative twenty
that adds up to to zero but more interestingly i can show the same thing
calling this current measuring probe
directly across that node
and notice that
the net current
that is entering into this note here is zero
OK so that's just show you that KCL does indeed hold in practice and it
is not just a figment of our imagination
so long
before i go on
i wanted to
o point one other thing out
notice that i've written down to assumptions of the lumped matter discipline
there is no assumption of the lumped matter discipline
and that assumption
in spirit at least shared by
the point must simplification in physics as well
and someone to function as
something which i did not mention
but you can
reading your notes in section in
section eight point two
in the appendix
what is the assumption that is shared in spirit
with the point mass simplification
the assumption we made here
is that in almost all the signals that we can study in this course
he made this assumption that
the signal speeds of interest transition speeds and so on are much slower than the
speed of light
OK that's my signal transitions speeds of interest are much slower than the speed of
remember the laws of motion the discrete laws of motion breakdown if you begin approach
if you objects begin moving at the speed of light
again the same token here are lumped circuit abstraction breaks down if we approach the
speed of light
and the following courses that talk about waveguides another distributed analysis techniques that deal with
our signals that travel at speed close to be like
so i think that that we go on to
talking about method one of circuit analysis this is called the basic
kvl KCL method
so just based on those to some simple algebraic relations i can analyse very interesting
and complicated circuits
the method goals as
so that's our goal
is given a circuit like this
our goal is to solve it
in this course we will be doing all kinds of things analysis and and synthesis
analysis says given a circuit
OK what can you tell me about this
OK so this sort of existing circuits for all the voltages and currents voltages across
elements and current through those elements
since says given a function
i mean i ask you to go and look OK so for analysis here
we can apply this method that i want to show you
and the idea here is that
given a circuit like this that has figured out all the voltages and currents that
are that a function of the way these elements are connected
the basic KVL and KCL method has the following steps
the first step is to write down
the element v i relationships
right down the element v i relationships all the elements
the second step is to write KCL
for all the nodes
and the third step is to write KVL for
all the nodes in the circuit that's it
go ahead and i don't mind rules KVL and KCL and then go ahead and
OK so what do we do an example of course
but just to just around as a refresher
we've looked at a bunch of elements so far
and for phototransistor
the element relation says that is
i are
there are the resistance of the
element here
four able to source
the is equal to
not that's the element relationships and for current source
the element is the solution is i is simply the current flowing through the element
OK so
these are some of the simple element rules for
the device is that the current source with the source and the resistance
let's go ahead and solve
so the simple circuit
and what do is go ahead and solve the circuit for OK for talk page
five of your notes
i'm going to go ahead and
edit this circuit here
you can scribble the values on
on the notes on page five
so the first
so yesterday i show i presented you that the directed graphical models
which are diagrams representing probability distribution over a set of random variables
graphical models provide
the u
on how to decompose the joint probability
the product of factors
each depending on your on a subset of variables say remember
this equation was where
we have to pretty as
over the conditional probability of the nodes even their parents
and i show also yesterday talk about how graphical mothers display
the conditional independence of nodes
i will try to
given the intuition of why this decomposition can be
can be interested
four four questions of inference and learning
is that
OK for let's go into inference
let's begin with this example that you know hate missing
when i was looking for critics that's why i
it's the realise that there was a very obvious
solution really easy
so you're going to hate it and
even more
so as you remember
we have over four random variables
is it love you're not has training not
this has been going on or not graphs what
we can decompose the joint probability
going from the top
the but
so what
the for those who here the question was given this graphical model
and that i give you some of the
some probability is related to the
the things
what called compute the conditional probability
the of
i mean of this was but the more not interesting to do is so base
and then taking
at the time probability of
wet grass and the spring on
and marginalizing it over the two of those variables
then you obtain the joint
you have a decomposition of the joint distribution
which is this one
which is which gives us exactly what we know
it's not it's not something strange because
the probabilities i have access to the shape of the graph
are are related
because this is the causality graph and what they measure usually comes from causes
so let's think about this so you you saw yesterday playing with these properties that
it was difficult to infer
it was messy you don't know from which place you have to begin you're you're
taking this principle way of saying OK i have my graph i try to find
again the joint because the know how to decompose it
plus if you see here when i'm doing this summation in fact
for example in here
i have two sons one over here and one overseas and in fact p of
these two first there
p of c and p of
s one s because when given c don't depend on are so in fact that
will be able to
to factorize them from there
the sum
of our making them so i will not have to sum over all the terms
over are entirely
two last terms that are going to be some
these are again
that that's that's too
i'm going to talk more about that but that's how
most algorithms we we're going to work on to some simplified inference
it's going to be true to intervene into these programs
we have seen with a simple model which is the
make a first order markov model
which looks like this
we denote english in the chain
and the errors of the same
the direction
so let's let q
from one to n these sequence
so be random vector representing representing a sequence of states
in the first order markov model
and each of my
of my
each of my vote variables can take
OK very useful almost i have case
the first order markov assumption which is the same what
what i see here in the graph is that the probability of one moment in
the sequence given
what was the previous all the previous
element in the sequence it's only
can be can be simplified to the
the probability of this element in the sequence and the just the previous one
so using that or using the
the graphical model
we know that the joint likelihood of the sequence
it can be the right in the past as in
in the cell
in mean because i have to have the probability of prior probability on the states
for the first element in the sequence
and then the product of these probabilities
six people
no because
you're right
should go from
because here it would be
and here to get right
let's not so we have this model and and now let's assume that we are
interested in the marginal probability
of one element from MSP nice sequence so what's the probability that of being in
one particular state at the given point in a sequence
taking the joint distribution we have two
to marginalize over
all the elements of my sequence
to know what's what's the probability of
of this particular element so
you seem to some that goes
i have
two minus one some then
n minus the
his other sons so that i have done some over over two but a sum
over all the others element in the sequence
bill and zoubin and carl what about a infinite hidden markov model where the number
of states
is infinite
and that and it turned out that a problem that is that
we have the transition probability coming out from each state is going to be a
distribution over infinite number of states
so this is the transition probability from this states two
each of the possible states is infinite
if you if we simply try to
do a it's if we simply start off with the bayesian by the hidden markov
model and place the dirichlet prior on the transition probabilities and try to take that
infinity we get exactly the same problems as we have in the topic modeling case
where the probably the set of states
for which
out of
out of each state
we have a set of states that have high probability of transitioning into
right and four different states
four different previous states we have a different set of probabilities and this probably a
different set of next possible next states and this sets don't overlap at all
if you just take the infinite limit and so again we have to place a
use the hierarchical dirichlet process to solve the problem basically that forces sharing of next
across the different states
and the models come given by this
i want to go into detail actually
in the last five minutes i'll tell you about the last
pittman yor processes
right so
it's basically a
somebody is asking about how
we can
the chinese restaurant process two
so in the chinese restaurant process that i just described the number of clusters grows
as long of and
the number of tables causes long the number of customers and somebody is asking whether
we can generalize this to a different functional dependence between the number of tables and
the number of customers
and this is a particular generalisation of the chinese restaurant process
so the first customer comes in will against it at the first table
subsequent customer so customer and
will sit at table k
with the following probability so
it was the custom and was set to book a with probability and k minus
over n minus one plus alpha
OK where nk is is going to be
it is the number of customers there is currently sitting at table k
but is another parameter which is between zero and one
and l fives are usual concentration parameter
and the
customer will sit at a new table with probability alpha plus b that big k
over and one class of
so there
became number of tables right so
if at some point in a chinese restaurant process we have something
like this one
and customer for comes in and decides to
and this has to decide whether to sit here and see here on the table
so the probability that customers for is going to stay here is going to be
the number of
customers are really sitting there has two
minus beta
divided by something probability that customer forwards it here
is one minus the data divided something
and the probability that customer force consider new table is going to be
how far past to be so this who here so we subtract bit here is
supposed to be here and working at the mass into here
so that's the two parameter generalisation of the chinese restaurant process and it also has
a rich gets richer property rights so if this table really has lots of customers
then there will be a chance that new customers coming in will sit at that
table is also going to be much
but it also has a different property which is that
if we see lots of tables already in if
if there have been lots of tables
that's used in the restaurant
there were in each table working sub a bit beta and we're going to the
probability that the new customer was it yet another new table is going to be
large two
because this kid has been ten will be quite large
he cannot produce this is interesting
the poll also behavior
so we can show that this thing is also if an infinitely exchangeable
and so we can apply different there again and say that OK there is a
random probability measure
there is a random probability measure that underlies this generalization and this is what's called
pitman yor processes
it also a stick breaking construction we show one more about
is given here if you're interested
can i want to see show you
this type here
this is the diagram for the dirichlet process and chinese social process
over here we have customers on the x axis and tables on the y axis
the point here
it is simply
the customers sitting at that
a particular table
and as the number of customers grows the number of tables also growth
get it grows pretty slowly is a lot of and
so this thing is logarithmic
in the case of the pitman yor process
the number of tables grows but at a much faster rate
so we can show that the number of tables grows and
on the order of alpha times and to the better
but that's all parameter between zero and one
and if you look at the
the distribution over the sizes of tables it looks like a power law so if
this is on a log log plot and it looks like basically a straight line
well in the case of the dirichlet process it doesn't illustrate the
o and with kind
and application of the pitman yor processes to language modeling so
the nice thing with pitman yor processes that it produces this
distributions with power laws of statistics
and one of the key
one of the domains for which we see lots of power law behavior is is
in languages in languages we have a few
words that we see all the time
what's like the and and i n you and so on
and we see we'll but also we have lots of words which we see that
really rally
i draw your attention
on these kind of
of approach for solving multiclass SVM
you want to find an and if you if you have classes you want to
find m w one
and you want to solve these communication problem
when you have a slack variable for each training point
and again the full you get in there is something you get the k k
you get
and you can get for the one that is so
all in this way computing there are lots of other issues and function
go back
binary SVM for
with the soft margin
i think is shown OK
i want to
you mention on the on another thing
before going OK so this is a
our optimisation problem
and another thing
that also nello briefly said this morning is that when you have an optimisation problem
you can
the on the
on the objective function and on the constraint
you know oporto in mind
for example we had the right
optimisation problem
you know and i will be
and the like
a general rule from
for the signing classifier you try to be a bit more clear
you can decide any and we try to classify by simply choosing a loss function
so that measures the head on the training data and the regularisation them
for example the four d so for the soft margin SVM
the loss function is the loss
losses these inspiration
imagine that you like in the expression on the hinge loss on the formula of
and the regularisation term the
no this i
of the of w
you you go back into our optimisation problems
but it can also the same is true if we put the square loss
and will
we get without having the division among us and this question norm i
of the
problem that i show this morning for fisher discriminant analysis
in general you can have a bunch of loss functions that are all operated bound
on the true loss that is zero if you have no error on the training
data one if you have one
and so the into losses the
los used by SVM
the square loss is the loss by fisher discriminant analysis but the men like columns
and depending on the loss you can sign your classifier
what sort
choosing a loss and changing the regularisation
you can do this and also
interesting article
i'll introduce
the cannot
maybe you
i got because we can
we we talk about model so when the w is apparent when is some nice
so when we
can use of margin SVM
but what about if we have
really nice there what about very problem
the major breakthrough will support vector machine which that
they have been proposed the simple algorithm that is able to deal with you in
a very easy manner with with the nonseparable
we do not so the idea of support vector machines to map the data into
another dimension of the feature space
when the training set is separable
you can see from the beach
what do i need
our marketing function phi
and we everything going to fight
i think having fishing mapping yourself expensive since five is usually very high dimensional we
want to solve the optimisation problem without explicitly mapping the that year to phi other
we do that we split problem and we compute the function that is the dog
the product of the five and it is called the
i want to say before going
for a specific into the topic of the can that can only possible way
to deal with nonlinearities
a bunch of algorithms from much learning to deal with nonlinearity with stockings so using
cascade of classifiers
i would say it was the match these but perhaps a multilayer perceptron the first
of backing but also very problematic is boosting when you combine
a lot of weak learners so a lot of very simple classifier
to get a complex issues and function
it features some of the state what i mean you go you combine a lot
a simple linear classifier to get to
separation of
so let's and that any more
kernel method
so they do have a problem of support vector machine when we have introduced the
he is this one
you know microsoft and and and amazon google
i've done that yahoo and we had to build the data group
i've got a bigger scale on how to do build yeah research
where we actually convinced a whole bunch of people to leave university careers
join a newly-formed lab
and it was really based on the scope of the vision
the ability to do stuff that you couldn't do anywhere else
and you know every start-up will have a unique
you know nish something that focused on where you know you can do that the company
and what you want do is really attract people who resonate with that so
i think passion and excitement or and the big vision or are very very big in attracting people
ok so let's move on we've got another audience question and can directs fun
to sama equals or you are involved in start-ups on opposite sides of the world's
and in both west middle-east
so the question is
how much does the location of the on stop mass
excellent question
so i would argue
for data mining or
or even big data company
doesn't matter
and here's what
it's the
maybe the norm is that your you want to be aware that talent is and all that kind of stuff
i'm i'm going to share something with you i mean i've been out of young now long
enough that i can share something internal with you
my in my last yeah
i think i made a lot of enemies
as as an chief officer
i came up with a with a rule
i had
a pretty large you know to pre big groups
reporting to me
he said actually
no one could higher
any engineer
in the bay area
without my approval as as vp an officer of the company
and people complain
and people made noises and all of that and the reason for that is just silicon
is a hotbed silicon valley is all the talent is whether all excitement is
but my my ultimate judgment was
you know overinflated titles
overinflated salaries
talent claims
no ability to retain whatsoever
so you know we went to a very strange places
and rightly went to acquire the whole company
urbana-champaign illinois to get talent
when i did my own startups
i had teams in places like chile
syria when it was ok to do that
you know you can find talent
if you train them you can retain
retention has a lot of value and and deep training you know at some point
in the was this place to do it you know now india's almost like silicon valley
or at least bangalore is
so so locations
you know matters from the sense so you know watching your costs and and and being able to
retain people
as opposed to going to the hot spots
that's data mining right
it's a completely different discussion it comes to marketing where you have to have your sales people
and all of that that's that's different you know design sales marketing is a different ballgame
but he was talking about the money
so that's i like to move on because i really like the question that just bubble up
to the top here
is it
still worth pursuing a phd as a
as as data scientists yeah or yeah yeah so one of the things that are to have
been advising these are for more than twenty years
at a certain point to everyone my students can take them aside
and try to persuade them that they should not get a phd
it's it's a major investment of time
as you very narrowly focused
what's the point you could be out there
having these ventures making a lot of money and it's only solve students who have graduated have kind
of past like blood and
decided to stay so why one reason is if you want to be professor
that's one of the things you still the phd uncertain companies it gives you access
certain kinds of problems
but often it does not make sense to get a pc i'll just give you one quick example
i had a student they work with
incredibly incredibly talented hacker
deep understanding of the data science the the math statistics
just not a great researcher
and i said to
go so you do what you're good at
and he for his own personal reasons insisted on getting a phd
we decided to work together he went actually a phd robotics
got his phd and anyone to google
anyone to google about three or four years later that would otherwise
and that was several million dollars
so basically if the burden of proof i guess that's that's where put concisely
if you want to get a phd
the burden of proof is on year
it's not like you know
god decreed you should have a phd if you're smart
why should you get a phd
and i know foster you probably shouldn't as professor but ok
yeah so i'm not professor
i play one on tv
what i would say my advice i think is not going to be very popular with with
academia but i think in the long term it's in the benefit of academia
i think if you just finished
your masters
and you're thinking of doing a phd especially in the field then
my strong advice is
don't do it
go get a job go get a job for five years
and then come back
if you really want to do a phd because here's what happens
you have no idea
of what the real problems are about
right to me you know
it you said that have ideas are below average
i think
eighty to ninety percent
of thesis topics
are totally useless
right ok this is not because the people some because the people are bad
because they don't know better right
they they just didn't see what's happening to understand what the problems are i actually think
if people work for five to ten years and then have it in them
passion wise to go to a phd they would do better research
professors will get better papers
and the weights selection basically measures how close
the different pieces of the different images are in terms of how sharper blurry
so what it does it ends of submit managing to combine the sharpest parts of
all these images together to give you this result
it seems the research from that's right
OK so here
let me go back now to the matrix formulation and talk about the mathematics a
little bit more
so now let's take this formulation that we had which was this linear combination of
of all the pixels and also let me remind you even though this is a
linear combination these weights w are actually a function of the data
so this is not really a linear filter but it just sort of looks that
OK so now if i take all of these weight functions and i stack them
into a matrix
i can write the whole image he had the whole reconstructed image he had
as a function of the input noisy image y
with a matrix w and this matrix w is going to be generally
data dependent
OK so from this point on i'm going to be working with this equations he
had equals w times y and what i want to do is talk about the
properties of this matrix w
so let's
discussed this w is very special matrix this is just a reminder of what each
of this
matrix w does
one way we can rewrite this in matrix form with to write WSD inverse k
where k
is the matrix k i j
and the inverse is the diagonal matrix which has the normalization factors
simply along its tag
so this is just a shorthand way of writing the whole thing all at once
now i can factor this the inverse k
by breaking up the inverse in two d the minus one half the is minus
one half and then putting an idea factory the identity into the the myself to
the one half
and writing this w in this fashion
now it turns out that the state of one minus one side one have is
positive definite and because k is positive definite and this is just the product of
that on the left and right with
positive definite diagonal matrices then both l
and in the one minus one has to do the one half of positive definite
so it turns out w is in fact a positive definite matrix as well
but w is positive definite but it is not symmetric
OK this is a little bit
sort of
unexpected in the sense so is positive definite because it inherits the property from k
but if you simply look at this equation here
you can see that k is symmetric positive definite
but because it gets multiplied on the left by the inverse w can be symmetric
but it still is positive definite because of the second position so that's kind of
interesting it turns out that even though w is not symmetric it is very close
to being symmetric and i'll make the precise very shortly
it turns out approximating it with the symmetric matrix has a lot of benefits as
we will see
OK so let me discuss the future of the other properties of the matrix w
we said is positive definite it it's also row stochastic which means that the sum
of each of its rows equals one
so for matrices like this is a whole theory the current frobenius theory for positive
stochastic matrices is one of the properties that its spectral radius is one so the
top igon value is one and it also turns out to be an on repeated
i can use is unique
and the dominant i can the corresponding to this i can tell you is
o ones
OK with the normalisation factor one over and whatever square would n
there's also a these measures also have an ergodic properties so if you take w
to the k th powers if you apply this filter many many times
you don't get zero
you get a matrix of rank one
where this you one is the
i left
singular left igon value corresponding to the one
OK now if i go back to this for a second there's an in in
interesting intuition behind this what this tells you is that because the dominant i can
vector is is just constant what it means is that this filter w is invariant
to constant images
so if you give it an image
doesn't vary
and it just gives it back to
which is what you would want for denoising filter so that's nice the math and
the intuition kind of right
OK so let's go on and talk about other interpretations of w are obviously
the you can think of w is the probability transition matrix for markov chains sort
of the standard interpretation for row stochastic matrices but also in terms of graphical models
of data and spectral methods there's interesting interpretation so let's say
you take a pixel at position j and then think about pixels around it or
anywhere in the image
indexed by ISI and i think this is a node in the tree and these
are the branches of the tree and so this is basically a weighted graph
with the weights
on each of the branches between i and j being k i j
so if you take these weights k
and construct
the matrix k from them
if you don't normalise it the way i just described in the previous slide
and then if you take this
w and normalized further using this
minus i what you get is precisely what's called the graph laplacian
in these other applications and of course the graph has been used in
so many different applications all around
so the point of this is that what i'm going to do is i'm going
to be studying the spectrum of this matrix w
to again a lot of insight about processing
and people have been studying the spectrum of the graph laplacian for all kinds of
other applications really equivalent
so the study that i'm going to show you know about the spectrum of the
graph laplacian
the stuff ought to make a lot of sense
OK so
let's take a look at
so it is the seat or house or the the underlying mechanical structure that gives
us these various abilities
these p functions are functions that we have by virtue of our brain so that
ten you into saying that our mind and the physical view is just the brain
but we probably shouldn't say that because after all shoot me there's my corpse lying
on the stage well there's my brain
you know my brain is still there in my head
but we no longer have a person
the person has died the person seems you know no longer exists whether strictly that's
the best thing to say another question will have to come to a couple of
but it seems pretty clear that the mind is being destroyed even though the brain
is still there so i think i was wondering when there is the need to
be careful maybe we don't normally have the need to be careful but when there
is the need to be careful we should say
talk of the mind is the way it is the way of talking about that
function name
of the body
and and our best science suggests that a well-functioning body can
perform these things can think and plan fall in love by virtue of the fact
that the brain is functioning properly
that's the visibles
if we take this we know that the other other jewelers do
what was death that is presumably the separation of the mind and the body with
the destruction the perhaps the permanent separation with the destruction of the body
what's death on the physical is to there's no extra entity
the soul
the mind is just the proper p functioning of the body
the mind gets destroyed when the ability of the body to function in that way
has been destroyed death is roughly the end of this set of functioning
again this probably should be cleaned up and in a couple of weeks will spend
a day or half period trying to clean up and make it somewhat more precise
but there's nothing mysterious about death from the physical point of view released about the
basic idea of what's going on and i got on a stereo
i suppose i hold my boombox for you and it's playing music it's one of
the things you can do
and i drop it on the ground smashing
no longer can function properly
it's broken
mystery why it can function once it's broken
that is basically just the breaking down of the body
and the physical is point of view so that it no longer functions properly
one other point worth
emphasizing in sketching the physical is to use this
so they said physical is don't deny that there are mines even though we say
we're just bodies that doesn't mean that we're just any old body is that of
the physical view were body that you have some illusion of thinking our bodies that
really do think
so there really are minds
we could
and if it was point of view call those cells
just like there's no danger in talking of mine from the physical is perspective the
one be any serious danger in talking about us all
and so in certain contexts i'm perfectly comfortable in my physical is smooth i'm perfectly
comfortable talking about you know
this person always got a good solar bad so how the whole stories when i
read shakespear or what have you that the
upsetting or improper about the language of the soul
even on the physical is point of view
but in this class just try to keep us from getting confused as i indicated
before and i want to remind you i'm going to say
the word soul
well it's trying to say the word soul but what i'm talking about the dualistic
so when i put it this way
the neutral term is going to be mined
we all agree that people have minds
sort of the house the seat of our personalities
and the question is what is the mind
and the dual this position is that the mind is the sole
and the soul is an immaterial object
so when i use the word so i'll try to reserve it for the metaphysical
view according to which souls are something immaterial
in contrast to that we've got the physical this view physical it's also believe in
but minds are just way of talking about the abilities of the body
and so they do not believe it was do not believe in any immaterial object
above and beyond the body
that's part of the person
and so just to keep things clear i will say that
physical this materialist do not believe in souls
because for the purposes of this class i'm going to
i reserve the word soul for the materialist conception of
the mind
though in another context no harm in talking about cells
so this is the these are the two basic positions the dualistic view on the
one hand the physical is to view on the other hand the question we need
to turn to take it that just as the dual view is the familiar one
so it's true that the physical is view is that the familiar one you know
whether or not you believe that you are familiar with the fact that some people
believe that are least you wonder whether it's true
the science require that we believe in the physical is to view or not
the question we want to turn to then
is which of these two views should we believe
the dual is position or the physical this position
the crucial question presumably is well should we believe in the existence of the soul
both sides believe in bodies
they say that the dual this position is we're understanding it is not a view
that says there are only mind there are no bodies jules believe that their bodies
they believe that are sold as well as bodies
physical is believed bodies but no self so there's an agreement that there are bodies
here's one each one of you is sort of dragging one around with you
i disagree with those bodies the question is
are there any thing
beyond bodies is there anything beyond the body
is there so other cells
so that's that
question is going to concern for you
a couple weeks
if we ask ourselves
what reason do we have to believe in a soul might start by asking what
reasons do we have to believe in
how do we prove the existence of things now for lots of familiar
every day objects the answer is fairly straightforward we prove the existence by using our
five senses we just seem
how do i know
there are chairs well
there some chairs in front of me open my eyes i see them how do
i know that there's a certain well i see it
i can touch and i feel that
how do i know that there are trees i see them how do i know
birds i see them i hear them how do i know that there are apples
i see that my taste and so forth and so on
approach pretty clearly isn't going to work for souls
a soul again we gotta minus metaphysical view quite which is something immaterial
until you reach some point
where delta g
equals zero
start here
sure react
and those
will react form some products
you however start with fewer
you have no idea
outside you will be greater than zero
so you'll be spontaneous
in the reverse
direction of reaction
so your products to for reactor
so here you go this way
here we go down this way
and here you don't achieve greater than zero zero getting radius here
their products
you're making reactor
still to this point here
where delta g
course hero
and when delta equals zero
then you are at equilibrium
the relationship between delta genes in the directions of these reactions so the wrong thing
toward equilibrium
so along with this
think about the fact that delta g
it's going to be changing
the reactants and products change as the composition of the reaction mixture changes
we start with pure react
you're going to have to
delta g
at some point equilibrium be
it's also possible to help i don't you for your product so i don't think
he is going to depend on your composition of your material
here are just a quick review from from monday
necessary introduce you to this equation
the relationship between delta g
delta g know not that
thank you
which is the reaction quotient
so delta g
is there any particular point
in your reactions
well you know
has to do with the reactor
and products in their standard states
here the reaction quotient
and then or the gas constant and t is temperature
so she also introduced to this on monday
i just want to
to review this i think she actually just talked about the gases be the same
equations and principles apply talking about reacted in solution
this reaction quotient
the longer sort definition two
depends on the partial pressures of reactants and products for the concentrations during solution
so i showed you this equation just a was going to be
and t
and that the top of the reaction quotient
these products in the audience reacted so you have partial pressure
some references
raised to power seek to consider the stoichiometry
of the reaction
and then
times the partial pressure of p
raise the power against the geometry
and the same for the reactor
and over here the solution you're just talking about things
in concentrations rather than partial pressures
but then this is the reference here with be
one or
partial pressure one more concentration
you often see these with the reference dropped out of the equation
and you think you being equal to
the partial pressure of being raised to the the partial pressure ridge
and all the partial pressure of the a and b to
the same form
the concentration
this is how you will be in general thing to remember what were your references
are there
so again she
went over this on monday just look at it again
so also
also on monday
we should look at this equation here
and consider delta g
one is equal to zero
which means you are at equilibrium
o point when delta g zero
the reaction quotient
equals k which is the equilibrium constant
so q equals ten thousand new
when you are at equilibrium
so we can take this equation
and substituting zero because the equilibrium
delta g
it is zero
and then this equation
and rewritten
this brings the RTE natural log k
to the other side
and again
the equilibrium constant
it has the same form
as you
when you're only considering the concentrations at equilibrium
so in the gaseous state
it looks just like you
these concentrations or
partial pressures are the ones at equilibrium phase equilibrium constants and likewise the solution
here just talking about the ratio
of products to the reactor at equilibrium before equilibrium things to remind you
these concentrations
at equilibrium
she also showed you
one day
you can rearrange
this equation
but they used to be popular and in high school so that you could
make a bendy smooth
smooth curve
so what can we do next
the demo i just showed you with twenty five odd hidden units
i do the weights at random from a gaussian distribution i didn't tell you what the standard deviations were
now i'm going to show you those standard deviations they were legal a moment ago
and this screen is now showing you four equal standard deviations four
the input weights
the bias weights and the outputs which are coloured now
the red
curve or
three blue curves are shown you three random draws
the gas in distribution
right so you can see those three functions and now what i'm gonna do is
crank up and down the standard deviation is just so you can see what effect
scaling the weights about
the random weights making bigger or smaller has on the random functions so first
let's crank up the input weights standard deviation
you see the functions have got
more weakly
and that sort shrunken because we've taken all the hype or hyperbolic tangents and made them all speaker
and if we take
sigma in
the standard deviation will be weight down yet get much s
broader functions that locally look just like straight lines
now let's treat the bias is bias is we can
have big standard deviation forum now we've got lots
the wiggles
we can have a small standard deviation and now we get something that looks like
it's a sum of about three or four hyperbolic tangent even though it's a function
of a sum of twenty five
so the standard deviation and the biases determining how many wiggles get
but it doesn't affect
be characteristic length scale of the wiggles that's being controlled by
the standard deviation in the inputs
finally crank up and down the standard deviation and the outputs this is trivial
the functions just become
higher vertically
all our
so that's the roelof those three standard deviations
so what we do next
let's give ourselves data
so just as with a single neuron
computing the gradient and we did steepest descent on the gradient
and we ended up
being able to perfectly separate the five yellow petals from the five blue raisins
we can do the same thing with the data set looks like this here of five
hand we can define a new objective function
which instead of
being this gene here
is gonna be a measure for real numbers
of how close
the outputs of target so we have
the neuron function like this why
you have some target values like this
user errors
is end
is plan
and we can define
call some of
she and minus one
what about measuring error could you possibly have well
obviously other ones but this is a standard things people often some west
and that's depends on w
on the weights
three uh
the wire ends which are all
way dependent
so what we do with at we say this is our objective function please make
the output as closely as possible targets
you compute the gradient gene which by definition is you
by the w
hand many people do steepest descent on the subjective functions so they follow the gradient downhill
alright lights down
and here's what happens after one iteration of steepest descent so i started off with
a twenty five hidden units neural network
shown by the blue line
andrew start going downhill and after one iteration is already looking quite promising
maybe another iteration andy two thousand three thousand eight thousand nine thousand iterations
and you end up with this green thing which perfectly goes through all five data
points and say here are brilliant i have learned
the function
from the five data points or maybe say
no rubbish that's stupid
because maybe you're dealing with noisy problem where actually what you really think is going
on is that there is the true underlying function
and the data points
differ from it by some
additive noise
and then you be rather irritated have
the green curve perfectly go through every single
detail the noise
and if you are dissatisfied in a way
what you say
well you say
i wanted to learning with regularization
so you've changed the objective function again
and you say
i need some sort regularization
because i don't like this really function because it's a bit
it's would leave and i was expecting
the expectation about not being super-duper wiggly
can be expressed perhaps with regularizer
you can go back the good old regularizer
we had a moment ago
he w
you can add alpha times it or maybe a bit more sophisticated and you actually
i should is divide the weights in the classes because
remember a moment ago the willingness
this typical function
a length scale is determined by the standard deviation of the input weights
had a number of wiggles
that was related to beeston deviation biases
number wiggles in a typical function sigma bias over sigma in
and it had a vertical length scale it something to do with sigma out
perhaps times square root
so since we
input weights
magnitude and the biases and outputs affecting things in such different ways it might make sense to have three regularizers
one for each of these things
and you can define
in w
one to be the sum of squares
all the weights
summing over there
that is
you go to
this element black by
the action of an element of g
so you are applying to acts who applied you want you go
go here
you applied to go here
you may return to LAX at some point
in your fly another element people here
so everywhere you go here
you some of the elements
this all the elements belongs to an object
this is the solution of one part of it
if you
in the theorem that we need the definition for all of its we're going to
do that so
but another important point here is to
fix space
this is the fix-it subspace of the element x
you have an element x there
and here
the fix subspaces all g element of g of the group
that fix x
you have of g on x and you to get x x doesn't change
with live-action
so for example in this case here
it's obvious that the
identity should be the right
so these guys here
this is the subset
of the group
four that fix the element x
doesn't change
and of course you when you see subset you already know that we talking about
core sets of this
this result here
it's called orbit stabiliser
and it relates
the size
of course act
of the subset
with the size of the orbit
this has intuitive
so he
look x here
you should be more clear
x is just
x is not the group along its axis
x is a point
right ideal acting like vector
and g is symmetric
some metrics times vectors
it's it's it's you have to understand this a bit more of
but this is
this is an element they represent elements by and by
by on
and is that he is just represent the action of these elements on the
this structure
in this in this can be having defined by you can do the action is
a matrix multiplication
as an operator
not you're the action of the group will have one with light elements of the
so here that's why i drawn this in different
the circle right
the group is here
and here is where
the x gold
on the action of the group
x imagine x is the vector
so o
so this is
before i start to piece of group
two names for
and that
but the main thing is this in this slide here
is that the size of this course that is the size
and the interpretation for these intuitive interpretation is that you take a group
they can group
and you take out
that doesn't change
in the action
and what you get
it's everything that moves
that makes sense
these is six it space
gx is the
the live fix it
and this is the orbits
the things that i will
this is this arm
relationship here
this is the number of cosets
the size of the course
the number of cosets
and this is the size of the org
so you need to use these relations together with the
lagrange theorem to prove the
statement of the
burnside theorem
he and innovation is
this axis here is the collection of all
of all
the fixed point
so you have the definition of extensive space for the next
then you collect all taxes
so this is a
so this is a subset of the x
the set of all orbits
i'm giving
by this information here
which is you know gx is just one orbit for one x
and then you run through all the axis you get a one
of this is the
but the number of
if you remember
this is a good place to start because
this is the left side of the
the right side
is this here
you know
the trick is you can because of this identity here
the size of this
you know you take one x that belongs to this
and you with one by one and his son
in some of these axes
then you have the size of this is a way to calculate the size of
the sum was reduced to that
and here you can see the change
and then
different people
you want
all right
well we have
and all
so really
and people
you think
so we have
required if you're dead
well we extracted information from the already in index
index sweet entities attributes and relations
also maybe
spatial and temporal relations
question have temporal point
at the time points in your view
from which you can enforce the temporal relations but spatial relations
here is also quite
you can't fix it right
so this here is also
a need for this kind of technology to
we have all the data points
you might call his natural language
let's go back to the more classical question think you have a question who is
the architect and you want to find the document collection the answer to your question
so i general procedures
you analyse
and you try to find from the
finding the question
as much information as possible
so first of all you have a large document collections
you will not analyse
try to analyse or what you will not try to make your question
and sentence in the document collection
it would be much too slow if you think analyses
and of course if you want to select so filter
and from the document collection
that might contain the answer to question so you actually
common retrieval on this and so so you to understand from your collection that might
contain answer
and then you can perform a linguistic more in-depth analyses of your question
among the
as part of this more in-depth analyses of your question
you might be to
the type of questions so here who which
so who is related to a person we have to find a person name
reference person
as an answer to a question
we do the same
he performed analyse
also for the answer sentences in the document collection
and then we
we select and rank
so also in the standards of document collections
we have
we try to find the expected and such
if we are looking for persons we should do named entity called recognition in our
document collection
and find
and find a person named in this
person names in the centre of the collection
so we tried to do
as well as we could
from which we extract the and expected answer type
and in my summary for h
so you see another
more schematic overview
so we have questions like
so how how much
what it calls
two events looks like that for a while
for one day
well in nineteen ninety six
o clock
how much would it cost
so first of all
we do
let our question to keyword
which we use also to
retrieve relevant citations valid sentence from our collection to analyse
but we can go deeper into the question and
so we can
the question presentation
we can derive the expected answer type
or the question type
it's quite so
because these terms
somehow changed
when you speak about question time and time
determine the posterior given the data
and if you remember this this theorem about the existence of the density than that
said that that this measure has to be absolutely continuous with respect to this measure
for this density to exist so what that meant was
whenever the prior puts
put zero mostel in any event
then the posterior will also have to put zero mostel
otherwise pointless reweighting doesn't work
and you see that this is not explicitly mentioned as a condition for
so one of the nice things about the theorem is that what it tells you
is if this condition holds
then this condition of absolute continuity here is implied by the
you don't have to check it
good but
another consequence here of of of this
being actually being in density of the properties of the posteriors with respect to the
prior is
that if this absolute continuity condition is not satisfied
then we don't have the basic wage
we don't we don't have this density there's nothing like this equation
in basically an finite dimensional models that never happens
any any parametric model finite dimensional space on what can think of
but what happened
one model but actually happens is the directly process on the real line
and so that's what we have already
if we if we define that the director process with continuous base measure on the
real line or an interval continuous set
actually this posterior here is not
it's not absolutely continuous with respect to the prior then we don't have basically
so you might have wondered about why i mean if you if you have already
seen a bit of tricky process literature then you always see the sampling equation for
the process posterior but you never see anything like
the bayes equation may have it directly prior over here and iterative process during process
prior over here and then some all and then some thirty process posterior
and the reason is that this equation is not
not defined
so you say if if this derivative here exists
this if this this thing is well defined as the implied
no so actually in order when you start when you start from
from the prior here
then you need some some notion of what x look like looks like in order
to define the posterior in the first place
right you need so you need to define x in order to
to define the posterior x also defines this
if you have a posterior defined and this is also defined
but it's defined in an abstract sense and you don't know how
you don't know know how to get from here to here in any
any computational or even analytic
so when i'm saying here that that this model doesn't have these equations are not
talking about the problem of what people call an intractable posterior
intractable posterior is if the space equation exists and if this integral down here is
hard to compute
or does not have a closed form
does not have a closed form solution
and this he says
there are some cases where we're actually this this equation simply make
you me OK so
the question is
when we have density it always has to be with respect to some measure brain
and says so so
the condition is there must be some measure
any measure
such that
if you look at this as a family of distributions for each value of the
parameter to get
you get a distribution here
for each one of the parameters this is this is one measure on x
the flag
figure and ground birds and fish at the centre but now this flow is with
respect to point cemetery each figure of balls
matched by figure below imperfect point cemetery
so again the figure and ground but with different layout in symmetry
this is probably actually is most famous for this is called day and night
obviously again dualistic title
and here with respect to run it seems as though this mural line in the
here you have a bright but hamlet
along the little river and over here you have its nighttime mirror image
and it seems as though
the dot product of birds bats flying over the summer village is mirrored by the
flock of light colored birds
flying over the nighttime landscape
in fact
these birds are not reflected images of the birds of the tails
the white birds have tails down
the blackbirds have tails up
it is because of the need to have it that way to make them rock
in the centre but still it's not perfect mirror images of each other but this
is a very nice again dualistic painting not painting the footprint rather
this is a very complex
presentation of the dualism of convex and concave
and that's the name of this print
and again this is a kind of neuron here
the balance is the two
on the left
you have a view that if you're standing up here we're looking down
you're looking down and over here on the right you're looking up
and depending on your viewpoint
at the centre things can be either convex or concave i'm not going to point
out one you have this
this is the prince you want to look at again and again because each time
you do you'll discover some new things
look at this from from the viewpoint of a woman who was going down the
she's going down the staircase
and this is the
at the bottom of the staircase and indented into that war is the whole fluted
on the other hand
if you look at this
from underneath
now we are down on the next row and we're looking
is this set of stripes the underside of an alcove but this is also a
set of stripes that the is the underside of an alcove
right here
and when you look at it from below
so this is a con
the next
plaster ornament coming out of the ceiling
it was the same thing which is convex
which is concave and so forth
ensure again love to play with these relativistic point of view in in this case
he's put them together to get to this duality of convex and concave
another aspect of symmetry
if we had describe
one aspect of symmetry would certainly say symmetry has to do with literally no
actually himself
it was
only person interested in order this particular printer his is named
the order and chaos
and you is kind of something you know you
the sort of kind a bunch
discarded stuff
and in the centre is this beautiful crystal like
global with
a list nodes
the do that
coming through it and you can see in this some of the reflections of these
that's of debris
around it
so here is kind of summing up
and care
having to do with water also
it has to do with quality
and as you know
regular and semi-regular polyhedra they show up in several of his prints this one is
just called stars
if you notice the stars are in fact some of the regular platonic solids
and some of the
uniform polyhedra and some of the compounds some very difficult compounds this one that funny
lizard like creatures
sticking through
is actually a compound of two
after heater
he also
this is very beautiful
when you
o where
based on
during which he found in the mathematics book by max brooks there
and this is a compound
o five regular tetrahedra
the company of course the tetrahedra regular approach their interests they are intertwined compound in
such a way
that's why have come here are not perfect
five fold symmetric point
and he is captured this very same symmetry
with this thing he did this with several carvings you'll see some others later
he explored the regular division of space this is called cubic space division
and he also explore the regular division of space
with respect to concentrate
spherical shells here
and of course what should probably is most well known for
his his pilings or tabulations
if you say the word elation
almost everyone says asher
here you have regularity but you also have
and this is another aspect of symmetry
symmetry as regular repetition of like elements
and in this room probably translations this one is very well he actually produced a
silk print of this that is quite beautiful with these fish actually swim in
in our intertwining with then streams and this is the print on which those based
solely have regular repetition
stochastic gradient descent
so the bottom line is can do this very fast
and to show you what we can do for example we can think it being
a network like seventy five thousand dollars and half million edges
if you ask what the space of four
what node correspondences it's like that one million
but this is by setting just a small fraction of these actually it takes two
hours to estimate the parameters so this is our parameter these are our parameter estimates
and refuses to generate a synthetic graph and then you
compare the properties for example degree distributions
cumulative distribution of plants
or distribution of the first singular vector
you can see that the matching
the reality quite well so basically matching the statistics of these networks
quite well even though we didn't
specifically said we want to measure the vision and we want to mention is that
we just said we want justice image is much
this now
is the first time
so basically what i show you some observations on evolving
network special about how to how you alleges that touched on how to create a
synthetic networks now i want to show you were confiscated
so what i mean by cascade is bayes basically behaviors that cascade propagates from node
to node in the network like an epidemic and there are many natural examples of
so for example the epinions
rumors were news are something that problem is easily recommendation so word-of-mouth marketing is another
infectious diseases again like flu you have to
come contact with someone in fact there is another example and then sort sort of
twenty b when such behaviors propagate the through the network they believe that based on
for these traits scale
so the idea is that if i have an network
and then i have started
then this activation propagates through the network
and basically
but there is the
propagation graph i call a cascade
now i can go and study this
the structure so what i'll show you next is basically two examples where work such
propagations naturally happens and you can actually obtained a credit basically we can obtain a
lot of such propagations
so first setting for which we had a was this by marketing setting
twenty percent and receiving commendations on products and they also purchased products so the idea
is to use data comes from one large online store when a person comes by
the product when they buy a product they get the choice to recommend it to
the friends get email they can come back
but just the product and so on so the idea is a person comes by
the product makes recommendations
the other person
decides to accept the recommendation by the product
they get ten percent discount for his
this person gets ten percent credit for making the successful recommendations
they both happy
and the whole process propagates OK so this is the first step and for this
we we have data
from anonymous large online retailers like four million people sixteen million of such a combination
event and half a million products so basically books dvds music and videos
OK so this is the first setting
and the second thing
is the blogosphere
right so we have a blog
like here
and now we would like to trace how information propagates through the blogosphere so the
idea is that
the machine learning theory blog which is very popular in the enterprise writes a blog
right post and then slams the scholarly says a general something very good so
now other blogs in the blogosphere discover maybe maybe both popular and again site OK
in this way the information propagates so we said this piece of information are propagated
to stand on the southern and then again some other block write posts but they
can propagate
in in a different way again and sees everything this time stamp them you can
go through all these blocked both we can actually get the traces of this information
and they used here was banned for than point five million both sixteen million links
between them
i mean this was like for about fifty thousand blog
in two thousand six
so the first question that you can ask is how this propagation that's this cascade
of the like right we see like long strings
well just somebody just cite your sources and we have this like long strings of
of propagation i seen starts maybe which is so that says something a lot of
people cite but nothing else happens and so on
so you going get this sort of frequent cascades frequent cascade subgraphs for
what you can see what you see is the the light bulb
top ten of them were information propagates down and this is they are decreasing ordered
by decreasing frequency
so and the action selection is that this post created a hyperlink to the post
of about so information propagates from the top down
so these are the information escapes from blogosphere
but you also take wider marketing basket so for example is a DVD recommendations not
well where the sum up again i'm putting them in the decreasing frequency but now
the semantic of the means that this person made the recommendation to that person that
person what OK so
one here
in both cases the recommendations sort of the influence propagates down what you can you
can make two observations so the first one is basically that lot marketing cascades that
sort of more social so what i mean by that we we have these collisions
get more people to recommendations from the same product from multiple different people
while in blogosphere this correspond to summarise i mean there's a blog who who cites
three different posts in some cases and we don't see such things in the blogosphere
and the second thing is
the marketing cascades are much more or much richer so we we have a nice
each non tree like structures one the blogosphere and things like three RR start to
OK so this is the empirical
the second thing that
i want to show is based on this very basic question which is basically what
how the probability of adoption depends on the number of friends who have already so
the question is what's the probability of buying and i was given the number of
your friends the following the nine OK
if you know what is the shape of this kind of thing can be like
that much more accurate models and so on
OK and that are the hypothesis so the first hypothesis would say that
if i put the number of friends already online versus your probability of winning it
it would be some kind of diminishing to strike your probability of falling only slowly
decreases as as as more of your friends have
so that's hypothesis the one that also makes lots of sense is critical mass critical
threshold idea the idea would be that you don't really mind until a critical number
you what that later
it was that OK for integration by parts
and then now i'm going to be of now i can combine that with this
value of x
put them together
so that all that stuff is multiplying v VAT
and then this is the boundary term i'm
budging on for the moment
now what do you say
then there done that's right
this quantity
as supposed to be always positive
so what's my conclusions
this is possibly the singers this thing is never negative
no matter what BMX i'd shoot
it has to be
it has to be easier
it has to be zero that's the conclusion i one
that's the key that the fundamental lemma of the calculus of variations when you get
this expression
but that has that has
that can never be negative
only positive or zero then sends v x has signed here sign
the only way you know it in this endeavor
we can give BMX which were free to choose we can give the x the
signed the same sign or the opposite sign we can choose the sign of the
and get a contradiction
so that's the conclusion
has to be
zero and that this quantity this integral
this integral
and no this concept that the integral and has to be zero at every point
because we can choose the effects
that's the
this is the DPD you we were looking for only
i'm using
it's the first variation rather than the first derivative we just use the word
variation as a reminder
we're dealing with functions were in continuous variables
the the so the big moment has just
it's just there
there is
good at what happened to this guy
yes no you're absolutely right so there there are two points that i have
not dealt with one is that one so let's deal with them
OK now how to deal with that
the reason is always the same that this saying we're our reasoning is that this
thing has to be greater equal zero for all the
now that we want to conclude that this thing has to be zero that's is
fundamental fact now how what's house are thinking of the
why why can we forget this which
well yeah but
it's always positive tribe and we we
this business
how do we how do we deal with well you probably say i don't want
to hear any more about calculus but how did we
how can we deal with the difference between these was
was delta x
f prime of x
plus then they were really more terms or there there was delta x
square over two have with double prime that's that's the kind of term we're looking
at here
but how why was it but the this they had to be zero
and that that i didn't have to worry about this stuff
and then we give me answer the question
take the
since these arbitrary take a very small
the to be
whatever sign we want to have it quite
make its magnitude really small
so that's the good idea there
i think of is just a little changed
if this was zero
we would get something right we get something in this part
we get something here but it would be
second order
so it's the sign of this would control
there's a subtle
now the but but the u s exactly the right question and the answer is
that because this has of v squared in it
when i think of the as being just a small perturbations this guy can
it doesn't affect our reasoning
it is it it is true that it could be positive but got positive and
so small compared to the other one that the other one that that that's in
yeah like that's true maybe i want to take these
as well as small that the beauty is i'm i'm allowed b
and and so that's what the limits when you get that much freedom
the only way out is for the thing that multiplies the these
that's that's right
that you're you're making a good point that well i could be could be small
i mean a mathematician might say replace by epsilon times v
so what the
replace v by epsilon b
and then this would be and would have an epsilon squared in
we you want to see any of that
sorry if
o is right of yet but this seem negative
no i i built in way back to the original problem i see with positive
just the way our matrix capital city was that what had to be symmetric positive
diagonal thing here
on law would go backwards in the world with
a lot of k
right but that's your absolutely right that that if c in other words let me
say because you're quite right