and one what's here's our hashtable
and what we're going to do is we're going use universal hashing at the first
OK so we find a universal hash functions figure hash function at random
and what we do is will
the hash into that level
and then we'll do is keep track of
of two things one is what the size of the hash table is at the
next level
so in this case the size of the hash table uses enormous losses going for
we're also going to keep a separate
hash key
the second level
so each slot will have its own
hash function for the second level
so for example
this one might have here thirty one that is a random number
he is here
these are there there
it is up there
OK so that's going to be the basis of my hash function the key with
which germany hash
one a is six and let's say this
and then we have a pointer to the hash tables
this is a a s one
four slots
fourteen twenty seven
two slots are empty
and this one for example
what are
so the idea here is that in this case if we look over all our
top level hash function
which are just call h
has that h
is equal to the age of
twenty seven
think one
because we're in slot one
so these two both past to the same
slot in the level one hash table this is level one
this is level two here
so level one hashing fourteen twenty seven collided they went into the same slot here
level two
they got
has to different places and hash function i use is going to be indexed by
whatever the random numbers are that i chose found for this and i'll show you
how we find those
we have then h
thirty one
is equal to one
thirty one r twenty seven is equal to two
level two
so i go
passion here find the
use this
as the basis my hash function hash into whatever table
got here
and so if there are no
if i can guarantee that there are no collisions at level two
this is going to cost me order one time in the worst case to look
something up
how do i look it up take the value
i apply each to it
that takes me to some slot
then i looked to see what the
he is for this hash function apply that hash functions
that takes me to another slot
OK and that
it took me basically two applications of hash functions plus some look up
because who knows what minor amount of bookkeeping
the the reason or have no
collisions at this level
is the following if there n
so i
a level
one slot
then we're going to you
m so by
which is equal to
and so by square
in the level two hash table
OK so
i should mention here this is going to be survive
the size of the hash table and this is going to be my
they survive
so many use
so basically i'm going to hash n so things into answer by square would
locations here
so this is going to be incredibly spores
this can be quadratic and size
OK so what i'm going to show is that under those circumstances
it's easy for me to find hash function such that there are no collisions
that's the name of the game
case figure out how can i make these hash functions so there are no collisions
that's why draw this with so few
elements here
so here for example i have two elements and i have a hash table size
four here three elements i need hash table of size nine
OK are hundred elements i need to hash table of size
ten thousand
i'm not going to pick something so it's likely that there is a lot of
that size
and the fact that this actually works
this gives us all the properties the one that's sparked the analysis
so everybody that the stakes order one worst-case time and what the basic structure of
it is
OK know these things by the way and not in this case prime
i can always pick crimes that were close to the side do that in this
you can use this faction that may be totally irrelevant for the problem
and if you know some properties of the distribution in terms of partitioning the space
instead of working in the whole space you can walk one block of the partition
at the time and just put all the blocks together at the end because you
move left in each block you get a much smaller violence at the
so nineties
that if if you know of any group actions
then you can implement your space
but it's not necessarily to to your problem for f is not environs by group
during one simulation you do all the all the orbit of your simulation by the
which is provably finite and there's one simulation you get an improved estimation compared with
one point
this is done
and if you're not lucky
what you'll end up is with an orbit
that is just one significant point
and if you're lucky enough if the action has something to do with your problem
or if you just your function is spread well enough in terms of this group
action then you get improvement
if you look in in in in in hypercube in own dimension you can
you can flip
according to all the symmetries
of of this this i hypercube prince
if you stimulate the point here can you can change either first component of the
second component
all the company
but of course
this is principle which were only if
you are
target distribution is not a small clump in europe q otherwise you just end up
putting more zeros your estimation
always importance weight you get from that are very small
there a recent paper in discussion paper in the last genesis
by making and about that
that's trying to make a principle of the
the point
that was
i'm trying to prepare the way for instances of correlation is something that would be
obvious and MCMC simulation rather blackwellisation is say that we will definitely use in MCMC
and it's called the creation because that is thinking of this work robert but if
you and that tells you that if you condition of the sufficient statistic you improved
don't need sufficient statistics because some would you know every everything is sufficient
can be sufficient in the sense that if you
x y
and if you start with st mary doesn't over x
if you can compute this new st mary
in downtown
of x given y which only depends on y
obviously the violence will decrease
and both estimators of the same expectations
therefore we are getting closer
to the true value
so if we can do is implement that in
problems were
you other joint simulation
of x and y
and if you stimulate your by simulating joint x and y just like in the
stochastic illegitimate you simulate the phi
and sigma m estimating in addition
all this xt
so you just have problems we need to supplement
to get the simulation
it's like way
well if you go and if you do that
then you have to try to produce an
got rather than the average of the age of x i have to try to
producer expectation of this process to matter by integrating out something carnegie otherwise for instance
you can do that either exactly or approximately you will get a smaller volumes
compared with his i had
for example is is fairly city but just to give you a flavor
i think function where i know
the conditional expectation so i want to compute expectation of
exponential of minus six square
it's just student with
degrees of freedom and i do that because seem interested in new
i first met in all
on the fly square so have a couple
x y to produce much simulation from x
and just throwing away the otherwise
i can try to implement rao representation and here
because estimate made this despair it's one x y one of two x and y
and rather than you think
one of n
the average of the exponential minus xj square
i could in that case i can compute
the conditional expectation of six months my six where
he one
which is one of our
two sigma square y
plus one
because they chose an example where it works really well
you can see here
realisation of ten
iteration so it is
standard average of the exponential
six j square
and here is so blackwell estimate
and of course again and again the violence is much much smaller
just a few words to to
in one sampling perspective is with bayesian
of course the problem when you want to compute an expedition against the posterior
it's just a regular integration problems so you may apply
the whole
the toolbox that
particular choices that are
of interest
i think if you kind
user prior
your importance sampling
the ratio
already important is just likely
so if your prior distribution is proper
one of them
one of the
when you were
or even more
one of the
i but
when they were called
one labelled her
this than
they are
first of all
o four o
how is
we're a
a lot of
you know
and you are here
the role of
there is
nine of
on where are
can be used
i mean
the only
he appeared
you want
part of
OK so now we don't need to have now the size of this page tables
is much smaller right there are no longer to thirty now there through the twentieth
bits which is some small number of megabytes big and they and but we still
have this this we have avoided this problem we had before we have some flexibility
in terms of where how these physical how each page maps into the physical memory
so i can create a third page here i can allocate a third page to
process and i can map that in any four thousand ninety six block by block
fits in memory is currently unused i flexibility i don't have this problem setting with
a where a c were colliding with each other
this is sort of the outline of how virtual memory works but what i haven't
yet described to you
it is how it is that we can actually go about creating these these different
address spaces that are allocated to the different modules and how we can switch between
different modules using this this p m a r register so
i sort of describe this as though these things cl suppose that these these data
structures exist now here's how we can use them but i haven't told you how
these data structures or put together created and set up to begin with
and i did this at the beginning
but in order to do this what we're gonna need is some sort of a
special supervisory module that's able to
look at the page maps for all of these different that's able to create new
page maps and look at the page maps for all the different modules that are
within the system and then the supervisory models can be able to do things like
add new memory page map or be able to do that or be able to
destroyed delete a particular module and its associated page so we need some sort of
thing that can manage all this infrastructure
and so this supervisory module
it's called the kernel
the kernel is really it's it's going to be the thing is going to be
in charge of managing all these data structures for us
here's a microprocessor with its m r register on and we're going to do is
we're going to extend the microprocessor with one additional piece of one additional piece of
hardware and this is the
kernel bit
so this is just a bit that specifies whether we're whether we're currently running a
user module that is one of these just just to programs running on a computer
whether the kernel is currently executing
and the idea with this kernel there is that when the kernel that is the
code it's going to be there is running is going to have special privileges is
going to be able to do so can be able to manipulate special things about
the hardware processor and in particular
we're going to have a rule that says the only
the kernel
and change the PML
so the PM hours the thing that specifies which process is currently running
and which selects which address space we want to be currently using and we're gonna
use is we're going to use work and but so what we want what we're
going to do is have the kernel beta the thing that's in charge of manipulating
the value of the are registered to select which thing is currently being executed and
we want to make it so that only the kernel can do this because if
we for example allowed one of these other programs to be able to manipulate the
PMA are right then that other programs might be able to do something unpleasant to
the computer-aided changes the PMA are to point at some other programs memory and now
suddenly all the memory addresses in the system are going to be really being resolved
it then suddenly we're going to be sort of resolving memory addresses relative to some
other modules
page map and that's likely to be problematic thing is likely to cause the other
modules to crash for example because the processor is set up to be executing instructions
from the current programs to make sure that only something this kernel contains the PMA
are in this kernel is going to be this sort of supervisory module that all
of the other modules are going to have to trust to do the right thing
and manage the computers execution for you
this kernel in except for this one difference the kernel can change the PMA are
the kernel is in all other respects essentially just going to be another module that's
running on the computer system so the kernel in particular the kernel
OK what they altered it
you sort of previous slide it took some fights of music
and classified them correctly and with respect to the composers so burgess together to parts
i guess the classical music because the stylus sort of probably more
so this applies a little bit of
and this
they're right in their paper that
also people
i feel that these
preload is different from these three
they did a lot of other applications of formby for optical character recognition for classification
of galaxies clustering novels for authors and some of the datasets
OK so i this was sort of integration a little bit but i want to
show you that
and this kolmogorov complexity is not only
cute in theory but can also be applied in practice quite directly and with great
we normally it's much more complicated to get from the theory to the application another
one is the MDL principle the minimum description length principle which is an approximation to
kolmogorov complexity
i mean rissanen like this but
he was
according to
doris definitely aware of kolmogorov complexity when he wrote in the paper but it doesn't
i mentioned that in this paper
so what you can do is what you almost approximate kolmogorov complexity and you and
compute an upper bounds on the two part MDL what do is
you take the shannon fano code
so you have
some probability class take
can kind of code
he new
and then you cold somehow
so what if code the distribution and then i think the distribution cosmic vision part
of this case
the complete called which is an upper bound on
oracle model of complexity
and MDL that minimizes the right hand side with respect to move
to get the best possible
so this clustering methods to summarize
so based on the universal similarity metric which is itself based on kolmogorov complexity
then they approximated by some standard compressed
compute the similarity metrics and then represented the similar larity metrics as three
and the three
because there is a computationally hard problem they approximated by the so-called quartet
which will grow into it and it leads to excellent classification in many domains
so finally
the OK and questions the
similarity part
OK finally so far the work was about prediction
but critics is everything you want agent which acts and influences the environment and they
come to that now
so cooperation agencies
sequential decision theory reinforcement learning value functions
and then the bayes mixture in
in the this general case and then the specific i model self optimizing somersaults
so optimizes great optimality and some
OK here's the down
you agent
environment if your actions which are called by
and your observations which are split into regular observations and reward
one of these are called a and b are called
this picture sort of in terms of turing machine so there environment which is an
internal state resources
the output is written on the tape and output the data written to tape and
reaction of environments with tape and then you know the size
so what you have is
four deterministic agents you have a policy p
which takes the observation sequence and produces an action sequence
given the observations up to k minus one it produces
and action y k
and p captures all these actions from
one to k
symmetric early the environment
deterministic environments function for
actions to
observations to the agent written in this way
as the some notation you want
k means one two k and less came in one to k
the input itself split in two parts the reebok in the regular observation parts of
the observations a video camera image
and the really what is the and
i assume that the rewards are bounded on the negative
the value in the deterministic case just from
the k two m
four policy p environment q is just the sum of rewards
and optimal policy is just the policy which maximizes value
and here assume that the light
time of the agent
i come to that later what to do with
so they before deterministic environments if you go to probabilistic environments what you do is
the observation xk is just you know
because the some for probability that depends on all possible actions in all past observations
so let's
continuous distribution sigma for that
if you multiply all this conditional probabilities together
you get the probability
of observing
this observation sequence given the agent
as provided in section six but remember there you know some
there's some interaction i mean this
x y two candy
this action this observation x took independent action y one
but not two that's also some structure on the left-hand side which is apparent here
without the conditions that but there are generic
product of conditional probabilities with these conditions some temporal
so and then the problem is the case you just take expectations to take the
river from one to n now say
and you ask what is the probability of observing this sequence
representation of course useless
so we always limit ourselves to a certain number
if you look very close to the minus one
notice that all the field lines
comment on the minus one we understand that of course because the positive charge want
to go to the minus one
a few very close to the plus
and they all go away from the plus being repelled
you can sort of thing is these field lines if you want to
measure the
but the plus
charges blowout air
like a hairdryer
and that the miners
suck in air
like a vacuum cleaner
and then you get the a feeling for those on the left side is
hendry which wants to blow out stuff
and then there is that little talk about wants suck something in
and it succeeds with some degree is not as powerful as the plus three term
we lost all information about field strength we had earlier with these arrows we had
the length of the arrow the the magnitude of the field was represented
you've lost that but there is still some information on field strength
if the lines are closer together the density of the lines is high
the electric field is stronger than when the density becomes low
so if you look for instance here
how many lines there are
a few millimeters and where you go further out
these lines spread out that tells you field is going down the strength of the
field is going down to one of our square field of course
if you want to make these drawings what you could do
to make them look good
you can make three times more field lines going out from the plus in this
then return to the minus one
so the field lines are very powerful
and we will
i often think in terms of electric fields
and the line configurations
and you will have
problems that deal with
electric fields
and with the electric field lines
if an electric field lines
is straight
so i have electric fields
get some range
so we have fields
but i like this
straight field lines
and i release a charge there
princes the positive charge
then the positive charge would experience force exactly in the same direction as the field
line because the tangential now is in the direction of the field lines
it will become
accelerated in this direction and would always stay on the field lines
i release it with zero spin
started accelerating would stay on the field
in a similar way
if we think the earth is having a gravitational field
is a to one we may never have used that was gravitational field but in
physics we think of the
of gravity also being fields
if i have here a piece of chalk
the field lines the gravitational field lines
june twenty six one hundred nicely parallel
and straight
and if i really this piece of chalk at zero speed
it will begin to move in the direction of the field lines and it will
on the field line
so now you can ask yourself the question
if i release a charge
would always follow the field lines
and the answer is no
only in this very special case
but suppose now that the field lines
a curves
you feel line
as you see in those
configurations very common
it now i release a
charging here
so point charge here
it will experience a force in this direction
so we'll will get an acceleration in this direction so it will immediately abandoned that
field one
so now you ask me what is the
trajectory of that
charge well could become very complicated i really don't know
maybe going like this
by the time it reaches this point
what i do know that then the force
will be tangential to this field lines
will be in this direction
so as it marches out and picks up speed
locally it will experience forces
representative of those field lines
and so the trajectory
can be rather complicated
so field lines
i'm not trajectories and not even when you
release the charge
with zero speed
only in case
that the field lines
i straight lines
let's now look at a field configuration
with maxwell himself the great maestro in some of his publications
but there
the ratio
one two four
and whether
this plus four plus one or minus four minus one
is not important
that's just matter of the direction of the arrows
next all the input errors in
so i leave it up appealing plus four plus one you have to put arrows
going outwards
and what you see now uses and lower effect think of them as both being
so there's a plus for trying to blow around like a hairdryer
and the prose one is trying to do his own thing
so we get
a field configuration field lines which are sort of
not perhaps easy that you can sort of imagine
why it has this
peculiar shape
if you
put it
plus test charge
in between one and four
then the four will repel it
but the one that also repellent
and so it is going to be a point somewhere probably close to one
by the forces exactly cancel out
therefore he will be zero there
in a similar way between the moon and the earth
that is the point is not too far away from the moon
we to gravitational attraction from the earth
and the gravitational attraction from the moon exactly cancel each other out
it's not too dissimilar from this situation
so when you have
charges of the same polarity
you always find in between somewhere point
twenty the electric field
is zero
that's not going to very special case
well by i make
the two charges
equal in magnitude
but opposite
in sign
and we have a name for that
we call that the dipole
plus charges he minus charges there
situation is extremely symmetric as you would expect because they have equal power
there's one upstairs
and one vacuum cleaner downstairs
being were behaving as a particle beam only so this validates
the broad and it also validates the whole concept of wave-particle duality wave-particle duality had
been applied the photons
they've already very comparable type individual photon but now
we can talk about waves of matter and so the bride has often been the
same Abreu his name many physicists the tag line they associated with the is matter
matter waves as distinct from light waves
waves of light we have ways of matter
that's important so that's number 1 caricature over to where we were earlier this morning
right number 2 we're going to have Werner Heisenberg Werner Heisenberg Heisenberg what did he
do well the study with poly in poly were bodies in graduate school they work
for Sommerfeld your Sommerfeld never won a Nobel Prize but we we should count how
many Nobel Prize winners he educated in his group
there's something very very important going on in the mentoring process that so
Heisenberg gets his PhD with Sommerfeld in Munich and then he goes to Copenhagen work
with born
and he was is getting burned out the dissenting vacation went up the north from
Denmark and we have to work on a deserted island off the coast of Norway
and stayed there for about 3 weeks and he came back
and with within brought the uncertainty principle
the uncertainty principle and what he said was that when you get down to the
atomic length scales there are limits there are constraints on our ability to observe
constraints on our ability to observe
at atomic length scales atomic scale
limits on our ability to and this is important because it means that since we
can observe
we can talk about individual electrons we have to start doing that because we can't
find an individual electron every observation we make involves the exchange of energy when looking
at that wall it's photons hitting the wall coming back to me and so the
photons hitting the wall actually put pressure on the wall
but the pressure so
who cares
you might say well what was that make any difference well I suppose I want
look at something like an electron in orbit here we know that this dimension is
roughly 1 angstrom unit right the ball radius for hydrogen is . 5 2 9
angstroms around numbers this is 1 extra while following look at that someone have very
capabilities in terms of the energy that I use the light that I use so
I would choose something that has a wavelength of roughly
right you wouldn't you wouldn't measure the dimension of a human hair with the yardstick
so I need something on this order so if I take lambda equals 1 angstrom
go through HC overland you'll discover that the energy of a photon with 1 as
its wavelength is on the order of 12 thousand 400 electron volts
while I'm looking for the selection was the binding energy the ground state electron hydrogen
it's 13 . 6 electron volts so I'm going go and I'm gonna look for
something that's got an energy of 13 . 6 electron volts holding it in place
and I'm going to use a flashlight with 12 thousand 400 electron volts
so I think I'm liable to disturb the very thing I'm going to measure
so you say well why you doing something so foolish why don't you something that
has much lower energy OK so let's choose something that has a 100 times less
than that so this be 13 . 6 over 100 electron volts well if I
go through that the wavelength of such a photon is going to be so big
that I'm back to measuring the dimension of the human here with the yardstick so
now you see the dilemma
if I want to get down to very very fine dimensions I have to bring
huge energy and disturb the very thing going to measure so this is the uncertainty
principle it leads to uncertainty in the measure suppose I ask you to take the
time of 100 meters spread in the olympics by give a stopwatch that's measured in
units of 15 seconds
what these people are blasting through at 9 seconds and and change general ledger runners
of 5 above all run under 15 seconds guess the whole batch is 1 another
15 seconds and all you've got is either 0 or 15
because that's resolution
so what does that tell you tells you can't resolve what's going on at that
In something else you can result
you can't resolve causality
when inserting it's that big you know which came 1st
cause and effect below a certain level of definitions
cause and effect cause and effect that becomes uncertain to
this is philosophical
has a lot of this is that should be
so what does that mean it means that we better get away from these deterministic
those sentences they usually long with each of the worlds
better summarize the use of all so that
coming back to the data i to this
google cluster
good news clusters
two sentences since this is unlikely to summarise the content of each of the articles
and this is going
so it's likely that
so sentences are also
about the same thing so this is the intuition
and that's what
what's interesting about this data is those sentences that
why not
so you can do itself get news articles in russian english and you can measure
the average length of the sentence is written in the long sentences and you traditionally
find significant difference
so for example for english which is about twenty eight thirty words which is can
be a very charming all along
new sentences about of twenty one
so it's very interesting for me
for this task because it really means that you need to start fresh
make more challenging
and it's also interesting because even the sentences
it's very likely that pass if you want to use that
which is suspected information the two processes to make mistakes the data
so we
go through the information society
two if you're going to publish that
o point it's not enough to just think about and
i think of
five examples
put them into the system get the results and then invented it looks to me
and it's not same
first you always need to do is to think of the proper operation subproperty relations
kind what it should be just she wants clean appearance of the centre
different from these means that you need to think about ways you can adjust present
results of system and tell
reduce the readers
we measure
the quality of our system on the from
twenty five we've got four point one which is a
so this is meaningless because it's not the point of comparison
we need to base
it just claim which
can convince anyone
so what i tried to do that
to prove what just to see what makes sense as i is the based that
sense and also very so i think this is what most people think of in
the context this task so it would have cost
similar sentences twenty
the building model running one
out only after sentences and what want to
get the space is the sequence of
c eight words because this is one of our approach is frame to produce
which is the highest probability with respect to this simple language models so this is
a very simple thing to it
this is still fail the
except baseline because it's not
so it's not entirely different words
random order still has some
motivation concepts in
the configuration which is the
first it
very simple configuration which is referred each edge
which is very and then the final formula which is all those adjustments so here
it is that it's not good to say he was very successful
i spent so much time thinking about how to see the result right so should
always see where this system where you didn't
i always complete suggests that it's not that you need to show that it's not
good enough really needed all the other things
and i did experiments to the initial state and also cycle for languages like russian
job and
french tell
very competent to judge the quality just as
because my
do it myself
it's not the simply thing people just looked OK
but the john results of which is also
creation of this language and all the
has very strict structure so you need to have the second position
if you have a small sentences
and access to the shortest path
the graph
you cannot enforce
so what you get there and it's very likely to be correct
so it took eighteen years english just
a new state considered classes which were not too small to be
something like between ten fifteen years out the average from the rest
i'm prepared to you
you know what
one of the weight so controlling the judgement on this is that we need to
make sure that people
read the output and they agreed that the results
there is also a good of that see some agreement that's why i used for
me speakers for every single august
OK so what we should look like this is one of the things they just
i come to light so this is
this is the one is the bag of whiskers heuristic right so this one when
i just got this small pieces that are on the edge of the network and
then when you come to sell picking community on thousand nodes i just collect the
appropriate basis for them in the back and say this is the clustering right in
the interesting thing is the
this disconnected clusters of clusters that this
from you know data analysis don't have much says
i have a better score better community score than something that is you know nice
coherent connected
so this is a bag of words
and and
the other method here is
if i'm using mac and i post process so you
matt also be disconnected clusters
that but they have a much better for the company
so if all i care about is you know the cluster the partitions or the
number of edges icon then this is the method i should use it but if
what about
let's call the semantics of the clusters then maybe this is not the method i
should use it because it's giving disconnected clusters so what you know exactly what can
i say
so that's the first and
just to complete
basically what is this
if i take the same network
but i my basically fighting the network with the same degree distribution as the network
but i said just and so i think the number of edges in every node
keeps the
and you can see that
then i just basically like an experiment i get something that's flat
unless for this can be used just sort of as a result of its so
what he says that he never much more community structure and if they would be
that's what
before i was trying to make the point that spectral clustering
has issues online
you know on the confuses long path so here is what i mean by that
this is the the graph i want to cut
and if i was the spectral clustering methods
what i mean got basically this is the spectral embedding so the got be like
the hyperplane in this in this space right and you can see that this is
not what i want to like it it confuses the basically the random walk is
the problem of like
mixing over long chains so i don't mix well so i don't think that so
whatever i whenever i can i will cut many edges on the other hand if
i was like some kind of flow based embedding
you know i actually i do i do you think i can't somewhere here and
i just basically this corresponds to that so i'm going to
i just want to go a bit more into
what kind of got to give
to make to make this point more precise so he's he's one one idea so
this is the the methods this graph partitioning of body basically you can see that
is said the better conductance so red is that
right so low over here the better
while using these local spectral that i'm using actually even worse cuts writing you
clusters that when i have to more edges
but the funny thing is
it's actually the real thing gives me
if the clusters that are internally that connects
this is what plot here is the average shortest path length between the all the
nodes in the cluster
and here you can see that
you know blue is below the red meaning that
these blue clusters are more compact
similarly if i measure
the ratio of external internal conductance where the idea is i have the ground i
cut away the cluster and now whatever i cut away i tried to cut it
it's a great honor to be here.
I I I think I might be able to compress some of the introduction to my talk but
because I I think you you summed up very well what what I want why i'm here and what
i'm trying to achieve.
let me start off just by acknowledging
the people who who did the work and thought, many if not
most, are even close to all of the really good ideas here.
these are res junior researchers i've worked with who, you know, over the years are now
gonna become rather senior themselves. Tom Griffiths and Charles Kemp were two of the first students who work with me.
they're now a faculty of Bekeley and CMU respectively, and their work is
sort of very very much the first part of this talk and their thinking
is deeply interlaced throughout it.
Noah Goodman and Vikash Mansinghka are more recent alumni of our of our
group. Noah is now a professor at Stanford, Vikash is a research scientist at MIT,
and that they played the lead role on on the key idea that i'm most
excited about, sort of what I hope will be the climax of this notion of probabilistic
and then I want highlight a few other researchers, Dan Roy and Cameron Freer, who've been
doing some some really interesting theoretical work and helped me think about so the connections
between probalistic programs, their role in cognitive modeling and Turning's original vision for AI because
of course in this year that's what everybody has to think about.
rightfully so.
and then researchers who are currently in our group who've done
the the taken the lead on the main modeling and experimental projects Peter Battaglia, Chris Baker, Tomer Ullman and Steve Piantadosi, actually Steve recently graduated.
so the the goal here, the the way I like to think of what i'm trying
to do, is reverse engineering the mind. i'm trying to understand
human cognition. if I had to choose am I a cognitive scientist or an AI researcher,
i'm a cognitive scientist first and foremost. but the kind of science we're trying to do
is a reverse engineering enterprise. we want to understand how the mind works in the
same kinds of terms that you would use to build an intelligent system, some some kind of
human-like intelligence in a machine.
and we do AI research and other, you know, related work in machine learning, partly for its
practical benefit but partly as that maybemost deeply as a proof-of-principle to show
these ideas, these engineering ideas that we think explain how natural intelligence works actually work.
it's it's rather surprising if you look at how many models, theories, informal and formal
accounts that have been proposed over the years in in cognitive science and psychology don't
actually work as engineering solutions, and that's central to what
we think counts as adequate science here.
as Barr mentioned the
these fields of cognitive science AI have grew up together, starting in the nineteen fifties
and I would say by the nineteen eighties were largely growing apart. cu cognitive scientists
looked at AI and saw a field of people who were increasingly just focused on practical
applications, had given up the big vision of
of real and human-like intelligence and were using a lot of math they didn't understand. and AI researchers looked at
cognitive scientists an and other psychologist and saw them obsessed with strange peculiar processing details that
didn't really seem to illuminate those big questions anyway and
you kno were very fuzzy and didn't understand any of the math that they should be
now these fields are starting to come back together. it's a very exciting time
driven by the shared sense that actually they might have something to say to each other
again and a common language, really that's quite fundamental, a common language in which to say
if you had to say where does this start from, let's start from success.
AI has been a success.
or we're living in an era of real AI success is maybe that's a better way to put it.
certainly this conft had highlighted some of these successes
we're all familiar with them in our daily lives, you know, even those even even if
we weren't all AI professionals here, you can actually read about working AI technologies
in the newspaper, see them on TV, use them in your daily life,
and these are technologies that the early founders of the field, whatever the big vision
they had, they would have to have been impressed, right. clearly these are successes these these systems,
you know, whether it's Google, face recognition, pedestrian recognition systems,
various kinds recommendation systems, things like,
you know, things,
Siri, their the new voice interface to the iphone, which works at least some of the time,
maybe most prominently, the news IBM's Watson
jeopardy playing system, or, you know, after this morning I definitely have to add Google's self driving cars.
I mean, who couldn't've
fail to be impressed by these amazing
and if we have to say well what's what's driving them, maybe the the the
sort of one word, one phrase story is something like statistics. statistics on a grand
scale. massive data coming in through all kinds of sensors and then various kinds of
sophisticated ways of finding patterns in that data. clusters correlations, low dimensional structure maybe even something
a little bit causal.
and that's has not
how could that fail to get the attention of people in many fields, in particular cognitive scientists,
you know, the people like me. I I got into the field in the mid
nineties and well that was well before these successes were hitting the front pages.
you know, there were much smaller scale versions that we also
clearly saw where these were coming from.
you know, the whole probabilistic revolution in AI that was that was the time I was getting in the field.
so that's got attention. at the same time the gaps are also clear. while each
of these systems achieves some human level, maybe even expert level, you know, as good or
better than the experts' performance in some particular aspect of intelligent behavior,
none of them we would say is truly intelligent. some actually intelligent engineers had to built them and
each one of them does one of these things, but compared with with you, you know,
no no one had to engineer you
to solve these problems, to
to, you know, learn how to drive, learn how to play jeopardy. may not play jeopardy as well as Watson
but you only have to watch the game for a couple of minutes, maybe maybe
not even be told the rules, or just be told the rules and,
you know, just a couple of sentences, and then you get it. and you can perform an
endless number of tasks without having to be programmed. you program yourself.
we want to understand that gap. so I want to talk about the the successes that have driven
the reconvergence, largely thinking about various kinds statistical approaches. but how do we make these
kinds of approaches more sophisticated to actually get at the remaining gap?
now let me shift over to the cognitive science side. and so here's the big question that
animates me as a cognitive scientist and a lot of a lot of other work
in our field and we we'll see how this starts to come back to where this
gap is.
wh when we look at at cognition, we see throughout,
whether we're talking about perception,
we see
this this fundamental gap between the data coming into your senses and what you do
with it. our minds build models, abstractions, generalizations but seem to go so far beyond the
data that's there. how are they able to do that?
here's a little demo that is is something that that we've been studying in the lab.
it's it's meant to abstract in a form that we can study
with adults the problem that the child faces when they're learning a word. as anybody who's ever
been a child or or had a child might remember,
a remarkable ability, you see a remarkable ability in children to learn concepts even just,
you know, to label a concept like
table, chair, cup, dog
from just a very small number of positive examples. contrast this with the situation of,
you know, most traditional machine learning, where classification is seen as something that requires many
positive and negative examples. so to remind you of of this phenomenon and how much fun it is
we'll just a little demo here to wake everyone up after lunch.
i've i've shown you these novel objects we made in an object generating program and i've
highlighted a few examples of tufas. and now you tell me which are the
other tufas. we'll just go through this with a pointer. so tufa, yes or
right it's too far for my pointer, my shaky hands so i'll you it like this.
if you can see. OK, yes no. this one.
wake up.
yes or no, tufa or no?
OK this one?
this one?
forested land
and all three
ways of being can on top of on the of entity images and you can
see that you have to do with that
my former sit eleven percent to seventy six percent
so is the typical example where you're going to be not that much
but again a few percent by considering a dual representation in you know in the
nice carnival kind
and i
what i presented so far is just like in the kind design in the simple
setting of course
o canal designs it is a bit and maybe a bit long to do find
new problem in you will have to be able to design the kernel automatically from
data OK let's be lazy
it if you can learn everything from data OK not having to go through all
we should have some nice links with sparsity inducing norms
OK so want to learn the kinds from data
OK so here
kernels there are is not based only constraint i put on kernels that a is
positive definite
so if we restrict the set of that allow the kind of consider so since
cystatin i consider iconic representation of my of my problem so you would assume i
know in advance i can be used in different kernels from my problem so get
images was supposed to be doing kind texture
the shape of a kind of course and i want to combine them in that
so i had to do before summing kernels is equivalent to concatenating feature spaces so
when i some kernels essentially considering one feature space documents
OK and in predicting some of of functions which now functions depend on the thing
so what i do
when you some kernels take x map it separated too few one feature in human
consider the effect of which is also
but in eighteen and you get this prediction function
this is just exactly concatenating the
feature space
so logic is what organisation should i put him
so first what if i put just as the sum of squared norms i exactly
get some of the of the kind of why because
summing the norms describes equivalent to
i think the norm of the concatenation
so now i would like to be able to do something different
and now we consider the sum of the norms without the square
so if this is where we go back to
two sparsity
if that image imagine if is one-dimensional
it is and one not
and now we have is not one-dimensional everybody
so what i want to mention and even sometimes infinite dimensional
so when you do that when you sum of the norms
OK another square the norms you get sparsity at the group level you want to
put the and they have yet to see all and not particularly inside
goal is all of all edges the all
and if not you don't really care about what's happening is if g
so what is we do you essentially
some some of the images and what this means we select good kernels
we can prove that
in fact this is equivalent to learning exactly what i wanted to connect combination of
and the mattresses so this just much involved by the end by using a sparsity
inducing norms which is some of the of the genomes you get what you want
to get sparse in combination of kernels
of course it's a bit harder to estimate than the good anyone on problems because
you have so you have a lot of work trying to do that and finally
of you also have some more between two and analyse when you give guide part
of the kernels
so in most of the work in in this sparsity inducing norm business we tell
you get both
organisation and good this team and then with this selection
but do you actually get
the good model
and you can prove that in the case of the one norm in this case
to get the more
if you only you have a certain condition which is satisfy
and this has led to a lot of work in statistics and the musicians
so what you want to you to use it for
of course
using bioinformatics so stealing between bioinformatics division
and then they had to retrieve it and analyse the data
nowadays she has about on the order of ten high performance
they go in in the spring they have a huge hard disk on they record
twenty four hours continuously until the fall
so now every fall she gets like on the order of five years' worth of
audio recordings
and she has three months to analyse them
so now you know you really have the situation you cannot even look at the
data ones
and this is a typical situation nowadays
so you need some fast method to just scan through for interesting portions and so
on and that's of course in machine learning problem
because it's hard to tell what's interesting
especially if there is the potential for things that you didn't look for
new things
there are some some species of whale out in the simple lawrence where it's not
even known if they have localizations and what they are
so you know if you throw away too much missing that
so this is the typical problem nowadays and that's really the the current problems for
machine learning
these are some of the random examples
one pulsar survey at a receiver with a huge radio dish right in
costa rica produces one tera bytes of data a day
and that's one survey out of half a dozen other running concurrently
on the dish
OK the website over a hundred page requests a second probably google would be on
two orders of magnitude more than that but
google doesn't do
as much adaptation to a customer as other sites do amazonas maybe a good example
because amazon actually
remember suing customize the pages for you and they probably get on the order of
a thousand page requests the second
london has over five hundred thousand security cameras
and again nobody has time to watch all the video
so we clearly need something to cope with that
we need machine learning algorithms but not just any algorithm we need algorithms that can
handle large complex nonlinear models
because the datasets are large complex and nonlinear
by that i mean up to millions of degrees of freedom so i'm i'm happily
consider in problems where n here is on the order of ten million
OK and now this is something ten years ago that would have been considered insane
it's still a bit out of limb but it can actually be done
we need to be able to deal with large volumes of very low quality data
we may have noisy correlated data nonstationary data outliers all kinds of nasty things in
and we need real time online adaptation we want the answer is basically as the
data rules in
that's the typical scenario nowadays
so we cannot actually sort of
collective training set you clean it up
preprocess it
run the algorithm for a couple of days
and then published the result
the modalities is data comes in answers go out
the learning has to happen online in between
now my claim is that
a lot of the current machine learning techniques have difficulty with that
i should maybe say the current optimisation techniques tend to have difficulty with
and here's the problem so classical optimizer
is this iterative process right you the loop over
and in at each iteration and the loop you take function and gradient measurements
and that measurement consists also of the loop
namely over all your data
so you have two nested loops and if you dataset gets big this becomes very
very slow
what you need is online learning here so you need to use stochastic approximation so
that your interleaving your optimize with the sampling of the training data and it all
happens in a single
this is also the scenario that people in signal processing
you know adaptive filtering and so on consider
so far as far as i'm concerned is all near synonyms
the adaptive control adaptive signal processing filtering
stochastic approximation online learning
this old people from different backgrounds talking about more or less the same thing
but bringing different tools and techniques
to the enterprise
here's a little bit what i've already elaborated what have drawn on a whiteboard
you want to
typically minimize with respect to some parameter vector theta
now this is the
a scenario where i'm making a statistical assumptions talking about the expectation over the data
of some loss function that is defined over the data so this is actually the
risk and we approximate that by the empirical risk where we have some sort of
training set from which we sample the data
you can use
and what we
what you
because of the
so think
or you can
what really
trying to use
of course this is
one of my life and
you need to show you know
we are always always always
with the way
i i
try to look like or or
because he
or or
one of them
the problem
even more
he was
the one was the thing that we
you will be when you're
and for a long time and that everybody uses more
you might want
the way
if you might
one of the
proof theory serials then i minister stand still so that the videotape look completely silly
with me just
going back and forth
so we we where we left off was with the
the proof theory and
what i'd like and we talked a bit about the difference between
intuitions logic and minimal launch four we and up talk about about the difference between
intuitionist logic
in classical logic don't talk a little bit about them it's program for using intuitionist
logic is the way of interpreting natural language and then move on from there to
relevant logic
the difference as i said before has to do with the negation rules
so the asian roles
we're effectively those two that gives us minimal logic
so the introduction and elimination rules for negation
those give us minimal logic class
and as elimination rule
that gives us costs intuitionist logic now to get classical logic
these are all that i was calling
that's a
another negation elimination rule a kind of looks like negation introduction rule
and i'm calling negation elimination two
i think called that its
so we have this distinction between negation elimination one in the nation nomination two it'll
come back to that we only get to relevant logic because it has
both of these rules site
with slight modifications
now what is that this rule does for us this rule gives us
very direct play
a proof of that
so in the hypothesis not not a
we take another hypothesis at a
we reiterate our p the first hypothesis again
some of the various systems where you don't have to do that i like to
do that explicitly because some of the week substructural logics that we're not going to
discuss in in
in these natural deduction terms here but some of them don't allow you to do
then we get to have
one that because of these two two and three
gives us
as from the negation elimination
now what we get from as well anything we want
and then we have to think what we want we start with this is hypothesis
and we wanted to prove that
we don't
the that
we from not a we got have
from now on we get at so we can conclude a
that's what we wanted to check that all
so that's
two through four
the nation two
and one through
you know
in this account
one to five
book introduction
OK so that's how we get
what's often known as double then the double negation road obligation elimination rule
that we can eliminate double negations
so not a get a that's not intuitionistic a valid
this also gives us someone mentioned earlier the law of excluded middle
which i had the true of that year and you know it's but
we can do that
excluded middle
so this allows us is a form of reductio argument
we assume the negation
and we try to prove and we prove a contradiction so we
take a right
intuition is often say they don't like reductio argument that's what they mean
the former doctor using a and you get as many can conclude not if they
like that just fine
this this form of reductio they don't like
OK so this thing here is called the law of excluded middle
or land
o experimental
and we can prove it like that
so we take this hypothesis you're looking at this thing what what what what
are you doing here
proving things with a focus main connective very easy proving things where the
negation is the main connective will you know you're going to have to do
something out of the negation is the main connected is here
disjunction as it establishes the main connective negations or something else the disjunction particular disjunction
is main connective that what you want to prove
and this is what we want to prove
it then
do using reductio this form is often a good idea in classical logic intuitionistic logic
can do it so
you have to find another route
disjunctions are actually quite difficult in intuitionist logic is you really do
i need to prove one of the districts
OK from here we get by right
from two and disjunction introduction we get that but that may contradict each other and
that's a good thing
we reiterate one
and we bring that now so that these and we can conclude from those at
so three
and negation elimination
what i we want to conclude
well then
my negation introduction
we get not a
OK what we want and what we wanted a non right
o from monday we can get a an on air
from these two
so this is really expensive
you can also use click through data but then you need to worry about that
so for instance you could otherwise then somebody could actually script bought differences let's say
really keen on my name coming up in your favourite search engine on top
and maybe
you know it doesn't so what i could do is i could just hire botnet
well have query for my name and then click on the link
and that way i can completely skew things
this is why sometimes you might actually want to ground truth
one way
of actually looking at how well i'm doing is what's called the discounted cumulative gain
OK so i need to
explain what this is
basically what you care about is
that the most relevant pages come up on top
and so you will get
a decrease in game if you relevant pages
lies somewhere in the forest in
so is the position where the page is placed
why i
is the score of that because of that
document imply i j
is simply a permutation matrix which places document i
at position j
why i j i and j is one
the combination of i j
and here
for any other towns in that row and column
this is a fairly complicated scoring measure there's also something called normalized discounted cumulative gains
we take this quantity and divided by the maximum value
there's about five other scores you could think of
this means the reciprocal rank
as winner takes all those expected rank utilities
the cool thing is they all look like this
basically you have some term which depends on the position
in another term which depends on the document
and then you just take the inner product between those
this is going to be very useful later on when we discuss ranking
this function here
i guess for psychologists come
i came up with it
there's another variant of this namely the ECG
at k
or NDCG k
and that just as
witness to the fact that well
when you
look for spring summer school on gold
you will probably look at the first ten documents retrieved or maybe twenty documents if
you set your browser this way
and you're probably not going to look at the next page
and probably even within those links you're going to look at the ones on topmost
and for this you want to consider so much
so then it would actually truncate the sum
at twenty
you just look at the first thing to positions and not care about the rest
of course we don't need to perform in school we need the loss
so what we do is we just use performance relative to the base losses four
so they just
have delta of y one and y
being the the city of one in one minus the DCG
of online
so i'm assuming that one
the identity permutation will leave everything unchanged
and i'm assuming that my documents are sort in the right way
causation design loss function
the feature map that actually exploits explicit order
because otherwise i'll get
stupid results but that's easily taken care of
all i'm doing is i'm just looking at the regret
of coming up with permutation pi
rather than leaving the documents or that they are
doesn't even have questions so far
but what we've done is we've now construct the loss
the next thing we need to do is we need to construct the feature map
of course what you want is you would like to design something like pagerank right
that for a query
and the document maybe some user feature
this inner product gives us the score
and this is what you do is you just look at all the web pages
you just computers scores
and then you sort you pick the top ten to fifteen guys to actually retrieve
doing something that at
deployment time
is much more than a simple sort or find that top ten guys operation
reasoning such that provable
using x
the derivation five
and this runs up against the little interesting problem that we discussed way back the
beginning yesterday
it might turn out that way
things like that are true
even though no particular name number
makes the truth
and we were discussing the possibility that for some particular predicate
you might have
a b
but somehow rather you didn't have
but for every particular
o thing in the universe that you have to nine four
p is true
might turn out less
this thing files
and why would that be well presumably because there are some things that didn't get
recall that was i think consistency
there's i you can restate all in terms of existential quantifiers as well
it's an existential quantifier form
will come out this way
it might turn out to certain complex thing is true
like this
this is something is a
but no particular numeral
not zero not
success is zero not success its successors zero
no particular numeral makes this thing truth
i was surprised to discover additional assumption that we had to make about arithmetic
about formal systems
omega complete in this kind of way
does the
the language have resources to name everything that we intend them to tonight
now in our ordinary life thinking about numbers
don't give any thought
we think would the numbers i just
zero one two three et cetera at any other numbers
don't get nine by
rather it
well it turned out that when people started to worry about this and make this
assumptions explicit
but i found what actually is the possibility of
models of arithmetic
in which these things for
so it significant assumption
there are as many
as many
constructing the language
needed to name any particular number that you one night
OK so that's a little thing i'm saying don't want here
right to left in general requires the assumption that there is only reach number
so that's
that's all little bit harder to select that to one side
OK so
the general concept here is proof provability got expressed by some recursive functions
probably by turing machine then just asserted through that there
there must be a recursive function
his recursive function
we can express the first order logic
so somehow or other
if you look through the details of the plan that you find
how the provability predicate would get defined in a particular case
using that we define provability
and that to
just as free for that
it doesn't make it so
still building up some mechanisms
the next thing we actually have to say about
simulating this
effect of the stuff here struggle
it's a list each one of which is either an axiom one
and it turns out that when you start to examine the thing
you have to
figure out what properties it's going to have
here three
typical properties provability
which might not have thought about
there's some things the theorem
then it's going to have to proof
and we want that proved to be expressed
that was the left half thing i put up for left to right
so that proof itself will be expressed in t
we need a little bit more
t itself and i was used to prove anything
that's provability predicate
then then that itself needs to be provable
there is this whole process
this turned to these things all turn out to be
properties of provability that needed to make theorems goes through another come from
from people thinking about the priori
they came from the people
i arguing about this capability stuff
only one
that's all
thank you
so i'm going to present this talk link analysis with bias
i would like to say that the most well actually the whole pike programme was
developed by ludmila but again in the of one that's why i also put those
web world emails here because if i won't be able to to answer your questions
they will
and of course materials elastic is also one of
of the three that
developed this bike program
why is there spider on the left side it's because like in slovenian means spider
that's why and by the next are some kind
networks so that's why everything was called
so far the outline of my talk
i'm going to first
explain how
the network is going to be denoted in this talk what kind of networks are
used in program pike
what kind of data will how do we have to prepare
the data for using this software
then some some statistics
well how some somehow the statistics can be computed by a and with these
this part
the big part is going to be about how
important part of networks can be extracted from
the whole network using different algorithms then
almost at the end of the pattern searching also how it
this is this can be done program pike and well this is just an example
well known example of temporal network and what kind of analysis we did
and the last thing here this is a new program that was developed by a
and october provide it's also one of the statistics students in slovenia and it's supposed
produced animation for temporal networks
so visualisation
OK and then there are some further readings of course with links
so this is quite useful for
the people who want to look
some more
in this bike or
network analysis
OK so the networks
the networks can be presented and will be presented here as
four sets the first two are present
actually from grad so the set of the v is the set of vertices and
a set of lines of course lines can be lines are directed can be directed
or undirected and these are edges undirected and are self-directed
and what we do
also used is the small and will be the number of
vertices in the network and the small and the number of lines in the network
there are two more sense this is
p which is the set of cortex value functions
and we call the properties so
that means that each vertex
you can have a number
attached to read and this is
the this vertex property and for the same for lines so line many functions wise
is the set because we can have more than one
function so more than one different
value offline
for a single line
and they are going to be
well we're going to call them weights
OK so this is the transformation
the lines
go to
some real numbers
are you
so by
go on
why it really
a few people have the right to OK let's go on
so the second thing i would like to talk about this is about a discriminative
so typically people used to hidden markov models here and you using again one of
the learning for improve gene finding
OK so this a big interest in annotating genes so genomes so since nineteen ninety
five have been like one hundred eighty genome sequence
actually already quite a few compassionate towards for gene prediction
however the gene predictions are still very in
and here we would like to contribute something so for instance they were told what
the c elegans this has been sequence in nineteen eighty eight so
the only thing twenty five percent of all the genes in this organism are pretty
good so i experimentally analyzed insufficiently to know the gene structure OK but this fifty
percent which partially analyse this twenty five percent which are completely i mean i'm what
it is purely based on prediction and this is like one of the best analysed
model maybe you would be better
OK so so that's why i mean that's the rest sequenced the other about what
it is and now the question is which gene finding problem which invited program should
be used for annotating that's why there was competition
in get competition and there were some control competition conditions and they call that what
i did my best so i'm going to show you that
it submission for
however tools stages the first stage was and he said well i
so we still haven't got the fisheries
OK so
it's in this picture before being so you would like to model like the different
parts of the gene and we can see this
essentially is the label sequence of so if given the DNA sequence we would like
to predict the correct sequence of labels and these labels are exon intron
excellent OK
so and
we consider a city block model which i think what
and we have a state model which describes the signals in the end of the
so the first part of the transcription start that's just the
thirteen stars
then at some point this the translation start then series by science
and at some point the called
and there's a few other signals which are related to to the which we have
this is the simplest model
so each
state here corresponds to a signal on each transition between states corresponds to a segment
the segment here point is between the stations started building that exon and between the
except the intro
so we have to labels associated with the
a more realistic model looked like this we also have a splicing once the
UTR of community
and we have some additional information which pick up here regarding reading frame rate much
very very much
OK so
we follow a kind of a two layered approach that so essentially we could simply
take the sequence and run label sequence i wouldn't very happy hour pi that sequence
with some string kernels each and the label some some labelled can
but this is going to be to expensive
so what we do here is to be one of the different parts separately
so we want to win since the splice sites in model the translation start the
transcription start and site so on so predictors for each of these different parts then
we tried to combine
OK what kind of things can be one
so it's good to start events translation stop and the acceptor splice site and he
positive examples of training set and a negative sample essentially all the other
so this is a very unbalanced problem
you can also come up the census for content
OK so so i mean x has a different kind of composition that intro so
we also have classifier which can recognise questions
so the typical approach would be to use a position specific corresponding matrix matrices what
i all chains
and here we want to use it to support vector machines you have seen the
results of splicing
the results are quite a bit of markov chains
so there i mean
one benefit of this machine is that what it and they continue to improve when
you use more data
the typically markov chains you've just housing examples and they don't much
so what's
against SVM is that originally
large scale to really deal with large amounts of data so it seems some techniques
to solve this
and SVM still produced
probability score so that we can really easy to use it with lot what's so
that's why we use spectral of learning to combine this one and this one
the idea is as follows so we have this tool a approach and this is
now simplified setting
we only have a splice site
so this is the
in next on the donor splice site and this is the start of in exile
which is the best place to be predicted for every appearance of GT four the
don't that every period AG in the for except
the sequence predict the score
now we consider again true supplies is true splicing of the sequence and wrong splicing
so this might be true but i like to see
so true segmentation into exonintron it is all about
and for every segment i mean every every segment boundary has to be the little
respite one except that some people
OK so we don't like that of every change of thickness think where every segment
boundary we take these by site associated with it
consider the score and see how much it contributes to the cumulative score so like
with the first thing here we have the blues
score here so we get vision here and segment and he
so is a bronze splicing and they have an additional
the documents let's see if you want to see whether part of one document this
copy of
a lot of copy of
another part of some other document again this presentation would be enough
well for any deeper semantic tasks this representation is too weak so we'll just go
further on so the next very typical representation would be that the document is basically
a sequence of words not the sequence of
a character sequence of words
this is a set of the most
common representation for text and most of the basically used these
so the first step is when you have the document b
try to split it in the
set of
works and the this is what we call the book tokenisation and so we
you can do this in various ways
so there's lot of different software packages for this so this is not too hard
maybe it's just interesting to note that the word is quite well defined in this
western languages while it's a already in chinese this is not because the work consists
from a couple of symbols and they don't have the blank as we know is
for no it in our languages so
the chinese is a be different but still this concept is quite important so
delete it works what's
interesting when when we deal with words
the first problem which we
see when dealing with words is this relationships between surface forms of the words
so first of need
so the first
is relationship between the forms of the words and their actions sense
so and this these are for the most common relationship so one is homonymy where
we have the same form but different meaning so
for instance for the world bank
this can mean means either river bank or financial institution so
the world bank needs to be
disambiguate in that sense
so this is
often the problem
so just seeing the world bank doesn't mean that we know
what sense was used
or another problem is policy where we have the same form of word but related
meaning it's again bank would be like the bank or financial institution so
but sort of banks what
what's meetings school something what's different types of
they have different form of word but same meaning like singer vocalist so these are
two different surface forms but
completely the same ink again usually for efficient text analysis we need to disambiguate this
one meaning people
or hypernymy so this is another
issue which we need to with is one word denotes a subclass of another letter
it is part of all sub of the
having this type of relationships usually we don't know this in advance occasionally have vocabularies
for this
which helped but
usually we don't we don't know this in advance so you just need to be
aware that this problem exists and we try to resolve these problems with
proper analytic techniques space
it was also very important which we would see a little bit later that word
frequencies in texts of the so-called power distribution so power law is
something which i would describe and later when we talk about link analysis
it's very fundamental and wallace all techniques in text rely on this so-called power distribution
we see this power law in in the in this simple observation so that so
we have a small number of very frequent words and big number of low frequency
words so this is this
diagram which
is that we see a little bit later on and
i won't go now into the details but let's say this is a very fundamental
property of the text and the never
you see the data with the same
power law distribution you can more less say that's
all the techniques which are used for text mining or text analysis are also applicable
for that particular in image recognition in link analysis in
maybe in some other areas you can you can spot this kind of distribution center
immediately more less you can use
a set of techniques from this area
on that day
i was keep this
the word sentence
stemming so these are just some
technicalities when dealing on the word level
the next presentation would be phrases
so words are just a single units but
location be would be
interested in a sequence of words
which means something let's say
if you have
in the text written in machine learning so if you
if you know the machine learning is one phrase denoting one
particular concept this
this is a valuable piece of information back to the fact that we would consider
this as a separate machine and separate machine and separate words not so machine learning
carries a little bit more information
phrases are
frequent contiguous word sequences so this is something which which we need to know here
and what's interesting
but this is
it's recently so this was
one year ago
this he released
n gram corpus so if you go to this
internet address
you can think or the
the whole corpus
is it you get the package of five DVD's
the impact this sixty giga bytes
and what it is
the event over the whole
english part of their index
basically all the web documents they
from that and they
identified as
phrases all the sequences of words for
dental the standpoint denclue two point zero that has nothing to do with the web
two point there it's just the second version of this algorithm and i thought b
got some
interesting enhancement of the origin of class grows which was published on ninety eight
in KDD conference because of workers collaborative work was intending gabriel just from
diploma diploma student of mine and w
like this first introduced density density based clustering and denclue one point zero
i layout the problem the problem which is seen climbing and reformulated climbing as an
expectation maximisation algorithm then there are some minor issues also identification of local maxima it
has to do this identify the clusterings
and then there's some some broader issues coming like you could apply general techniques to
this new algorithms and i
present some experiments
so when we talk about density based clustering we have the assumption that the clusters
are regions of high
density in the data and we assume the attributes in this case numeric attributes from
a d dimensional space and we have an of those dimensional data points
and the question is how to estimate density there are several answers to this first
you can say we too parametric models
and like mixture models and things like this
this is
something i'm not going to talk about than they are nonparametric models like histograms or
is it more advanced stuff like kernel density estimation
the idea of concept kind of density estimation is to
to model the influence of the data by point by canoe or
in this setting you could also say by generalisation you call a membership function and
the density then its enormous sum of all these kernels
and then there's the parameter coming into play this smoothing parameter called h and depends
on the with
depends on the on the value of this parameter all these comments
small data fusion to the very small then you have basically peaks and
you have many local maxima in the future to be bigger
then you moves datapoints together and you get less local maxima
this is from a song from the textbook in this case the are i'm talking
about goshen college
they are written like this and casey some of the data points and you put
and you apply the kind of function and you have these
data points
going into the kind of functions
so the clustering dental one point here are defined by the local maxima
so clusters
these are the points which
correspond to the same local maxima
so basically these two points in one cluster these are another cluster and the origin
if had an additional part XII which is used to separate between outliers but this
is not of main importance you can choose imagine this to be to set zero
originally we sort we did the following approach to find local maxima climbing the computer
gradients of this density function like this year
and then we started in iteration
starting on the data point computing the gradient and moving a bit into in that
direction of the gradient and we choose to to be constant is constant stepsize and
this created some problems
the one problem is that is not very efficient you make many and this is
this is a small steps in the beginning you see here need many steps to
approach to local maxima
and the second thing is that it does not converge to the local maxima in
the end
if you zoom in here you jump around and you don't you don't converge to
so you just come close to this is something some things which are not too
nice and basically there's other problems we just solve for his new approach
the new approach
can be in
if you don't want to whole series you can mention like this that you take
the density function and
you basically differentiate and said it to zero
you can cancel these constants here and rearranged and you get this equation
but this is not very good this is not the solution because x still here
is kind kernel but you can sink whom i not have a solution but it
can iterate until
do it like considerations and you can iterative to form and this does not seem
what we want it automatically adjust step size
basically at no extra cost if you look
thank you have the same sum over
the data points which we had before here the gradient that the sun appears twice
doesn't matter at the same computation so on the same cost
and yet you have much fewer steps and you really converge
now also question why is this going to work
so this
it's likely this and
first introduction there's no proof but
you can imagine that you
cast the problem of maximizing kernel density function
by rewriting it you
just put
in here the kernel function and in u
reformulated and you can sing it looks like a mixture model humans and components
and what you have something some constraints to piece of fixed and the emus are
set to the original data points so you can think of the density is the
kind of likelihood of mixture model and now the difference deficit that we don't maximises
likelihood of the parameters mu and sigma and p pi
but we maximize over them
but this is this doesn't make a big problem because here in this formula
you can see that you can places xt by mu t this is interchangeable because
of this guy clear here