as sort of a is an intermediate step two
doing then something with this
understanding so for instance your data points
the plane or in high dimensional space and the clusters
and why is he had these clusters
and you want either input maybe
where the clusters of the number of clusters shape classes
related density estimation
OK and then this reinforcement learning which is in between supervised and unsupervised learning
it's usually used in the agent framework an agent like a robot
ect and observe and occasionally gets reward for his
which means
positive remark if it does something good in the negative remarks punishment if it does
something that robert walking around falling down the staircase is negatively what kind of power
block getting which positive or if you play games if you win the game with
eighteen wins game gets rewarded game to get
punish and from this very scars feedback
they should learn and
the field of reinforcement
and the others
which is sort of in between senior supervised learning
quite fashionable in recent days
something in between supervised and unsupervised learning part of the data is labelled active learning
sort of a limited form of reinforcement learning
what is supervised learning
you're in for a rule in newly is
use this rule for
predicting future output
from inputs
or you can use it for knowledge extraction to adjust to understand what is going
or for compressing the data
or outlier detection other application
so here
so i said
supervised learning is see the classification or regression that's roughly true and he a classification
another credit card problem your new customer and you want to evaluate them
where the customers rolls having a credit card which type of credit card and you
have to
point of information given in common
and every savings of the customer
if the customer has a high income and a lot of savings this it's a
low-risk customers
but if you know the income is lower the savings are lowering of the even
are all negative side then it's a high-risk customers
and you could classify so you have some data points here from past experience these
o would grow through the credit card in these customers were fine
and then you could
think of OK maybe this is the boundary here
which classifies them between low risk and high risk and in this case the discriminant
with differences if income is high and savings high and low risk high risk
so that's the classification who
and regression is
they have some input
for instance the age
of a house
he is the average price of this house
they in a given suburb and you want to
now we have a house with this age have no data point and you want
determine what is a reasonable price
so here's data points
they look like maybe they're lying on straight line so you make a straight line
regression which minimizes some error
and then you can
determine the price for
so this ge
both are class both supervised learning problems
OK unsupervised
we have no output
i want to learn what normally happens
for instance clustering
i have an example later
OK so in reinforcement learning
as already mentioned
i want to learn a policy of an agent which acts with environment
so you want to
determine a sequence of outputs which is good in the sense of maximizing reward
if no supervisor which tells
the agent
what to do
what would have been the right action but only the action is
good or bad and also the reward can be delayed and that makes a huge
difference in the design
i rhythms and analysis of the problem
because you have the credit assignment problem
should be above comes later and you run into the exploration versus exploitation problem
they can always has to consider should
what i know and maximize greedily my reward in the next time instant
should the learner a little bit more
walk around
i explores some possibilities
if the agent knows
this doesn't need to
good reverse immediately but
learning means that
may lead to higher revenue in the long run
i mean you all sitting here
learning something
some of you probably in the hope of getting better which later good jobs
learning some more intense
catching up with
most years quotation
i mean some of you learn because they have found in learning but
it's quite interesting i mean why do children like to play they like to play
because they to build it in a good thing because it maximizes long-term reward and
most of you would like to learn
because of
genetic or biological reasons because it's good for survival
or in former times go for survival in the long run and nowadays it's maybe
could force could celery
OK so so some more
ways you can classify machine learning
OK with the slide out of all the slice of the blue and black has
no meaning
OK the blue means that the scope the typical scope of my lecture
my research and not
of this one here
OK so
there's the
the classification between the statistical and machine learning approach to intelligent data analysis and sort
of the good old fashioned by isoco finding good old-fashioned AI i
based approach which is more knowledge-based logic orientated inferring
classic rules and so on
is not zero
so let's have this charge
that move in this direction
and so
there is no current
that is angle theta between them
they are going to be important because it's across product
between velocity and b
these the sign of the data comes in later
you will say
i hope you'll say
well listen then this is ridiculous
the positive charges don't move through wires
it the electrons
the move one vein
responsible for the current
and electrons have negative charge
and they go in this direction
perfectly fine
the negative charge going in this direction
it is mathematically exactly the same as the positive charge going in that direction
in both cases do we agree
the current is in this direction
i have preferred
for mathematical reasons
take a plus b q charge
going in this direction
rather than thinking mind is dq chart that goes with this philosophy that
there is no
difference at all
in the outcome
as you will see
so in this charge
there is a force
this magnetic force
and that is the charge
that equation
thanks me
the ones that drift velocity
and here
is the magnetic field at this location
the current through the wire
everywhere the wire must dq dt
because that's the definition of current
how many calls per second
because there's always security
so i can also write this
as i dt
but i remember a to one
that is p times a
time is the distance
and i call the distance
it's the distance along the wire
put the distance in here now because i don't want to clutter up my
my drawing
so this charge in time
the team
moved over that distance vector
a one
so i can write down for this
product i can write down dl
so i can also write down that
the f of the
well this is telling you
this is the force
over a small segment of the y which has remained dl
i is the current through wire
and b is the local magnetic field at that location the that's what it means
and if you want to know the entire force on the wire
you have to do the integral along the whole
so you have to
one integral
along the entire wire and every portion vl after the
what this
and you get them
a force
which is the vector you have to have those factors victoria
could be paying next
but that's the basic idea
i want to calculate what the force was
on this wire roughly
when we ran three hundred and PD through their
and i make geometry so simple that we can execute that integral
the wire
we had current running through you
which was three hundred and PD is roughly
and we have a magnetic field
it was right in the gap there
the magnetic fields
and that was
ten of the first one
that magnetic field was only operating here
it wasn't operating there
where the target will be the solution and you know the truth is a special
case of junction tree which can be efficiently implemented is arithmetic circuits
that's what happened
so the language features actually dictate what's in the langevin solved
that should actually be happen invisible to the user the destination so gets picked if
you want to say no i really want to use algorithm for this second set
of parameters to do that
but representing things in this way
does not imply that with maxwell into the
max maxwalksat happens to be the thing that we have implemented a
we actually have something else which is a graph cut algorithm which are all these
problems is enough we have an incompetent or can one incorporate is a general purpose
exact inference of
so that's that's a very good question and you know it's important to realize that
all i'm talking about here is the language in which you can represent things and
you can write complex models in this way
do inference that depends on the organs have under the hood
OK so
let's look at an even more ambitious examples
let's try to do information extraction
so information extraction is of course very important problem these days is the problem of
extracting database from text
also some sources like web pages or XML or spreadsheet and whatnot
and of course the canonical example of this is that it have a lot of
research is expecting editors of publications from citation lists the citeseer problem not in the
internet example that i gave before i assumed that the data was already pre segmented
into database records and all i need to do is figure out which records correspond
to the same paper
here i'm going to go all the way to start with the raw text as
the input
and i'm going to do that by combining two of these models that we just
saw before so one of the
it's going to be into resolutions
the other thing that we need to do segmentation
we need to go to the input string of each citation and figure out what
is the author whereas the title was the venue
and for that we can use an HMM
or more precisely than is the CRF because it's going to be trained discriminatively but
this is a typical people police for segmentation is to use an HMM or CRF
to label each position is being you know title author venue or whatever feels interested
it could be you know city person organization et cetera
so what can we do this
well here's the complete ML
that does information extraction for you
it contains
four predicates and seventy four
i should think about it this is quite remarkable because if you want to wrote
in information extraction system you know using java c plus plus it probably wanted to
thousands tens of thousands of lines of code and politic you weeks to do
in alchemy you know just need to write these seven short formulas that offered on
this slide
so what are the formalism as predicates well
all i did was go together the HMM and into resolution approach that we saw
before so we have to come now
it's going to be predicted good position and the citation is argument so this is
this just this is going to be the evidence
the input it just says what's the kind of each position in the input
and then in the field
so that this position is in this field in the citations so this is what's
going do the segmentation
so this could say that position one in citation two is in field
and then same year the same citation are into resolution predicates that we saw before
and now
here's the HMM segmentation it says
here's the observation matrix if you will it says there
this talk
is indicative of this you so this is going to learn the correlation matrix between
tokens and fields like for example conferences very indicative of a new so is journal
if if positions
i is in the field after them so its position i plus one
notice that here i don't have time anymore
because for four
for segmentation it's actually not that important to model the complete transition matrix between all
feel types all you really want to model is the phenomenon that you tend to
stay in the same feel time if and the title you probably going to be
in the title for a few more tokens before he switched to see that
so to do that you just leave the formula in this form you learn fewer
parameters and naturally you know generalize better because there's this true parameters to learn so
that's what i'm doing here
and and here's another subtlety
in general
the position when he might not be any of the fields and the way people
typically do this is by introducing this pseudo field called the
but the is is because now you the correlation between various things another and of
course it's a list of a bunch of things a lot of very well anyone
something quite nice well here
we we can allow we don't need to explicitly introduced another type all we need
to do is relax the restrictions that the skills be mutually exclusive and exhaustive
let me thank you for this wonderful talk
in professor chomsky here is that the problem is provided in shows the monash elbassuoni
the largo b
so that is the economic another chance at what i felt pressure and you not
be similarly lists alibi set
it's the easter island usually you publish on started
studied this enzyme microphone you need so that familiar that could go to the museum
of critical reviews per channel
you my colleague of so much then capability there
not be solid mechanics in
this this a good evening is actually is needed to separate the process so that
is not shown here
it's all to the as was this
it was among the started to
but it still needs saying that within so that only as the microphone
the question is going to be
the reason i really
the only thing preventing
the cook blood pressure in in the sentence
this one
OK you liberal
professor chomsky
you may not be aware
that we have
two US embassies
in slovenia
one of the first one in slovenia
it is located at the very centre of ljubljana
with an official figure in the person of US ambassador why other american embassy quote
books are because
all over slovenia is in the society
libraries and private sessions
of american authors like you know
it's a
citizens on that
norman mailer and many others
which of these
representations of america is chomsky
and indeed the representative of the base
well actually
the first comment until i heard the rest reminded me of
something that i was told by an old
friends and close friend who was the
middle east correspondent for
television in the united states you've probably seen him on television
he once told me that ABC had three
offices in
one was in japan
one was in tel aviv and one was in jerusalem address the issue of the
as for the two american way
this were you know that's really something for you to decide that
if you look closely you'll find
documented the distinction that a briefly mentioned
mainly there's a very sharp divide
american public opinion
and the
consensus of the two
political parties
the media
and the intellectual classes quite generally
on issue after issue
i mentioned if few
major issues on which there are sharply divided
but it extends quite generally
just to and it's not reported
i mentioned that these major studies were not reported right just prior to to the
us election which illustrates i think the recognition
on the part of editors that it wouldn't be a good idea to let people
so that others share their opinions
people should feel isolated and helpless and there's plenty of more evidence about this
for example the federal budget government budget was announced
in february months ago
and shortly after it
the most important institution in the world that monitors public opinion and academic based in
tution in the united states carried out an in-depth study of
public attitudes towards what the budget ought to be
and it turns out that attitudes are diametrically opposed to the budget just about every
so large majority of the population
i felt that there should be cut back in military spending huge substantial increase in
social spending
more spending on support for the united nations
more spending on foreign aid
continues like this
exactly the opposite of the budget that was approved by congress in just about every
major respect
well which is the real america
the complicated story let's take for example the war in iraq invasion of iraq as
in this example to illustrate the complexity of answering the question
about seventy five percent of the population
i think it's you with enron two
invade iran
iraq was developing weapons of mass destruction
to use against the united states
and it was cooperating with al-qaida two
organised terrorist actions
using weapons of mass destruction
against the united states is similar to the september eleven bombing
so that seventy five percent
who say the words wrong
that was the case
even the government has long ago conceded that there wasn't any truth to this claims
nevertheless fifty percent of the public
roughly still support war looks like a contradiction
until you
i realize that fifty percent of the public still believes this claims
government media propaganda system is sufficiently powerful
so the people continue to believe the the claims
we can look at the unlabelled part of distribution to really strong
some probability
there exist two hypotheses in
capital h
which there's a disagreement
this is the key e
the key difference between
this active learning and cow
is in the definition of h
h is going to be defined as
this is the boxes
you might eventually converge
rather than set of policies which are consistent with all labels you've seen so far
that is the sort of the key difference
so one biggest the it's the bounds and the bound arithmetic which is going to
control you know the number of one might eventually converge to this
that's a very simple question
i don't know the answer i think is is the answer
we're not really using the line here
the valve is going to return
an epsilon optimal hypothesis with probability one minus delta
and so we need to what the problem that this recursion process america's best going
to terminate at at some point
two new termination condition
to termination condition is going to be that the
the difference between
your upper bound your small of around and small slow around in times the disagreement
is this this person and so on
OK so so these are the basic
and this is the are so
if it is inherited you want to fit in any set of classifiers
you can check initially to see that
you not done
and then we have this inner loop here
which is going to say
given to labelled examples
weekend decreases as the path space
so we start with no labelled examples
and we start with
so we have our current hypothesis space
we have the new one they going to create after we you're a recursion that
we're going to
finished the recursion step
when the size of disagreement region
or inequalities around way
two what this
and on the right way
right so h primal will are store for the old one
and we want to
recurse by factor of two
one side the disagreement region to decrease for factor of two
OK so we have to cheque to
it's possible we reach termination condition inside the loop so it so we are done
if not
we're going to double the number of
unlabelled examples on which there is disagreement
so we're we're going to take a bunch of unlabelled examples that could be from
the stream from pool
i which there's disagreement for a current about the space age
and are going to ask label for these examples
they're going to
are upper bounds and lower bounds
what what
new reduced
of hypotheses it's prime we have
or keep doing this
we managed to have the size of the disagreement region
so this is just
this is saying
so the complex way because we don't know in advance how many labels
we need
we ask what we label enough
on current disagreement region
to have the size of the beam reached
and there and then we have this recursion step here
and at the very end after done we just returns the past this inner meaning
ten six
that is a good way
that's really good
there's always turns out
but you're right that that's why it's not being used here
you have questions
so there's various things you can prove about this
some of them are pretty straightforward
the claim is that
very easily passes and for any distribution including ones with arbitrary noise between the x
and y
for it was at someone
with very high probability you can make this be anything you want
even to return and have some of more classifier
OK so the that's says that
because in supervised learning you have learning algorithms PAC learning algorithms which have these kinds
of guaranteed although
so it is if you know your computation you can you can get cancer guarantees
generic and so
so maybe the numbers was acquired one being something like the VC dimension divided by
epsilon square
or something like that
so this is the a safety guarantees
this is another safety guarantee you can say
for every
the hypotheses very distribution
the number of labelled samples is not much worse than in what you get for
supervised learning
and the can probably see whether that's true mean in the worst case you never
and if you never occurs you just using the standard upper and lower bounds for
supervised learning
and then the termination condition is about things which you would get with supervised learning
OK so now
i would like to do better so the claim is
for all hypothesis spaces for all distributions if you have disagreement coefficient of theta
and some
VC dimension
now we're going to have independence
new parameter
which is no
so this is this
the minimum error hypothesis
in you said about six
the core the the the colors
a walk at their own pace so to speak and then the smaller the wavelength
close it will be to to zero order and then the spacing between first and
second will also be smaller than in the case of the long wavelength in this
case red
and this is something that i also
i want to demonstrate to you it is not so easy
you get a very strong
a powerful source of white light
i'm using for this a
a reflection grating you can also
use gradient in reflection you take metal and groove metal on metal
and you get a reflection which we will
have there on the wall
this reflection grating
has a spacing in which is four times smaller
then the one we have here
it's only two and a half
microns so the angles they don't one one the three and a half degrees but
it will be four times larger
the main purpose why why i want to show you this is i use white
light that zero order is white
and then we'll see also of course the first and the second order
if we have
good eyes because of the the whole thing is not so
so very bright
make sure that i have the
so your eyes may have to adjust a little bit to the darkness
if x is not overpowering because light source is not very bright
what you see
here's my laser pointer this is the zero to maximum
and there are the maximum is very wide
the reason is the divergence of the
white light beam
it's not this factor of and again again much less
i can turn on also
these are
which i was at the same time
you'll see that the red laser
give its own
then they come to the zero order of the red laser is of course also
you all colors a year
and then you see here
first order of the red
a large angle with these very small you see in the first order of the
red second order of the red
you see the first order of the blue
first order of the blue you see a big difference
between the separation
of the red
and the separation from the zero order
and the blue big difference
there's actually
a much better way
that i can make you see all this
and that is
if i ask you which i think i'm going to do now
two usual grading this hold all the four seconds before you get your
your on gratings out
our equations
that we have the right so far
only hold
if we look very far away
these angles of fatah only through if you go very far away
for reasons that we discussed last time
because the surfaces of maxima hyperbolas
and is only the angle theta is only an approximation if you very far away
we can however
do something very clever we can use the lens
and if we have elements
we can bring in it's very close without disturbing the angles
this is degrading
the number of sources that i have
and so the light comes in this direction
and if i put here lens
this is the screen
the focal point of the lens
and if
the angle theta
if the angle theta
for which
i would have expected
in this direction
my first order maximum and you of course my zero or the maximum
then the lens will not change that angle
we never discussed lenses so it may not be so obvious to you
the ends will always maintain integrity
of angles
the angle theta that we derive here is the correct angle but of course in
terms of x
that's enormously reduced if this distance is very small
so when we have the option that we don't have to
allow for very large distances like now ten meters
and so your eye is the perfect tool
to use for that because you have lens in your
in UAI that's the whole idea here and so i want you to get your
gratings out
and i want you to hold the gratings in front of your eyes
and manipulate the gratings a little bit
so to you get the lines vertical
you will easily
he able to do that
this is your light source
o lines
you're gratings a thousand lines per millimeter
that means the spacing of your grading is one micron
one micron is
ten times smaller
and this number solely angles are you in your case
the way larger than what we have there i will make it completely dark
and then i want you to
i rotate
creating such that you get this backtrack on either side on the left and on
the right that means you're
groups and then
in vertical direction
and what you see now
when better than what i could show you my previous demonstration
you see the zero order is the lamp itself
all the colors right at the center that's the land that user and maximum
and then you see
if you go to the right
you see the blue coming in beautifully first because at the smallest wavelength
going further to the right you see the first order red
with the acceleration
now comes the fact that we discuss their that nothing goes out in the direction
of the acceleration
and go out in this direction so no electric field is produced in this direction
and the maximum is produced in this direction
and somewhere in between here
that is there
reflected by
the sign of data
a is zero
nothing goes down
if data ninety degrees you get the maximum that's the whole plane perpendicular to the
oscillating charges whole plane
maximum electric field
and then
that may
not be so obvious to you now
it's also inversely proportional to the distance are
double are
electric field strength goes down
a factor of two
and the poynting vector
which is the product of a and b
he is or proportional to be
so the poynting vector then
is proportional
to q square
proportional to the square proportional
designed square of data
and inversely proportional
we are square
that is obvious that it has to be inversely proportional which are square
because if you go if you ever sphere
radiation goes out
and you twice as far away
then you know
that the area of the sphere is four times larger
and so the amount of energy per square meter must be four times slower so
the poynting vector must fall off as one of our greatest conservation of energy
and if you accept the fact that the poynting vector falls was one of our
square then the vector must always one are
because the poynting vector is the product of and b
bnb must both fall of
as one of or
i want to show you
a picture that may help
the radiation
electric field is
oriented relative to a
charge that we are accelerating in the middle here
the accelerated charge up and down
frequency omega
whatever radiation you want to make
fine with me you can make only as large as you want
one thing i as these these waves here these snakes
represent electromagnetic radiation and nothing is going on in this direction we understand why
the maximum is going out in the plane
to this direction that is this this this and this
and notice that the vector that you receive when you're here
is perpendicular to are this are
and this perpendicular
and notice is what i said that a
and the
in one place
eight which is the acceleration
and he e in one place
i e e i in one place
i e i in one place
so you can always determine the direction
of the oscillating
electric fields
and if you go at an angle fade out which is neither zero which here
nor ninety degrees which is here here and here but if you have something in
and notice that the effect here is drawn a little smaller
that that sign state here
and consequently the poynting vector in that direction
will be smaller than in this direction and in this direction the poynting vector
will be
we call this radiation where you here or there are there are there we call
the linearly polarized radiation
for the simple reason that the electric field
it is oscillating in one direction
it's linear
and i'm going to produce for you
linearly polarized radiation
and i have two demonstrations for that
so i get the lights back on again let's discuss the
i have here
which transmits at
ten gigahertz
that's a wavelength of three centimetres
you wouldn't call the radio you would call the radio that's just a matter of
and we have also a receiver we have the transmitter and we have a receiver
the transmitter is here
and the receiver is here
to give you a three-dimensional picture
this is my coordinate system this is coming straight out of the blackboard to you
that's what i meant by this
then the
it is aimed like so
just like this
current is going to be oscillating like this
and the receiver
i think of this is my radio which is receiving
it's here
and the intent of the radio is also in this direction
and so
the electric field
which you see here which comes from these oscillating charges
which also made by the way over here the frequency
ten billion times per second
the electric field
is perpendicular to are these are
and the electric field
are a and one plane
so that means
that the electric field that right here is also leading like so
and therefore this on ten this receiver is very happy the radiation comes in exactly
in the right way
and so it will receive it
we have modulated this signal with an audio signal amplitude modulation as we discussed earlier
but you also use radios
and we modulated was approximately one kilometres audio signal
i will make you listen to the audio signal you can tell them
this receiver is indeed receiving the three centimeter radar
from this transmitter that's what we will first two
well this turn on the
new year one
and received by the time straight line like this
administrators really goes from here
i put my hands in between
my hands up to three centimeters
it's not there anymore
really optimizing
the controller learn dynamics model
through usually ten twenty iterations
you get to a point where it fully and the flight entire trajectory
is something called a learning control it's where you know you do the same task
as we use that knowledge to find your controller through real world trials
so go back to step forward after around this loop about
ten twenty times
busy for about an hour
and use the top result you get
what you see here is completely autonomous
starting on the ground
helicopter flips over
and it shows that this particular airshow show was i stand it would demonstrate all
past capabilities in the first five sections and everything after that's what people couldn't do
so however was done before
this was done before it's a profile by absolute
centralized before starting with done before
now on these manner somebody was able to do
it looks
it was a great
here which at the top
stopped and that's the way generation where you climb rather than burning
your kinetic energy the fraction
can fast circles these helicopters are
about their blatter's eight hundred millimeters long almost immediately for single label itself goes up to fifty miles per hour
so this thing is quite pretty fast and coming down
and this is all the hardest manoeuvres wired is the hardest manoeuvres
when stay in place
helicopters working in areas just pushing around
so it's much harder to predict what the influence on the air flow is
on the helicopter
and then we do this we
done that you haven't seen this particular video are autorotation landing which i mentioned earlier it's where r u
let's say your engine dies
you still might come down safely what you do is
your helicopter blades will set you back some exactly like it when turbine but you can think about the way
and absorb here also energy
in two plates spinning energy which there will be burned on diffraction
and so you can still land relatively safely
usually in a relatively high water will be broken the people in the helicopter will survive it's well done
now the thing is something called cows it's worth you're essentially flip around the place
well spinning the tail around
the sum of the minimum that we've done that when this take part this figure
show but it cannot completely entire repertoire our pilot had
one question might ask yourselves okay you maneuvers step
extra powers can do but
maybe you're doing very nicely you're just kind doing them they look good but they weren't well done
let's take a look at how well done they work
so remember white is what we're trying to fly
and black
it's how because we were so lucky showing
where you actually was
this is a graph actually play with this replay
recordings position orientation and the helicopter is actual flight they were replaying here
shown that were within a metre of where we were asked to be
this is very high accuracy even for people who spend their lives on fine-tuning helicopter hover controllers
they get one meter accuracy that can be pretty happy
okay so fly exactly where we want to fly
how to teach helicopter to fly
by mean extra powers
machine learning are and
so should the court probabilistic inference
then we combined
with the optimal control together and defined maneuvers
well the point that they change anything control side
we just
will read a lot of control papers
tried a lot of things and conversion of control stick just make me down
would work best for our problem
and although was or indeed learning the specific dynamics models forties trajectories
made this work and exactly how a digital-only control which is a little different from
what other people have done before
but in general they could be more than one normal
process usually make sure
number processes and only one
and the third and most
sorry of outliers may
represent different classes of generating mechanisms
so the outliers the set of all points may be very large
the basic model
usually assume that outliers are observations and not
i said all that's not very large
so these three
basic points here
should illustrate the basic intuition behind the statistical
approach by balkans is very limited
and you need more
techniques to
conquer nowadays data
so the consequence is that a lot of models and approaches have evolved in the
past years
in order to exceed limitations
and yes i think not
that's easy to keep track of of the solutions so one
m of this tutorial courses
try to give you
some of you know this
and what's very important is if you look at specific outlier detection
models and approaches is
each of them usually
involves sometimes you
but very typical
assumptions and restrictions and
very often these assumptions and restrictions are hidden
are not explicitly discussed in papers
but usually each paper for each approach
has one
at least one
you have to keep this in mind when we
discuss different different approaches to action
so there are generally some general application scenarios
first of all we have supervised scenario
because in some applications you just training data
o of normal and abnormal data
and in this case you can try to train the classifier
this is a supervised task
usually this is an unbalanced classification problem
because you usually have a lot more
normal observations the training data that
OK you have to
the second scenario seems to provide
so in this case usually have just training data for one class
normal distribution or
the abnormal
data points
and you have to learn again
rules that bias
to do the job
and finally we have them so unsupervised scenario where we don't have any training data
and in most applications this case i don't think and
in this tutorial we focus on the unsupervised scenario
so you won't find in this
the tree nothing about supervised things like to julian
if we are talking about unsupervised learning unsupervised data mining then
maybe you
just have a question that
is it
is also detection very related to
and similar to
clustering so our allies not just decide do
clustering algorithms
true on the first side maybe because many clustering algorithms
not assign all points of course but can come from noise of the
the option that applying one of those are in
retreat noise it as outliers
but there are some problems with this because clustering algorithms are usually optimise find clusters
and not
find out so
it's more orthogonal than
it's related of course but it's these two
problems of detection clustering are called
and that means that the accuracy of all the detection depends on how good the
clustering captures the structure of the cluster
and not how good it
he then defies of
and again a set of
vlachos in nuclear physics
i'm going to
give you some examples of recent studies that are made nowadays so
the samples
experimental and theoretical studies
so they are made only
all of the world so
in many different places and some are made here is that these are facilities
so i went first to describe the figure of merit of the present approaches theoretical
because of the new computer were very high now we can make some systematics and
really challenge the theories
and to compare extensive comparisons between theory and experiment
so then if we have something which is close to experiments we can hope to
make some predictions for all these exotic nuclei
i will talk quite a long time about exotic nuclei
and this is there are really many many experiments were related to these
i will talk about the isomers so isomers are metastable states
they can appear in different class region and
there really
had to go down to structure
of the nuclei
we talk about shape coexistence search for super heavy elements
and then i was in this way is hope to test fundamental symmetries
for example of the weak interaction
so today is really devoted to class structure
so tomorrow we we talk about the reaction in the vicinity but sufficient to to
their structure
so first figure of merit of the present approaches so this is one example
so this has been a panelist mean field based approach is so the beyond mean
field but still the main assumption has been
that means so you have a comparison between very
in experiments for the first two plastic citation
the energy of this exhibition in even even nuclei
there are five hundred fifty seven
experimentally observed to press levels
and we have calculated all except sixteen
these like one
so the you know why we have eliminated this light elements
so the answer is the mean field approximation which is not valid for human birth
nuclear sorry
because when you're doing so it's an average
you are a very cheap over all the particles
so you need to to be valid to have huge number of nucleons of particles
so that's where we
that's why we don't trust
calculation for very small systems
so that's this is the energy experiments for perfect calculation it would have been the
straight line here and you see that we have some scatter point
so in more detail as you see that this is this is the same feature
is energy spans three orders of magnitude from twenty kb to three mb
it's really a challenge for any theory to represent two want to reproduce feature that
are so different from one place to the other one
so you see here the following states we have a very good agreement
we have the experiments
if we look in more detail we see that its for strongly deformed nuclei
so it means that these
approach works well for strongly deformed nuclei
here it's not so good and it appears in fact for semi magic nuclei
magic nuclei stanley magic light nuclei
so we can explain why we don't have such an agreement
it because as i told you yesterday there are different ways of exciting and you
can use either can be collective like
rotational it's different vibrational
or it can be of individual excitations from moving from one show to the other
this mechanism is not allowed here
and here
it should have a role in so you should have cooking between these intrinsic excitations
and collective motion of nuclei
and that's why we don't have such a good agreement
is because of these that has been here
and here there are six
bad nuclei where we are completely and in fact it's for some neutron deficient later
mercury isotopes
and we are now lies in that it seems that is because of shape coexistence
so we don't have the right information
of these nuclei and
since the energy of the two places is
related to these deformations
if we don't find the good information at all
we are completely so
a lot of work is no
that they can to improve this and all to understand better this nuclei
we have also calculated quadrupole moments
of these different to close states differently so this is also very experiments
so there are not so many experimental data
this is there some
and you see that we are quite close to the experiment
and even better we can make some predictions because in this case
some displays the dominant thanks to
the sign of the moment was not known so we don't know if it was
tried to relate
so what we have done that we have the them twice positive information first and
they get minus the
and it appears that for agreement very
we can predict that this nicolai are prolate
with a negative quadrupole moment
to summarize all these which has been published in different papers again that the series
appears to be reliable
and that some predictions can be made in exotic nuclei
so now this is the subject except technique
there are different topics that can be studied with exotic nuclei for example neutron and
proton drip lines had to a new shared structure
anybody want to try
come on
yes what you say
two people holding hands pressed together very good anybody have different readings
yes and that yes
dancing bears
OK gotta right here named
reported it helps to know that that thing is that i think is very good
anybody else one other yes
a man in a as
it turns out
that there are right answers and wrong answers or shock tests
according to the test this is from a real rush shock tests
it is important to see the bodies two human figures
usually females are clients
good work over there
if you don't it's seen as the sine of problems relating to people
if you want to go for cave friends or butterfly or vagina that's also okay
the raw shark test is
transcendental useless
it is when it has been studied and explored and it is as useless as
rolling dice it is users is leaves
none the less
people love it
and it's use all over the place and it is used for example in child
custody cases
if if you've broken up with your partner and you guys are quarreling over who
gets to keep the kids you might find yourself in shrinks office looking at this
and in fact this is why
they end up on the web their services there are people have been kind enough
to put on the web
using plots
including the right answers
to them
but they are worthless as psychological measures
can we do better well
we probably can
the study where he went through the dictionary and took all of the traits that
he believed to be related to personality and he got eighteen thousand
but what was interesting was
they were necessarily independent rates so the traits like friendly
so see about
while komi warm-hearted
seem to all tap the same thing
so could tell
and many others try to narrow it down
try to to ask the question in how many ways
people's personalities different from one another
how many parameters of different you need how how many numbers
the can i give you that was narrowly wins and say what personality you are
one approach was from icing
who claimed or just two
you could be somewhere in the scale of introverted extroverted
it somewhere on the scale of neurotic unstable
and these are basically two types of traits with two
settings each there are basically four types of people
later on he added another trade trade which he described as psychotic system versus non
cicadas is and the cruelty meant whether your aggressive are empathetic
and three traits with two settings each giving you a types of people
later on
i can tell
drop down to sixteen factors
so the sixteen personality factors are sixteen ways people with different
and so if i ask you to describe your roommate
along the sixteen dimensions you should be able to do so
more recently people have come to the conclusion
two or three is too few
but sixteen might be too many
and there's psychological consensus on what's been known as the big five
and the big five personality factors
are these
and what this means is when we talk about each other
and use additives
the claim is
we could do so in thousands of different ways but deep down we're talking about
one of these five dimensions this means that when the psychological
test measures something about somebody
about her personality if it's a good test is measuring one of these five things
and that means that as people interacting with one another in the world these are
five things that we're interested so one of them is an erotic verses stable
is somebody sort of nineteen
and in wearing or they com
x river introvert
open to experience versus close to experience
which is a courteous friendly versus non agreeable
rude selfish
the value of the appropriate each mistake
then i can
capello lower bound on the image page
OK or even equivalently i can find a lower bound on increase of these difference
is the same thing
then i can use the
one the number of mistakes made by you in terms of the
object SVM objective
so this is the
the clear
but this is actually easy
this is actually needed that
but it was quickly
in that we just
so we are interested in by number of things not not the loss of the
square of the interval in two
but directly number of mistakes
so we get a slightly weaker commitment for you you one
because it is
angelo describing losses is always nicer
the with
we claim
that whenever he makes mistakes
that the man of one
x being
one of the around
this implies
but the value of the dual
of the game
when p is chosen
the optimal values
at the start
he was one of four
is the least
but these are
times the
all that the minus one
so remember that out the star
now that i'm not sure how
this can be
we know that everything is bigger than one
and we know what it is but it so it
once again these people get the mistake bound
just because a lot the the one
but the main thing that we know that this is the same
and then let me take healthy because i'm assuming for simplicity of all the
writing this many
that i'm assuming that this is the normalized for just for the sake of simplicity
and he is at the
o that the human one
so lot of the of the guy that we are going to update
OK two cases
this is the mean
i the mean we have to look case one
i mean is actually by l
i mean is achieved by LP so the loss of the minus feel that determines
what's more c
so now we compute the
of his are
we you have written
on your notes
every year
so check should be equal to minus
which was the first negative but there
quit because they were the output feedback
we can expect
which is
which is exactly
but these are have been because of what he is the case
after the star
is that because it's
half of our everyday and i have
a second case
this is more the LP
then the the eighteenth of all the things that are
we have minus serious growth high
laugh at sea
now i know
c is more entities b and c
and i know that is positive so i can be
i can make this
smaller by replacing one of these is seen year
one minus the
l p
plus a
l in equal
which is equal to the game
how is our
and and and and they both case
for what is that we have this
it inequality here
we can now what this is about one
i write it here because something
i have
so what we know here we can write
WP minus one is the indicator function of the one making a mistake that he
this is
find mean
see common ones
this is that most
what is the most that
and that
of WP minus one
why because that mistakes
this guy bigger than one and this is an indicator function
times we
the extra row and column of cake
that's why it's difficult to embed new data points in all these algorithms they actually
tend to work with a fixed number they point however it is trivial to introduce
new data feature
so that's something we're not used to thinking about doing because normally we won't parametric
models i theta model so i'm going to classify all you people here as
i don't know
what i classifier was
something classifier used as as as the
of friends or enemies now
and every time i see one if you like classifier as a friend or enemy
of data about u i know what you're likes and dislikes are yeah
but what happens if i find a new big data about
what do i have to do in the standard parametric modeling framework
i have to learn a new model
so if you wanted say if i'm asking questions and deciding whether i like or dislike u
and i say
do you like or new feature
how to accommodate within a model which is a classic independently across data points i can't
not without refitting the model
but in this model i can trivially just as you can introduce new data so
that fixed number of people in this room
this is the right way of doing it someone else walks in the room
and i have problems i have to rethink this model
but model every time ask a new question i have to refit the model
the point in i mean the lesson from this bit is
just because you what all things in a certain way doesn't have to be the
way you think about things in the future
because large computers and so on and so forth mean that things are slightly different
this is always from the classical way statisticians will teach you things and i think
it's much more interesting to think in these weights consequence model definition
there are problems by doing models way as we just described but there are also things things become easier
so what's going on here another point about this is
the covariance interpretation we were looking at before about how we get the distances from
these models what we now know is this is a new kernel matrix is the
inverse about classy we saw before
so in all these models what we were doing with canopy see and view is
we are doing and i can value decomposition on kauai
taking the largest eigen values
we're seeing that little plasticine is inverse okay plus a diagonal constant that doesn't affect the i can vectors
so what that's saying is
me skip because i can talk about and realize how about the next
and also
short time
the i can decomposition and the covariance is this
the i can decomposition the laplacian is fact
so how these related
the i can vectors are the same
but the igon values are one over each other
and there's also this annoying little guy
he doesn't affect the i vectors
he has to be there for the mass
principal eigen values okay
are the smallest igon values for all
so in other words
when you're doing the smallest igon values at the laplacian igon maps and locally linear embedding
you're just doing the same thing you're doing kernel pieces maximum variance unfolding
but you're operating on the glacier
why is operating on passing a good idea
where they come from where
you need to compute the inverse
actually don't really invested in igon value problem anyway
because was you i can values the universe is just a matter of inverting
he igon values
you don't need to compute
like about problem
so because the power methods and so on and so forth i can vectors and this easy to extract
i convicts on this slow to extract
so you should if you can operate on this
and what this i mean i haven't what is through maximum variance unfolding what the
implications are that it would be really nice if you could maximum variance unfolding never
specify capability that's why slow you gotta specify the full matrix kay
which is actually depend on some sparse
not network underneath
so nice algorithm it it's slows the result
isomap doesn't quite fit into this framework doesn't because isomap we never actually that they
whenever define the probabilistic model we don't look a little plastic
what goes on in isomap is your feeling in you can work out what implicit kay was
you're not filling in
the elements okay by
maximum likelihood or anything as i'm suggesting hear just putting them by shortest distance on a graph
it turns out have short on time so you have the time to go into
the details on this but the distances that are associated with these models are effectively
random walks on the graph going across all possible routes and the sum across all
diffusion distances on graphs so in one case
for the
last in models
what you the distances they are implied are the distances associated with summing across all possible routes in the graph
point is born up here which is then
splits into two critical points and then t is equal to five
the first critical point which came from way back merges with one of these two
and the other one survives and goes on
for the first question that follows the situation of the critical points of the function
f as time goes on depending on time
one it again
here it goes
OK so this is a very very simple example
just to illustrate
what for
talking about here
so this parameter all this algorithm was actually applied to serious computer science application
taking part of it so this is this was used to design an algorithm for
teaching a robot the concept of occlusion so robot with an onboard camera
was or was taking pictures of simple scene which if i understand correctly consisted of
coloured balls and and then as the robot is moving around these two boss at
certain stages you see both of them and then eventually one of them will be
covered by the other one and now the analysis of the critical points on the
images or give give you information about the song clues and this was used to
be devised an algorithm for teaching a robot the concept
here's an example that we did together with gregory set which shows the naive way
of using well and they've approach of using this parameter discrete morse theory for sequential
image analysis analysis now for computer scientists which is the majority of the population here
i apologize because this is not the serious and i know that there are many
many many very good algorithms for tracing figures along images
in the field for example in six sequence of images but i believe strongly that
this is just the
an experiment and i really believe that it's a good way to try to devise
a good algorithm for doing this but there's a lot of work a lot of
programming and computer science involved in this and were just
simple mathematician so
we do what we can do
OK so let's see
the first part of his phd thesis
OK so let's see here is the
experiment which we came up with
so we go
so we have this very nice cure going down three great slope
and the algorithms follows the year so the idea here is that you're looking at
the great grayscale values
the pixels in the image as discrete morse function what you're extending the discrete morse
function of the regularisation of the domain so the domain is just the square here
triangulation is a simple thing going to extend this to a discrete morse function another
figure would be local maximum of the the discrete morse function of course there are
many of them and we're just following one of them so there are several maximal
several critical points and this is just the one that we we concentrated on and
as you can see the algorithm follows the skier quite twelve
there's another really nice
between the beginning see here in the beginning two critical points one of them is
the here the other one is the shadow
kyrgyz jumped off a cliff and flying and then when he when he comes down
he joined the shadow the critical points more the united
it seems to work quite well here
the problem of noise which is just mentioned before and i really didn't go into
is really relevant here because you can imagine that an image like this has many
many many critical points they're much too many of them there are little saddle sort
of pure over here which really are not interested just little the answers in the
image or you can have some actual laws
you can just have a little
sift in the value of the grayscale function which would like to ignore
the way this is done is it's to really nice mechanism which is caused cancelling
critical points if you have to two critical points local maxima
and the minimum
like sorry a maximum and the saddle someplace over here and if you have a
discrete of going from one to the other
such that the function values along this path so this is the maximum for this
in nature but the next step of what he is interested in what rather because
according of this information is not meaningful that's the problem of this is in our
log fire and the idea of this approach is that
he tried to encode all the information which the use of corresponding to an ontology
so we have a concept it's a few of our website as onto a pass
and every question which was asked corresponds to an concept every click corresponds to an
concept and now we have if we do not only capture
the html
do right so if he also capture to the concept corresponding to do well in
our log file then you know what the user are looking for the and you
know what he percent today and today we can analyse this semantic log file easier
easily and they need no further steps to look behind the information that's another idea
to enrich or to to easily analyse usage five usage log fires
the help of ontology that's not only to get some
so let's come
to last application where we can try to work
you know
some ontology is so i talked about this crawl document and this focused crawler and
you can control the crawler to find some information about a certain topic drift ontology
and i suppose we have to this set of documents crawled and could it describes
some information in the next step would be to present decision documents to use and
if it's a lot want them and then we have a lot of documents quality
and the idea the next step is to control to class do information if to
help of ontology we have a description what interested in and we will be interested
also in find some groups softies documents which relate to each other i each other
so we cluster this information corresponding to all ontology we get some info to get
some clusters and we presented this to help of the ontology to the use of
this information so we have now an insight into to collect some information and not
only then will the decisive will normally you type in some keywords and then you
get a list of that pages in this may you give our system and stopping
point somewhere and then he tries to find the corresponding that pages and group them
together way that you have a chance to understand them percent and it's another example
that we are working on quite successful i presented some thing to marko and some
other yesterday that
and we tried to use ontology is tool
present and analyse
data so i give back to your cave cubicles you're issues because you can get
so last but not least we are coming to an end
reason where we are heading for what do we see as the next steps that's
what is important for us and this is basically work that was performed for project
proposal in collaboration with marko and some other partners which might be of interest for
you too
because it also shows the directions where we are actually working on so for the
first eighteen months we see that we need
a tighter combination and integration of three core technologies which is on the one hand
ontology and metadata technology which we seen a little bit then also human language technology
and knowledge discovery so these are the three key
technology which we see are necessary
to provide the basic infrastructure
then for the next three years we will transfer this combined technology into other application
areas of not only semantic web as we presented today we have some mean machine
process of all information for example within websites but also
you have other application areas like web services peer-to-peer multimedia and you can imagine a
lot of other ones but these are the the key ones at the european commission
for currently and what we see as the far goal
so this is really our vision
is that
there's no boundary between the document management content management and a knowledge retrieval so if
you look at the current product market what can you get from companies what they
sell well you have a document management a content management and you have a knowledge
retrieval on top somehow but there's no really integration and if you are the worker
in front of your are for example you have to switch between different tools and
applications to perform your daily working task and what we see is that there will
be no boundaries in between so like for example microsoft is trying to combine all
the products into one we also see that these different application areas will grow together
so that you don't have to switch your tools to to achieve your goals as
the so-called knowledge workers
so in a nutshell the knowledge management tasks hopefully become an almost effortless part of
day-to-day activity so that's the marketing story behind that
and we hope to achieve that end hopefully upcoming so-called sect project where we will
closely collaborate with marko and his group and some other groups for example the competence
centre in sheffield for human language technologies but for example also major industrial players like
and pulleys and bertelsmann so we see that this is a quite challenging task is
a nice project and we're looking forward to working there
so last but not least i hope you enjoyed our tutorial
i felt quite comfortable you learnt something hopefully a lot and if you're interested you
can also look at our website we have
some publications available you can also contact us personally if you have detailed questions please
feel free to do so
thank you very much
you have questions
so our oldest languages which are if you want to say well is
one of the things he was saying only
in each
or you can do not mentioned two which is done and then found out that
and and so there's a little bit of history is the first of all we
have a lot of different representation formalism especially if you look into the description logics
community specialised dialect of description logic to reduce complexity when different as to make it
to make it a solvable task
if you look at the history the current standards then the european initiative called which
was part of a tremendous project then the american initiative called back and then they
once all N customers have come in and sat down around tables every table is
gonna correspond to a cluster in our partition and basically the customers correspond to
elements of our S of our set S and tables correspond to clusters in our partition
row okay one of the the main property of the Chinese restaurant process is that it
has this rich gets richer property right so if we have a table with lots of
customers then the chance of new customer the comes sitting at that table will
be large as well because this N S term will be large so this is
quite useful because if you think about clustering right so if you see that there's
a there's a large cluster of objects then the chance of a new object that
you observe next coming from that cluster will also be large because that's kind of
if we have a large object then you expect to see more of that type
of object in the future okay you can also multiply this conditional
probabilities together and that gives that gives us the overall probability of the
partition probability of row given alpha and it has a fall given by this okay
and this is called the exchangeable partition probability function is basically a probability function
tells us tells you the probability of a partition under this process and is exchangeable I'll
I'll come to that a bit later okay again we can work out you know as just as
for the the Dirichlet process we can work out the mean and the variance
of this process and one thing one quantity which we'll be interested in will be
the the number of clusters in our partition okay so the expected basically this
is the prior mean of the number of clusters so the total number of clusters
in row in a among partitions of the set one to N keep
parameterized by alpha you can work out that that equals to something which looks
like this okay is basically alpha times log of one plus N divided by alpha similarly you
can also work out that terms are interestingly that the variance of the number of
clusters is also gonna be exactly the same form okay so approximately really okay so here's a plot
which shows what's happening so we have a number of clusters that a number of
customers that increases from zero to ten thousand and then on the Y axis we've got the
table that the customer sat at so the first customer was at a table one and the
second table and that's gonna be the second table the third table the forth
table and so forth and we're gonna plot a point where on the table that
the cust that customers sat at okay and we see that as the number of customers grows
the number of tables will keep on growing as well and the growth rate of
the number of tables is logarithmic in N and the other thing which depend
which this depends on is that it also depends on alpha so that if alpha is large then
we expect we can expect more tables and if alpha is small we tend to expect less
tables and the variance in the number of tables or the number of clusters
is in fact quite tight so if we think about the standard deviation as the
square or the variance then the standard deviation's typically smaller than the expectation and than
the expected number of tables okay this actually has and if I'll come back to
this a bit later when we talk about how we might use this for clustering
this histogram is just we sample from the number of clusters under our Chinese
restaurant process logs of times and we just plot the histogram of the number of
times that we might we observe a certain number of tables oh no we
fix the number of customers to be a hundred and we draw lots of samples
we we we run this process lots of times every time we're gonna get
a number of tables and that number tables is gonna be random right and we're
gonna discollect the number of times that we see that number of tables among
that among one hundred customers okay and we can now plot the histogram and it looks basically like
this and the mean is gonna be that quantity and the var the variance is also
gonna be that quantity okay yes now there's actually not no emphasis is it's just that it's
a perceptual thing right because we if I just plot down a random number of points on
some area then you can you cannot see the boundary of that area and in
this case the boundary of the area is given by that that curve there okay so how
OK so we collected off here on the project that have actually has had a
very good question what's needed to celebrate what what what to lose with the project
you actually lose the bit i mean works well it's kind of elegant but it's
nowhere near as good as the simultaneous out and there's a couple reasons for that
for this reason so it's past and so it has a lot of good uses
will actually show it using a working
so what i want to show that
civil work
and this is just a kind of a hack together once is this is that
they are kind of state-of-the-art was still kind of
getting this but hopefully with you
help you with your relation
it's a little bit there but they can be about
so that using the so this is off the shelf and b and saying it's
just basically
matrix multiplications
referring to actually doing every frame we're doing twenty five twenty five iterations
and that's a pretty cool you can kind of
your nomination was kind of doing
having a problem like about another
this is what we did for the discovery channel
with a
a kind of greece because we can always skipping ahead but somehow to protect them
so is my friend ralph
and so
this is kind of showing him just in the kind of living space around
that's the sort of
there go
so this can maybe and smiling
so this is real time systems records time was in the sequence
things and then we incorporated the face recognition and so it's green recognising
and then you could walk off
it was built
the tracks me
and this is not real because right
was another thing is the the nice thing with this stuff to is that this
whole problem so i like expression variation
and all these other things that are problems with advice as soon as you start
doing the registration and it all falls apart because you actually can normalise first expression
you can normalize pose as opposed to dealing with these kind of these boxes
things and so
so it's kind of funny because it's going to it's coming away from this box
detectors and we're trying to do stuff now and ameicans people walking and we're also
doing a lot of stuff on actually structure from motion so basically what can i
from this viewpoint of my advisor by register properly
can i infer what i look like france is actually a bit of work done
on this famous work by
a guy called volker blanz and he's really good work on that but the problem
with his work is that he does a really good job inferring the frontal view
but it doesn't do a good job of actually doing tracking for the registration for
patients so we're trying to do both things at the same time so that we
one asked more about it and this was is or cut up to i see
magic in the school
in the math and we were all together
you too could put that together pretty simple so
so we can keep on going going with that so the thing that so that
was project this or that and so the nice thing is that because of that
it was projecting out the appearance variation so maybe some illumination changes in
prices and things but you do those things because
with the simultaneous of
i'm actually at every iteration
i'm getting what update in an appearance
and what i'm doing also is instead of with so with project at every iteration
i'm essentially
projecting out
this appearance of the forgetting about i'm not doing anything with it
so i said you kind of projected but with the simultaneous that one does is
it takes it encompasses well i know that this is how much the appearance changed
a lot that's no longer
i'm going to update
and so what actually happens is that instead of me trying to
slowly just rely on everything in terms of the war
intense my optimisation on country
increasing knowledge intensity appearance increasing knowledge in terms of the war
both at the same time and so the sum of ten is the is inherently
a lot nicer in a lot better so
there has actually been i'm not covering it here because it's still a really kind
of far research topic
but there's been some really interesting work done by a guy called adrian but only
a ring road in europe and he's done some stuff called is called tool
inverse composition
and what he proposed is that you can not only invest compose
the geometry
of the shape you can actually invest compose the texture
and you can actually think of actually
you can actually think of one of the following what's on the texture so you
can have like game by
so i like to into the
in seeking three points
and then
in one d the final is essentially just
where positioned in the scale
and so
because it's composable
you could in theory invest compose and so he sent stuff for investment posing for
the game boy as
it's a lot trickier
and it's interesting we we think at the moment it can be done but it's
right things are for so everyone so yeah
i've been tasked to essentially given introduction on neural nets
so what i'm going to talk about this fairly basic
concepts but those are concepts that you're building on for the rest
of this week and i mention this just so aware of the amount of pressure
areas put on me for in this talk so while essentially cover is
you know basic feedforward neural net multilayer perceptrons
is another where people describe them
what i'll go through our first talk about
essentially given some input x i'll we make predictions using neural
net well refer to f of x as the output that is
if you're already somewhat familiar neural nets we take an input
vector x and p per neural nets will compute
a series of layers of features which are hidden layers and eventually
ultimately compute an output layer that serves to make a prediction
about the label for some input x i'll focus mostly on classification
during my my talk and there's all talk about furs
how you compute all these units in the neural nets to forward propagation
the different types of units activation functions that people
tend to use have a bit of discussion as to what is the capacity
of neural nets and and why they are interesting
in terms of their ability to model various complicated functions
and then i'll move on to actually talk about you know given
that we've accepted that this is the type of model multilayer neural
net that we want to fit to our data how do we actually fit it on
they are we train neural networks i'll discuss type loss function
we use for classification talk about the backpropagation algorithm
which loss gradient to perform some gradient based learning
and describe some of these in descent algorithms a few other tricks
of the trade kind of information that you need for apply
neural nets in practice and ultimately i'll talk a bit smaller
about you model weighting the case of deep neural network and talk
about some of the more recent advances that
have surface in the literature and that were sort of inspired by
this you know addition of trying to learn deeper neural networks
things like drop batch normalization unsupervised pre-training
yeah this is sort of two lectures yes so i am not crazy
so thanks to any ject so and the first part i'll do is that i'll
cover forward propagation and backpropagation mainly all the computing
gradients then we'll talk about that we have lunch and after i talk
about the complete learning algorithm for fitting neural net
on data and talk about the learning part
i curiosity who has seen for propagation backpropagation before
raise your hand ok we super useful so yeah
presented layer so hopefully will be like
watching a movie really like for the second time more
and hopefully will not be like when you watch a movie you liked
and you realize all this special effects one that great
so right let's get going on for propagation
and i'll just start simple just start with describing what we mean
by an artificial neuron so and artificial neuron will be essentially
characterized by a few things will take some input x
and it would have a set of weights which connection between
the inputs and the activation neuron itself
rather a bias and i will have an activation function
and we will compute the activation of neuron
is that we will first take the bias so what i'm
going to first compute what i call the pre activation function
i'm noting a of x it's going to be a bias
loss a linear combination of the inputs where each input dimension
my vector x is weighted by some way w i the weights w guys are just
the elements dimensions my with vector w
so this some i can represented as vector operations
bias b plus the dot product between my weight vector w in my
input x that i get my pre-activation and to actually get
the activation in some zero we refer to as the output of a neuron
will just be some nonlinear function or g which is our activation
function applied on the pre-activation so our role everything
it's that equation here and so this is kind of visual illustration
of what neuron is and often the bias will is represented as actually
a the weight of on a unit that is constant and equal to one
that's another way of representing that full some as just
multiplying a extended vector with w and
be added attended that vector so ok what kind of functions can
we represent what artificial neurons we can just plug the output
of some neuron if i do that into dimensions
x that's easier to visualize so here we have one axis where have
the first dimension of some input and here second axes of
second a second axis for the second dimension my input
and here this is just the output of the activation of my neuron
and so typically what we have is that in some region of the input
space what i'll have is essentially flatten
small value and as i move along in the direction of the vector w
eventually the activation starts increasing
that's but we typically get and often we can even get a
kind of bridge that separates due to regions so this is the kind
of function you can represent the so the bias b will determine
where l long vector w that ridge you will be
and the range of the values taken by the activation of a neuron
is going to be determined by the choice of my activation function
that's a single neuron or please do interrupt me any point
during the presentation yeah questions
be happy to make this more attractive than
discuss some the sum of the details so
i talked about activation functions one of the choices one
a set of
so the most likely set of whether tags so somebody mentioned before part of speech
tagging has problem like part of speech tagging
it is part of speech tagging of a sequence of words
and for every word you have to assign a part of speech like now over
so in this case one of the words
so the number of ice friends right that's what we observe and the hidden things
we're trying to reconstruct instead of part of speech tags we're whether tags instead of
having forty or fifty then we'll have to called
because that will make it possible actually visualize it
if you have struck down the problem to only three words and only two part
of speech tags plus start end like the special beginning sentence and the sentence words
four million well
i want to say that those words and tags that i should say that there
are special tags
OK so
so how do we get this graph
we did by a
considering all possible tag sequences so there are thirty three days in the diary
so how many possible tag sequences
two to the thirty third place
each one of those of pattern this crash so this is the past hot hot
this is the past
cold cold cold so how likely is it to this well what is the probability
of cold
let me explain what this graph means
this state here if we come to the state this is this means that the
first day was higher than the state is representing midnight at the end of the
first day
OK and records whether that day
it was hierarchical
so called
with the first day
it was a hot day we end up with the hot stated in i
second there was a hot day thursday was a cold a
and this here is the intervening day
this part here is the intervening day between the two minutes
so the first day we want know there are some cost the first they can
be either hot or cold we decided to choose high
we point five chance of picking high
and point five chance of picking called given the the previous day restore that's different
here here we have a whereas hot state probability that the next day will be
high is point eight probability the next day will be called is only point one
so here we choose whether to go to hot or cold were more likely to
choose heart this is a higher probability patterns that involve this are or higher probability
perhaps there is another reason that this talk is more likely than that of
on the second day we have to decide only
we have to decide only not only whether it's going to be harder day but
given that choice how many ice ice-creams
when i say we have to decide what i mean is something like you know
the world decides god decides what the weather will be
somebody decides randomly what the weather will be
and how many ice-creams getting
many god decides the weather and i decided i screens so
so this is saying
eighty percent chance that a hot day and then a seventy percent chance that we
decided three ice-creams
this is saying what a ten percent chance that called a given that the previous
day is high and then once i decided to call what's the chance that i
would be three ice-creams only ten percent
there are other choices that could have happened right so i've only shown to be
sort of being hot they are called a
i've only show the cases where we even write three i three i didn't show
the other choice of be one or two ice-free because they didn't have we don't
have to put them in the graph we're only concerned about has that actually explain
the data that we observed
so this is an article that explains why i three streams it was a hot
day and i chose transference pretty likely
o point eight times point seven this alternative art is another way of explaining why
three history it was called a and i race and both those things are unlikely
there's an unlikely are point one point five six
OK so we prefer this are other things equal
but other things might not be equal because in order to take this article we
need to take other works that get here and other works that would get away
from here
so that's kind of the inside is we're interested in looking at all of the
past the probability of the path is the probability of all of the weather events
and all of the ice cream that's necessary to make that after
OK so there's two to the thirty third past so very interested in knowing whether
the second it was hard
we want to know whether we went through this state h at the end of
the second
that's what we want
of the two to the thirty third past how many go through here
i think i heard
more than two
here's one
here's another
i here so once we get the it's true that there's only two pounds that
come to here but there has to go away also so there's actually a lot
of has to go through here
two to the thirty two actually so there's two to thirty three has about a
trillion right and having to go through this and having them go through that
so does that mean that the probability we go through here is i half
no because the path that go through here maybe on average more likely than the
paths that go through
so we're interested in is the total probability balthazar go through the state and the
total probability vol passing through that
well it's not too bad so we have up four trillion pounds here and four
trillion pounds there were done
and you could actually do that
just be slow
so can we find a faster way
so what we're interested in knowing is you know maybe seventy percent of the
actually the let's just take a moment and think about what these numbers are so
what's the probability of the first three days being hot or cold
given the evidence that we're sorry what's the excuse me what is the product of
these three hours later let's just right there
so we've got point one times point five six times point
o one
no that is actually fairly likely
i really like the likely outcome for the first three days the most likely path
is hot hot hot point one times point five six times point five six still
seems pretty unlikely
so why is it so unlikely
hi guys sorry sorry didn't quite work for
so what's the
why why is it that these patterns are
the patterns are not only predicting possible whether sequences remember
there are predicting whether sequences and the ice cream that i so there's eight possibilities
for the first three days and you can see all the patterns there
each of those has its probability is a different way of eating two followed by
three followed by three ice-creams which is in fact what i a
on the first three days
over here we have
two three and three ice-creams so we have these a has
all we get is we've divided on my ways of eating two three three
in eight possible into a possibilities just as we divide it up horses into a
lot of possible ways of getting horses there are mutually exclusive we add up the
probabilities and that gives the probability beating two three three ice there are a lot
of other choice of ice creams like one one one one one two one one
one three and one two one one two two one two and so
for example
i don't have
some of them but it means that i am repeating
and thanks
so it would be like having one first treaty
three scenes then and time tree nodes tree nodes connected between them but it's repeated
several times
and so here you see that we have two plates one in the world space
i have here reputation for each of my words
of this this part of the of the graph
and here a repetition over the the number of documents in the database of also
and these are the d school run
so it looks like a fairly simple
was the
latent variable which is the topics we've seen examples of that day yesterday
which because so we did that will give me conditional independence between
my documents and my
and the words
so let's call it a little bit into into detail in this document
so the the PLSA model
and in fact it's a
the its aim is to have a modernization of the words document
color called co occurrence occurrence
for each document
in the database
and each word in the dictionary so
we have the joint probability of documents in the database
and the
words in the dictionary
OK so is just to put across
using the
common main assumption
i replaced the probability of a
word given document
as this mixture over the
the topics
so here everything is represented in this clearly similar everything is represented with
every conditional probability
is there is a multinomial probability
i don't know if you know what i mean so in this probability of w
and given he got it's it's a it's an element of language and on the
you have the probability of each of these one
the same for four days probability and this is the
i don't know how he could that
but this is fairly simple also something review committee on
OK let's go to the next one
in terms of the model and
we are not considering the
this time is not the model of the culture itself
document in words but it's a it's try to model the probability of document
and so in
in this model the document space is partitioned into
eight steam so the standard x variable of my document space is in fact
available over
random variable saying which teams with steam on
and so the idea is that you have the document which is generated
bye bye
by team so i was first i select team then
this team will give me probabilities over over topics
and topics we give the probability of over
you can see it as a mixture of documents is seen as a major
over over the probability of the image given
the team
this probability
we do
we did we do the assumption that
given the team
we have
independence between the the words in the dictionary so i can
that's right is as as the president
over of the words that are in my document
of the products of the probability of one word given the team
here is our main assumption coming into into
i can replace all the CC k as the as the sum
over over the topic so that's that's what we already the common assumption
of the probability of the word given the topic
OK so here again everything is represented as
as multinomial probit so the probability of a of
so first the probability of the team then the probability of topic given the team
and in the end the probability of word given the topic of that our tables
so this one
OK so that's that because you can have a word that appear more than one
time in the document
so i have to raise it
so is the for the ten the frequency of these words in the document
so one is at the level of the document and the other is it's the
level of of words
so let's give an example
it's a have i have no comments about support and the comments about the history
and so that's two different teams
i'm just it's it's not what he's doing but let's have
imagine that what that he's doing so
that's my two team and then i have in the
the talking about sport i have attacked and he and so on so really war
and in the in the history also i have this discovered this kind of words
which will be in the topic which would be the topic war for example
you get
OK let's go to the last example last model which is the last thing to
the euclid allocations
which again is as well as i say is there is a model of of
the document
and this time instead of having a partition of the
of the space
in two if you number of teams
we have a random mixture over
that's topic so it's
you can see it as it has
infinite mixture over something
being in close to two
to the things
so this in this in this model the x j x is replaced by a
tall variables
OK so again it's this one is really