you can see that by
writing down the formula for each
of the
of the functions
what we're interested in most particularly is quadratic functions
i'm interested said
in cliques of size two
cocliques size only two
then you would be able to have
because every variable intakes every function takes two variables
good recall of course look closely at x one square the same thing as x
one because
x one zero one
and so you never have squares as if you only got two variables it just
has to be
what makes one x you can't you can't have x one x two square
so it's always of the form
and i prefer to write it in the form where i
on the right a i j x i x j
the first one is bad
the second one is not
also unique representation
given that i've said i've listened to order
so basically
energy function that you're trying to minimize
which only has likely size two can be written
in that form
look at the two
displayed formula
this is instance of the way that you
i think these
if you take at node i
the its corresponding
its corresponding
very exciting
then you can write the linear
linear term is
just the cost
he i
so excited because he
i zero
x i ivana was that this means the effect size one
as in this one
that's zero so the cost
it's just a i one which is the cost
of the i being one
x i
well zero
fixi like zero
and that is one
that gives you the cost of being zero so
if you just
in tabular form so what's the cost of being zero was cost being one
that gives you
similarly the quadratic terms
can be expressed in terms of what's the cost of find zero zero
what's the cost signing one one cosine zero one one zero
and so on with high degree to you're interested
i described
what the general
markov random fields
processes leave in the two variables
this is an NP hard problem to find
the maximum probability of cost
now with
all intents and purposes you can do it
particularly if you're dealing with images which may have a million pixels and have tens
of millions
random variables
this is not a polynomial you've got no
and it's easy to
see that is the case because particular example of this
we just had a few terms
like this cubic literals
i think it comes down to
the so called
three SAT problem
is there a way
probabilities to each of those terms each year
the the ninth reset satisfiability boolean expressions with three times
so well known standard NP hard problem
get out how this is how we can be represented by graphs
as shown you
how to help
previously basically
if you think a weighted graphs
the the
the vertices on the edges have weights to give weights
and think of pseudo boolean function
you can see the graphs with n plus two vertices in the interest to this
is one of the six regional variables because you have this is zero one
what we're going to do
is up
i think in situation where we have some function f
longer names
and we already know the actions are through motor cortex perception is through all these
areas in the back
and then through frontal cortex so we can map the this whole thing onto to
the brain and people are very excited about this especially because there are two nuclei
two dopamine ergic nuclei which seemed to
project the same kind of signal but two different areas so that many people immediately
think hot actor critic right this one single goes to the credit in one single
goes to that it's the same signal because two different places
so is there any evidence
for this
in the brain i should say this is a very very prominent theory of learning
in the brain and i think
my my opinion that this might be wrong but there are not many such a
neuroscientist here to tell me that i'm wrong but my opinion is really it was
because of this excitement of two
nuclei of dopamine
the signal the same thing to two different areas not not based on
more stringent
it just looks really good
but there is some evidence
and if i show some evidence of small side
the functional imaging
and how that helps us look for this kind of evidence and i'm doing this
where i didn't do it for other methods in neuroscience because this is kind of
the new wave of research into reinforcement learning and the brain so it's good for
you to know how it's done
fmri functional magnetic resonance imaging and all start with the big man it looks like
this and the subjects lies on the bed and is inserted so that their heads
is in the magnet and they see stimuli that they have like married basically the
stimuli from the screen to have about box and they make their choices are do
whatever the experiment tells them to do or even get you into their mouth
it was a little too they just do the experiment lying down and looking at
the camera and the former
and trying to not move their head at all
the police we hope they don't move head because the idea of what we what
we're measuring these experiments
what's called a bold signal are
that's right for blood oxygenation level dependent signal
what happens is
in the brain there is there's a lot of blood there are lots of blood
vessels every neuron its blood
because it needs oxygen
and there's the difference in the magnetic properties of oxygenated and de oxygenated
chemical hemoglobin in the blood
so after the accident has been taken was by the neurons the blood has a
different magnetic properties than it did before
we can detect this these little magnetic fluctuations with this
huge super conducting magnets that makes a lot of noise and cost lots of money
and so what we're relying here is is on the fact that the brain is
functionally modular so different areas of the brain get blood by different vessels and if
one area is active it will use up more oxygen will actually asking the body
for more oxygen than it needs and we will see more oxygenation in that area
because it was active
so what is does reason it's called functional MRI is it shows this function shows
us what brain area was used at what time
to some very very coarse
resolution so
the spatial resolution is about three millimeters
cupid so we can kind of tell
these kind of these small voxels of three by three by three which is certainly
not at the level of one neuron to the level of thousands of neurons but
the motor cortex sensory motor areas that they are differentiated enough that we can tell
them apart
the temporal resolution is also quite shabby
it's five to ten seconds because it takes time for the blood to get there
and to await like for every spike of the neuron we see some blood supply
difference but if the whole area is active for a while
five seconds later we'll see this extra blood that
what happens is that it asks for more blood than it needs so we see
signal five seconds later
so what can we do with this
we can study reinforcement learning and the brain in humans
we can take this hidden variables the model prediction errors inference and say OK during
my experiment where my subject was playing some games choosing stimuli getting rewards doing gambling
or whatever in my
little experiment video game the model predicts that there would have been prediction errors over
time the second one would have been positive prediction the second for negative one and
so forth
so i predict these prediction errors
and i know
the BOLD signal usually has the typical time constant or response it looks like this
so if there was an event here
five seconds later we'll see a peak in bold
fifteen seconds later will feed it any you the the whole thing levels out after
about thirty two seconds basically five seconds later we'll see
a peak so we can
convolve our prediction error signals
delta functions as we call them although they're not really delta function to have different
with this
and yet
the signal that we're expecting in the brain were expecting a p caused by this
letter trough caused by this p caused by this etcetera
and take this in use linear regression to regress this against the activity of the
brain and ask is there an area in the brain that looks like this
like this green line
and so that's what
o'doherty et al
did in two thousand four to look for actor critic mechanisms in the brain
so this is the same as here so we can send which in between so
this is lower bounded by this
that is what is written here
now we take the lambda square to the right hand side
and divided by lower case are
and we left this thing was that this thing here
so what have we shown we shown that
if we assume
w is upper bounded by lambda
the dataset is shutouts dataset of are points is shattered by canonic hyperplanes
the data set is upper bounded length they are
and then
as a consequence of these assumptions
the numbers are must be upper bounded by this thing here
so if
dataset shadows
it cannot be larger than this
therefore this is an upper bound on the see dimension because we see dimension is
and the largest number of points that can be chapters
big big are is
where is it written it's the length and the radius of the smallest sphere around
the origin that contains the data set
and we use it in the proof
i think in the second part
so in the second part we derive this upper bound on this quantity and now
we are saying each one of those
is upper bounded by our square dance
so then we got this thing here
because they're so busy we have two things one is the radius of the
the smallest sphere containing the data points
and one is
in a sense the radius of the sphere containing the weight vectors that are large
so it's an upper bound on the length of the weight vectors
and one can also
intuitively understand why it's reasonable to have this kind of a bound on the dimension
that is should play an important role
one way to think about is
would be just say well and this is just a purely intuitive argument
what if we have some kind of noise in the data points so this fringe
there's an old paper about neural network
chris bishop that
argues that
putting noise in the data
it a monster taken off regularization on network
so putting on noise and data is some form of regularization of a function class also
in implicitly in here
because if we were to put bounded noise each data point
maybe we sample from each data point many many points
with the distribution that has this bounded noise
and then we train a normal hyperplane without
looking for optimal margin
we might get something which is similar to this
the maximum margin kind of hyperplane if
radius the noise here is as large as it can be
or another
way to interpret maximum margin would be minimal in terms minimum description description length
so minimum description length is an approach to
inference on generalization
and we trying to say
i uh
finding a function that generalizes amongst generalizes amounts to finding
a short description of a data set amounts a compression of the data set and
the smaller the compression the better we can generalize
and here you can also find a large margin hyperplane is a compression of the
labels of the dataset so we
we are given the data points
what we can do is we throw away the labels and instead store the hyperplane
because we know we can regenerate the labels using the hyperplane
and it turns out that if your lies in a ball of bonded radius
end if the margin of separation is large is rho
and then you can work out how accurately
u u have to store these ants in this simple picture here
storing the hyperplane monster starring this angle gamma
and the larger
ratio of rho
two are
the small of all the
new so you can store come up the less accuracy you need for storing them and therefore less bits
so in a few if you work this out in this simple picture again you
end up with this ratio of of robot are
anyway so now it's created about the theory
just this just accept it's good to classify
uh uh data using large margin hyperplanes
you're going to have a certain probability going left certain probability of going right in
your opponent knows this probability is the a now
in new way of thinking is just think of kind of you know you can
see thing now
you can go left
and they can stop you more often than not you know you can go right
they can study more often than not the best strategy in this game
tissue fifty b then
the goal you only have a fifty percent chance stop
that's the minimax optimal strategy this to the minimax optimal strategy is randomized strategy that
the best thing to play if your opponent knows the strategy
to make sense to make
will do some examples
you can solve for these and my own game using linear programming or not
because this can we just said that the minimax optimal strategies for both of the
shooter fifty fifty and for the goal is also fifty
if you shoot fifty fifty is guaranteed whatever you're part the goal goes left to
right here in the fifty percent chance of getting the goal here is that is
any other strategy
we do worse
the opponent knows your problem
fifty fifty
all right so i think of a will be more interesting game with the goal
is weaker on the left so i have done is change this entry here
so goal is weaker on the left so if you shoot left even if the
goalie dies left is still a fifty percent chance the ball
now what's the minimax awful thing
i mean since the goal is we can't allow the user forgot the right this
is always the overlap
because then i a fifty percent chance of online
but not really taking advantage of that we going to even before a fifty percent
chance of one in now really should left fifty percent building better
one think with minimax optimal strategies here so the goal is to something for the
shoes let's say you're the shooter in you know
the goal is weaker the last issue activity potentially it's going to go and even
if the goalie dive left
course going wrong way in percent
if you should decide it go going only if the goalie dived by
the most of the time left but occasionally to the right
i think that is stretching OK
how occasionally
that's right so you want you can't mean fifty fifty
see if you always go after should always goal after fifty percent
what with the shooter do for the going to if you're fifty
if you're fifty fifty what should the goal
and the goal is to go right
and you also a fifty percent chance came to use two different strategies about fifty
the somewhere in between there's gotta be a better shot right
so we could solve
some probability on the left and some probability going right
so if probability p going left and one minus going right
and if the goalie dive left are part of the our total thing is p
times the have
plus one minus p one
going the other way we get p one plus one minus zero we want to
make the
maximize the minimum which you can do by setting make
if we do that we get
exactly what what
he said about two thirds probability here
one third probability
if the goalie that's left over two-thirds times one-half to one-third plus
one for terms one two thirds chance of getting in the way that left
and we also have two thirds chance of getting in the way that
he causes the case
building from the goal is perspective what should the goal
minimax optimal strategy for the goal
the as this this guarantees expected gain at least two thousand so this strategy for
that guarantees the shooter at least two-thirds transfer exactly third chance
getting going
and we call six always perspective
so the only the side
the i know the shooter and knows well what's what's meant by minimax optimal strategies
what the deletion i go left i go right
you can sort of the same thing
this game symmetric so it's actually the same answer
the goalie
should have two thirds chance diving like one third chance five
that guarantees
whatever the peter decides to do it
you know one
well good luck to that
two thirds meinshausen
one third in one
they thirds
this way
two hundred twenty one people
this strategy for the shooter and the goalie guarantees whatever she decides to do
the goalie has almost two-thirds of the only the expected loss legalism of
is the kind of interesting things that the shooter can
take a strategy that guarantees whatever the goalie does is at least two-thirds chance in
the goal only can pick something so the matter the shooter does he is most
two-thirds chancellors
so clearly the only the only help to guarantee that the US
since that would contradict that
this shooter could guarantee by some countries for us so that the shows you of
i mean that's theorem tells you at meeting always happens
good time for game
so here's the game now i really like
this game is american centric
the talks about a quarter of the so quarter is twenty five cents and nickels
so here's the game so i i i what i have
either twenty five cents in nickel five cents the conical because they were made of
nickel were five cents
and i have one of those banned you get to guess which i have
if you get it right
you get the coin
if get wrong
you know
you get
the second n
so cell
this again makes sense
and when the whole OK now now peak in australia
blah blah blah blah
which are all strings
integer but most of them are strings
and and this is called
the earliest documentation
which means instead of writing machine readable five it should the low to to plug
reason and that and so far they say
the web is full of people
and people in need documentation
and needs to use what's
OK so there is a XML and very it be
OK so
amount plus interest
is what we want to use and if you go down
here you would see
these exampl
which is the one that i run
you can see it just plain your
OK says go to these URL
and we get
and they get should contain some stuff then the list of keywords and then if
you like the location
and then if you like the thought that is something that happens in the future
and this is the rest service
i mean it goes to o two to is also which is there are here
and although these researchers performs things that you normally performed on the web
so what you we perform is it gets posted things like that so if you
have to get information to get if you have to update the post
more or less this is point
and so you have these different way of thinking which is
now nowadays because the rest of this
but i'm not sure this is a good way to do that and that people
that try to bridge the two
for instance the the reason i stuff which is quite interesting
where it is in the
like the one that i was talking about then when i was talking about the
OK this microformats should be in lightweight machine processable
approach two
describe service
it's like the we the so i
the same things of wisdom but it does it in a much lighter way approach
to rest for all of you
it's just technology so what i'm doing here
so if i didn't explain it but i thought it was not the pacific
i be too
did i mean that i will but he also enjoyed that did is not is
almost caught by using his arrest idea
and the rest idea is right to you
and get results
nothing more than that
OK so we are here talking about linking
got the idea of linking
so we are close to the end
now we have all these data we have all of them represented
in their own content sources we just have to write these big query
but gets the results out and then to represent them in a way that
can be understood by the ajax framework that we choose
let's talk about his ajax framework is name exhibit as i said
it's a fast sector browsing tool
we're far sec means that given result set you can navigate
you can select a subset of the of the results so you can or you're
the resulting you can show the result set in different representation least a timeline map
and things like that so
what we want to do is to allow grouping and filtering by name nationality side
time better to have the right answer calibration
OK so bayesian work is focused on coherence
well frequencies work hasn't been too worried about causing a brief affair statement so bayesians
get kind of coherence for free because they joint problems which undermine everything and that's
the source of the coherence and they love to bash frequencies because they find places
where frequencies work not coherent and lots and of other papers written about that the
frequency and not so worried about that they are interested in a particular inference problem
at one particular time and do the best you know finding lost function the targets
that law that problem and you know you can go here all the time you
know that's life has kind of you one lecture one so you know i'm not
that cohen while cohen is a hundred and cohen mornings
but consistent is perhaps there were that's another technical meaning so you might consider i'll
tell you one thing one day in the northeast something else six months later and
that's life
now had frequencies workers focus on calibration calibration again kind of like the sort of
coverage that you the kind of numerical values is so severe procedure really come out
in practice
can have been taught about calibration
OK now that's kind of a bit of a problem with the basic perspective you
know you are writing much of priority right procedure when your data and that's it
you're done
i will guarantee that you give me and can you tell me you know that
you do the procedure multiple times it would come out have error you're going to
turn out to be true
i will be starting to worry about that you know that much time enough now
good bayesians almost bayesians and statistics are actually a little bit frequencies two and so
they will often look at a little bit of a frequency analysis of what they're
doing to compare the coverage for example of their bayesian procedure
anyway if you don't do that if you just to appear bayesian then you certainly
get caught coherence but you know you go don't street calibration on the other hand
if you're poor frequentist so you just
they're worried about pure calibration you can be calibrated completely useless so know ninety five
percent of the time about error bars that are appointed the hunt and in europe
by the time you get reversed to cover everything
so the average works out to be some kind of confidence interval but on any
given saturday to give out a useless answer
so you can make use of your account history completely incoherent you can be completely
incoherent and completely wrong it is clinical here to give out the answer wonder whatever
request problem you ask me
going about
OK and so most statisticians find some kind of bland a natural way to proceed
because they tend to achieve both terms calibration but in some sense given you the
answer my question my title
i think many statisticians not every single one but many of them find that they
are both a little bit a little bit frequentist and these things can be made
into conflict are ways of focusing on calibration coherence and showing one perspective doesn't achieve
it but they really do act complementary and each other
and it's a little bit like wave particle duality one we think about it sort
of waves and particles are both there they're both can always be true there's something
write about both of them but they don't quite really work you know together as
well as they should i think it's true about bayesian frequentist two
they're both right in some way they go around forever ones i could vanish
but they don't quite know merge entirely they do fight each other in various ways
in particular in intestine model selection problems and i think they'll probably be eventually be
some more resolution there even but it's going to take
all right so your comments about the sociology really so
the the frequencies world is this hodgepodge of people you to do any kind of
technique is largely given analysis that's frequencies and so it just a big big field
bayesian it'll smaller and it's really gets to student main subdivisions so you have subjective
bayesian objective basis simple but these are the kind of two main schools
and the subjective bayesian is believed that the prior comes from some from a person
or maybe a small group of people
and so the goal is to work with that person domain experts and you want
to figure out what's the prior that person has in their head and what loss
function they have in their had also the model to somehow come from the domain
experts also figure out what the model is list the model OK
and the the subjective bayesian argument is that if you got a bad answers from
your your bayesian procedure didn't work hard enough to get the prior and the loss
function model
she worked harder
right and put that weights are hard to argue with phi space a million years
ago the right prior you know
something you would get out the right inference
so what kind of if there is you know just what you have the prior
loss and the model you're done you know they use bayes rule and so on
there's not much else to talk about the what kind of research he is about
to be quite a lot of things you start here last two weeks i think
a lot of the work you price i was in fact only subjective bayesian natural
words are not used what it was mean what you about the new kinds of
why well because i'm subjective bayesian go on face some new problem i like library
of models i might bring bear new problem
so some some of what people worked on models of the big library
so that's what you could do the other thing you can do is the bayesian
know bayes rule integrate to get the denominator so better developed lots of procedures for
integration that can be hard to do a lot of work goes into subjective bayesian
research on immigration and anything you print talk as much about but if you have
real subjective bayesian you really have to worry about how to get the priors it's
not that easy and you better work at techniques for eliciting in assessing person individuals
is a whole literature on that and a lot of bayesian neural networks and machine
learning you don't focus on that nearly enough really are going to be these new
better worry about how to do that
anyway those kind of some of the main areas of research there are others with
the main so there's a lot of focus on analysis of did my procedure work
and so on and that's really what frequencies do because you know if you have
the right
input bayesian outputs could be a good one
right so
again you can really argue about that from a philosophical point of view it's coherent
it's pretty it's it's nice but in practice there are really lots and lots of
and the main one is that you know what with really complicated models are hierarchy
is there's more than very quantities there's no matrices
so on and so forth and all those in brain to new newport new parameters
in the problem you know whatever a wishart distribution that whole matrix the parameters set
in there
you got put distribution on that
right well that's hard
and so the more common here model gets the more primaries and it's not to
take you know a long time to get the domain expert to kind of say
well i prior on that wishart thing this is this
i know laptops in your hard drive your cellphones all of museo control codes even
a grocery store
so whenever you scan something like a barcode
right if use the scanner scanner is misaligned you might misread the digits of the
so what barcodes actually having them they have some extra parity checks
they have some extra numbers it's say this is the first second third number should
sum up to something maybe that's zero in march two that would be a simple
example of
the parity check code
it means that when the scanners misaligned even if it gets a few digits wrong
those parity checks allowed to correct or
fix those errors
now it turns out that the lord of the best codes the things that are
actually used in practice are
based on graphs
here i'm showing you a a slightly different kind of graphical model that something that
you'll also see in the literature something called the factor graph
right so in a factor graph you have notes these are what we've seen before
these represent variables
in the case we're talking about these would represent things that are being transmitted for
when your cell phone works
it uses radio waves but to transmits essentially sequence encoded form sequence of zeros and
so this is what's being transmitted or noisy version of this is being transmitted
and what these boxes represent these boxes represent parity check so this box saying on
look at one five three five and seven and whatever you send i wanted to
be the case that that adds up to zero in march two there should be
an even number of ones
right so
how many
so it's codeword is something that satisfies all of these parity checks to to sequence
of zeros and ones
of length seven in this case such that the first third fifth and seventh you
add them up is
zero in march two and so on for the other three once
so how many codewords how many sort of valid zero one sequences can you send
in this case
right there's two to the seventh possible sequences but not all of them are valid
right this guy is not valid are one one is not valid why is that
he must violate something
yes he would violate this parity check because only seven is one
and five three and one or zero so he has an even number of one
so he would not be valid
right so the total number of codewords to to the four
he started with two to this seven sort of had seven degrees of freedom and
you lost one for every parity checks seven minus three
three checks you end up with four
so in this case there are sixteen code words total
that could be sent in a much larger space of two the seven
now in practice people don't do this this was seven variables they do it with
something like ten thousand one hundred thousand variables and
what really has revolutionized and what's implemented and in many other devices is the sum
product algorithm
so many people the sum product algorithm
you're OK understand so when to talk about it tomorrow it's a message passing algorithm
what's important about the message passing it means that it does local operations at the
nodes of the graph
it sends things along the edges it's an extremely efficient algorithm and it's very parallelizable
section many of your cellphones are running a version of sum product right now
and it's very very fast because obviously if you're speaking you want to decode the
class a will be
at the three seven and twenty
class b will pick up tons five
twenty five thirteen and therefore i'm going to be able to differentiate between them but
let's hope there's no indication that will happen
so we actually in right
that we're not going to hope for these women forced
well can enforce these two cases women enforce
that if you learning to addictions for two classes they are good for one about
forty hours
OK because it might happen that for bikes is also good for non box you
know that
and we are going to impose
the different classes use different coefficients different that when imposed that into the variational formulation
and this is related to some works in the
in their probabilistic approaches of generative and discriminative so this is a big
controversy in the learning community between generative and discriminative don't want to go into the
so let me just give you one example
OK with multiple dictionaries
dictionary one is because for class one but for class b
four class two
and they had two is going to be bad for class one and good for
so this is what we have before
we're gonna
try to
fixed the image ix approximate as good as we can with the dictionary so this
is why we have before
nothing is and what we had before
but we going to be more sophisticated this is what we had before
and we're gonna put a term
that comes from
regression from SVM from whatever classification you like
and the basic idea and look at these mine was
and this comes with supplies and this comes with a minus
so this is encouraging
two have smaller or
for the right class
and large error or for the other class
because one comes with a plus that was the mind
so just classical logistic regression or techniques like that so the same time i wanted
to make sure good to be good for bikes but for everybody else
OK so i'm not leaving this detracts
so just some examples
this is the standard brought texture database
this is what you get out
this is there are about ten percent what you get if you learn one dictionary
per class
but they don't know
that they're going to be competing with the other direction
if you tell them that they going to be competing
you have there
so you're telling the dictionary
you be good for your class but the but for the rest of the same
OK and these are basically is competing with eleven eleventh hour classes
OK this is our right it's alright this image that actually comes better here this
is this is with the grass database that we actually trying to learn to detect
bikes against non bikes
and these are the results
basically every patch will tell me
if it survives or not by going through that part and we basically draw this
that's hot pixels so here is to identify regions that have a very high chance
of being
what do i mean by that
these parties are very well represented with the bikes
dictionary very badly represented
within on bike bikes dictionary
and similar for this other images
and once again i can show you we show in the paper that if we
don't impose that the results are not as good
let me give you a different example
in the previous case i say let's learn dictionaries that compete with each other
you can do is to of learning the dictionary
you can actually impose that it with efficiency use for class one
are different i they could that the coefficients used by class two
so basically
this is this is just one metric that we use but the basic idea is
i one day vector for class one to be orthogonal to the alpha victor for
OK just as one example you can put
other things here everything makes the there
optimisation of this even more complicated and i am skipping that part
but the basic idea is that you can put the task
in your optimisation
the reconstruction one b is good because the picture has to sacrifice
but the classification would be much better
and if you want to flag and show you reconstructions with their
pure reconstructive dictionary so reconstructed plus gasification to another school
let me just give the results it works OK
but the but i want to just give you the concept and you can combine
both concepts of learning dictionaries that are
separating and learning outputs that are separating and this is related to a paper and
we had last year NIPS with chilean and and our colleagues and once again i
think the important part is to see
if you put the discrimination
so this is for the for this dataset for the digits dataset if you don't
the discrimination you get the four percent error the moment you step
and then we learned dictionaries for discrimination you go down to one percent
and it's more fair because i'm telling
it is unfair to use these because my optimisation they might task now my optimisations
including my task
so some more fair
that was the second part
we're going learn
to classify or to other task so the last part of the dogs
is to learn to sense
and that's related to compressed sensing
compressed sensing say the following
just very
rough waters saying that amount of sensing them out of samples need from the signal
is proportional
two this sparsity level of that scene
OK not tonight nyquist
but is proportional to the sparsity level of that season
that means that in the more sparse signal is
there's some unit so that we have been addressing already because i've been creating dictionaries
to get
sigma is very sparse
so we have been doing
a service
to this already without
doing it on purpose but it came out
that's a request from the dictionary
now how are we going to sense
part of the beauty of the theory is that most of the compressed sensing literature
is about sensing with random actresses you get your image you multiply by random image
by random matrix and that's the way to sense
there are a couple of reasons for random sampling one universality
it was for the for every signal and the other is because the inverse
problem is very stable
but we like to learn things we don't like to take off the shelf dictionaries
or off-the-shelf sensing mattresses
so the first question is show we other the senses to the data type and
OK so we can start by the first thing i would like to thank the
european community for supporting
me through my body
and so european fellowship so in this presentation i will give you an introduction to
graphical models so let's start by
defining graphical models and give a little bit of motivation why we want to
to to know about them so graphical monocyte graphs
o which contain links and nodes in order represent random variables
y means represents
statistical dependencies between the variables so graphical model give us provide us with these what
for reasoning under uncertainty
and as we know
machine learning and related disciplines which are concerned modelling of the water is that information
about the time
uncertainty arises mainly from two sources and our limited understanding of the four and the
limited amount of data that is available to us therefore having methods which account for
uncertainty is very important
but why is it that these are the representation important
what about when point can we do with that graphical models allow us to
answer to question about independent random variables by just looking at the structure of the
graph and therefore
without requiring complex algebraic manipulation and in machine learning and related disciplines
when we have a probabilistic model of something we normally
i have to deal with a huge number of articles so
i did break my feliciano despite what is often very very complicated
graphical models also fine
i use the full because they enable us to define general i agree that form
fee efficiently inference problems
as a consequence of that we can say that the graphical model provided us with
a framework of common framework for representing and understanding the properties of probabilistic models and
enable us to
late modernist which were developed
independently in different communities such as for example statistics physics mission that control theory and
engineering and other many other communities and they have also isolated in my opinion
progress in modelling because they have enabled us to have overcome
some difficulties
there are many types of graphical models in the literature and today will focus on
mainly on belief networks markov networks and factor graphs
so the yesterday they gave a very nice introduction about probability the passion so i
will go very quickly through detroit we've seen these already so i just
i remind you that if we are interested in
a and the
we have a kind of prior belief about the
and then we we observe b
we can update our belief about failing to compute the
conditional distribution of a given b by simply multiply our prior distribution
you will be given a divided by p of p
also give you a little bit of refreshing about what we mean by condition
imagine the dependence between random variables intuitively to the bible
a and b are independent if the state law in the state of the
one of the bible doesn't tell us anything about the state of the art body
formally we can write that by
think that the probability of a given b is equal to the probability of a
or equivalently
we can write down the joint distribution of a and b as in the factorized
form was the distribution of times the distribution of b and similarly for
conditional independence between a and b
now before starting the description about graphical model we need first introduce you to the
to the notation of graphs
so first of all graphs consist of nodes
they can be undirected or directed so here for example i show an undirected graph
while here i show a directed graph
apart from node to another node is the sequence of connected nodes
for example
x one
x two
x three
former box
of nodes
which is in this case undirected
and x one x five
eight form apart from x one to x eight this part is that you can
notice that in the in the second is also
undirected part within directed graphs
in order to here x two is said to be
department of and all other nodes x five because there is direct thing from x
two to x five is similarly x five is said to be
child or of
x one is an ancestor of x a
eight states
it seems that is that part
starting from x one
and nineteen at sixty eight not x one on the other hand is not an
ancestor of axes
because the line here is
is in the wrong
and similarly exceed is going to be a descendant of x five or x one
because there is a path which and the dixie and start x have five or
the last finisher we need is definition of a directed acyclic graph
a graph is said i cyclic even by following the direction of the arrows in
with like the model outright there's just that's the rationale there's no moral scruple they
destroy these helpless but still humans were chafing under the tyrannical and unjust and uncaring
in the biblical story when the when the israelites told the story they modified it
it's god's uncompromising ethical standards that lead him to bring the flood in an act
of divine justice he's punishing the evil corruption of human beings that he so lovingly
created and whose degradation he can't bear to witness so it's it's saying something different
it's providing a very different message
so when we compare the bible with the literature of the ancient near east
we'll see not only
the incredible cultural and literary heritage
it was obviously common to them but we'll see the ideological gulf that separated them
and we'll see how biblical writers so beautifully and cleverly manipulated and use these stories
as a set is the vehicle for the expression of a radically new idea
they drew upon these sources but they blended and shape them
in a particular way
and that brings us to a critical problem facing anyone who
six to reconstruct ancient israelite
religion or culture on the basis of the biblical materials
the that problem is the conflict in perspective
between the final editors of the text
and some of the older sources that are incorporated into the bible some of the
older sources that they were obviously drawing on
those who were responsible for the final editing the final forms of the tax
had a decidedly monotheistic perspective at the gaumont theistic perspective and they attempted to impose
that perspective on their older source materials
and for the most part they were successful
but at times the result of their efforts are deeply conflicted deeply ambiguous text and
again that's going to be one of the most fun things for you is readers
of this text if you're alert to it if you're ready to listen to the
cacophony of voices that are within the text
in many respects the bible represents
or expresses a basic discontent
with the larger cultural milieu in which it was produced and that's interesting for us
because a lot of modern people have a tendency to think of the bible
as an emblem of conservatism right we tend to think of this as an old
fuddy-duddy document it's outdated has outdated ideas
and i think the challenge of this course
if you read the bible
with fresh eyes so that you can appreciate it for
what it was in many ways what it continues to be a revolutionary
cultural critique
we can read the bible with fresh and appreciative eyes only if we first technologies
set aside some of our presuppositions about the bible
it's really impossible in fact they do not have some opinions about this work because
it's an intimate part of our culture so even if you've never opened it
already yourself i bet you can
satan line two and i for an eye tooth for tooth
but you don't really know what it means
the poor will always be with you i'm sure you don't really know what that
means these are things increases that we hear and they create with and as a
certain impression of the biblical text and how it functions
verses are quoted alluded to
whether to be championed and valorise or whether to be lampooned and pillory but we
feel that we have a rough idea
of the bible into a rough idea of its outlook
one in fact we really have a popular misconceptions
that come from the way in which the bible been used or misused
most of our cherished presuppositions about
the bible are based on astonishing claims
that others have made on behalf of the bible claims that the bible has not
made on behalf of itself
so before we proceed i need to ask you to set aside for the purposes
of this course
some of the more common myths about the bible have
list here for you
the first is
the idea that the bible the book
the bible is not a book
with all that that implies that it has a uniform style and message in a
single author the sorts of things we think of when we think in the conventional
sense of the word book
it's a library
it's an anthology
of writings are books written and edited over an extensive period of time by people
the coupling constant of the
so you see that
by comparing this to you get a universality lation heterotic string theory which relates
the young males grappling in our case the grand unified coupling constant
this scale the string scale the state should be
the thing scale
and thanks constant
are known to measure the fewest assuming unification therefore there is a very precise
prediction for what this thing scale is if you believe the meaning
heterotic unification
in particular note is that this volume has dropped out in their ratio that's crucial
so it doesn't matter what this volume was this relation is universal
now i have you done in a assumption that i just mentioned earlier views but
there is a completely general and honest argument which
they do that independently of how you do this compactification this universe isolationist correct in
the heterotic string
so the obvious meaning hypothesis is that the the string scale is the unification scale
that's where things should meet because that's the fundamental scale string theory
and if you buy these you see that now we have two parameters for for
predictions as opposed to two four three eight
because you can also predict new tons captain constant or the gravitational capture
so in a sense you may system theory or at least this particular class of
theories predict one more thing for you
and this could have fallen anywhere and actually if you calculated
it follows that into the seventeen gv
whereas in reality it should have been two point four times ten to the eighteen
now here you may a one of platitudes
so well doesn't work
but of course that's a bit too quick we don't want to throw out the
baby with the bath as they say way because
when you think about this prediction on a logarithmic scale it's only off by a
few percent
there is if you think about it there is absolutely no reason why the standard
gauge coupling should know anything about newton's constant and here we are discovering that we
do they need
in such a way that they predict the gravitational coupling very close to its real
they could have meant when we extrapolate this carries anyone else including into the forty
TGV or someone
so i think this is a very successful prediction of is minimal heterotic unification and
in this sense it's the one hundred billion
extra prediction which fits nicely in place
i have here
this debate is namely this
calculation was classical you have to correct for this vessel corrections this depends on what
there's a lot of work has gone into trying to
improve this calculation get rid of this small discrepancy
there's no compelling model organism two
i believe that this discrepancy goes away in some nice
way although there are nice ideas about how this may work but here is then
again the this picture which i think
they suggested regain that meaningless string unification seems to be on the right track
here are the three weak strong and electromagnetic gauge couplings and said they meet
and actually if you also try to promote the gravitational force on the same plot
this has very different behavior because instead of evolving logarithmically with energy
it involves has the power to know gravity couples to energy shows you raise the
energy comes from different stronger on the log plot this is an exponential rise
like any dynamical system that satisfy the constraints i talked about finite action far observation
this week time
mean that one
this is not control by this is describing the system so
every deterministic system then after one thousand years
the deterministic system then prediction to be one of them
but in general to stochastic systems these and all the data
all right
his car
of course somebody said
his first here is the reason why all this
one of the coordinate system this way
the system has the right
which is the rank of this matrix
we call that
let the rank pn
by whatever the and is capital and
what i'm going to show you that this is a good measure of the linear
complexity of this of the system so let's go one more step
it is
this one i think yes
so what does it mean for the system to have rank and it means that
there are at most n linearly independent columns and rows in this matrix
let me for pictorial is imagine that the n rows the caught between these dashed
lines are
linearly independent
let me give special name to those future q one qn called what are called
in the core tests the core features
here's the point here is the key point of this
this this this this material
the fact that this is some nice matrix has rank n means the following has
the following implication
that for any history h any past
if i give you these and numbers
then i can make any predictions
what any future from the same history
by linearly combining these are numbers by that's what right means
that is any column is linearly can put a linearly is a linear function of
these and columns
therefore if i want to make a prediction for any particular view possible future
it's just some linear function of these are numbers
so let me first that right to the protection of any caste t any arbitrator
any arbitrary future all in this history h is a linear function of the the
numbers let me give this special name that's p of q given HEQ is that
set of special test score test is the vector numbers
brigadier you know in april and and seventy is the set up is the parameters
that compute
this answer for this test e
the critical thing is
that ends up t is completely independent of history
that is no matter what their what history it was
to get the answer for this test
requires the same linear combination
by this definition right
OK so what i what i just showed you what i've just shown you is
that these and numbers
all the information there is
arbitrary histories
because i can predict anything about the future i want from just these are numbers
it is their relationships
two this has that flavor yes
i mean i mean no i mean i made the
and could be infinite
that's exactly what i didn't tell you what it is and could potentially be infinite
OK let me anticipate the result of that work my way do it
the result of the the main result that we have on the discrete sites is
the following that if you have any system that can be modeled by a partially
observable markov decision process think humans i think many of you have more knowledge about
and ponte piece of engagements any HMM any system that can be modeled by an
HMM with underlying and states
well i rank no more than
so i'm going to show you
is that we have an alternative representation to HMM upon the piece
it doesn't use any hidden variables
the same dimensionality as hmm
after the same cluster systems
but without using any hidden variables at all
because that's where i'm going
right well i hope how many of you know what a tremendous
not all of you
OK some of you
OK i'll i'll talk about politics led mdps you have a few minutes and that's
when going i'm trying to build a model of dynamical systems that would otherwise the
model is a tremendous upon peace but without using any any hidden variables at all
so i have yet to find the model completely but
i'm going to keep the key concept for this concept of the rank of this
so so but i can be something which is that my representation of state
it is going to be these are numbers
in order to nothing in this
there's no reference to any hidden variables all in this matrix
but there's no notion of underlying unobserved states
everything is expressed in terms of statistics of observable quantities
so they show you some some results like the restructuring of the power of this
idea which is some results suppose you have a markov decision process
with n states
i'm going to show you the rank of the
system dynamics matrix corresponding to the MDP copy more than
not the case
pretty straightforward right so they give you a markov decision processes and states what that
mean that means that the future from any history that and in the same state
is going to be identical
but that would mean for the probably markov that the last observation determines the entire
if these approach affixed to exceed sixty things and this is the big table that
was showing you what you know this is simply the probability of a given x
one x two
you're in all these factors as factors tables have been given to u and i'm
just going in fact is explicitly
so so then what would do is that i'm going to write the joint distribution
as a product of local functions i'm doing an obstruction right and the reason i'm
doing an abstraction is that if you don't understand
why low-density parity-check codes
and viterbi decoding on the same algorithm
units abstraction because through this fractional understand that this thing has been rediscovered so many times
so this is a joint distribution px y of x one x two x three
and this is the exact same formula just plug these back and you will get
the joint distribution
what i managed to do
is it by introducing these factors and i have introduced all the right places you
know this is the vector which includes x three and exports about this vector so
this fact nor will connect those to be able
i can actually write it as a bipartite graph
right with factors on one side and variables on other side
and this back the the simply show which variables participate in which factors
the hope is
the factors involved a small number of variables
each factory was a small number of variables
there can be many factors many variables that's okay what i'm asking for each factor
only involves a small number of we ts
it's a product of local functions that's what i'm calling it
if that's indeed true there a very efficient way
to some this kind of thing over here
let's say everything other than x one
or something on that's are
so the problem is we mostly interested in and this is the inference problem
is that's given
a product of functions product of local functions they inference problem is simply
to marginalize
i want to some all
x two x three
x fourteen x five
so so i want to get your fix one what what remains on x one
i want to marginalize out all the other guys by taking into account the dependencies
now if you'd just write some missions outside the force missions outside
if there are any variables and each each variable x two values
then we talked about in some missions
right to do then comes in the summation and that's an exponential time algorithms if
you're trying to do is to do this in my day
it's an exponential time algorithm however you soon realize that you can push
some of the missions inside
it has further to go
right so so export
can be summed up by purely summing this combat everything other than next three
x five can some out what that supporting the summation inside
have a name
in mathematics called the distributive law
with simplices
that people are
please see is eight times people see why am i going for kids and that's
the reason i'm going for this
is that what we are trying to come up with efficient algorithms
let's come the computations on the left side
i have modifications and one addition
on the left side
i have one multiplication and one addition on the right-hand side distributive law is a brilliant competition
right so
so this whole idea stands at how use distributed line a clever way and this
is about pushing sums has the real goal
you know not repeat computations dynamic programming one one right so so this is this
is what we're trying to do
but we need how do it far like the examples we can of course do
it i'm gonna show you examples with millions of variables in a in a few
but we have to pull this off
you can't write it out and try to push the sum so we need an
algorithm i'm not going to go into the details of the algorithm
but but it's in the best sense of the algorithm is bad
if you're think the bipartite graph
all that stuff
over q one
now the first law
is going to hold in all of these steps and we're going around in a
right so what does that tell us about of the state function like you what
delta u going around the whole thing
of course in the answer what's delta u
MIT students yes
OK so the first
we know that
going around the cycle
delta u
and that has to equal
q plus w summed up for all the steps
which is to say
q one
classic youtube
the album minus w one plus w one last year two
was w two
so that means we can re write this efficiency we can replace this sum
by just the sum of q one plus q two
right so
q one
q two
over q one
or you can write it as one
plus you too
or q one
that already tells us
what we know which is the efficiency is going to be something less than zero
because we've got one
and then read in q two and q one
two it but we got negative q two is positive
number right he was flown in this way
so q the heat in this way is negative
i q two i q one is negative q two course positivity flowing from the
reservoir two engine
so that efficiency is something less than one would like to figure out what that
let's just
state that
well now
let's go back to each of individual steps somewhat based on what we know about
the how about the weight of the dynamic changes that take place here let's look
at each one of the steps and see what happens
from one to two
it's isothermal
and now we're going to specify what to do a coral cycle for an ideal
it's an ideal gas is an isothermal change
what's delta u
you know it's like like lots of course is in all sorts of things that
you sing
there are always the same
what delta u
delta u is zero
and it's also
equal to this so that says you want is
the opposite of w one
it's an isothermal
w is just
native pdvt sort this is just the integral from
one two p
and it's an ideal gas
isothermal right
rt over they were
make it from all gas are times t one
and then we'll have dv over v
that's just the logo of the two
v one
one more
n equals one
two going to three
that's this is a back
so delta use just equal
so the work
we also know what happens because the temperature is changing from t one to t
it's just a CV time t two
minus he one
he received EDT and ideal gas
and that's equal to w one prime
this is the reversible adiabatic passed
so there's is a relationship that i'm
sure you remember
he two
over c one
is equal to
the two
over three three don't be confused by the subscripts that we're talking about a quarter
is both starting at two we're going to three
so v two and v three the different times the temperature of the water is
the same as it was once restored ten t one
and you
exponentiated both sides of the
the inequality
and because the exponential is a bijective function
this is true for any variable x
the probability that x larger than is is the same as the probability that the
lambda x is larger than exponential and that he
you apply chernoff again and that's what you get
and since this is true for any lambda
it's also true for the infimum over land
so this is
i'm not saying that we will use all of this but just these are inequality
you might encounter everywhere if you play around with their probabilities
so it's good to know them
OK so
now let's come back to
our topic
we wanted to see if i come back a few slides
we wanted to
this quantity the expected loss to the empirical loss
so one thing that we will do now
is to rewrite this into form which is slightly more convenient i mean it's there's
no magic here but it's just that is
comm more convenient to see what it means
so we introduce
some kind of meat are random variables
which is the pair x of x i y i write so this
pair here we call it the i
and same x y with quality
and in addition to that
we define
another set of functions so remember we had this set of classifiers which were functions
from x
to y
now we define functions from
x times y
the real numbers
here it would be zero one
that actually correspond to taking the loss
so i should have written
the small and here but
now we're kind of restrict ourselves to the the binary classification setting so it's the
indicator that your text is not equal to y
OK so this is
the loss of pain by my classifier
and for each classifier in
capital city i define such an and i take the set of all such as
and i couldn't capital
now once i have done this
of course i can
we're right
the loss as the expected value of f
computed at x y or z
and the empirical loss
as the average value of f computed at
the data
OK it's just a simplification of notation
expectation of functions sometimes denoted by
p where p is the distribution of this function
and the empirical expectation
five years after that as pn f and n is usually called the empirical distribution
so it's kind of your some of diracs
centre that the data
so is just
to avoid having to
fridays and x and y now we just have some of f of z
some of the above the i here an expectation of f of z
and of course we can go back and forth because like for each f in
f there exists g corresponding to it then for each t there is a christmas
once we have done that
if we look at these quantities so this is nothing but lost minus empirical loss
OK so it's this it's around and viable
and if we look at the collection of all random variables that we obtain when
we vary
the function
g in in capital g or f in capital and equivalently
then we obtain what is called an empirical process what is a process is a
collection of random variables and an empirical process
is a collection of such random variables for which each random bible
as the so-called empirical distribution which means it's the difference between
and expected value and an empirical average
so that's what we have here
i mean
again this does not bring any
significant information but just for you to hear this name empirical prob and that's really
what we are so
there is a whole series of empirical processes where lots of tools are developed
o thing upper bounds on quantities like this
so why is this quantity interesting so now
is where this
fundamental inequalities come in
but before that
i give you some properties of the empirical distribution
o thing lost minus empirical loss is the difference between
the empirical average
and then expectation
as we say
or as
you probably know
there is this
property called the law of large numbers that ensures that if you have
a random variable that you and you take the value of this from viable several
times you take the average value
in the limits
if you do that enough it will converge to the expected value of the random
variables so this is what is written here
when n goes to infinity
this quantity goes to zero with probability one
not only
is the expected value
of the empirical loss equal
to the true loss but also when n goes to infinity they expect the empirical
loss converges to the true
so now the question is how to quantify
how's fast this convergence occurs
there is
what is called of things inequality which does exactly that
can do without you being able to get
possibly all the details
but this is you know
where the questions are and so on
so i think it's more useful for research
in general this is how practical methods
you have the target distribution
over space that increasing
every time i add of blue note that graph
what's really happening is that the distribution is increasing over time one interpretation is that
the dynamical system is
you're only interested in the current time slice
another interpretation is that really what's happening
if you look at the graphical model
is that you're learning a distribution that keeps growing
you keep having to learn more and more and more and more
so you target distribution time n
is the distribution of an unknown
the the next time step the distribution of and plus one nodes and so on
serial our learning over this of the joint
the problem is we never know the normalisation constant z
we don't know the normalisation constant we do have an expression which is usually
in the basic a surprise comes alive
now particle filters are not
something that she is on probation but you can use them from many other things
it's good to look at it from the more general perspective
again said and this what makes this thing some one would think
we define the weights
as the ratio of the quantity of f over q
just like we did yesterday and importance sampling
and what we can do that is we can take the weights
we multiply by the weights and the bias by the weights
because if n minus one divided by q and minus one is just w n
minus one
so this step all i did was i multiplied and divided by the weights
this is the way to minus one
my goal is to obtain the recursive estimator for the weight
that's what i wanna do i wanted the recursion
and q n minus one distribution
so this is p of a and b
this is p of p
so here what i get is p of a given b
and that's the more general expression for the importance
for the importance weights
that's how you would arrive at
the important thing is you writing this importance weights on the past and the whole
part of the problem not just at a particular step
and that's the only way to the right there is the way to the right
the marginal space
but it turns out the competition successes and squared
this is the same thing
so example
bayesian filtering in bayesian filtering
the joint this at is really the product
if all these
increasing the graph rewriting all these stages you know having the horizontal
you know you you you have to say
is at is that if any of these then you have these then you have
and the vertical lines of the pure white is given xt is the horizontal ones
effects is given xt minus one in this distribution can grow over time is important
and the normalisation constant is the integral of the sky
which in this case is just be i want to add which is again the
which is the thing that you would use like if you had two models
you would compute this quantity for each of the models and that's what you would
to choose between the models
the weights in this case
following the expression with arrived in the previously
and you just replace your fnx one two n
the guy
and by the same guy within the only goes and minus one
everything councils except the last guy so you get this expression
in fact the checked
so this is just a combinatorial question
so let me just
a very simple way of viewing a solution to that
so essentially if we view those
m slots here
pigeon holes
and we're gonna put it
symbols in
some of them might have any balls and some will have more than one and
so on
what i'm going to do
so these this is if you like corresponds to alpha one
and this would indicate that alpha one was equal to two because there are two
balls there
and so on alpha two beta two alpha three will be one and alpha forward
is zero and so on
and this will be
alpha m here
which would be equal to two in that case
now what i'm going to do is put a sort of a blank line on
the bottom here
with entities in
sort of
space at the bottom of the
the slots
and now i'm going to do is read off this
sequence from the left
into a single line
it one
start at the first ball
and read to the bottom so in this case i get talked of blank
dot dot blank
dot thank
and so on and i finish with actually dot dot because i'm going to actually
ignore them
that one that the final one will be ignored
what i maintain is now this of course is is now of length
minus one
because remember there were
and banksia and there will be balls and i actually dropped off one so it's
plus be minus one
and now
clearly here we have
in these plus b minus one slots now
we have the balls placed book people's about placed OK
now what i maintain is the one to one card there is a one-to-one correspondence
between putting
b balls into this sequence of n plus b minus one slots and putting the
into these pigeonholes
and i've shown you how you convert pigeonhole allocation into
an application into this
length m plus b minus one
sequence to get the other way round given any sequence in here
you simply start at the left
whenever you start filling this
hole here
and you feel it until you reach a blank
and then you move to the next pigeonholes
so in this case the two
dots indicate that those going to the first if i was doing it this way
those two but thanks those two balls going into the first pigeonhole
then there's a blank so i moved to the second pigeon hole
there are two there so i put them into that
there's a blank side finish that one then this one ball in the next pigeonhole
and then there's blank so i moved to the next one is an immediately another
blank so i don't put anything in this pigeonholing go immediately to the next one
another blank so that gain is is empty
and then this one here and so on
and however you put the balls in
you can perform that operation and you will exactly fill up
a certain peoples into the pigeon holes and there is a one-to-one correspondence you can
see i think quite badly
another reason for doing that is it's not very easy to i mean the
the actual way of counting the number of ways of putting the balls into n
plus b minus one source is just the standard combinatorial
a plus b
minus one
choose be
so that's the that's the result
it i gave it in a slightly different form because actually isis
this is the definition we're done
step three is probably the hardest part
step four we've already done
let's start with step one
so the first thing i need to do is to find a convex function because
we're gonna
manipulate that definition
so this is notion from
real analysis
analysis of fancy work calculus taken
proper analysis class
should have seen convexity in any calculus class
convex functions one looks like this
one way to formalize that notion
is to consider any two points on this curve
so i'm i'm only interested in functions for real to real so
looks like this this is for something
and this is the something
if i take two points on this curve
and i draw
the line segment connecting them that line segment is always above the curve
that's the meaning of convexity
it has the geometric notion which is basically the same for functions
this line segment should stay above the curve the line does not state above the
curve extended it farther it goes beneath the curve of course
but that segment should
so i'm going to formalize a little bit of call this axis
and then this is f of x
and i call this
and this is after y
so the claim is if i take any number
between x and y
and i look up
i said OK here's the point on the curve
here's the point on the line segment the value of that point the y value
here should be greater than or equal to the y value here
to figure out what this point is
we need some
and i would call it geometry features
analysis concept two
but i mean geometry
i get to college geometry
if you have two points
p and q
and you want to parameterize this line segment between
so one approach for some point here
the way to do it
is to take a linear combination
and if you
should have taken some linear algebra
linear combination looks something like this
and in fact we're going to take something called an affine combination
where alpha postpaid equals one
it turns out
if you take
if you take all such points
some number alpha times the point p for some number of times the point you're
output has been equals one
take all the points you get the entire line here
which is nifty but we don't want the entire line if you also constraints
alpha data to be nonnegative
just get this line segment
so this forces have invaded between zero and one
is that the sum to one another
so what we're going to do here is take alpha time axis was beta times
that's going to be
our point in between with these constraints about the possibility because one alpha and beta
particles zero
then in this point
is f of that
for alpha x
plus ba y
and this point
is the linear interpolation between f of x in f of why the same one
alpha times f of x
because data times from one
that's the intuition
he didn't follow is not too
big deal because all we care about are these
the symbolic cancer proving things but that's where this comes from
so here's the definition
function is convex
for all x and y
and all
alpha and beta
great american zero sum
this one
we have
f alpha x beta y
is less than or equal to alpha f of x
because they from more
that's just saying this why corner here
it is greater than this what are classical of this one caught
but that's the symbolism behind that
OK so now we want to prove jensen's inequality OK we're not quite there yet
we're going to prove
a simple and
from which it will be easy to derive
jensen's inequality
so this is the
there more proving
there's a lot more about convex functions you may have seen before
it will be crucial jensen's inequality
we have
suppose this is a statement about half combinations of and things instead of two things
so this will the convexity can be generalized to
taking and things
so suppose we have n real numbers
and we have and
values alpha
one of the alpha and
they're all nonnegative
and there are some is one
the sum of alpha
OK i guess
OK because want and
it is one
because of the assumptions
is the same thing but summing over all k
OK i want and
o k x k
take f of that versus taking the sum of the alphas times the earth's
because what
less than 100 million accuracy and in those year dollars but it was an excellent
program every tests that was conducted was documented analyzed and and we can make that
so that concludes the things that I had to take a year and we get
there are just about right and do you have any questions it should like that
if not I'll give you test yes all of the right of the highway effect
the train on all of you
1 of the most
this is going to be give you the rest of the building of all that
kind of stuff like sites
and when I say hypersonic let me take it down to modify
was probably the best its predictions that we had
a flat plate which the belly of the order has a little bit of surface
depending both in the page playing and in the all playing for
for stability if you put a big sphere segment of sphere you could place the
on that in UCI so I know us fear sadness fear stability now at the
turned out not to be a normal forces or even sad forces pitching moment is
the 1 that you tend to to miss the most and sometimes you don't know
if you have a wrong pitching moment are wrong center of gravity they
most precipitated delta pitching moment coefficient changed and the big born doors we have that
in the system we control not only a rate control system but an attitude control
systems and so it takes with the 70 square foot Volodymyr just takes a small
amount of change to correct any that you might have in CG pitching moment so
you control mechanism is with the big elevators and also the body flap a little
bit if you would use that as the reaction control system is right system and
I didn't mention that in that we intentionally put the act of
reaction control system in the wake of the vehicle even though for orbital manoeuvring we
have an jet-setter the forward firing about so much uncertainty and how that changes the
dynamics and surface not a hard surface and that interaction is you can change things
in such a way that you amplifier reduce it and so we elected not to
gotta grapple with that problem and you just cfgs but it's just for a control
system and pH
at distance that separated that any all both on both sides and enrolled
so those that that's that's where the theory of information and
x 15 was a lol angle of attack airplane type configurations from March 25 to
modify add new flying a spacecraft can configuration where you basically role about the velocity
vector OK you wanna maintain that pitch trim
and wrote about the velocity vector for crossrange in either direction now when you begin
transition because you gotta be down here when you landed and you pick the best
place to do that and the best place to do that is back in the
market below 5 courses and above the sub sonic regime and we try not to
have any maneuvers Rosetta required during that time period anytime you going from a totally
separated flow in the back of the vehicle to 1 that is now attached separated
flow can make up its mind sometimes it will be separated as you be attached
not the whole vehicle but even on small pieces of the vehicle and so there's
uncertainties that come in there but but that's that's the area uh that that that
that today but you can be sure enough for you or OPT as far away
as we and became more and more brave and to get those coefficients and in
another 100 per good job of it you have the thats right here thats it
instead of the things like that of the area
OK what you do doing you're change in the Newtonian flow now my flat plates
70 square foot per serving here at very end the India
so now I've got a normal force coefficients assigned squared of the angle OK and
I just change the angle up and reduce the forces on that and that gives
me a knows about bring it down that gives me a nose-down works beautifully which
means body flap elevators both
about 5 and a half control services based on the white hats off the best
of their land and what sort of reasoning that other factors transitional itself and so
actually that we safely energy know everything and then we have designed and these palate
test inputs to extract aerodynamic characteristics same technique that the Edwards developed and they did
develop that by the way on the x 15 and on other vehicles to and
we use the same technique which sent to 1 or Manhattan he spent about almost
a half a year learning all the techniques Robert that bag and developed that the
and of work reaction at very very closely training for those manoeuvres we extracted data
for those manoeuvres we would change the aerodynamic characteristics and not tell what they are
and see you know and in in the simulators and make sure that we didn't
get me difficult and making sure there'll people could extract the data right and tell
us how we change it they all got ladies and were very very well so
far from the notices that did that when that was for the approach and landing
test but for the entry those were supersonic any of you here and you have
a sense of what was the 1st full of what was the 1st phase of
the of the of the of the of the only
the technologies that people
the wording of the question of what you
with the local of because I know all about it the and removed from
so we would like to thank you for your help
and all the other kinds of
because the computerized so that we would like to do
she on of this side
you can see
thank you so he
so you
my advisor
he did not know
he was
so it
he's is of course not
it is
and this
she was the
that's not
this is
he was