to find points that match each other one configuration to the other in
this notation that saying Xi J equals I K A that is they both correspond
to the same hidden point that's the here is the formulation so this this sketch
shows you what we're trying to do the anything's we know are the red points and the green ones
X and Y drawn for emphasis in different spaces we're trying to infere
rest so it looks like quite a heroic thing to do so we're inventing this new process and
the points generated by selection from that and adding noise there's the Xs in the
case of the Ys selection from them adding noise and then transforming through this transformation
A in case we're trying to make an inference about everything except the the data
which are the red and green points now there's a what we're gonna do is start
getting rid of some of the sup you know superfluity redundancy in this formulation
the first thing will do is notice that really the the indexing of the hidden
points is arbitrary and if we don't observe anything based and all we really care about
is this matching matrix one oh zero depending on whether the J F X point matches the
K F Y point so that who M J K so this is a binary matrix there
is most one one in each row and column because you can't have multiple matches and
the total of all of the entries is the number of matches and that's of course
so unknownso this this M is a key objective inference this this is this provides
the matching we want and we want a prior distribution for that and that's set up in this
way we're going to suppose the hidden points which are you know our our creation
it's our model I'm gonna suppose they form a homogeneous poisson process so that's the point secure completely
random at a rate lambda per unit volume of a certain volume V and then we need
a model for whether or not these hidden points are actually observed in X all
Y or both and what we do then is set is set independently for each point
that those hidden points can give rise to either no observations account
be seen in either the data sets they can be seen only in X only in Y
or in both so it's four possibilities so what we're thinking basically with each of the hidden
point we're gonna through a four-sided coin to decide which of those possibilities happens and
if we assume those two things together with a third point that all
matching matrices with the same number of matches have the same probability and that's simply
action exchangeability assumption saying I think equally about any ordering of the Xs or
or the Ys I think is equally probable so under those three assumptions we we can construct simple probability
theory you can construct a prior to the matching matrix and it has this geometric form which is slightly
misleading cause of course there's a set different numbers of matrices with the same total match count so
those are prior to M and if you I'm not going for this now cause I want to mention
a little more detail on the slides about a detail how you work that out it basically corresponds to the
to the well-known fact that if you randomly thin a poisson process you still get a poisson process I
now we're gonna think about the data given the hidden points and this
matching information what's the likelihood of the data itself you can you have to
do this separately for each possible class of transformation so I'm gonna do need do a simple case
for now I'm gonna take in fact throughout today I'm gonna take an affine transformation A is a norm singular matrix kept
his rotation scaling and possibly shear and there's a translation as well and it turns out
that under that that setting together with the the assumption that we've made about the poisson process
for the hidden points it turns out the actual locations of the hidden points
can also be integrated out okay you just you can just do these integrals analytically and
very often and not absolutely always it's a good idea to remove variables analytically from
your model if you can so that's a slow at the dimension of the space the
things we don't know and then we have that fairly explicit form of of likelihood
then again the slides is a bit more detail about that where
that arises so in terms of this cartoon we took this picture before we observe the
for a the other way
that is the
is feasible
then we can prove it by
describing a convex combination
this well describe a finite set that i said earlier to had these characterizations we
it's important that we have a easy description
of the system of inequalities
and we also have an easy description
of a set of points whose whole
is that so
i think i neglected to mention we want an easy description of the point who's
also by having both we have one
kind of the characterization just described
and of course we be
there is
we've got an axe
we want to know
does not
maximize cx subject to that
x px means
cx does not maximize
cx subject to that
well it's a it's that's
and that's in the knowledge that doesn't it is so one
you show that you have shown exit make cx bigger
but that and
and then of course
we have an easy description that enables us to
that we're showing
x bigger and still feasible
and yes if the negation of the predicate is true that is that is actually
does maximize cx
because we have an easy description of these inequalities we can
we can prove that
x optimizes by displaying
a dual solution
well so i got this idea for a couple years before his photos
papers that
i just showed you get these ideas
this this philosophy couple years before i had any examples of it all
and i started looking for examples of it
and the
and submodularity polymatroids is is one of the things i found when i was explicitly
examples of
so let's see other places
i recall automate radius
by a scene outcomes from the columns of the matrix are
finite set of vectors in a vector space
you know you certainly learn in your first out of course
and every for finite set of vectors in a vector space
for matrix
areas that called that americans every maximal linearly independent of columns is the same size
and that's rather magic is and you know you do your girl seen that in
any way at all and you end up with
with the degree of zeros
and so on that day but it always sends out the same number
that it
and this is called the
this gives you the so-called rank of the matrix
the largest linearly independent that well
may try to simply an abstract statement of the same thing
you've got to say
the models the set of vectors
and so called independent subsets
so that
any subset of the
well first of course every subset the seventies and then but for every subset s
every basis of st
is the same size
and so on
every basis of s is the largest
and then it's up that's and that's called the rank
so there is a direct reflection
i mean
a linear algebra there now i don't like the existing books called matrix theory
because this is a they stressed pushing snacks themes around
there are close to this definition and
winners and they try and given by over by matrix over a field
and things like that all that i don't dislike that
reach this point here and that gives you the final evaluation and here's the recursive definition
of how you evaluate so the the zero row is set to one for
M greater or equal to zero and then the X is equal to zero for
the if your M is less than the you know if you haven't had a
chance to get down that far because you've only seen X features then this
must be zero all that corresponds to is  you know things out here can't
be can't be zero nonzero and then there's a recursive way in which you evaluate the next
sorry the next node here say from the values here and here so you can
evaluate those by just adding the two paths that you can reach that vertex from the
left or from below with the extra feature add it in and the final kernel is that
bottom right-hand corner value here
D is a user-specified number you know you say I'm interested in using up to
find features from my hundred dimensional feature set and it will select all possible combinations
of Y features so you might I mean you could of course if you wanted
combine you know essentially reading off here you've got DD minus one up to so
could combine those if you wanted to have a sort of spread of different combinations
add these together and you get a kernel combining those different amounts of features that you
might want to include
so again you I'm just trying to give you this flavour that you could move away
from sorry not moving away from microphone move away from these sort of very clean like
the  polynomial kernel it's a slightly more complex combinations of features you can sort of sculpt
your feature space to the particular knowledge you have of your particular feature set you
may know that there are certain features that should be combined certain that shouldn't and you
can set up graphs even basically define your own graph any directed acyclic graph
in which you have a source and a sink and your edges are labelled with with
your features you can define it and impose your understanding of the way the
features should be combined essentially every path through that graph will correspond to a combined feature
the product to the features on that path will make up that feature
and every you know you just have to think of how all of those paths
should be defined in order to create the feature space that you think captures what
what your data's about now I you know this is coming to the the crux
of kernel methods I mean it's sort of sounds too good to be true and
of course in a way it is  it all comes back to defining the
kernel you know you're essentially building in your prior knowledge of your data into the
kernel in such a way that it will contain enough information for you to do
the job you're interested in doing and and will  present it in the right way
so at this point it would really be useful  and probably I should've actually
described the the bayesian view of what a kernel is basically is a
covariance function over the expected covariance over a a distribution over the possible functions and so
you can see it is encoding a prior belief of the possible functions you might
be choosing for your learner and so points that are close in a kernel
space in the kernel measurement are points that are similarly classified or similarly have similar
outputs in the or likely to have similar outputs in this distribution over functions so
that's a way the bayesian view a kernel code as a covariance function I think
it's a very useful way of viewing it when we come to thinking about defining
kernel functions they are our way of encoding our prior knowledge about the likely functions we're
going to see  in in in in our learning that said you know I
think that it's often easier to think of them as a similarity measure and to
define I mean you know by defining that similarity measure we are defining a
prior over those functions but in a way if you're thinking from a user's point
of view defining a similarity between inputs is something they can really relate to
if you go back to neural net days you'd ask the user will how many
hidden notes should I use you know that's you know he doesn't even have any
interest in in in how your  classifier's constructed so here with sort of I
think making a more user-friendly way of defining your prior knowledge about the particular
domain but but it is not as friendly as it might be because part of
it is having to define these ways of computing these efficiently but also having to
make sure that the function satisfies this rather arcane property of positive semi definiteness so in
the general case of acyclic graph we just need to have this numbering so that
the it's compatible with the acyclicity in other words if U Y has an
edge to U J then I should be less than J so the ordering is compatible with the acyclicity
of the graph and then we just run this dynamic programming algorithm initialize these source
node to one and this is the sort of iteration that node I you look at all
the nodes before it that are connected to it put in the kernel on those
nodes I mean this is you know you  could component kernels on your features
does the berkeley passed through and the boundary passes through something like water and to
the demise one boxes then we say that this is a d minus one dimensional
curve or box higher dimension is d minus one
so everybody understand that idea it's a way of characterizing the fact that the boundary
is one dimension lower than the ambient feature space
so it's a pretty mild assumption something probably holds in most practical problems
and further refine
the attention to such subsets of this d box the classes
learning problems
when you also index with can
and kappa guinness's transitions from this we're showing people one where we have chance
between the between the black and white area kappa
greater than one where there are some sort of smoothness so kappa greater than one
means we have some smooth derivatives saying that transition region
and the smoothness of the transition region affects how well we can approximate
decision boundary
if we look at different resolutions over partitions so i'm just looking at histogram like
partitions this is the approximation of that decision function the decision functions above if i
look at
resolution of two the four to the minus five into the nineteen sixty you see
as we increase resolution we get better and better approximation to the bayes decision boundary
and what happens is if you actually look at the difference between the probability of
error of approximation of the bayes decision boundary it will take a liking to the
minus cap so the larger kappa is the more smooth transition is the more we
can be kind crude rough about we're reporting are approximated boundary and will still get
small difference between the probability of air
so that they everybody
so this and to
kappa decay approximation something that's important in world war i use that later when we
look at some of these rates of convergence but the main ideas again as kappa
gets larger i can be more sloppy so for example
if i had equal to say
which is maybe what this case notes
the difference between this approximation and the idea of bayes classification
boundary which would look like the curve up there would be smaller
we have is equal to the main campus is one
so the way that you approach this problem is using something we call dyadic decision
trees and i just want to be clear about what we're talking about we have
labelled training data
there are some bayes decision boundary that would like to learn
we first small partition the space into lots of tiny boxes
and then we prune that partition that based on the data to obtain some approximation
to the bayes decision boundary and the main the reason that this is called a
dyadic tree is because although the cells have dyadic sizes size like one by one
and one-half i one half
one four five one four and so on and so forth so we're just doing
dyadic cuts partition of this feature space we can dyadic partition
two very fine
level and then we can prune back to
something adapted show here
and everything that will be talking about the rest of this talk is joint work
with my former student clay scott
so the partition
we would take majority vote on each cell that gives us the decision trees i
talked about before
OK so what time try to walk you through is the following
if we look at this class of problems that i was considering
in i mean focus on the case where you have question back there
and so on
why is binary
what we actually do is we divide
one coordinate time in practice and you can either do that in a cyclic fashion
ranges serve cycle through coordinates or you can do it more in you even more
flexibility where you choose which one axis to split on each time so we really
are just using binary trees as opposed to larger is when we do this and
that one of the reasons for that gives us more adaptability and it also allows
us to tackle higher dimensional space is divided the dimensional space and i was doing
a d dimensional split
i go from one box into two to the d boxes and of course to
deal with ten
that would be
pretty problematic so we split one point access is that at the time so i
was really thinking about binary trees so the progression things
so i'm going to focus on the case where the boundary smoothness is is equal
to one and also more about that later it's tricky problem to handle smoother boundaries
don't worry about it right now
kappa is the transition smoothness will throw either be from a job at that level
set one half to some smooth transition
and d is the dimension of the problem so for these situations we know that
the rate at which we can learn as a function of the number of data
can decay faster than and to them cap over two kappa let's d minus two
that's the lower bound we
no from the theory was developed by them in same coffin what i'll show is
that by using these dyadic decision trees and with appropriate pruning scheme we can actually
get a similar error decay rate
within a logarithmic factor just another little notational practice quickly lesson equals means i'm ignoring
the constants that might be from just looking at the rate of convergence as a
function of the training set size
so that's what i mean try to explain to you in the next
forty minutes or so
OK so
well the drug was introduced to them
drug users from the previous year and so on and so we we had this
for five years and of course we can begin to do
a lot of analysis
well in by could we have two different possibilities of how to describe those temporal
networks because
one time the one is more suitable any other time the second is more suitable
for example if we look at this one
we have three vertices and for vertex a for example is present at timepoint tend
to timepoint time point five to ten point ten and then into timepoints eleven it's
not present but it's still it's again present from time point fourteen twenty twelve two
time points fourteen
this one here means that e is present for from time point four
to the end of time points
and four edges
cause this one or this one is present just in time point seven but we
have to be careful that link is present only if both and vertices this is
also present by also controls for that
if we have the second description this would be
with events well here we have a table of all the events that are possible
and how we can well then
this is the description of this temporal network for example we start with time point
one week and we add vertex two
we a b
then the time point three and
and we hide vertex two
that point four star
we add more vertex three
that that has name e and the time point five starts
we and vertex one
with the navy and so on course or this for example here we delete edge
vertex one to vertex a vertex two and so on this how
he goes OK well i have also
one example that we can looking pi
and we're going to his friends
don team network what
so we go to far
time events networks read
we have this team
OK we opened it
and we get this our network in this
in this network
part of the pipe
of course
what what we have to do is still if we just draw this
this network
we get all the lines and in
that are in the
the network at any of the time steps so what we have to do
is we have to generate
the network
time steps
and we start from time one to time step
eleven because i know that there are just too many times
and we're going to go back to to step one
so we will get
now we get
different networks
and if we just go to the first network
we see that we just had
the vertices so in the first
in the first time step there just
eight vertices and three
go next
in the next time step
more well there's means in this
network and then this
start to change well what's the difference between the
black and blue lines
the blue line describes an edge and the black is an art
OK so that's how we go
tell time
eleven which is the last one
edge we
and and are the leagues
sorry i don't i i
it contains for a
so once you try this disguise
you can compute some statistics and we will need some notation you are to be
able to do that
so in all the time timestamp mind you have tried
the arms eight times the number of times we have tried
an online after this time for
so this capital t one
at t minus one
so four
this the same for two
and so
our choices are going to to be made by carefully one can two and so
what the because there an extant right
we have tried one two three four
so far relating the program you define this loss so was this
so you could check if you could take the optimal are don't know which which
one of these two answers to optimize denote its indexed by k such so that's
an unknown quantity
what you want to compare this
is the
support turn
received that are
imagine that you have for this
during the first cabinet he tries so what would be the return receipt so that
this one here
so this is our baseline
and what do you get
this quantity here so
at times the
he you've chosen a after he
and this is the number of times that are was chosen
so far and so this is really what you are going to receive the funds
you compute your
the actual return
and compare it with the proper that returned that you could have received if you
the optimal
are from the first times that
minimizes the grand prize
the scale
these are on the road we're going to take expectations and that takes care
you can compute the high profile
this is the loss that we want to control
so we can conclude this loss on in retrospect so once to learned
the identity of the right so then then you could compute the laws but nevertheless
we want to design and target and that
that makes this laws
not increase too fast
right so i think about it it's like that not dividing by
by capital so this is not the average loss per time step so the average
loss per timestep should idea decreased is towards the right
but if you're not dividing by
cavity then this loss is going to grow
maybe at a slower rate
but there is nothing that would prevent it to grow
so what it would mean that if this loss would stop growing
it would mean that after a certain number of times that
this hundred person accuracy you have identified the optimal are
you do that
maybe not
OK so internet this loss is going to grow his capability
and what you want to do
is to limit the rate of growth
so what's a good rate
something that sublinear in t something that grows smaller and g
because if if you have such loss then if you divide by t and
the loss per time step is decreasing prices
and this is what want
very simple idea
it is to compute the action values
for the arms
that you have
just to pick the best so that would be exploitation all the time
and why is this a bad idea
what is the a certain it can happen if you are not
what is that is a star
that can happen
exactly so
you could have you can be unlucky because of similar at the beginning right
if you're lucky is the optimal arm to estimate the
its value is less than the value of the other and so if you just
exploit all the time
we are going to stick is that are which is the salt of our and
your loss is going to grow in our
so you want to explore
in many ways
most of these methods what they do is they just compute the action that all
the computer action bias value basically take average
standard planning computational tools to actually use policy search reinforcement learning inside
the box so here again expert prioritize the space of possible policies how do you
want to say in response to this kind of state how do you want to
send control action and then there's an offline search just goes on and on
some building some places grinds away and finds an excellent policy for the model not
for the real world but the model close enough to the real world so that
when they take this policy actually put it in a helicopter well
i have to show you if you think a lot of people have seen these
before i apologize but
there there wicked call bear watching multiple times
so there's a helicopter on the ground making lots of dust in the second test
at this point that's taking off the
upside down
right now it's about flying
this can have an around i think even that hard but compared to these other
stuff doesn't look are so
first start
he so-called split so it's diving and then twisting in diving
and then going around the other way
and then going upside-down that's still starkest alterna
the helicopter
that's supposed to be able to do that
there are there are people that can do the stunts but they didn't that's not
how they trained
big just train the flying normal and then maybe little upside down i guess and
told what the what they want distance to look like that was actually falling backwards
tail first
it's now flying backwards in the inner loop
this crazy
i don't want to be in and out of this model helicopters by the way
so these are these are like you know you a big appeal big enough that
you want to get hit by the blades but not big enough that you have
any threat of writing it
stationary roles it's just sitting there flipping over on its back
and flips so
so tailor overhead head of retail
one not moving otherwise
the tax it's acting like a pendulum
what you know
no they told to do this
twenty minutes
why does it never fall down
it's throwing itself in the ground and missing no idea why does it never fall
down because it's it's controlling itself right so it's it's very carefully adjusting the angle
of the rotor is the speed of the back the speed of the top thing
so that it's it's
fuselage goes through that series of positions
so it's very carefully flying
so those purely because there's been a
the estimate the
the this is
eight of the high
you know so it knows yes that's right it's trying to it when i was
told to do the stationary roll it with the goal of the way that the
reward function was specified is you should stay at all
you're delta altitude should be close to zero
but your feet should be where head is and then the other one so they
specify the reward function that way and then
through the control policy has to figure out what controls are going to cause me
to go through that series of
so it's it's pretty wacky
they were the what they are i mean they have to have pretty good sensors
on it so they can detect position pretty well and
o yeah they treated completely as an MDP not upon the first when you said
how noisy was michael the people are wearing headphones some pretty sure it's loud
yes they know that this is this work is all done assuming that the state
information is accurate
right so that was that was pretty impressive here's some other some other core results
just kind of powering through here you can also combine
this is again the sort of nested idea where you learn model and then based
on the model you learn value function based on the value function you act so
this is some work
like to thank the organisers or is this i added to the particle momentum modeling
and applications
meaning that
i will say much about theory of convex optimization and not about the word for
solving convex optimisation problem
and this is based on work with stephen boyd this book and courses that have
been teaching at UCLA and and
so the the the the three lecture the first of those being introduction some background
on convex sets and functions
part two the talk about the standard problem classes and some recent problem classes semidefinite
programming second order cone programming have been studied recently
and then the third lecture you look at applications and three
classes of applications
been the focus of most of the recent interest in light of the decision problem
three of the
areas where people
i have been very active
so start with an introduction on
the power lectures
be talking about mathematical optimisation problems minimizing nonlinear cost function subject to linear equality inequality
constraints vector variable x
and that's the general framework of the nonlinear optimization problem so obviously it's very useful
throughout engineering statistics and
estimation numerical analysis
and the most important thing to to note first that this problem is actually extremely
hard in general
the complex is very much dependent on the properties of the function involved
inequality and ecological function
and actually
that's what i think textbooks optimistic optimisation iterative scanning
we don't have good methods for solving the the general linear optimisation problem
so that means in practice you have to make some compromises
and usually that means that you resort to local optimisation
which can be done efficiently but you find only in suboptimal local solution to the
unless you're willing to do global optimisation for most applications that do
now there are important exceptions
there that's the situation is much better
there you can find the global optimum is very reliably
and the best known exceptions only scratching the programming
also convex optimisation is actually more less the most general class of problems that can
and that's something that people didn't appreciate very much until the last fifteen years
the full expression in a programming this has been very well known for a long
convex optimisation problems
it's more recent
so let's take something about these linear programming
contrast that with a convex optimisation
so what you are familiar with these squares of minimising the norm of x minus
the euclidean norm
and as a user
of these stress
in practice
the most important things to note probably the only thing you need to know what
the user
is that there is a formula for an analytic solution for the solution of the
the rank of a it's for people the number of columns
it can be solved efficiently the very good model software just three took back in
the solution is really no need to know how the solution is obtained
and the computation time is linear it's polynomial is linear in the number of rows
of a and about in the column
and that's
very efficient and for senior large a you need to look into you may need
to look into exploiting structure to do it more efficiently for most problems is sufficient
and if you want to use the best in practice formerly practical problem is the
scratch problem
then there are actually very easy to recognise because it's also very specialized problem minimizing
the sum of squares of linear functions of x
take an extremely
specific class of problems
but they are also easy to recognise
people have a few standard tricks to increase the flexibility
for example you can handle
constraints to some extent by adding weight
and the quadratic penalty on the interaction
by solving a weighted least squares problem you can
handle constraints to some extent
but it's basically very limited and only a few a few standard techniques that increase
applications a little bit
linear programming is this problem that we minimize the objective function linear in subject to
linear inequality constraints
and they have the same
kind of
properties least stress the only difference is that there is no analytical formula for the
but that doesn't make a big difference in practice because you solve this problem by
computer anyway so the fact that you have formula for the solution is really
that much
there is also very easy very easily obtained and reliable software
and computation is roughly proportional to
and square m
and n is the number of variables and m is the number of inequality
basically that the cost of an interior point method because of one iteration in the
point that it would be
and square
and the number of iterations
roughly constant as a function of and
get this for dense problem
so again as a user that's all we need to know about the algorithms for
and then if you want to pose a practical problem as a linear programming problem
then there is a little bit harder to recognise the least first problems because problems
always come in the form you need to do some of you some reformulation of
information to get exactly in standard form
but after a few examples you know all the tricks people use to
four minutes
problem as a linear programming problem
and after a few examples that come very easy to recognise
so for example typical example that give is actually piecewise linear function minimizing piecewise linear
function of x
it is a problem that can be solved NLP because it's easily written as an
LP can be solved
the programming problem
other problems involving one or infinity norm
it can also be written as a linear programming problem
and finally for a convex optimization problem is so we say much more about this
this is not actually a very good explanation of the data because
in something happened here which according to the model should happen with almost zero probability
it did happen
that seems a little odd
the probability of the data under the scouts in isn't very good
so things are looking a little bit better here
so what if we make me if you make catcalls very wide
then of course
initially things look even better
all of the data points actually lie relatively speaking quite close to the mean of
because the gaussians was extremely wide
again it's the same argument right
the gas an extremely wide so it could account for any dataset
so we shouldn't be too surprised that also accounted for this one
and actually it's likely the right solution here would be to write down
the likelihood function to maximize likelihood
one of the white likelihood function look like well if this is a gas distribution
centre and zero
then the
the likelihood function which is the gauss in the log likelihood
with the with the zero oil with me knew was chosen to be zero
it's just the log of the gas in and that the log of the
exponentiated term the longer the normalisation constant
this is exactly the same expression is read before
it's a data fit term
otherwise should lie close to the mean
as measured by the red
and also
the volume should be small this the data complexity term at the same time as
before except that the one-dimensional version of that
there are also the same
nine cost the
so the marginal likelihood that i
giving the process
it's just the multivariate version of this
please you believe this then you should also believe the of
it tells you
it it tells you exactly why this overfitting problem is happening right if you only
if you're only interested
in the observations lying close to the mean
as measured by the variance
then this can be done trivially by just turning off the variance
this is this is just the sort of the data for term the data for
term in itself
it's also
you can just maximize
the only way you could do that if you are working somehow constrained class model
then it might work like
all right so
but this is another way of of of thinking of these girls in process
so tried to try to just use to slice through two to look at different
of thinking about golf courses
the notice
this sort of
it's unusual to think about distributions of functions right
so probably most of you are a little bit uncomfortable this still housing uncomfortable with
it for years
also i didn't have any which i to ask you can ask me for to
you're in a good position
so the point here is a construction that comes from that goes from a parametric
model which were used to
to the corresponding isoprofit
let's first two in a very simple case that's doing it into interesting case on
the next slide
here we go to now
we look at
possibly now functions functions are extra p
but now we think of the coefficients
as being random
if the coefficients here are randomly
and that somehow implies also that the distribution
but is the distribution or
somehow the distribution
overall mean function
let's say that the
these these are random
they have distributions that gauss distributions
which is zero mean
and the distribution for a has the variance of the distribution for p has to
now this distribution over functions is actually about process
we can compute which counts processes
by just computing
the mean function and covariance function
OK so what is the mean function
the mean function
is the average
of the of the of f evaluated at any particular x
so now
in this expectation
x is fixed
and it's a and b that around
this is an expectation over the distribution of a and b
for any fixed x
OK so we just plug in to the
formula for expectation so that the integral of f of x
the joint distribution of a and b
i happen to be independent in this case
and integrating out
a and b
OK so if we
so we just plug the value for
for the for the function of here we get any intercourse part so this one
term that depends on a in the long-term depends on the
this can be written on this
seven tentacles
in both these integrals have value of zero just because of symmetry
so this is just the average of the
these b has average to zero
this thing here
it's a x can go outside into google and then just the average of a
times x
which is also zero
this is not so strange just saying if you take an average over all functions
within this class
then the function value on average
i this has done lots of people enjoy exploring the slightly
complications or ramifications of very
hearing this that so
OK i'm several extreme but i really like
having the discipline of adhering to a simple thing and making sure we've said
all the important things about that simple thing rather than
you know making more papers by coming up with special cases like special case of
the the main cases hard enough and rich enough that we should be able to
address such OK
so anyway you don't have to do that but i i want to put this
on the table you to say that
reward is the is the basic things that
this key two
the the the impact of our field that simplicity
and this is a clear statement OK so in particular was a little more this
we get autonomous the the other half of reward with we we don't know the
reward and value i haven't done that i want to talk about
why is it so why is it so important one reason is we don't have
to teachers to desired things we can have things we learn for self reward let's
so if you're playing so here the examples TD gammon appointed again as i said
you can play the game against yourself and see if you win or lose you
get the outcome in the end you did when you did lose you can learn
from that you can learn to play better than any human player you don't require
teacher you can just get that if you if you're flying helicopter you can fly
helicopter perhaps in simulation and crash or not
and you can you can learn from that you can verify whether or not you
have a good policy someone do the robocup dogs is just one example of this
issue this kind of kind of clear in the power of being it's what's really
almost like the same thing in genetic algorithms that can run many many simulations and
to find something which really good and have been there is the power of search
being mechanistically tell whether or not you have a good policy so this has been
done in robocup soccer where they have these robot dogs that have to learn to
play soccer in this is this is the learning center the reinforcement learning center they
interview to play soccer it's really important you could always win actually if you can
run faster than the other guy you can do quite well
and so there very concerned making them run faster and what we have is the
field where we put these robots in they they can see these pencils
and they basically walk back and forth they try one style walking towards to the
pedestal and they they have the clock see long takes and they turn around a
they run back and they can they can they can be used for weeks and
weeks they can figure out a good way
to walk so here's
one the sound
just a little bit so here they're just walking back and forth you diseases the
clicks stopwatch
turned around and walked back forth and they do this for a long time
its key
they you know they can figure it out they can try different ways walking
takes and try different ways one day sockets this
and you can use to this over and over again and find a better way
better way to to what
so that's the power being verify for yourself and so they did this and then
after a while they end up with the best way there's anyone had ever found
to walk so here's the robot from
here's me
from the initial this is the before
video so
you program them to the variety of ways walking up be very good
and this was a very good one and experiment to try different things
and then after after awhile after
a few weeks they end up having the fastest way than anyone had ever find
bound to have these robots walk not you can walk and zealous
who'd have thought
that turns but also knows he's gone kind of faster
it's going to be play faster than before and so this is just the power
we'll tell for yourself whether which you can you can save
human programmers of time and you can get up with much better results than previously
possible and in fact all the robot dogs pretty much that there is robocup cup
soccer now he's learned
policies for walking
OK a little bit more reward
because from reward
follows the idea of value
given equation is this later
the value function you all know is just expected some of the future discounted reward
OK so that something is really simple theory that value long-term goal is maximizing the
the short-term goal and the value function hypothesis is that can use all again because
i want to be
the strong
all efficient methods for solving sequential decision problems
estimate as intermediate step is made value functions as an intermediate computation towards
to find a good policy finding good solution
i think
this what i feel we learn
the last
and know how many years of
the field that we need value functions and this is this comes from when reward
you're in the world of value functions pushing those from
from optimal control from forever
and and really
we're just carrying this further
and relating to different fields OK so i'd better move on to some other ideas
but want to mention so really the whole computational theory all the film it's really
follow what you reward after value functions and natural models and temple different areas dynamic
programming and much of much of things
OK the idea certain idea
so the idea is sampling
time reward now sampling so i sampling i mean first sampling as well trial and
error learning like a rat in maze tries things samples different actions also as in
and is
you see them on
well and we
he also
yes the fire
o thing
you mean
it red
our vision
you are
the problem
so far can be
here we are
all right
so that
well i i
after all
it used
you know
get lot
they are
and now we're going to discuss how to take the lousy this right actually flipping
ten percent of bits at encoding and decoding systems to deliver
this sort of performance
and three months eighty ten minus fifty
OK so what we want to do
it is come up with some ideas about what this encoder and decoder going to
be to start off with the anyone have any suggestions of an example
of the encoder way of adding redundancy in the way that we think might be
an example of adding redundancy
duplicate repeat
if the source file
has got a one
in it
we duplicate some number of times
how many
the team
OK so
so everyone gets turned into three once a non-zero gets turned into three zero so
the sort of thing you had in mind
OK but possibly more
let's start with a simple one
i'm going to call this code are three
for repeat three times so when i say repeat three times the total number of
times the bit that sent is three times already it's not four times that would
be another convention for what we mean by repetition
so this is the source
and this is the transmitted we read the source one but of time and we
use this encoding rule
so for example
if the source
the entire source firewall were zero one one zero one then we transmit
zero zero zero one one one
zero zero zero ongoing online
binary symmetric channel we can describe the noise
that knox things up
as being a binary string as well as a list of zeros and ones with
zero showing the bits that luckily didn't get flip
and one showing bits that did get linked so is the noise factor
might occur
right so that means the receiver that would be
now we add modulo two along has zero zero zero one one zero
one zero one
one one one one one one one one one
OK that's an example of going
this far we've encoded and we've gone through the channel tunnel received signal now we
need to invent an appropriate decoder for the right hand side his slide showing what
we've done so far
i've actually reordered the bit so you can see the three repetitions spread out in
time the conceptual it's just the same thing
a way of implementing this
it would be
to buy
to sell sorry when you're selling it destroys actually sell three of them inside the
OK and every time you store file if you put the bit on strike one
two and three and was one destroyer in here
but we need to decode
that is that it goes here
what's the decoder going to do what what is the right decoder habitats to your
what's that he carried out his various ways of saying and say yeah
OK so this is just the code is
read that the number of the middle and ignore the rest OK
so this would
one one you want to take one zero one one zero one
two zero and zero zero zero
he z
the suggestions on the
so majority vote
you go to which a is
the most common sense
we say
one one here one or disagrees and analyst
zero that everyone understand what we mean by
majority vote
you suggesting a different account of what you think of the choice between these
di very good i think it's a really good way to learn is by examples
but some sort of
some form of overfitting may have happened
what's another way of motivating decoder you said majority vote decoder only came up with
this idea of how could you have derived the decoder what does
estimation all i'd say inference inferences voting would say how probable is that the
source signal
i mean for example
take the zero one one
so given that you've got received signal like zero one one
how probable is it
it was zero
and we use
based there because that's the right way to do inference it works with the red
comes it works for any well-defined inference problem so we can use bayes theorem write
down probability of getting zero one
given as zero find the probability that this is zero
normalized by dividing by the other explanation and this one is
the first step
and the other term that could have been upstairs is everything with s replaced zero
replaced by s is one one
one given as equals one
and this is an example for some values
so when LP
and this is also the nominal value of R LP
if I now assume that
a normal vectors of each of these inequalities is a random vector
with the symetric distribution normal distribution than
and I have a point X that's somewhere on a hyperplane for example this hyperplane
for the nominal value or the mean
of the normal vector A I then that vector will also in fifty per cent of the
cases with fifty per cent probability will still be
even if I
if A varies in this distribution
so if you
require this with fifty per cent probability
the robust or the solution set for this feasible set for these M chance constraints
it's still the original nominal value
but if you take a different value of fifty per cent it's very different so if
I require that the inequality is satisfied with the probability of the ninety per cent then these
lines become curved so this instead of a hyperplane now I have this curve
which is actually the level curve where the probability of satisfying at inequality is exactly ninety
per cent and
so we have one of these for each of the inequalities and the feasible set shrinks
to something that's smaller and convex
that's the feasible set for these M chance constraints inequalities if eta is
ninety per cent
if eta is less than fifty per cent it's actually the other way around the we get a larger
feasible set
and these level curves of consonant probability
curve and the other have the other orientation
and then the solution set becomes concave nonconvex
and this problem becomes very difficult
because if you have a solution set like this
even if the curvature is not very pronounced then you can easily have and you
minimize a linear function over this set then you can easily have multiple local minimum that are not global
so we see something interesting here that if you have this chance constraint problems if
eta is great than fifty per cent we have a convex feasible set if it's less
than fifty per cent it's not convex
so what we can actually in this case if you assume that A Is are normal
we know the mean and covariance we can actually easily calculate this probability
probability theory
and you can write this
constraint and this form so you have the nominal value of the
inequality that's A I bar
and then this extra term involves the cumulative density function of the gaussian
this function phi of T between zero and one
and then that's multiplied with the
two norm of the square of the covariance times X
so this does actually this makes sense because it tells you that if eta
is large is close than ninety percent then
In order to make X feasible it at high probability
it's not sufficient to satisfy the inequality for the nominal value of A I
but it has to satisfy with a certain slack or a certain margin
that depends and the value of the margin the required margin depends on the value
of eta
and on the covariances and actually more
precisely the product between X and the covariance
and this also explains why you have this transition between eta at fity per cent
because this coefficient here the inverse of eta and then this cumulative density function
changes sign for fifty per cent if eta is greater than fity per cent then
that's a positive coefficient
we get a convex constraint because we have a norm with a positive coefficients on the less
than an equal side of inequality if eta is less than
fifty percent then this coefficient becomes negative and the sinus's wrong we have the
negative term on the wrong side of the inequality
so that's a stochastic formulation of the robust LP
we can actually give a deterministic interpretation to exactly the same
problem so in deterministic interpretation
we make we don't make any assumptions on the distribution of AI but we impose a certain
set of allowed
allowable values of AI so in this case we assume that AIs are unknown better
known to be in a certain ellipsoids with a center AI bar and then a certain shape
that is determined by this matrix PI
and then the robust version of this inequality will be that we require that X
is feasible for all values of AI
actually we can
so if you work this out in order to write this more explicitly you will have to
find a maximum of AI transpose X for a given X over this ellipsoid and then you
find an expression that's exactly similar to this previous one
so this
inequality is satisfied
for all values of AI and the ellipsoid if X satisfies this second-order cone constraint
so again the first term is just a nominal value says that X satisfies it for the center point
of the ellipsoid and then we have euclidean norm term that involves the product of X and
PI transpose
so mathematically it's exactly similar to this
constraint but with a different interpretation
and again we see that in the robust version of the LP
it's not sufficient for X to be feasible for the nominal value of AI you add an extra margin
and the value of that margin actually depends on the size of X
and more precisely the product of X and PI
what's going on whether it can be
defeated somewhere
and once again create
a lot of controversy
a few people
speaking very loudly
said that is not possible
lots of other people i guess someone
just going to keep working in seeing what we can do
right so
and we get out of the question
m earlier
so this is
a famous quote from
i guess is philosopher
mean mister good the british philosopher
about an ultraintelligent machine
and this is kind of scary because this is something we need to think about
OK so
eleven altamont ultraintelligent machine be defined the machine that can never occurred
so far surpass all the intellectual activities many many
since the design of machine one of these intellectual activities
an ultraintelligent machine could design better machines
then there would unquestionably be an intelligence explosion
intelligence and be left behind
that's the first ultraintelligent machine is the last invention meant
provide the machine epsilon
tell us how to keep it under control
OK so
in nineteen sixty five
inciteful remark because
this is something to be said for this
maybe this one more slide
as i said we know it in the realm of science fiction
although not everyone agree with that
the concept of singularities of intelligence explosion is now going to form online if you
look on the web you find this
there singularity organizations
and there are some pretty woman people that subscribe to view
so the idea is that
through intelligent machines
technology will advance more and more quickly
advances in night more and more quickly
and that
the horizon
we can see to the end of the
the idea what's going to happen is getting shorter and shorter
and there's a lot to be said for this
i mean if you draw graph of
human advancement in technology at the time
it's basically flat four billion years
perhaps being warned and so on
the start of the run
that's right pretty rapidly
but even in my lifetime
i've seen this
when i was
lecture back in the problem with this chap on the frontier
twenty five years ago
things happen very slowly compared to what they do now
i mean the b-side was that the seventies cycle avionics upgrade some got worse
but i mean basically things happen incredibly slowly in the whole universe has been upgraded
every i mean
witness the fact that schools are schools that affected these colleges
it really is very nice just in my lifetime
this kind of effect is not question all
but israel
the question is whether you can take the files with the tag so the idea
is this
that in competitive small number of years
and depends who you talk to just ten years it might be
the shortest estimates
the order thirty years
the things will advance so quickly
we just have no conception of what can happen beyond that
it's like disappearing into black hole
first first first
so there this this this graph
started to climb
and including michael room will give
one the talks in djibouti sessions so i wanted to much there but
what it is doing is
using one can another
the basic cameras indicator
is pretty similar of pi of
given each of of war using the simulations
and therefore that explains
all that
the air
can be evaluated namely z
the the range over here is for the bias
in terms of of these square
you've been
is is that the tyrant
and the violence is one of be
and so the deed is here is an acting upon the violence and there's not much we can do
i increases in
except seems easier
increasing as well
okay so these are skipped
it's hard to skip and seems to be that well
two to move after to the last part
and to go it's more literature than than anything
i knew but
i'm trying to replace maybe see
fuzzy inference words rather than the computing world
you may have seen this is trans this slide a few minutes ago i'm just repeating the same thing
so four
and we cannot get much farther ahead
maybe see
has been justified has
the con convergence methods are in some cases has been justified as a convergence message
other simulation
approximation methods it requires further simulations to
two given up to give evolution the approximation except when we start looking at the nonparametric perspective in which case
we don't need to run
more simulations
now what being pragmatic
it relies on a lot of calibration issues we have to pick
the summary statistics and from there we have to pick the distances and also the tolerance
and in connection with the nonparametric perspective
and the stressed in in the recent white paper by paul van had in
the new strangle
pushing epsilon exactly two zero or as close as possible to zero
in that's respect
may not be
the optimal ninety because
we are losing
in tatively
a certain amount of simulations that are also increasing
the vines by trying to reduce
so if you're using maybe see maybe
dangerous to you are
maybe not enough but
warnings forum
the general surgeons or whatever
so let me through a few points of few papers that relates to society
one important paper in this respect is
the pianist favorite there only it
redmond courses
because epsilon is
both essential
and the trouble nuisance
because it doesn't appear in georgia inferential problem
they include itself into the picture
by drawing inference not only
on feature
but also
on epsilon
and said that they used are
but approach to to do that by putting a prior epsilon
and transforming the soul
likelihood into a function on its side so absent became part
partly the air on the methods and partly
the violation
of the around today
case because this is not
exactly available
there's an apprenticeship approximation involved at this level as well
and then the technique don't go the technique
for lack of time but
it's it's using
and since e two to move around with this trick that's that's all tricks the
first one is that the distances do not
summarized into a one dimensional object any longer
and that's the strings all the methods are many
and so epsilon becomes a multidimensional object
the distances can be negative which is interesting for resistances but that's another positive point
being negative right
and the last point is that because there are so many
that's all
the distribution on
directions are summarized into a minimum
which is another unusual objects
into into the picture
and from
intuition of of new objects they get away to compare models as well
because each other directions so this is stolen from the paper
always permission
from each other directions of errors
you can build a distribution prostitution absolutist institutions this errors and compare what happens in different models to spot
the model
is behaving
strangely namely is avoiding
it's a zero value
relates to are absent equal zero
justification of
kids out and we had a few questions that ask integrations
now another approach that's
with rich allusions and in internet
that has been found in many papers subsequently he's
the fact at
so now
maybe she can be inter turn into
gone exact obesity
although it's not exactly an exact pieces
and next actually
you're looking at
that is connected with the prod product or simulations
we're assuming from from pi cedar from part
then assuming to there
from the true likelihood
and then
because we cannot wait
we have this weight
that is zero on security more maybe see
or is it is a kernel
of are any flavor
in in the job market
we use tolerance epsilon
so when you look at things from from that's where you
looks like true posture
but from
another distribution then
the true distribution namely the convolution between enough then
the key
can we get enough others even see the time scale of one minus e has
the new distribution
i mean that's
maybe she is exact but for the wrong problem
is asking the wrong question but then we get the right solution
so if we do that's
it's as if
we were getting observations
the john
noises noisy
in the true observation is whited out from have a weighted a given scene
but then
because we don't know what to do with the white noise
it's a sign from cape silent we do get this convolution
term into the posterior
okay so in that respect
maybe see is an exact
vision competition but following noisy
causes has drawbacks has a perspective because
wrote something that's
solids have a random arrangement an asterisk next to random because it's not totally random
there's some local water but there's no long range order
so the order is short range and what we call such solids that ordered solids
recalled crystalline solids and we playing
word everyday word for such an ordered solid it's called a crystal and I've been
using that term alive
I talked about Davison radiating and nickel crystal glass to distinguish the material for something
that's disorders this disorder we say that the atomic arrangement is amorphous and as a
simple anglo-saxon word for amorphous solid glass glasses an amorphous solid you might think glass
has to do with whether something is transparent and I wanted disabuse you that we've
talked about transparency of talked about transparency and what we know about transparency if we
want to talk about transparency of something is transparent
transparent what do we do we ask ourselves as the band gap and that material
greater than 3 electron volts if the answer is yes it's transparent
it's less than 3 electron volts that's an absorbed
so what is glossary
glass glass means no
long range work on a long range order will give you some examples what we
could say
for example we've got diamond a diamond diamond is critical dynamism is crystal and yet
it's transparent it's transparent wiser transparent band gap about 5 . 4 electron volts obsidian
of cities
this is a glossary
glassy rock
it's got no long range order
it's an amorphous material and it is opaque obsidian is so here's an example of
an opaque glass in a transparent crystal so as of now I wanna make sure
that nobody in 309 1 from this day forward ever ever says glass is transparent
I will show you before the end of the month metallic glass metallic glass how
can it be a Madeleine glassy well it must mean that there are metallic bodice
metallic bonding operative but the patterns are not in regular arrangement and that material was
not transparent visible light because you know that metals have no band gap whatsoever so
something isn't something important something important here to retain so
this parents will now learn what the students have learned when we go to a
new unit we begin with a history lesson so let's go back in the way
Back machine will go back to early efforts and trying to describe ordered solids
so that's why crystallography is the study of ordered solids crystal comes from the greek
crystal comes from the greek and personal which is 1 of the top terms that
might refer to isis certain former Vice but anyways it's
that's the origin so let's go back to the 1st
marking point in history of robin hood
Robert look back in the 1616 was studying cannonballs they were doing military research are
factor when you think about it and he posited that a crystal almost all its
regular shape to the packing of spherical particles
packing of spherical particles so Tupac regularly you'll get long-range order then about a decade
later there was Neal Stephenson who was a danger spent most of his scientific career
in Italy and he observed that quartz crystal
had the same angles between corresponding faces regardless of the size
the see what they were looking for is trying to make a connection between the
macroscopic and the atomic world in other words here is a simple question if I
see something has a macroscopic shape very regular and cubic can i infer from that
that if I divide divided by divide divide if I get down to atomic dimensions
there will be some cubic repeat unit yes-or-no that's the question and then around the
end of the century Christian wagons in 1690 studying calcite crystals made drawings of atomic
packing and ball shape
and here's a drawing from his book in 1690 and time if I could have
that they could switch the video over to the euro
document projector calcite crystal here here's the calcite crystals
right and no of focus of focuses on our focus is on OK so now
you can see this is to look at the regularity of this imagine you're looking
at this is all you have to work with there's no scanning electron microscope there's
no meaning national stalled nothing that's you got to work with and when he comes
up with time if we can go back to the computer video please so starting
with the crystal this is what he posits was not that remember this wagons is
the same 1 that gave us optics you see these people were polymaths narrow specialist
they were generally
the substantial contributions in more than 1 field Tom let's go back to the to
the document camera was good but the document camera with so here's here's a piece
of 10 right so if I had to draw this piece of 10 I might
draw a different drawing from 1 avoidance true because you can see the angles of
different here look at these right
well here's a piece of their own
this is a beryllium aluminum silicate litter that that's a hexagonally and almost so
what's going on here is a piece a cry like
some important dropped
the bad data measured from city to have will of the samples cutting edge research
on the
OK Tom let's go back to the
computer before I digress right so here we are in the here's a here's another
example I could bring this 1 and is a big chance of being sold off
the coast of Iceland and you can see they have they have others forms
so so far so good now let's go into the about a hundred years later
over to france this is running is used only he's studying at Sorbonne and he
studied the cleavage of calcite basically what he does he comes into work every day
breaks things in any breaks the cleveland breaks the calcite and he looks at the
little pieces of calcite and what he observes is that all shards around does matter
how small he breaks the calcite crystals down he always gets from medieval shots so
then he says I'm gonna posit that that's the basic unit of calcite and furthermore
because he's a Frenchman and the steeped in mathematical tradition he decides to to model
this mathematically says OK we we all know that if we wanted to fill 3
with the same unit we could choose a number of shapes right we could start
with acute and I could fill this role of cubes of identical size I could
fill this room with
server or that boxes and also of rectangular but square cross section I could still
have something is rectangular with a rectangular cross-section I could do something goes wrong behavior
hard-liner look at cross-licensing holes here so what what did all he did is he
said mathematically I want to determine what is the maximum number of distinguishable shapes that
and so this turns out to be equivalent to minimisation over a finite dimensional space
of dimension n so practice and is not obvious but this is what was
like you said support vector machines remember that your decision was was over
victor i found that mention the number of points this is the same thing here
OK and this would be true for all kind of falconer method
as an argument about this thing you know that the solution will be indexed by
numbers so you can write this as a minimisation of fractal dimension n
and then you need to minimize this
they want to minimize the depends on the loss function
and convex loss function then
this is be a convex problem min this can be solved by and
i mean that
OK so so scenario of this
is the following
i define you know we started from the idea of what is can positive can
also you can actually can ask to properties has to be symmetric and positive definite
and when you give you can also wants to able to give you a
but if you define function in the set on any set that you want to
then in fact you comes with many things the first thing is that it comes
with some implicit mapping of your initial
space to human space so implicitly defined
this tendency is to define inner products your initial space thanks to the kernel
of course you don't you don't want again you don't assume anything before that
OK the space can be do whatever you want to overcome all you have implicitly
embed it into deep space
the second thing that comes with the RKHS and so we saw that can be
methods that the public commissions and many others in fact
use the RKHS because they do some of the musicians RKHS and they put it
but used in on the RKHS which would be
thought of as a measure of smoothness with respect to the metric induced by the
so the which
that we try to to study the in the rest of the lectures
is soul so that there was a a question for as several years so is
what is it that we should use
OK even for pictorial structure is very not can answer those question
how do i put all the put whatever it turns out that you see that
when you change now you can get some additional what happens when you change we
can all change our only
you can see that changing the way you embed your your point into the space
you can also see that changing the way you measure the smoothness
for instance in the
you can tell you can only done here
get the camera is not here not in the first that can only appears in
the norm of the RKHS so when you change the kernel
you can see that changing
the number RKHS where you define a function of most
and iteratively change canon is that you will focus on different functions of focus in
the sense a bit of you
bayesian prior like you need to say in which part of the space you want
to look at
here you will look at this function
and tracing can amounts to define what you mean by small
so it seems some examples that when you as for some reason if you have
some prior knowledge that the ocean you looking for
should be smooth
with some notion you have then you it may be interesting to find it can
also that this was this measure but can all is equivalent to what you think
should be
so it's probably quite a bit fast and i hope i can use to many
people here but
what's important is that we know what to with the topic and just focus given
his background on how to define kernels
not vectors but things which are strings which are crossed
but before this i can take any question they are
this is
what's the
OK so and so this is a
good and difficult question because there's no simple answer so for that is the same
as you as you
so the question is not so much an argument also like other which was seen
as you well i mean in theory you can have some theoretical ideas on how
that could be taken
for instance
here typically long that should decrease with n because most of the reasons for the
number of points increases you know that you have to register position of consistency is
that there are so you have some ideas there's about that but in practice i
am not aware of any
a good rule of thumb
is better world than just train does
evaluating the performance by
what you are supposed to be here is is because the shows could be whatever
you want and then make it shows choice
after that
so typically lambda is
of course there is the choice of the council on the twenty canisters and all
the chemicals have only one parameter
this and
and there is no automatic ways what to truth that there are many heuristics can
the books but i don't have any better accuracy than trying different values
so the exact meaning is
so probably to be precisely equal to to one over another
OK because you can just right
and so minimizing this is the same as removing designed writing one of our land
and and in the information you minimize
the norm so usually is just an number the w same as foreign fourteen functions
that the number of the new list see time
the set five which is what in the
as you because of the sea is one over one other than that
so we were walking to school large seemingly small
here here the
for more on regulations although that means you regularizer
so we have a very small function and this is the kind of small c
in as
other questions
so this is what you're saying she
you know
chris to do the same
the reason for this is the reason
and this
this is some sort of sense
because this is certainly
good news
well is
this is the
so that that's the by the size and shape of the world's most and the
best one to the what was that is user
are you can also gaussian come off because interestingly we will see that the function
is smooth if you don't have to consist now i decided to use the smoothness
so my what the way i'm doing it i going think the average case so
when i say i mean when i say i want to optimize the expected reward
that that everything works out if i would be working on some kind of adversarial
setting then things get more tricky
OK so this is this is a good news right so
something that we can't solve exactly now we know that we can sort of of
solve it by paying only a constant factor of
and know i can just briefly tell you why why our functions such someone to
right so we have this structure
so basically the adding benefit of adding a sensor to a small placement is larger
than the benefit of adding set in the same sense of to the larger placement
and so the question is why why does our problem have structure so what do
we know about submodular functions the first thing that we know is that if we
have a set of all it is submodular functions and we just create a linear
combination of them this new function will be also submodular and then second is this
natural natural example of a submodular functions right when we say we have these sets
and the reward function is the size of the union of the sets
so this is as sets of sets a and this is now the
the set of sets and now we can ask how much this
how much how much benefit to get from place in this new new setbacks and
again right we can clearly see that when adding it to the to to this
set of sets
the benefit we are getting of place index is much larger than when when we
would place it to a larger sets of sets so and this is clearly the
case we have no problem
so the first thing and i won't go into too much detail is that so
this objective functions that i was talking about what we find is that of the
water sensor networks which is a competition organised by i think US environmental protection agency
or something and they find these three objective functions and first thing so that the
detection like how long does it take to detect a contamination detection likelihood means how
many contaminations we detect out of all possible contamination that could happen and population affected
is how many people drank contaminated water before we detect and we show that all
these nodes are submodular so all these different objective functions have this property of diminishing
as i told you
that greedy hill climbing algorithm can be constant factor approximation i can just show you
what i mean by hill climbing right so the idea is that if i had
my water distribution network i e i would go on forever is for every possible
location we would consider how much you want to get right now we will behave
greedily which means we select the the sense that give was the most rewards what
we do next is basically we need to go
and evaluate the benefits of having
of adding additional sensors to something that you already placed right in this would be
this gives us a new set of rewards and again the maximum
we would need now to again going to evaluate all this simply the highest one
and added to the place and united have this is what i mean by future
planning so just like greedy algorithm and as old as i said we have constant
factor approximation so this is the worst case sixty three percent of optimal but there
are two parts to the story first but is that this only works for unit
cost case so the court the case where all the locations have the same cost
OK so we don't have different costs for placing sensors in different locations and the
two point seven
and then the other thing is that this climbing algorithm is slow and the reason
why it slows because for whenever places as we have two in the re-evaluate all
other sort of marginal benefits you would get from adding additional sensors again we need
to place the document one and then the
the one the highest one again re-evaluate everything right so so this is this is
scale where
so how can we go and solve this problem so
they said if if if i would just use hill climbing in in order to
cost so just pretend that there is no cost and try to the best sensors
during the cost to sort of try to respect the budget then this will fail
arbitrarily badly and the reason why this will fail is that we will always prefer
more more expensive sensitivity with the reward are i know also much cheaper sensor because
reward our mindsets now and now
this can get arbitrarily bad if we ignore the cost so and here's the here's
the idea that what we can do to
but what what one could do to to solve better so what if we instead
of just optimizing the reward optimize these benefit cost ratio right so we would go
and everything with the sensor that gives us best best increase in the in the
war and divided by the cost of that sense so we would sort of sense
so the distribution is going to result from this
right if you places into the expression of the milan is one the the exponential
a time c
right this is true is going to be added otherwise it's not
plus the
o b i f i c
these are the features if i see that i find these other weights
so this is the
this is the of what is the walls of the class going to be
well it's going to be the log of the ratio between p of c
he calls one of the few sequels era
when p once sequel zero this becomes and becomes zero so this is exponential of
which is why when sequels one well at times one is a and b i
times one is just by five
so i get exponential of a plus b i five k
so now this is one of the two councils have some expression that have up
so this is a very simple example why
ML and can represent
one of these statistical models
OK now here
i used conjunction features
which if that comes in statistical modeling and in the maximum entropy models and so
forth is probably what you'll find most intuitive
if you on in logical in ILP
you probably find this for more intuitive which is the implication for
the application forms to write that for each feature that that the future implies the
so like the natural language descriptions this is well if the page and has this
feature then she has or does not have breast cancer for example
and the reason can do things in this way
is the forward
it is
if this is evidence
then this reduces to the class
just like this
so even though these formulas are different
one to using these as evidence that become the same
the deep reason is the following
is there
all i'm using these features for
it is to build
the model
for the joint distribution of the class and the variables
and it turns out that if i have the unit clauses as well
any of these binary features we can construct like this conjunction of this implication or
any of the other things like conductors is sufficient to completely model distribution
so the weights will be different but we will have three parameters the weight of
the joint feature the way to the unit clauses
it is it's easy to see if they can represent any joint distribution of those
to available so which this you want to use it's really a matter of taste
here i'm going to use the implications since
it seems more intuitive in terms of what it's saying that if you prefer conjunctions
you know just replaced the implications by conventions throughout
here's a simple concrete applications
let's suppose we want to do text classification
OK here's an email in the test specification
you have three types page from one to the number of pages were which are
all the words in the language and topic which are the topic so you want
to classify pages into like politics sports science whatever
and they have two predicates
you have the predicates topic page topic
the next mission like this means that each page can has exactly one topic
now in some cases the page could have more than one topic in which case
you can remove the explanation
here i'm just going to look at the simple case where the topics are mutually
exclusive and exhaustive and then i just try to get has word page one which
means that this page is this one
so these all the predicates i need
now here's my complete mln
i have a unit clause
that says that by default the page does not have the topic which is true
most pages are not on most topics that i have
a single
for the cells
has p plus w implies topic people st
what is this doing since i have a plus
here in the past year
i'm going to grounding into this formula for every word topic here
so essentially in the matrix of parameters that's a highly indicative of each topic each
one hundred years precisely as we just saw is the logistic regression with across the
top topic of the page and the features are the words it contains
so doing standard
classifier in in
alchemy is really just writing to find in fact if you omit the things that
are optional it's really just this
OK so you can input this
two of me
with the database
of text into give a text classifier
just click to predicate
and the way formula
the need that by default
so this becomes very very simple
well now let's look at a more complex example which is to do hypertext classification
this is what you make the jump from i i d
well classifying each page separately to non i i d we're letting the the
topic of the page influence the topics of the page that links to
this is something that people for
know when the when to call was that if you actually used hyperlinks
to to help classify pages in addition to the words you get much better results
in fact even if you have only the labels for very few pages you could
get very good results on this because such thing for me
so in order to protect specification
in order to me
all we need to do is add one more predicate predicate links page page with
the obvious meaning one more formula which is topic pt
and links pp prime implies topic people ninety
this is
one pages on one topic on that page points to another page then that page
is probably on the same topic
OK and has some very that is will be reflected in the way that you
want for this formula from there
so nodes we can build a complete
hypertext classifiers
no i i d model in just two forms
contrast this with this paper
that was almost ten years ago when this was like you know twelve page two
column small paper about how to solve this problem
there's been a lot of work to do this
but with the now that we have all the bases incorporated into something like me
you know doing this complex
or apparently complex and the problem becomes a very very simple matter of writing down
a couple of points
well you can imagine using something called for information retrieval
of course this examples just for illustration purposes or can be doesn't scale to websites
that somehow the diameter of the influence of these models can have is limited to
be limited by the degree of conductivity in you know this this is said again
and again in vision committee still being said the people say well we've done a
low order markov models where the connections are short range now we should go to
higher order markov models because we want to get influences over the bigger diameter and
it may well be the case that one ought to go to higher order markov
models and the benefits from doing it but not for that reason it's not it's
not good enough to say that that we need to get influence over larger and
larger distance it must be something much more details about exactly the nature of that
in that influence
this is the
i can do i mean it will
you know i can actually what you know what you can do is set up
against markov random field where these were all the probability the gaussians and the the
the functions that think you know this is jumping ahead of it but the functions
that link the
adjacent nodes i guess you know that may not mean too much the materials used
and see what it means and everything about it is you know this the whole
thing in fact is a great big joining guassian and if now i solve for
the most probable state of such a model then it turns out the solution comes
out in bessel functions and the rational functions are asymptotically exponential so yes
it can it can work out the the the the the case exponential but
i don't think you could say you know in the case that said discrete model
that you very hard to i don't know if anyone can put their hand on
my heart and say that the decays exponentially
the wonderful if you could say that there is no
in fact this
the band
i don't completely understand the question
john you know i call you know that's a higher order models like i could
draw a graph like this one and i could make linkages for example the obvious
thing to do next would include the diagonal linkages and then i can make it
jump over one pixel like with without predictive text model and you know one could
certainly do that but
i guess what i want to say is that the effect of making those longer-range
linkage is on the range of correlations if you like on the on the distance
over which decisions then becoming joint is a non-obvious
linkage it's not just the case that by extending these conditional probability range conditional probabilities
the explicit you will then automatically extract exchange extends the diameter of the decision making
but i'm sure i can make a go backwards you know like yes i'm completely
like omega backwards that is i could take a model extend the range of the
links and make the diameter of which decisions are made this exponential fall for example
i can make it smaller
OK how do we
do this how we actually set up these models well
you know now look at the time has come actually to give an explicit algebraic
form for this joint probability distribution so here's the same graph again here's the conductivity
that said i was going to have and
you know in terms of conditional independence and so now i can write down the
joint probability distribution of this kind which is just a giant product over all these
possible pairs that have been marked by blue lines here
product over all of those guys and you know with some function which i haven't
specified yet so this is
this is going to be
a real valued function of two binary variables in the case of my segmentation problem
because you remember the binary variables in the second just foreground orbackground could represent was
ones or zeroes
or they will be an
other problems will come to later where there are where there's greater range for the
variables to cover for example i might want the variables to represent colours in an
image and you know there's a palette of two hundred fifty six
q colours and so maybe these labels will be the future activities q to them
or else i might want to explicitly to make the labels real numbers i might
be sort of because example that's just you color really is there is there is
the set of real numbers not not quantized thing so as this is this sort
of underlying model the unobserved part of the model you might say well you know
colours not really quantized there really real value so you know you can imagine wanting
these things to be real numbers but for now
we're going to restrict ourselves to having the hidden variables these these axes as
binary variables just zero or one
and i've got a proposal for what we might choose for these g functions that
neighboring pixels in the proposal is supposed to be something that captures this idea of
encouraging the neighbouring pixels to have the same labeling in this foreground background labeling problem
so here's my proposal that let's make
this function equal to one when the two neighbours have the same
label either background or foreground but we make it something less than one when they
have different labels so then the joint density
for this to this distribution will go down because the labels are different and the
extent to which goes down will be specified by this constant k
so now i could simulate from such a model
using a particular kind of MCMC simulated that sufficient for this this kind of thing
and i'm going to simulation for different values of k where i'm
changing the degree of penalty
allowing different labels adjacent pixels so here's the love value penalty and an increasing the
value of the penalty and you see now there's more encouragement for adjacent pixels to
take the same level labels of the blobs in the simulation is a typical sample
from the joint density is getting bigger and now increases even more
and the blobs are getting still because
and so you know i got a one parameter model here with some control over
the degree of coherence not to say that you know these things are looking very
much like typical objects are not going to go so far as to say that
you know captured the nature of the objects in the natural world with this very
simple one parameter model but you know may be doing something helpful in the way
of tipping the prior towards coherent and it turns out you can do a surprising
amount with this model
OK so now what i want to do is to take the model and do
like the speech people i want to embed it in a hidden markov model