OK good morning ladies and gentlemen my name is craig right and this is listening
to music the most basic course at the department of music has to offer its
aim is to teach you how to listen to music
wait a minute you say that's preposterous
i listen to music all the time i got what my ipod i downloading mp
three files continually swapping files
i've got my car
what we call the city will be aware is that tape that you can take
your ipod plugged into the here this is serious system in your car got that
i was musically dorm of my computer and bookstore wherever i bet i listened to
a lot more music than you do you all go
and you're right you probably do
what kind of music are you listening to well probably pop and that's fine that's
OK fair enough pop music but are you getting the most out of this particular
experience are you getting the most out of your listening experience
i contend that perhaps were not the gene that you are not maximizing the time
using time most profitable
how do i know that's what makes you think that you are not getting as
much as you possibly can out of your music well experience to some degree but
also experiment i just last weekend i have four children the last of the four
has now turned seventeen so i said
last weekend criticism
always with the chris what you're listening to
go with your body
running my life so
but come on let me listen to this i mean this is when you listen
to so i listen to it so i hear you listen to this and tell
me what you're hearing
and what what was the tracking he was tracking the text he was tracking the
beat of the peak
i ask what what's the mode of the piece
what's the metre the piece was the based you follow baseline you can you identify
any chords in this particular piece nothing zero and this from a reasonably sophisticated kids
had twelve years of serious cello lessons
and that brings up i suppose a a point
that although i don't know much about your music i think i can teach you
a great deal about your music by using the paradigms of classical music so we
talked a lot about classical music and his moats by beethoven it will be the
locus of our cause how many of you already listen to classical music raise your
hand OK great a lot of and that's wonderful i'd be interested to know gentlemen
down here how do you do this is it's streaming off of your computer
are you downloading mp three files and saving them how to tell me how do
you do
if you go to youtube are very interesting i should have known that but i
didn't you go to youtube and you listen there anybody else do it in a
different way
on the radio OK that's interesting will come will come back to that point anything
else anybody
OK apparently these records that's wonderful sort of the old technology here but some of
those are all recordings might be very very very good now here's a question for
you know why would we want to listen to classical music
why do
why it move just answer the question from here those folks to raise your hand
what to do when you're going to appear you're my sacrificial lamb this morning why
do you like to listen why would you want to listen to classical music
OK very interesting national public radio asked exactly this
this question in a survey a year or so ago and they got the following
principle responses that
why people listen to classical music one
it helps them relax
and relieve stress so that this is this is but perhaps the principle which two
helps is centre the mind allowing the listener to concentrate three classical music provides a
vision of a better world vision of a better world refugee beauty
of majesty perhaps of even of of love and sometimes at least for me personally
it suggests that there might be something out there
god or whatever bigger than ourselves and it as is the think sometimes
think about
the that's what i think these great fine arts do great literature poetry painting music
they show
human beings can be the capacity of the human spirit
this suggests to us as indicated maybe there is something a larger spirit out there
than ourselves and they get us to think me to think frequently about what i'm
doing on this earth
what are you doing this
don't answer that one of my living on this earth with regard to this particular
cause what am i trying to accomplish in here will
maybe two things one change your personality
change your personality i want to make you a richer person broader personal
by instilling you with india
a deep and abiding understanding of classical music so that's part of this not just
here for you but for your life after yale i would hope that how you
believe your life ten years now twenty years now thirty years now would have been
significantly influenced by this particular experience in this cause
and secondly if i'm successful in my teaching i will accomplish this second in here
i will party you a love of classical music
later on after you know your attendance at concerts by in one fashion or another
downloading mp three files of items or whatever happens to be maybe being members of
the local symphony board opera company something like that may be giving music lessons to
your children you will become
the pervez areas of classical music thereafter you the intelligentsia the next generation will be
those that preserve this great treasures
of western culture and it is a great treasure of western culture OK how we
going to do all of this how we can accomplish these two things on our
list of agenda here
what are the mechanics of course to do all get the syllabus
everybody's got syllabus i should have grown up here but i didn't doesn't matter first
three four weeks so i'll be following the elements of music rhythm
melody and harmony
and then test
next we will deal with what's the what arguably the the single most important thing
when we listen to any piece of music and that is its musical form
here's a question for i was thinking about this the other day so a preparing
a lecture for today what's the most common type of musical form in pop music
we can have not just objects but unknown relations as well
as long as we're willing to go to second order markov logic
in second order markov logic we allow predicates that we all variables that range over
predicates as well as variables that range over objects
and without
in this in essence just by reading the same from as that we had before
know they get grounded with predicates as always with objects and i can actually resolved
relations like for example in my text i could have and is the friend of
bob cannonball bob who are friends and her boyfriend and strand but these are all
instances of the simulation
and that could result
and i won't go into the details of that here
but there's actually a paper that stanley kok is going to be presenting tomorrow cost
it good predicate invention and so you're more than welcome to go there to to
see in more detail how
know the things they can do
with with second order markov logic
so it's getting pretty sure let me just mention the last couple of things
he his his another even more ambitious application which is robot that
anderson continues to illustrate very briefly i can handle continuous domains in markov logic which
is something that we haven't seen yet
so we know about nothing as many of you probably know
the goal is to build a map of the environment that the robot is moving
so the inputs typically is laser range finder segments
given by the start and end point coordinates
and the outputs are labels of the segments like wall door there
and we also want to assign wall segments to towards
and also to figure out what the real position of the walls is so we
have a bunch of noisy segments that don't quite aligned we want to figure out
exactly where the wall is so here's his the real example of
publicly available datasets for robot mapping
you can see there a corridor here and corridor here the red segments of walls
the green ones outdoors
the ones others and so our goal is to actually figure out that this is
the environment that we're in
just from the coordinates of the of the range finder segments
so what we do this
in order to do this
we need to talk about numeric properties of objects and numeric features
which is something that we haven't done so far because after all logic is just
about boolean variables and building features so how can we do that
well it's very simple at least syntactically
because first order logic already has numerous times in the syntax for can have a
function that's numeric order constant or variable that's numeric so that's not a big deal
so all i need to do is to allow
the numeric properties to be nodes like for example i could have no that's the
length of x or the distance between x and y
and then i will allow numeric terms in the standard syntax of first-order logic
maybe with some extensions like infix notation and whatnot as features like for example
i could have the feature minus the length of x minus five square
this feature is basically saying that link has a gas distribution with mean five
and variance one over two times the weight of this form
because if you think about it if you exponentially this times away what you have
is exactly agustin distribution
and now we can allow a very useful piece of syntactic sugar
which is to just right off equals better where alpha and beta are arbitrary numeric
expressions as a shorthand for minus of minus better square
for example i can think of x equals five as a short for this
and what this is saying is that the length of an object is typically five
they can vary from it with the gas distribution
and you don't have to explicitly said that the distribution is gas we just like
you do this
because this is what you're going to be doing ninety percent of the time is
putting us in distributions of various things and combinations of things we just like you
write in this way
OK so using this syntax and now
what is the set of this sets up
where some of the variables are numeric some of the features are numeric but everything
else goes through you need to extend the inference algorithms they the numeric case but
the weight learning is still the same the former seven change so again at least
a high level this is a straightforward extension
so here's another way
that the to the state of the art in robot mapping
that we've recently developed this just as a bunch of things there a natural
and this functions need to be small
with respect to the underlying geometry of our data
what does that mean so this is just on the probabilistic setting
we want to learn so why is the space of all labels so we can
just thing minus one and one for simplicity
probability with some probability distribution on x y pairs so each x some probability and
given the probability there is some probability that the blue and some probability that's right
and the same for regression except to say really
we have the conditional distributions
p of y given x as i said before the probability of blue given the
point sources probability of red given the point and i don't know if you can
see that and put it in
and probability
and the marginal distribution which is somehow the distribution of access when you forget about
the labels so the marginal distribution is the distribution of all access and the conditional
distribution given x
the label
what is the distribution of labels
OK so the
two important objects and the assumption this
if that the conditional
if most respected the marginal so the conditional probability distribution does not change between points
does not change too much between points which calls on the manifold itself
and if you go back here
you will see that
it is much more likely that this red
because really we don't want to class
labels to change and it would have to go to blue and black to red
and this is somehow much sharper transition in carrying out of this thread mostly turns
it into blue here
so now now what is small for now i said that i want my class
conditional to be
most business back to the marginal to with respect to the structure of the data
now what does this mean
so this one can say the following so when what for example given the function
and it's just assume material for well functions when this function nice and small well
the function is nice and small
when you
take all possible values around this function and you look at all differences and this
this quantity
the integral over a little sphere
of the difference is not too large
so for each point i want to the point i want the values of the
function around this points to be pretty similar to the values of the function at
the point at
so this is somehow an intuitive notion of most is i don't want to change
so locally i don't want to function to change globally i don't care
and i integrated of all points so if function is nice and smooth if it
doesn't change locally for each point
and i have to do with way this problem which from and this is basically
the same as the gradient the limit of this some constant from is actually the
so the gradient is a measure of smoothness
as part the size the previous talk
and this is closely related to the laplace operator
fuller plus and this quantity
this is in the product on health tools of this is integral
times LPF the LP the plus measures how smooth functions
and the manifold assumption
can be said that
class conditional p one given x
if most in this sense so when you
integrate the gradient of class conditional you get the smaller
that that's all the rest
OK so that's the key
that's the key somehow idea
the integral of class can of gradient of course conditional has to be small
effect can be pretty much any probability distribution of course
this quantity is need to make sense of some conditions on it but
i mean i'm not putting any strong conditions
so p of x you have some distribution of you have some joint distribution of
digits and then for each thing you know if it looks like this it's very
unlikely to be in line so that zero but there are some things which you
like before you can imagine for nine days sometimes extremely close so you really cannot
so that presumably the fifty fifty
OK so now let me just remind you about the graph plus and so i
will describe the algorithmic framework and
in the graph the algorithmic framework is based on the notion of the graph laplacian
graph laplacian is the following think of this summer from graph which has nothing to
do with
to give you an example
did you deduced from the feature mapping phi
and the metrics this is cleavage the metrics
so suppose there actually prelearned classifiers if p
and actually if you can learn about adding technique using the
trinidad from either the author domain all the time dimension of from both domains
so in the experiments way
the if piece learning by this man with the labelled training data from both domains
and we propose the target decision function like this
in this equation
because is linear combination coefficients and i don't i fix is called the the perturbation
function and then the target decision function the first term can be considered as prior
and because of the good interpretability of the multiple kernel learning we model the perturbation
function derived by using multiple kernel kernel learning so you might you might have occurred
our kernel learning MKL the kernel is assumed to be linear combination of multiple base
kernels k
and came is deduced from the feature map phi and so was MKL we can
we can rewrite the in the distance as a function omega d which equals two
the transpose of h times
that d
so here the method is composed of the linear combination coefficients of the countries
so finally we propose our adaptive multiple kernel learning has the following of optimisation problem
so in the objective function
that's two terms
the first term is and determine it minimizes the mismatch between the two domains
and the second term is the structural risk functional
and in the traditional MKL the training data are assumed to be from the same
domain however our method
the training data from different domains and our method is actually attempted adapted from one
domain to the other
and to solve this optimisation problem and the structural risk functional jt is really retains
dual form
and for that we can we get to the
that might have occurred algorithm iteratively solves the linear combination coefficients d
and the dual variables alpha in the dual form of g
so here it is several existing customer methods the first one is the future applications
so far it simply
augments the features
and second method according to the domain transfer SVM DTSVM and this is our previous
work by using this method there's no prior information used
and the third method is adaptive SVM and this method is similar to ours except
for two major differences
the first one that the linear combination quite coefficient gamma p these predefined in that
and the provision function is model by a simple MKL
the symbol is mentioned
so here comes the experiment parts for the that it we use one hundred ninety
five consumer videos and in one hundred six it connected by our ourselves and also
from kodak consumer video benchmark that's it
there are six events that wedding birthday picnic parade show and sports
and for training data we read simple three media was prevented from consumer videos and
all the web videos also considered as the training and the rest consumer videos are
considered as the test data
and the experiments we use two types of features that time feature on same feature
and we also use four types of kernels that does in that that's an inverse
square distance and inverse distance
and we compare our aligned space time pyramid matching with the loudest whisper matching
this two tables tables show the results for some features and space time features respectively
from the table the observed that the space time pattern matching is better than the
loudest whisper matching label one for every
so we call that this is our proposed to tackle decision function
in nineteen dollars payments we use it base kernels in total
there are from two pyramid levels two types of features five kernels parameters and four
types of kernels
and the way we treat eighty base classifiers based on this data base kernels and
for each level and each type of feature web content based classifiers learned by experience
and then we reached this content based classifiers to get the average cost for a
total there are four average classifiers and then use this average cost per to construct
the prelearned classifiers p
now here we compare our method with south across the minimum methods three settings
you said a usage SIFT features
basically we will use space time features a post that both features i used
this figure shows the
average precision of all methods for each sheet for each event
and do you have any sitting c which uses both features our method outperforms the
other methods in four out of six events
for example taking parade for example
our method which is seventy five point seven percent
average precision compared with the second best result sixty two point six fifty application
which is thirteen thirteen point five percent improvement
and were use mean average precision in the final evaluation
we observe that in the multiple kernel learning based methods the performance performance of city
it is much better than the then those of sitting in b
so this might have occurred in the current learning based methods can actually better fuse
SIFT features and the space time features and they can also handle the noise in
the loose labels to some extent
and for each method we find the best result among all the three settings and
based on the best results we compared our method is all other methods and here
the relative improvement of our method over the other methods we can see that
methods significantly outperform outperforms the other methods
so in conclusion
we propose a new event recognition framework for consumer videos by leveraging a large number
of loosely labeled web videos
and we develop a new aligned space time pyramid matching method
and also we her
present a new cross domain learning method adaptive multiple kernel learning which handles the mismatch
between the data
distributions of the consumer video domain and the web video domain
and that's all for my presentation thank you
other questions
yes please go to like if you can
so it seems to me that approach two components the first component is carried matching
the second one is a political party
so how do these two points i mean in the first component the matching score
the right and then what features to use for the multiple kernel and actually
we just use that
limit theorem intuitions stuff now all these properties of correlation got by
lots of methods but we we saw this volatility clustering means immediately that what we
read about in fowler where events are
are really
stationary usually
cannot be used to we need other techniques into common technique study trended fluctuation analysis
which is the site and over eight hundred times is used in many fields
and the newer method bicarbonate
in our collaborators could be in training moving average the essence of which is here
the the jagged curve is the stock price
and the
smooth curve is just moving average average over the previous in events and when you
look at the at the little sausages that are formed like this red sausage
bush there was like a train the worst there formed you abide by the intersection
of the moving average and the stock price itself
you have some objects that contain information important things in these little force
good information and the two is used to measure the things are the lifetime that
how long this along this forced is and its total area by how much how
many calories
in his first and and both of these scaling ways to give the critical exponents
OK so
all of this is the end if i'm going to talk about with making log
log plots
and talk about something different now
and something that economies has apparently due respect
and that's in part because they didn't already doing
and the reason i do it this is a method random matrix theory that was
popularized in physics by eugene victor
from budapest great nobel laureate in physics not the colours the very and then he
was confronted in the thirties with some puzzles in nuclear physics
and he formulated an approach to the puzzle
using random matrix theory what is random matrix theory in this problem
it is to take the cross correlations of the change of price every pair stocks
so this is coca-cola
this is pepsi-cola and they are generally correlated one goes up the other goes up
i do we have a positive
elements of the
matrix element that has coca-cola because the classical the right
you do this false a thousand stocks whatever thousands of a good number include
almost every company that has a lot of data
and then you get a big thousand five thousand matrix diagonalizes find i can values
the graph the histogram of the eigen values and what you find is that ninety
eight percent of the site and values
under the curve
this exactly what eugene victor
derived would occur if the correlations were purely random man and that nothing more than
random there will always be apparent correlation right
if i leave this room in the same time
you shlomo leaves this rule we could say we are leaving because we're correlated question
what happened to collaborate or we could say is just sheer chance and there's no
way to know
almost no way to know but statistically you can by forming this large matrix of
everyone is leaving the room together and you find ways that most things are pure
chance so the fluctuations and stocks almost all pure chance but there are these twenty
o two thousand DVD i get values
and what can we say about what every igon value has an i can factor
and we can look at the components of that i mean vector here is just
the right and that
her so this is just the
the twenty deviating eigen values studied by vessel key player rules and go because standards
obviously got there
and and their collaborators
and the remarkable thing is that
i can vectors are dominated by stocks from individual business sectors
which means that the
the problem that we physicists always have an economics we don't know what the three-letter
except that you decided that we believe in bank of america i can never remember
and all the little ones we don't know but if we came from mars we
did nothing other than this we will find exactly what they are because you would
be all code dealing with transportation
this all paper this with drugs and so forth and so on so i mean
that there is a means there is a way of finding coal movement of
of stocks to belong to the same sector and that in turn leads to practical
that i'm trying to sell to bloomberg
not the mayor bloomberg company bloomberg new york which as you probably know makes it
he he's the richest man in new york and made his many billions of dollars
trivial sort of physicist dream idea putting software on every traders that with click on
the keyboard can tell you anything but he doesn't do this now we can diagonalizable
matrices so fast you can make a graph of the companies and when stock price
that deviate from where it belongs
the trader comes out of
it has to be a reason for that
because this is not just random
and the trader can take appropriate action may be sounded by more try to figure
out why
now now we come to the last thing
which is i introduced by showing you the slide thomas looks
showed yesterday which is the phase transition
where it starts the idea that you should somebody mumbles that you you might want
to buy the stock of access
and i guess in this case it looks like they want to sell it to
sell the stock xl
and then this amplifies cooperative way just like the first order phase transition metastability
and then everybody cells and cells and cells and cells and goodbye goodbye goodbye and
then some little creepy guy
he says by it and that amplifies and everyone buys so this is the cart
and nothing more of it is inaccurate cartoon roughly what happened so we have to
take seriously we physicists being so simple-minded are allowed to take simple things seriously
we have to take my what does this tell us
what is the time i have no idea for sure but i would like it
to be as priests price tobias price spent part of his phd with us
and he came not only with his good brains but it came with
he came with the database
and the database he brought
classes good brain is we're that tell about a couple of minutes
and the question that we ask is this kind of cartoon show to sort of
critical point light phenomenon namely the amplification of fluctuations as if as if we're giving
you a critical point of course is not a critical point but it is a
kind of switch point based which when i mean
trend in the market which is going one way suddenly switches to going the other
way and experiment every one of us can do if you have your laptop on
data volumes have grown fifty four
you know
we are able to observe something like ten billion new
media consumption events every day ten billion those web records
every single day
this is because we have participation from a very broad range
of media companies around around the world in millions of small sites many of the
largest sites in the world rely on our service to understand their audiences to make
editorial decisions and to develop better package those audiences monetize them and therefore create more
content for those consumers
this is a very data rich environment this is one of the sort of
one of the fascinating things about the online advertising online content area we have we
have you know it was possible almost too much data
just incredible volumes of data every month we have well in excess of a quarter
new records of media consumption covering over a billion
global internet users across millions of sites
on peak days
we have about fifteen terrabytes of new data
and within that we have a set of
pretty interesting
data mining challenges and ongoing just touch on one of these in detail today first
of all
got this fundamental challenge audience estimation using reference data to pieces of information that you
know how high confidence in the first small number of people in a small number
of websites
infer the attributes demographics business cycle graphics
but and otherwise
the audience of all sites
so starting with this a small subset of things you know about using inference mechanism
to understand everything now the counter to that is
using media consumption records
an audience estimates
determine the characteristics of an internet user across arbitrary dimensions and the reason is going
to be arbitrary in different markets are very different things they're interested in
now we actually developed a pretty inevitable novel approach to actually combine these two together
the way we do is we build a graph theoretic representation of internet consumption we
call it the visit graph so there are media assets and there are internet users
the consumers media assets based on common media consumption you can start to connect these
things together we've been able to develop an iterative machine learning approach that actually passes
information around this model and as it converges can be cross validated against pieces of
data that we know that we have chance to people more than one time to
get into it today
i will talk a little bit about look selection today is really key to what
to what we do is key to making advertising successful the idea of look like
selection is if you have a small number of people that have exhibited some behavior
this desire
for example they bought to given product
you have this depend their
find the features
the best discern those people
to everyone else and then find more people like that's ultimately what advertising is all
the last piece
which is something that is completely unique to the online advertising ecosystem is live traffic
model is not enough just have static models these models have to be applied in
real time literally in
eleven seconds two
thousands tens even hundreds of thousands of requests every second and actually the information that
is available in those requests
can make the difference between the campaign succeeding or failing
so given time limitations them into touch upon
on one of these and that's look-alike selection
the idea behind collection selection is that there may be a set of users archetype
done something interesting there one of the really interesting things about about the digital landscape
is more than ever before
markets are actually in possession of data about their own customs historically they often rely
on whatever third-party to provide them with but increasingly markets operate websites that people interacting
with the content of those people might actually be purchasing online for example they might
they might go to the commons product online and obviously advertising is all about getting
people buy products is the ultimate evil advertising even though what's called the purchase funnel
may take some time to get
the purchase purchases the very in the final before you can purchase you've got to
be interested in the product
four you're interested in the product you've got to be where the product even exists
advertising is the process of introducing people to product making them consider that process highly
and getting them to actually buy it
and even if people can't buy the product line they can still exhibit behavior which
is a good proxy to an offline purchase if go to the the automotive website
they can configure the car
they can download coupons to get money of detergent in store
so the idea of lookalikes elections to take some archetype of a few thousand maybe
a few hundred people that have done something that is interesting and valuable to that
particular market and then find the feature set the best separates them from people not
these features can be positive or negative indicators of content relevant to consumer this piece
often makes people to think about one of the things said someone's going to do
actually advertising not targeting is just as valuable as targeting in terms of the return
on investment market has
finally one should develop this model
the task is to find more people like them
different features different behaviours interested consumers
can predict the relevance of particular messages to them what we have here are two
now it is a very short summary you
to sentences like the one i just showed
that is the find a single words and then you build a graph to the
right and
you have to also like start
and in nature between two works represents it uses information so you see the world
if you ever since ABC then in this graph from a to b from b
to c
and from such a procedure and so this is just consisting of three words in
i'll illustrate method very simple example so that's a false sentences
they have short hillary clinton wanted to visit china last month but postponed her plans
to one day last week
you're going to need is visit to the people's republic of china monday
final last week the secretary of state missus clinton visited chinese officials is
so what happens is the following
you take the first sentence you know
all top descendants built just
so graph just a stream of words so that humans we wanted to visit china
last longer than a very short for readability but postponed her plans to one day
last week and then
so this is just an abbreviation fact there are more
note somewhere in between
and what you know about this is the first word for example six string representation
you know the part of speech is now you can get part of speech tags
and you know the better
since the first position
so this is the information you have not only for the first one actually for
everyone you know it's all lowercase
from you know it's part of speech know
its position in the sentence
so now what happens next the following you take
four percent from your cluster
we had work there was you
people's republic of china
and you have
words sentences one after another but
not necessarily in this order but you that those words they considering free
group supports so first
works picture
well compared with what you already have the right
and you have some those still word you just create a new node with m
edges connecting them then you get ambiguous words
UTC mean words for which you have
two nodes in the graph british
given that this word appears
so what is this
so i want to again it's not clear which of the two
and you have this would appear in the records in the which would you want
to happen there exists
so for example if you
the with clinton twice hillary clinton and bill clinton in one sense there was just
before the wife of the former president
bill clinton hillary clinton and given that i would like to hear from
so you don't have both words on but instead look for local context and see
that in the sentence were you we can invent in front of the second term
is going to end the director of the world killer the map
the ones which is similar to what happened
in the graph and then finally you all this before so he doesn't any syntactic
information what you do is
the words into separate words spoken words on the board
and this is the time for many languages it's much easier to to get
syntactic information
for example
this is a
what happens when you have sex with
you may have the word hillary into the work here so it's when we sex
you updated information so you know the people
but his speech otherwise they wouldn't stand up to get them you know now that
this particular it was not only in the first and but also the second
important sentences it's the first position
for example
the word is is not enough to the
note this it because the different parts of speech so here is it
the thing here is unknown
so they don't end up together
this is the third we bring together with which really is what about the same
things non different
so in the end you get in there and when you merge all four sentences
we are making some parts of the
it's good for
but is it
so what you see now that you have that it corresponds to from this that
you can get to the first words of sentences had one cluster and to today
and you can get from all the words
with which
those sentences and their
so this image of the story
you start this is that you want to get to the end and we just
don't what
on the edge of
so what you can get a human being to want to visit china
monday last week
while the former US president bill clinton missus clinton visited china on monday so you
can work well in that have space to get to the to some settlements
but that the intuition is that if you follow
the right if you follow
the words which occur in many sentences that what you get is nice
compression of their
asked so if you go over that hillary clinton
is a child last monday jumped and try to wait
what you get is actually the just a sentence so this is what
four sentences were
now the question so he wouldn't have any syntactic information on
part of speech tags makes
the game is to get the data on the percentage information
so we you have very few sentences it's unlikely that you have something meaningful but
given that
this is a fair chances are high that you will find it
a good shot at
so you find a path which is short for each sentence and which will give
you you
a good
compression summarisation percent expressed
OK this is what is happening now the question is how can we find a
most of the background to computer science and the show
it's not neutral so this is how it can be used for
sentence compression so in this is the shortest
the reason for this is important them that it's not hard to find the shortest
in terms of nodes travel changes in terms of edges
of a certain number function in this case is this exponential function
so from this thing you can can reconstruct all moments of a random variable off
its distribution and therefore you you know the whole distribution
in our case rather than having these exponential quantity here
we have a strict we have
a certain strictly positive definite kernels is even so-called universal kernels
and this thing here is actually an example of the universe can but they are
the university council
a slightly more general than
this is a classical concept
another interesting question that i'm not going to talk about is how to to study
this empirical mean will approximate the actual mean over the distribution that generated the data
this is something that can be studied using methods from statistical learning theory and then
we will find that subject to certain conditions we get a nice convergence with the
rate of one over the square root of the number of observations that we seen
so that's nice because in this case we can we can do things like testing
for equality of distributions
based on empirical samples so this problem called the two sample problem the two sample
problem amounts to testing whether a given two samples x and y so given two
sets of observations from two different distribu of from two distributions p and q
so we only given the observations and we are supposed to decide whether p and
q are identical different based on these observations
and you can imagine that
so we can do we can compute this kind of difference for the samples and
you can imagine that if we notice that for the samples x y for these
sets if it turns out that they have a very large different these two empirical
then with certain probably certain probability we can also say that the actual distributions are
different and therefore we can decide this two sample problem so that's also related to
existing theory and there's a lot of things that i really don't have time to
talk about now but maybe kanji will get back to this problem
so there's a second area
but actually i'm also not going to talk about this instead i would use the
the remaining five minutes maybe to tell you something about the so-called representer theorem which
is also basic results
from the kernel methods
and then maybe we have a few minutes for questions before play maximal announcements about
the summer school
so what's the representer theorem
the representer theorem tells us something about the solution of certain optimization problems that come
up when you train
kernel machines
and here says assuming we are given a positive definite kernel
we still call our inputs x
and we have a training set of size m
suppose we have a strictly monotonic increasing real valued function lambda which we use over
and an arbitrary cost function
so what's the cost function does is given are labeled points x i y i
and given the predictions that all function makes on these lines cost function will assign
some cost values so alex when i was talking this morning about the square error
the square there will be a special case of this kind of course function
so we have but here we have a fairly general class function that given some
candidate solution to the problem f would tell us what's the cost on the training
so let's look at this function part and this is what people call the regularizer
so overall this thing is called an objective function
and a lot of learning problems consists of minimising objective functions
so basic probably almost all the machines are like this you have some objective function
and you want to find a function f from a certain class of function minimizing
this objective function and points out function in this case is the reproducing kernel hilbert
space associated with our concave so we have this problem and it turns out that
the solution under these conditions the solution f
of this problem
admits a representation of this form
which is the kind of form that we've been talking about all the time when
we talk about the space weather surprising thing about this expansion is that these kernels
are centered only on the training points
so here we have an general optimisation problems with the property that
empirical loss of the training hours only evaluated on the training points that makes sense
because it's the training error and here the second term is something related to the
norm of all function in the reproducing kernel hilbert space to monotonic transformation of but
so if this is our cost function then the solution
lives in the span of the kernel sitting on the training points so it's surprising
because we are we working in potentially infinite dimensional hilbert space we only find many
training points and then i'm telling you the solution actually lived in the finite dimensional
subspace that's nice because it means that this kind of optimisation problem to find the
function that minimizes the objective function
this kind of optimisation problem infinite dimensional space can be reduced to an optimisation problem
where we optimize only all functions of this form
so that's quite useful in many domains and that's why will briefly going to look
at it
let's take a look at the proof
so to prove it
we first decompose maybe eventually here on the screen
we decompose
are an arbitrary functions of hilbert space into two parts one part is supposed to
be in the span of the
kernels sitting on the training points
in one part which is orthogonal to it
we can always do this because it's a hilbert space
so this is the first part of its in the span of the training points
this is orthogonal and because of orthogonal
it's not all
kernel and on training points to this equation here is true now let's apply this
function to an arbitrary
o point six
see what happens
so if we apply this function takes a
we point evaluate it we can do that by taking into product
because we know the curve represents point evaluation
so we take the dot product between this function and k sitting j
we use the fact
the first substitute is and we use the fact that the product ontology engineering
so the first
the product this
and this thing here
the second term b dot product between this thing and this but we know that
that's zero from here so the second term vanishes so what we're left with is
this going to be here
the crucial thing is that this quantity is independent of the particular part of the
function f
so first so that means if if we start with an arbitrary functions and we
want to evaluate its cost according to this objective function then if we were only
interested in the first part whatever is orthogonal to the training points we could just
as well throw away doesn't make a difference
OK so now let's look at the second part
so the rewards of
so let's look at this this quantity you
is it
you can say
to say
and this is
just right
OK thank you can hear me
thank you very much for having me here
i think this is my first time at ICML i've course many ice in all
papers but i don't think i've actually been to the conference before so it's great
to be here
let me just start off by acknowledging a bunch of lab members including one former
lead member tom griffiths who is now
faculty of berklee i just want to all of these people have made some contribution
to the research i'm going to talk about here
i want to highlight the charles kemp over there in red because the most of
the good ideas and hard work in one minute talk about come from charles' thesis
czech he's just about to graduate and then he will be starting a faculty position
at CMU
so if you if you like these ideas you might look
now i don't i don't think i need to tell this audience about the probabilistic
revolution in machine learning and AI more generally across
pretty much all subfields of a i may most prominently in machine learning but including
vision robotics natural language expert systems reasoning planning
the field's been revolutionized by the adoption of sophisticated mathematical techniques that give principles and
in some cases efficient and certainly effective methods for dealing with uncertainty in particular for
trying to make inductive inferences from very very ill posed problems very an ambiguous data
but if you look at what you know i i would say what sort of
the informal survey of the leading practitioners of the state of the art probabilistic AI
machine learning most of them would say
but there is that they don't think there's any necessary connection between the math these
probabilistic methods and the way the human brain actually learns and increasingly as statistical machine
learning has become more
mathematically sophisticated in these up until a few years ago there's been less and less
of connection between the field of machine learning in the field of human learning to
me that's too bad because someone who sits between these fields have been was saying
i think we still have a lot to learn from each other i hope i'm
not the only one i i i want to start here with quote that
zoom in rome over email
when he was inviting me to speak and we talking about topics he said many
people in machine learning get into the field because they are interested in how humans
learn rather than how convex functions are optimized and how we can get machines to
be more like humans so i hope that he was representative of these much of
the audience here and i hope that there will be some interesting insights to be
to be had from this interdisciplinary discussion
now the particular problems that we're working on here are what we like to call
everyday inductive leaps these are problems where
sort of this essential core problems of human learning where people seem to learn so
much about the world from such that apparently such limited evidence
classic examples that have been studying for a while as you even mentioned are basically
problems of concept learning in categorisation so to take a paradigmatic example consider child learning
their first words like this is sort of rough reconstruction of my daughter learning the
when she was a year and a half old we went out to the country
for thanksgiving western massachusetts and from just a few experiences like this scene of course
paired with an excited label from one of her parents horse
she was able to grasp this concept and pick out
and if not perfectly almost perfectly other horses you know she might be confused about
the occasional kaur
four camel but more less got this concept from just one or a few examples
if you want to think about it just for the simple mathematical abstraction
there are some you know basically infinite set of objects out there in the world
it really is infinite if you think of all the horses you could draw
and if of course this concept is going to generalize to draw on horses as
so this infinite set of
all objects you could
preceding an infinite subset of that
which you could say is the subset of horses and somehow child learning word like
this is able to grasp more less the boundaries of that set from just one
or a few
randomly chosen points with that's a stunning achievement and we want to understand how it
could work
in case you forgot what it's like to be a child learning word let me
give you an example of a sort of a demo of the experiment was done
in our lab where we try to put human adult
in the sixteen kind of situation so you're on the planet because you
these are some of the because you being objects and we're going to give you
a few examples of various words in the gives language
so let's
show you a few two first here now even
i think if i think if i'd only just given you one example and certainly
giving you three examples here but you've never seen the word to for before seeing
most of these kinds of objects before you have a pretty good idea
of what things are too busy which are
so let's try this out for the audience participation part of the lecture
just yell out is that the two for yes and no
a little more and certainly there
that's good because our model predicts that
so you get the idea
the the problem of generalizing for a few examples isn't just about learning words and
concepts all that's one of the main places where comes up but also comes up
and we studied in other contexts such as learning causal relations relation between cause and
with what kind of scientists call theory of mind learning about the internal mental states
beliefs goals plans of other agents from observing their behaviour or for example learning intuitive
learning intuitive theories that govern our psychological world social world social rules and conventions into
the physics
all of these are versions of this kind of problem just to give one another
example which will come back to time permitting at the end learning cause-and-effect right so
we all learned in our
most basic statistics classes that you can't infer necessarily causation from observing the correlation right
could be confounders and hidden variables and things like that directionality isn't so clear with
with more recent developments in causal bayes nets argu there are some cases now you
can infer causation from correlation
and there are modern kinds of techniques for controlled experiments which allow you to do
this under intervention but think about the case of the child learning causal relation or
or inferences we make all the time we're often just one or a few examples
did with the right kind of pattern of suspicious coincidence can strongly suggests causal relation
when again from just one or a few data points you couldn't even computer reliable
correlation right so the problem isn't going from correlations to causation but rather observe are
inferring causal structure when you when you have so little data you can't buy these
conventional statistical means even computer reliable correlation
so how can you solve this problem well
in some sense the answer is pretty simple and we all know that is right
if you're learning a lot from little data it must be because in some sense
you already knew alot you must have some strong prior knowledge is an inductive bias
this is the lesson that the field of machine learning has learned and taught quite
well right
pretty much any paradigm for machine learning has some version of the idea that there
there i think that
if you really
i know this entry is i've seen and i've seen that is whether conditions lighting
and there's also contains sliding we also try back is all the time
you know
just to summarise the textual portions of the talk page about what function and to
me was surprising lessons on working everybody's last few years is that it's actually really
hard to specify reward functions on i think it's important demanded enforcement to encompass have
as well
as well as ideas of learning dynamic small and i actually see a lot of
problems in robotics especially when you can't come over the dynamics model
but somehow humans can learn to do it and then after alpha able to do
so to by some way on and you know a recurring theme in how we
do a lot of these has turned out to be prince
there other articles out there that
i guess it in there
sort of encouraged me to put it back on so kind personal thoughts and then
you know how home show you the story of how i to work on robotics
i used to do fairly theoretical work and
because that was a paper that still and jitendra malik pointed me to that strongly
influenced my life and the way i think the research and the way i transforms
whereupon my wife show this to you just as the personal story and on them
just as they have and definitely not suggesting that anyone else should think the same
way as i do not recommend want be bad idea everyone wants to know if
you have all the messages from say well this is how i tend to do
is just one piece of work is strongly influenced my thinking
this is based on property who's writing about databases but that story to two to
how cars and a high rates you know someone has a bad idea of building
mail delivery robot right so that's something we all agree once we have the robot
to deliver the mail into offices every day this this could have also time so
on their papers on these twenty five years old i imagine very much all the
one on the on trying to build robot
the nature center prague as is then you know what happens we now on to
figure out what i think that what we need to build them out of the
robot well obviously any obstacle avoidance because you will navigate the hallways of office buildings
to deliver mail not in objects and you need robot motivation so the robot can
pick up me on those and drop them off in your office
and i'm going to alice like that on to know that you know these circles
are done in support of the males are well so each of these circles to
represent one research paper or one research idea one research community was sometimes entire research
conferences on that is how
science progresses right
to do obstacle avoidance on we obviously need object detection to detect the obstacles in
the path of the robot and we need navigation the robot navigate around obstacles the
saxons is actually how we do it but i mean i my since i we
and we do this on our robots today
do object detection
you know on many of my on on many robots around the world cameras are
by far the cheaper sensors and so on what you like is on and what
the problem even in the environment is that the lighting often changes right so if
lights on after the sun is different place on you like colin variance the robot
can still recognise it as podiums same thing even those who makes all the different
so one thing that really holds object detection of what is going to be a
little bit in invariant to the to the illumination
so it is that well on his love everything work recently on similarity learning in
which i would like to understand given to RGB vectors of the the pixels are
these the same colour not so can
you correctly recognised the same object even though the illumination has changed little since the
learning free dissimilarity i things very promising approach is
to really understand freely similarity learning
on i things most as a were is on understanding the differential geometry of the
manifold sitcom on developed the most probable ck sound algorithms to
analyzer can make sure the conversion of all these good things
and you can tell is going
and eventually the guy
working on i mean that i have no idea what that is and you know
this guy sitting out there in some you know isolated lab in the middle of
nowhere on thinking that maybe is hoping on to military robots the reality on the
guy working on this slide began work that's is actually not relevant she thinks is
applied to that there really is not doesn't quite apply that special case of quite
apply and you kind of years maybe holds the whole system is also there made
of stories and so
and that's not because i think real theory i think of all the most high
impact work in
if if you
limit yourself to trees
where the edges all on one side of the of the
the words and don't cross each other that's called the called projective trees i can
give you more formal definition but that's sort of the simplest
we say it
the graph the graph is restricted to be on one side it's completely plainer
the edges never cross and this actually works very well for english you can explain
most of english this way but
occasionally we really want crossing are so this is an example of a non projective
tree a talk is scheduled on cats ears today
perfectly good english
nobody's going to jack because this is the linguistic stock
on cats ears is attacked that phrase is attached through on to talk causing a
crossing link or nonprojective arc
nonprojective seems to be much more important in some languages than others
choosing not to be not to use it not to model it is perfectly OK
but you might sacrifice and accuracy
in doing so
so we've been doing sort of progressively as i've shown more and more these problems
is we started the top and talked about words which you can mostly c
now you should be skeptical of course you can completely see them but mostly and
we just move down we've been moving down to deeper and deeper structure so now
i'm going to i'm gonna
got a little bit lower
i'm gonna show picked my version of what's called linguistic pipeline and what i want
you to be aware of is that as we go deeper and deeper and try
to analyse more and more of the structure of language we're getting what we're getting
further and further away from the particulars of the language itself and more into physical
and cultural nonlinguistic things that language is really about
OK so this is this is sort of breakdown maybe in the field of linguistics
plus plus a little extra so up at the top just imagine the iceberg superimposed
on how to do that later but imagine the iceberg superimposed over top of this
at the top we have the the acoustics the the phonetics which are the physical
properties of speech the sound waves that are moving from my mouth into your ear
or the the orthography units of writing that i that i put down the pagerank
slide that you can read and then we start getting to things that are harder
to see and we have to reason about more carefully like the units of sound
the structure of words the structure of sentences morphology and syntax so what i've been
talking about mostly so far and then we get down into this thing called meaning
what is what is a sequence of words actually mean what is referring to in
the world what is it's what its literal meaning or what the active communication which
are intended
when i say can you pass the salt
and as you literally a question about whether you're capable of passing sort
i want you to do something and i'm conveying it to you in a polite
way that you're not meant to interpret literally and further we go down there's there's
discourse which is i say something you say something in this case you sit there
instantly awkwardly because this lecture scenario there's there you can pass this course which just
one person speaking as well
as we move down we're getting farther and farther from the things that are easy
to observe
OK so i'm going to go a little bit further
and you start to see everything come apart at the seams
the problem of meaning would be to convert descends into some kind of canonical meaning
representation language so if i get robin swam across the river and delivered the message
i might pass this into two sort of predicates like swimming delivered there were two
events one in which somebody was swimming who swimming a around which is the agent
and she's which is when should swim through she one through the river that's medium
and i'm sort of making this up as i go the agent is the technical
term but you can you can sort of assign these semantic rules to the arguments
of each predicate
you can convert this into some kind of first order logic i took a stab
at it you might disagree
with exactly how to represent this in first order logic there are a lot of
things in natural language that you can represent this way but nobody quite agrees and
nobody feels like this
these representations are quite everything we need to represent the meaning of language
so i'm going to say first required there's no consensus yet
it's good exercise coming in finding the semantic structure we don't know there there are
a lot of things on the table
the semantic roles are one that's getting a lot of attention this year was part
of the college conl shared task at the natural language learning conference first order logic
expressions have always been around a case where there was a little bit of a
resurgence there are a few recent papers out of MIT and then there are other
things that people have proposed for very specific problems that often what you have is
if you have a particular problem you want to solve people will design a problem
specific meaning language so for example i had a student who is interested in automating
understanding of cooking recipes
so it took us about three months and we sat down and we designed the
meaning language for cooking recipes which is a fairly low dimensional space you have to
talk about everything in the world only a few things in the kitchen and we
came up with the primitives and we were able to do it without a whole
lot of work
but it took three months and then we had to annotate
and people don't always agree about what a recipe means
so so you can see why this is not getting quite as much attention it's
maybe a little less hard is figuring out which real world entities are being mentioned
in text and where
so here's here's a piece of text from the news recently you can guess who
it's about might be a little bit more helpful
to understand if i highlight the things that are being referred to
OK so you made all the policies right
so exploration is a different subject so we are not
doing and is and any learning here we are not exploring it adjust their mathematical
problem right now
i want to know the existence of an object there exists an optimal policies so
this is independent of any learning procedure
that is not shown to be non that it's it's known for the mathematician right
this is the definition given in this environment the expectation is assessed with respect to
the environment
no just at least one
that's enough
OK so what's certificate
so that that would not be any difficulty OK so there are two difficulties one
difficulty is that if the maximum is taken here on
and let's sidestep difficult to so let's assume that the maximum mistake
at every
state x
so that's what the what does it mean doesn't mean that there access the policy
that that is optimized
it just means so far that given stem state
you can find the policy that gives you the optimal value from that state
then how does it follow that full that there exists the a policy that she
the optimal value at every state
so there is a difference between assuming the value at a single state
initiating value at risk
this is what i wanted to emphasise
so the optimal policy has to be science that
it achieves the optimal value at any stage
no matter you start
so that
the ideas
OK so maybe we should
is it true
OK so this is very simple
because what you have to do is is that you want to have a policy
that's optimally at the state and you have policies that are optimized for any single
and you just combine them together holding the combined them together what will be the
resulting policy
so there is result does the resulting policy act
the resulting policy activism histories say that OK i mean the state
i my coming from i'm coming from the initial state over there
the optimal policy corresponding to that state was this and that
how does it act
i just follow that policy
so if you remember your start position
you can use that knowledge to
there exists an orbital to my policy policy that's optimum for every state
so that's easy
at least
OK so
before going go further into detail of terry e
some applications so
i don't have much time but not the less so
there are
a very large number of applications mdps
the main fields that people are studying and the operations research econometrics you know studying
economy and
maybe money investment and stuff like that
conference that the stakes in our various applications and games in the iron i listed
some of these applications here
there are many more
come to that
the OK OK
this is what started
we said that mission that the status of the book but we see that we
do learning we don't really need assumption or we are not going to make that
but you need something close close enough to that still
the OK so
by the way
applications not like
i just possibilities applications that people have already tried and the bees and
various learning methods and they were pretty successful
and so i i not listing here and the success stories but but there are
quite a few success stories or the of suffering first
you want to know that there are many variants of mdps so we consider discounted
and it is but you could have and on this continent and the
it was just thought i expected
return on this continent returned like in the navigation problem
if you
modify the problem in such a way that was the goal state is reached
the agent
stays that no matter what happens so there are elections left
phase there and doesn't receive any reward and this is again about defined problem
if you want this is just a generalisation of the shortest path problems
maybe to infinite state spaces and
the problem was stochastic as well so
for this reason this is called the stochastic shortest path problem
there are other criteria like the average reward criterion when about up this con thing
you just
in addition to this trick
we're using local connections which removed a lot of parameters that we didn't know how to train
we also use trick called weight-tying
as yet another scheme
for removing additional parameters that we don't have to train
so if we don't have a lot of data we have very few parameters representing the
neural network
and the basic the idea is
that we want to constrain or whole bunch of elements in w to be equal
so rather than having a hundred three parameters
maybe we could have just ten but those ten parameters show up at multiple locations in the matrix
the reason that this works is because images for example tend to be stationary
so the features that we think are going to be good for recognizing things on the left side of the
are probably going to be good for recognizing things on the right side of the image
and it turns out that you're working on an application that's not true
if you're working on application where you know that the left and right side of the images are
very different
then you should be wary
of using these tricks blindly
the basic idea is
going back to that sort of one example
before what i had was have all these neurons are arranged
or in this
spatial direction
and each neuron
for each location in the input i've got several neurons looking at that at
that location
and only going to do is say that the parameters for this neuron over here that specify
how it depends on this input window are going to be required to
are going to constrain them to be equal to the parameters for these neurons next door
even if we have a constraint we can still have a whole bunch of different kinds of features
because you have many different neurons looking at the same locations and still have different parameters for
so this is sometimes called convolutional
neural network
because if you set the step size between these windows one
you can think of it is being
taking that filter that represents a neuron parameters sort of convulsing with your image to get all the neuron outputs
so we see a convolutional neural network
you can just think that
as a regular neural network
with these local connectivity and weight-tying tricks at idea
it's not it's architecture necessarily
so some other things that you'll definitely come across that make a big difference
things pooling
so if you work on computer vision systems you probably you've probably work with pooling architectures
like a bag of visual words
and we can basically build these
as just another functional unit just another one of those black rock on black box modules
into our neural networks
are so for example
we could have some pool neuron here
represented by h and it's again just going to look at some local window inputs
like the neurons from the last few slides
but instead of computing say linear function
and it's going to compute something like maybe two norm
or max norm of the things in the window
and if you take the max of all these neuron responses then you can represent invariant feature
because if one of these neurons turns on
regardless of which one this will output
the value of the largest and if
thing that you're recognizing activates different
neurons in this group
this neuron at the top will still stay on
and as a whole bunch of work trying to figure out what are the best kinds
of pooling functions how do we train them
for example
when you first start out it's worth recognizing that you can just fix most of these things
to pool over a fixed set of
a fixed set of neurons
but there are also algorithms actually learn how those should be connected up and so forth
as well
contrast normalization turns out to be a pretty handy trick so again
and the computer vision literature
turns out if you contrast normalized things can be very helpful
because sometimes you have
inputs that differ in scale
or in contrast and it's just not useful and can confusion algorithm
again even though this is sort of
computer vision centric idea turns out to be useful in a whole bunch of places
and you can think of it as just another black-box module
as long as we can compute gradients are of the output with respect to the input
we can just drop this in any of our networks
so it turns out
that i think i told you so far so the back-propagation
a bunch of different tricks for making the optimizer work backprop
and these
two or three different components that are more specific computer vision
are enough to build
which is currently one of the sort of state of the art systems
in not only in the deep learning world in computer vision world
so alex krizhevsky sutskever and hinton have this
pretty amazing neural network
trained on gp use
from millions of images on imagenet
and is currently the top performer in the imagenet challenge
and the main components of that
modulo few details is
convolutional neural network using this local connectivity with weight-tying
we just talked about
max-pooling to give you some invariance
to represent invariant features
using these rectified linear units
that i showed you earlier just a non-linear function
contrast normalization and the local connectivity i said before
and it's really just tall neural network trained with back-propagation momentum these tricks i talked about
according to to independence assumption the product of the individual
probably it
so for each class
so we have an object
which is described by number of features
and we compute the probability that the object belong to the class
so we do actually we
this probability
the highest so we do actually
so this is likely cause
it doesn't affect your
thank you
because the time only the best
last point may be the two best classes
so we don't take it for you just call
right image page and also with small zero probabilities
but usually used in practical implementation we also for rank
we can
the location of the value
and of rules can be
well it's translated into the local of the some of the company so we use
the equations that implementation
now we can also
have a normal life forms
the other thing is equation
i integration not press somehow
would be microsoft powerpoint
i tried to get it down
i didn't see equation so there
the value
can actually be normalized
so taking into
well computing
this probability for each class
and why
of the class so we normally you might say that the range of the key
we have well
the probability that a certain class of critics prior probabilities
we have to estimate the
and also we have to estimate the conditional probability that feature words maybe our case
given us
so there are two months
a binomial of model
and we
you know by
we just
consider the option
whether or not feature of curves in the
one of
one of our feature vector by
the future of course not
among we take into account
the fraction of time diffusion occurs across all ages
which means that if we take it would cause
i find in an object in the document
some information
we take into account that occurs five times that we say well we consider the
yorkurbandb that feature across all the edges
so which we have here that this position independence assumption
because we not take into account the position of
so here i don't know if you can read the
but i will go
so this is my
it's a very simple implementation for multinomial model
training and testing now this is not your mother if you do information extraction
they were quite well
so that's why
i told him that are
so we have
so please don't you
which i would have to classify the document d
so the class p and the document d
so we have a look at the end
fact vocab from document set
this of course comes from and you look from information that people might have mind
it designed for classification of documents based on the terms that occur in the document
so you
so that's why i had
feature that
it's called the vocabulary of like items
consider not
so you've got to number of documents which gives you
and then for each club
you come the number of documents
in that same class which is called the
and have a
if we are trying to estimate the number of
consequently classified by the number
and that's what
you compute the conditional probability of that term
it's only one
they also talk about them mean the paper on drug networks
the same conception most method allows classification of drugs by their mechanism of actions based
only on the properties of their mutual interactions between drugs
so all of those problems
the real problems on very large scale in which you can
you can model of them as problems of a bicluster
i want to do it
that's why
by perspective of the world not to develop algorithms but
prove theorems
i mean so that was trying to do and if you want to prove theorems
the first thing you have to do is to have some precise definition of what
is the goal of this by class
it turns out that in many of these applications no such
objective function have been formulated so
here is a sum
potential candidates
because functions
objective function that you may
so is the formalisation of the problem
our input is a matrix
of entries in a lot of size n times and we can also consider matrices
with real valued
input of a discrete set
other than zero one but let's for completeness
just concentrate on c one
and we have two parameters which can which indicate the number of clusters that we
expect to see in the rows and the number of clusters that we want to
create in the columns
what do we want to output we want to output a partition of a set
of columns and the partition of the set of roles
now the question is how do we define
the quality of such partition of such a pair of partitions of set biclustering
and there are several ways of defining quality and here is one of them which
we call the minority cost
and what we do here
in this course is
we sum over all blocks
and what do we do in every block i look at all the entries
that belong to this block so i'm looking at the i j
all the entries in this blog
such that
the label
in this entry
it is different than the majority label of this blog
so kind of time counting as
any entry in the block which is different in the majority of the block
if i have nice matrix
or something
and now i partition my column
and rose into blocks and say that
these are my blog so i account i have no what it is
on this blog is if i have
equality between zero and one then i consider half of them as errors i mean
i just look at one labelled and ask yourself if a kind of this block
is once how many entries are going to be
miss classified
and in this not have too many quality blocks so let's make it like this
so into this block the majorities one
so i have to have somebody this block
i have two LC one l here
so it in
i some the number of entries which are in the minority value of the blogs
and take the ratio of this the total number of entries
so my goal is to make my blocks as emerging as possible and this is
one way of formulating this
so that's the minority cost
there are others
a possible reason below
objective function so that to because it is much genius covers maximal margin covered what
you want to do is you want to partition it in such a way that
the maximum number of entries is covered by purely homogeneous
so this is a good block and all the other blogs and the question is
how can i arrange my block such that the size of the total size of
the good blocks is maximized
and they treat all the genius
on the non which is blocked as if they have background noise
so you want to try to explain as much of the matrix as you can
we appeal
blocks and the rest of it due to noise and you want to maximize
the size of the explained a portion of course we can take some kind of
middle ground between these two
types of requirements
and the other one is the mean minimum weighted variance and this is mainly applies
two matrices with real valued entries
and in late like the
the gene expression make
so what you want is for in every blocks so now we don't have his
it was once they have written and so
in every block i can look at the value and
you can look at the variance of this blog
and i want to minimize the but the talk to the sum of the variances
of the blocks
i want to have my blocks as centered around the
average as possible
so far we invited mattresses consider this
and when i say weighted variance a way the violence of each block by the
size of the block
and they want to minimize the
a weighted sum of the variances in the blogs
so all of those
reasonable size objective functions they we consider
we can view it i mean there are several ways of viewing what are you
doing here but one interesting way of doing it is the only the compression you
have initially
the matrix has size
n times and you have intense in many entries once rearrange
the good charlotte
it's already going
so you see
we have the current
and vertically
we have the voltage
and so it takes about the second
go from zero
this goes from zero to four vols you see that the current is beautifully
i'm looking down on my reflection that's interesting
well doesn't allow for that
so you see how beautiful many that so now
you may have great confidence
in ohms law
i don't have any confidence in ohms law
the conductivity
is a
strong function of the temperature
if you increase the temperature
then the time tall
between collisions
goes down because the speed of these free electrons goes up
very strong functions
of temperature
and so if top
goes down
then clearly
what will happen is that the
computing will go down
and that means
road will go up
so you get more resistance
so when you read out the substance
the resistance goes up higher temperature
higher resistance
sort of moments that the resistance are
becomes a function
of the temperature i call the total breakdown
because i are
a total breakdown of law
if you look in your book
they say oh no no no no no breakdown
you just have to just the
resistance four different temperatures
that's incredible performance way of saving all that
very badly
the temperature itself is a function of current high and the current i in the
and so now you get ratio
the divided by night
which is no longer constant
it becomes a function of the current
that's the end of vauxhall
so i want to show you
but if i do the same experiment i did here
but i've replaced biological
o fifty ohms it's a very small light bulb
when it is hot
fifty ohms
when it is cold
so are called the light bulb
roughly seven hours i believe
but i know that when it is hot
it's very close to fifty ohms
because of the low
what do you expect no
you expect now
the resistance is low in the beginning
you get this
and then
and the resistance goes out
you you get this
i may end up a little higher current because i think the resistance the load
fifty o
and if you see curve like this that's nowhere near any more
that's the end
of the well
and that's what i want to show you know
so all i do is you have this little light those of you sit close
they can actually see the light bulb
glowing but that's not important i really wanted to see that
the first is i is no longer linear there you go
you see every time this is libel going
it's up and running the heating up
the resistance increases
and the end of small for this libel but will find
forty other sister but it was not find
for this libel
there's another way
but i can show you
was law
it's not always doing so well
i have on the twenty five vols
i was applied
these hundred and twenty five goals
the potential difference
and i have like
you see here
the light bulb
happened is that the first the first nine people would say that sees the the
the closest mainland and then the last person would say same
which is again like
the pressure sort of time
i think they would be because becomes because they must undergo going long period of
time by
so these are like the flavor of the studies that that that are going on
and now
i want to
just a bit of of labour so for example a very basic question from model
this phenomenon is what's the probability of of adopting new behavior
i know as more of your friends
i don't so basically how does this influence propagation on you and there there are
the hypothesis that could could make right please the most evident ones are first one
would be like diminishing returns type of typeofgood right so if all x x is
a lot the number of friends i know quality on an ipod and y axis
is the probability that i go and buy and i i do something right and
the idea would be the more friends more friends of the more likely i am
to go and buy but
as as the number of the increases sort of the probability that in some parts
of the city for example one one hypothesis the hypothesis would be would be the
critical mass of some kind of this kind of behaviour you would say i don't
really care when only a few people
i don't own and i i i phone or ipod but once i know some
critical mass in the homes of the things i'm going i would also like to
go out of their behavior some
so these are these are two
i notified him of densities but
the only the only recently we were able to start to measure this so until
i two years ago
the sample size for which you can produce
you need to be the sample size to be able to produce this curve i
know small bars and only recently been able to start doing so and there are
a lot of questions that i mean i mean touch and the later on the
there's a lot more time behind but this is this is like a very basic
question about what if you want to have a model of how the whole something
spread over the network should be able to say how likely am my
to become idol to adopt some behavior or something as as more and more of
my friends
about the behaviour and
either the
it will be all over the world
or one
so i think this is a general philosophical question there is always this discrepancy between
machine learning models where i know all we care about is precision recall or whatever
you like that that these physics style models well
you want to know some
large-scale property to be modeled by by small and i think that's the question the
same question you are asking right i can always throw an SVM agreed and say
this is my position but
use SEM the model from life
explaining the process SVM is not the model even though
we have one hundreds of parameters and should work well
so i think it's here is the same as you can see what i mean
by by models here is something that may be that you would be able to
generalise across domains but then if you really want to go into other solid particulate
prediction tasks or a particular model does
mention should would go to more
i machine learning data mining type of models
is that
so all i want to say here is
there are these this let's say competing hypotheses and this will have a big impact
on how think about processes spreading over the networks and how to model
and now i want to touch on some of this money she's right there
two flavors of types of questions that people ask when they think about diffusion one
is about the virus propagation models where we want to see
two when we ask ourselves how how does it the
the this is spread over the network and the the
most basic or the most interesting question there is this what they call the wind
in the wires they taken so basically
so this is this is what are interested in whether the particular what that has
really take over the network or then there are two ways to describe what this
is or the basic ways one is the SIS model where which is something like
if write your subset susceptible because you become infected or in fact and after a
while he loved but as you like you can get infected right so this would
be so this is one model and the other one one is something like a
school essay
SAR where you become susceptible infected and you are covered remove so chickenpox or play
would be something like this right place the outcomes fatal and you removed from the
network with chickenpox is sort of become immune to the disease and these are the
two most basic models that people think about them
i will also talk about the diffusion models where i will touch on two most
classical of the and what people who
do that they are more interested in when does a particular person about the behavior
and so so so in the diffusion you sort of have control of over yourself
one virus propagation sort because you don't
let's go about
the virus propagation so basically the question is how do viruses propagate over the network
what will look at very very briefly is like from like while wires and the
question is whether you like
staying the network forever only to become extinct
and there would be two parameters with the reduced to
to describe
the devices so we have the virus but which would be like a probability that
a particular infected anybody affects the other
so here i have a small social networking let's say that disputed guys are infected
so with probability based on each one of the effects the
it is
but i haven't put in the story so i'm not gonna talk about that's all
these iterative methods multidimensional scaling what i want to talk about the is the machine
learning communities contributions and how they relate to what i've talked about so here's an
idea to get a nonlinear algorithm
so compute the distances
in a space that is non linearly related to the original data
we can use the distance we like so why don't we map to a non
linear space compute the distances there and then use the linear algorithm so this is
like the citric the banner was talking about where u nonlinear eyes and then you
do something linear and non linear space same trick it
i'm going to introduce
it's not always the same trick in the way it's being applied
although the kernel people would tell you know the nice thing is bernard's not his
so i can be very rude about can appreciate as long as the cameras not
switched off dialog and we wrote about sick is very important algorithm i
and it doesn't rely on this idea
but here is my interpretation of what's going on with it
so it should be i and after
let's nonlinearly map the data to a new space and compute the distances there and
we're gonna do this using basis function models i think these very nice simple models
and i'll show an illustration of this
so i provided moment so we may apply
a new representation and why i and we set up by the function why i
such that is a linear sum of some basis functions computed each why i and
the end basis functions and this is then the squared distance between that should be
enough i and j
absolutely late-night notation change
i have a common basis functions used is this what i like to call
an exponentiated quadratic
because it's not a guassian is also not squared exponential
and some people don't like radial basis function but it's got all these names
and it's just as we'll see in a moment and a little blob
now and then we've got these elements over
these basis functions which we can write as a matrix and we tend to write
these sort of things in the form of the design matrix for the set of
vectors so each
column of this
design matrix gives you evaluation of one of the basis functions all the data different
data points and error and columns
one column for each
location when computing the basis function so there's this location parameter u mu
which you have to make a decision about this which the basis functions so for the moment
we're gonna decided distribute basis functions uniformly along a one dimensional input we cannot assume that the data
as i mentioned reducing is one dimensional
i know that's a bit strange that that makes it easier to port
in matrix notation as i said all vector notation
we have this that they are
function of the data is given by w transpose phi i where this is
rho from thee
from this design matrix is so that's one of those rose and w is the weighting in vitro
okay so we're going to do this
mapping of the basis functions but where we now introduce a set new parameters which
is a little bit annoying because
what parameters should be used for computing this distance well
let's just generate random functions and look at the expectation that these random function so we're not gonna specify
values w is gonna specify probability density
and then we compute the expected squared distance is now the nice thing is that
if i minus the jay squared
is equal to this
so this is the basis function transposed w minus
the basis functions computed for the i th data point
in a product with w minus the basis functions computed the jay data point in
product w just using the notation there
multiply broken out
we can see it in this form
and now we take expectation of these square distances on the pier w
let's just assume that second moment this distribution we're not saying anything about the distribution
of haven't said calcium haven't said it's anything all i'm saying far second moment exists
and the second moment distribution is gonna be
the identity matrix
so the expected squared distances on the these random functions with projecting
is equal to this
basis functions minus about computer i minus the basis functions computed jay in the product
with themselves
if we also said that the mean this thing with zero the covariance of this distribution would be zero
now if you could think about it if you like but i haven't said
it could be anything at this stage actually show you
so illustrations i'm going to assume it's calcium describe the sample from something but it doesn't have to be gaussian
so is a set of basis functions
we think which one hand location parameter minus one zero one one
so that's the design matrix is
being computed now this is a visualization of the design matrix for every point between minus two into yeah
so what i'm saying i'm saying well to compute the distances we're gonna sample weight
vector three dimensional weight vector in this case it's going away that's a plus that's
plus back with some calcium waiting
and now give us a function and we compute distances on flat function
that's what that looks like so here's our input this is the original why
and where mapping from out why
two example one w
and it's given me this function here
and the distance between these two is given by the fact
and what we what we've written down is what the expectation that the square error
that's because we are interested in squared distances
so a mapping from
input why
two and not in a nonlinear way some space
given by some function space
okay so that's one sample but we're gonna do over multiple samples now look at
this was nice is that if these because this is a smooth function if these
inputs are close together here
they're actually gonna be close together in there as well
if there were further apart
so here
if they were the
zero and minus two then the distance without much greater not always at much greater
because it could be the but biggest by randomness
it could be closer on average the distances will be that much greater yeah
so makes sense clear
so doesn't seem like a good idea and will compute distances and that's space
so there is some other samples
again it seems like quite a good idea
i quite like the idea so we're gonna then do
classical multidimensional scaling on that's space
there is a slight problem with the idea because we located basis functions
minus one zero one so can tell me what's gonna happen if i have data
points which is why value is minus four and four
yeah will be zero apart when the same small distance apart
that's gonna be pretty bad so
here you go
if we got point just outside the span of basis functions
this doesn't work quite so well
well part but they'll always be zero
distance apart in the new space
she's annoying
so that's slightly problematic so this is very small despite the data being far apart so there's an issue there
and this is a side effect of bad basis function placement basically if you put
your basis functions over where your data was this would happen
zero then of course
why is it is also the things you see so these zero is is a
very simple visible point
so in this decomposition procedure usually is start from from from the zero vector is
you intend maintaining feasibility so so from one iteration
two another iteration your solutions always feasible
so we start from zero vector
and if this happens in the end
so you have to optimize
a lot of support i mean the number of support vectors uses all sorts of
only very few of length they are not zeros
everything is zero then
in this situation the composition is they work very well so we
we need to we need to have i want to be to select you stop
changing several components OK so maybe the first iteration change some of the second problem
here the end of the because up only a few are nonzero so it's very
possible that loss
but as you victories in front of using many components and they were changed
so you only touch this
the subset of components
in optimisation procedure but in a situation that this decomposition is going to be first
to this is an example
machine learning knowledge affects the optimisation procedure because it is an optimisation decision they
i don't think according to the loss minimisation is is good
but for this one
they have certain properties for sale
so that this is a practical procedure
so i can show you an example
so we training fifty thousand instances so you can see in some way
so we have a lot of iterations time for so many iterations it tough but
the total number of support vectors is
resulted of his own is much smaller than the fifty so this this is a
very good situation so very likely that you start from the zero vector and many
components and they were changed
so so these this takes five minutes
just go to the top
well you go go looking at the whole matrix q OK fifty by fifty seven
fifty thousand
just just just means calculations that may already know already take more than five minutes
so the reason is because number support vectors is much smaller than the number of
training instances
but of course it is
these may not always have have evidence in some situations
there are lots of issues
about this decomposition method
first we need to know how to select working set so that we should use
what is to be decide the size of the working set sort things at each
iteration you change how many variables we can change you only made as i said
there are only two variables but you can change more of course if you if
you change more than the course at each iteration is going to be hired by
the number of iterations may be small you only
there are a few very few components then the cost per iteration is it is
all about that number three since is quite high
i would be very tired
i think we would all agree
and if i stand here twenty four hours like this
but i would get very tired
i haven't done any work i might have reported here that
the table just
hold that
briefcase from so it's clear that you can get very tired
without having done
any work
what is the the way we define work
in physics
now let's go from one dimensions two
three dimensions is not very much difference as you will see
i go in three dimensions from point a to point
and i now have a force
could be pointing not just along the x direction but in general
in all the actions now the
work that the force is doing going from a to b
after dot dr
are is the position
in three-dimensional space where the forces at that moment and the are is small
this is from a
to be
the are here to go in this direction
this will be little fact dr are
and here
that would be an ineffective dr
and the force itself
could be like this
in the force
could be like is there
the force can obviously change
this past
so that the force
f of x
x roof was ever y
my rule
was f of c
zero of
a movie is a up a little
but it here
and that dr
general notation for vector dr
equals dx
x rule
plus the y
it was easy to you
cannot be any more general
so the work that this force is doing
when it moves from a to b
in the world
let's first
small displacement over the are
then i get the w
that is simply
dx scalar
this is the dot product
thus f y
was at seen
that is
the amount of work if the
four is this place over
distance dr
now i have to do the integrals
the entire
pass to get w
a to b
the integral going from a to b
i don't need it anymore
in going from a to b
now we home free
because we already that this
this is the one-dimensional problems
and the one-dimensional problem we already know the outcome
we found
it is one half
the squared minus the squared which in this case is obviously
the velocity in the x direction because this is the one dimensional problem and the
one dimensional problem indicates that the velocity that i'm dealing with is the component in
this direction
so we have
this is
one half
the squared
and this is the x component
minus the a squared and that's the x component is also one dimensional problem except
that now i deal with the component is the y component of the velocity so
i get one half and
time VB
y squared minus
y squared plus one half and
the square minus the a z
and our home free
because what you see here is you see these great
in the x direction create y component discrete component and if you add those three
you get exactly
the square of the velocity you get the square of the speed
so if you add up the three terms
you get up you get
the square
a lost more than put my hand in there
one half
time the squared
and here you see
a x created
it was created a c squared
the squared
and you get exactly the same we felt that you had before
namely that the work done
is the difference
in connecticut
you can always think of these
well as it is created
the speed is the magnitude squared
of the velocity
all right
i'd like to return to gravity
work on the three-dimensional situation
we have here
that is bx
and is busy
and is here this is the increasing value of y
and as you point eight in three dimensions
like this
and there is here
o point b
so you get a rough idea about this
three dimensions and y of b
miners while because h is to give to a high difference between eight and the
there's a gravitational force the object moves from a to b
i suppose it moves in some crazy way
because gravity alone could not do that there has to be to force if it
goes in a strange way
but i'm only calculating now the work is going to be done by gravity
other forces i ignore for now only want to know
the work the gravity is doing
you all that has a mass and
and so
there is a force and g
i can write down
force in vector notation it's in this direction
so now
i notice that there is only
value for f of y
but there is no value for f of x there is no value for
next day is zero
so f of y
equals minus gl
so if i calculate how to work
in going from a to b